For Miranda, the only thing worse
than being Charlotte's
34-year-old bridesmaid
was being a 34-year-old
bridesmaid without a date.
With the wedding approaching,
Miranda fell prey to the siren song
of a singles event.
Multi-dating.
$20 bought you seven mini-dates,
each eight minutes long
which is as long
as blind dates should be.
Hi. I'm Miranda Hobbes.
Dwight Owens.
Private wealth group at Morgan
Stanley Investment Management
for high net-worth individuals
and pension plans.
Like my job, been there five years,
divorced, no kids, not religious.
I live in New Jersey,
speak French and Portuguese.
Any of this appealing?
Sure. Portuguese, that's impressive.
Obrigado. What about you, Mandy?
Miranda.
I'm a lawyer at a mid-sized firm.
I was recently made partner.
I'm a lawyer.
I went to Harvard Law School.
- I'm a stewardess.
- Really?
But before the wedding bells,
there's the rehearsal dinner.
- You said you were a stewardess.
- I was testing a theory.
- The theory being...
- Men are threatened by good jobs.
- They don't want a lawyer. They...
- Want a liar.
I was the liar.
I'd finally ended my affair with Big,
but the guilt of lying to Aidan was
like a hangover I couldn't sleep off.
I'm just saying, as a lawyer -
a partner, no less - I got zero dates.
As a stewardess,
I got one for tomorrow.
- The correct term is "flight attendant".
- Not if you wanna get laid.
It's how you say what you do that
matters. For example, "I'm in PR".
Translation - "I give great head".
- What?
- He's actually an OK guy.
Harris Bragan,
emergency room doctor.
Yeah, but you can't date the guy now
because you lied.
I'd tell him eventually. If he got upset
he'd look completely shallow.
And it would make you look schizo.
Excuse me. I...
We...
See, mother, I told you
I'd become a "we" sooner or later.
This is a "wee" toast.
I'd like to thank everyone for coming,
especially the out-of-towners.
My cousin Caleb, who's in the
wedding party, came from Edinburgh.
Someone had to bring
the real Scotch, like.
I know what I'll be having later.
But the person I'd really like to thank
for showing up is this woman here.
I love you more than words can say.
Those who know me know I'm a man
of many words. God knows I've tried.
All righty, then.
Let's eat, drink, and be married.
- She's so happy.
- She doesn't have to be a bridesmaid.
We got off easy.
The groomsmen have to wear kilts.
I like the idea of men in skirts -
easy access.
Is it true that
they wear nothing underneath?
I'll find out and get back to you.
His name was Caleb, right?
Hi there. I'm Samantha Jones.
Caleb MacDougal, Samantha.
Pleasure.
- First time in New York City?
- Aye, and it's brilliant, like.
The architecture, the energy.
It is, you know.
Samantha could
barely understand him.
But if his tongue could do that,
she wondered what it could do to her.
I'd be happy
to show you around town.
That would be great.
Trey got lost bringing me back
from the Stanhope Hotel, like.
Samantha wasn't the only one
feeling lost.
- I'm thinking I have to tell him.
- Tell who?
Aidan.
I might have to tell him about Big.
- Why would you do that?
- I don't know.
Relationships are supposed
to be built on trust.
No offence, but that ship has sailed.
You're right. You have to tell him, but
not before the wedding. It's my week.
It's your day.
You get a day, not a week.
There's no reason to tell him.
Men lie about this all the time.
- And women find out.
- What if he finds out?
You fucked Big all over Manhattan.
Why should he find out now?
Could you not use
the f-word in Vera Wang?
If my boyfriend was sleeping
with somebody else for three weeks,
I'd wanna know about it.
I'd wanna have all the information.
That might mean more coming from
someone not posing as a stewardess.
What?
Nothing, but at your wedding we have
to pretend Miranda's a stewardess.
I don't wanna pretend anything. And
I don't want you and Aidan fighting.
Don't you think
this could be a little shorter?
- The skirts must the same length.
- Really?
- What about Trey's skirt?
- It's a kilt, and it's tradition.
Can't I ask you not to wear your dress
round your see-you-next-Tuesday?
My what?
- C-U-Next...
- Tuesday?
Oh, my God. Was that
a Schoolhouse Rock I missed?
If I have to be a bridesmaid,
I'd at least like to look good.
- You don't have to be a bridesmaid.
- Then why am I here?
Frankly, I didn't want you
to feel left out.
I would love to be left out. I could be
in bed with a hot Scot right now.
Fine.
- Don't do this.
- What? We're just being honest.
Honestly, I hate this color.
I started thinking about honesty.
Maybe the idea was overrated.
Maybe coming clean is the ultimate
selfish act, a way to absolve yourself
by hurting someone
who doesn't deserve to be hurt.
I cheated on a test
in the fifth grade with two friends.
They confessed and failed the class.
I never told anyone,
and it never mattered.
In a relationship,
is honesty really the best policy?
Evidently, dishonesty was
the best policy for Miranda.
As a stewardess,
she was a charming date.
Once you work first class,
you can't go back to coach.
- I imagine.
- Oh, yeah.
- No warm cookies in coach.
- You get to eat the cookies?
There's always some actress
who doesn't want her cookie.
Free travel, cookies -
this sounds like a great job.
You've got the great job -
a New York ER. I'm not saving lives.
You are, in the event
of an emergency.
Inflatable slide - I'm in charge of that.
But once we open the slide,
it's every man for himself.
That night, Harris got to make love
to a stewardess.
Miranda didn't have to fake anything.
- Wow.
- Yeah, wow.
I'd love to ask you to spend the night,
but I've got an early flight to DC.
The 5:00am-er.
I should get some rest too.
Saturdays at the hospital are non-stop
since roller blades were invented.
- Do you have a boy in every port?
- Every airport.
Seriously. I bet you're a heartbreaker.
In truth, it's a Ionely life.
There's a wedding I'm in on Sunday.
Days later, the four of us celebrated
Charlotte's last night
as a single woman.
I can't believe you're getting married.
Is this the beginning?
Are you next?
Oh, yeah.
I'm headed for a storybook ending.
The little girl had an affair, lied to her
boyfriend, and lived happily ever after.
Marriage doesn't guarantee
a happy ending, just an ending.
- The end of dating.
- All right then.
It's also the end of the possibility
that your next great fuck
is around the corner.
My next great...
- Yes?
- Say it.
...fuck is just around the corner.
I finally get to sleep with Trey.
- Excuse me?
- You haven't slept with him yet?
Before you buy the car,
you take it for a test drive.
I wanted to save myself
until we got married.
- Sweetie, you're not a virgin.
- I am with him, and it's romantic.
It's romantic until he can't figure out
where to put it in.
- No.
- What if he's terrible?
He won't be terrible. No.
He is an amazing kisser.
- Really?
- He's so sexy, and he loves me.
I want to do things to him
that I have never done to anybody.
The other night, I was thinking
of putting whipped cream
all over my body.
Low fat Cool Whip is the best.
It's less sticky than other brands.
- Low fat Cool Whip.
- You haven't slept with him!
It's been...
Too long! I am so horny.
Horny.
Those of us not getting married
celebrated with a booty call.
I'm so glad you called.
As soon as I landed.
Samantha's vertical Scotch tasting
that turned into a horizontal one.
I had no idea you Yanks
were so bloody friendly.
She couldn't understand him,
but understood he was hard.
I decided to crawl into bed with Aidan,
but he wasn't in his bed.
Hey, beautiful.
What brings you down here?
I was trying to surprise you.
You can't surprise a man with a dog.
I see that.
What are you working on?
- The wedding gift.
- This is for Charlotte and Trey?
You wanted to give them
a piece of my furniture.
You didn't have to make something.
We could have picked a piece.
I make all that stuff too.
I know, but this is too nice.
I wanted it to mean something.
God, I was about to get them
steak knives.
What does it mean?
- It's a love seat.
- That I get.
It's two different types of wood
from two different trees.
They blend together
and make it stronger, just like...
A mixed drink.
- Kind of like two people in love.
- Right, that too.
Are you gonna make fun of this?
It's really...
nicer than anyone deserves.
You see this piece?
This big old flaw right here?
It's not a flaw, really.
It's just the way the wood is.
It's interesting. Beautiful.
Flaws can be good?
Flaws are the best part.
This was the time to tell him.
I could feel the words inside me.
But if I told him,
could he still love me?
I wasn't ready to find out.
There was another
booty call that night.
Hi, sweetiekins.
Charlotte Yorke, are you drunk?
Yes. Yes, I am, Trey MacDougal.
And today is
officially our wedding day.
And I can't wait any longer.
Could we please make love
right now?
- Are you sure?
- Oh, yes, I am.
Take me to your bedroom now.
All righty then.
That was unfortunate.
Has this...
ever happened to you before?
Every now and then.
I just didn't think
it would happen with you.
It's no big deal.
Sometimes intercourse
just doesn't do it for me.
I can get the sails up,
just can't bring it into the harbor.
- Is there anything I can do?
- Yes, there is.
What?
You can marry me.
- I'm already doing that.
- I love you, Charlotte.
Sex is such a small part of it for us.
That's what I love about you.
It's not just about the sex.
Charlotte couldn't sleep at all
that night.
Neither could I.
All I could think about was
that I was a cheater.
I cheated and lied in fifth grade,
and I was still doing it.
- This isn't gonna work.
- What do you mean? Us?
I can't have you sneaking out at 3:00
in the morning for a cigarette.
I tried to quit. I just couldn't.
Well...
I'll just have to learn to live with it.
- You said you can't date a smoker.
- You're not just a smoker.
You're a lot of things.
- I'm not perfect.
- Oh, yeah? What's your flaw?
You tell me.
I don't know.
That was another lie.
I knew what his flaw was.
It was trusting me with his heart.
- Aidan, I need to tell you something.
- What?
But suddenly I couldn't tell him.
I was afraid he'd never
look at me that way again.
So I didn't.
I love you.
I love you, too.
- Let's go back and go to bed.
- No, I should get home.
My stuff's at home,
the stuff for the wedding.
I'm the maid of honor.
I need to be presentable.
I'll come with you.
No, stay here.
Just pick me up in the morning.
I'll get my stuff. I have to go.
Is this wedding black tie?
I don't have a tux.
The groom is in a kilt,
so pretty...
- What happened?
- I cut my finger.
Jesus.
It's OK. It happens.
You haven't made breakfast
till you've made it at 10,000 feet
in turbulence.
- It's really bleeding. Look.
- I saw it.
- What should I do?
- I don't know.
- It's deep. Do I need stitches?
- Stop putting it in my face.
- I think it's really bad, look.
- Stop it. Blood makes me queasy.
But you're a doctor. Aren't you?
- Not really.
- What are you then?
Assistant Manager of Athlete's Foot
at 81st and Broadway.
- You lied?
- I'm sorry.
I always wanted
to sleep with a stewardess.
For a moment,
Miranda considered coming clean.
But then they'd both be liars,
and he wouldn't have slept
with a stewardess.
You should go. I hope I never
have you on one of my flights.
- I wouldn't be on first class.
- No, you wouldn't.
I'm running late. Charlotte will never
forgive me. I need to...
What's that?
- It's the wedding gift.
- That love seat packs up nice.
It's a Polaroid.
You look too hot to be a bridesmaid.
I thought the whole point was to wear
a bad dress and be humiliated.
It's not that kind of wedding.
I thought maybe one day
I'd build us a love seat.
We're gonna be late.
I'm just gonna grab my...
I was supposed to be
at the church ten minutes ago.
You never let me hold you anymore.
- Why do you keep running away?
- I'm not running away.
What are you afraid of?
Aidan, I slept with my ex-boyfriend.
You met him at the furniture show.
Then we slept together.
I didn't tell you, and I'm sorry.
You slept with that guy?
When we were going out?
- Once?
- No, more than once.
He was married. It was a mess.
I don't know what I was thinking.
I wasn't thinking.
It's so over. And it was wrong.
I just hope you can...
Here. I want to be alone.
What about the wedding?
Just go without me.
- I'm gonna take a walk.
- Will you meet me there later?
- Please don't bleed on my dress.
- I'm trying not to.
- Here we go.
- Where is Carrie?
She'll be here.
Charlotte, my grandmother's necklace
looks beautiful on you.
- Could I escort you to your seat?
- Excuse me?
He asked
if he could escort you to your seat.
Certainly.
I guess it's time.
They do wear something under kilts,
but it's easy to get off.
The wedding was complete. Charlotte
had something old, something new,
something borrowed,
and someone Samantha blew.
- I'm sorry I'm so late.
- It's OK. I'm glad you're here.
Jeez, you look perfect.
Honestly?
Honestly.
- We should go. Come on.
- OK.
Despite all her bitching, Samantha
enjoyed being a bridesmaid.
Miranda, back to being herself,
found a last-minute date.
Carrie.
- I have to tell you something.
- Right now?
Yeah.
- Trey can't get it up.
- What?
- Last night he couldn't get it up.
- Was he drunk?
No. I was drunk, he was fine.
Then it must have been
wedding-night jitters.
He says it happens sometimes.
Since she was in the white dress,
I reached for a white lie.
Happens to everybody.
I should have slept with him
on the first date.
Maybe he jerked off
before you got there,
and he was
too embarrassed to tell you.
- I do love him.
- And he loves you.
Maybe he did jerk off.
If you don't wanna go through this,
you don't have to.
We'll just get a cab, and everyone
will just have to get over it.
No. I'm getting married.
- OK, go.
- OK.
Carrie!
Come here.
Don't tell anyone. Go.
OK, go.
Charlotte was 34, single,
and standing in a $14,000 dress.
She was getting married.
Not even a low libido could stop her.
- Could you hold this for a second?
- Sure.
Hey, you.
I walked around for about an hour.
Couldn't bring myself to go in.
I'm so sorry, Aidan.
I know that.
I never meant to hurt you.
I know.
But I did. I'm sorry.
Couldn't it be like the wood?
That's my flaw, and...
...and you're the other wood,
and that makes us stronger.
It's not that simple, Carrie.
I wish I didn't know about this.
I just wanted to be honest with you.
People make mistakes.
I just know myself. This is not
the kind of thing I can get over.
I just need to be
on my own for a while.
Me on my own.
I really loved you.
- Carrie, they need us for photos.
- OK.
I told him.
It's hard to find people
who will love you no matter what.
Here we go. Smile.
Everybody looks beautiful.
I was lucky enough
to find three of them.