Subtitles - Ripped (and Hacked)
by RavyDavy - Part of the [RL] Crew
Some outfits wait a lifetime
to be taken somewhere special.
The same can be true of people.
Hi, it's Aleks.
Stop packing.
They have clothes here in Paris.
See you tomorrow. Safe flight.
Hi, it's Miranda.
No, this is not
my 40th "Please don't go to Paris" call.
It's been three weeks. Is that funny yet?
Anyway, I got us a dinner reservation.
You're leaving at 9:00,
so we have to eat at 6:00...
which makes us senior citizens, thank you.
Or should I say,
merci beau "please don't go."
It's me. I'm in town.
Look, I'd really like to see you, so call me.
Same number,
and in case you've forgotten, it's...
Deleted.
After many more hours of packing...
I was off for our version of the last supper.
If Mohammed won't come to the mountain...
Hiya, kid.
Hi.
I was in the neighborhood,
saw your light on.
Can I talk to you?
Well, I'm late for dinner with the girls.
It's 5:45.
Come on, get in, it's cold.
Raoul, give us a minute?
No, it's okay, he doesn't... It's cold.
He's a tough guy, right, Raoul?
I'll tip like a Rockefeller.
I'm sorry for not returning your calls.
Yeah, I was starting
to feel like a needy chick.
Did I do something to piss you off?
No, it's...
I've just been busy with other things.
Look, I know I freaked out about us
the last time I was here.
No, it's fine.
- You were amazing to me, and l...
- You were fine.
Would you let me finish?
And since then,
I've been thinking a lot about us...
You don't have to do this, okay?
There's really no point.
It's all fine.
Raoul's freezing,
and I have to go meet the girls.
Got it. How about dinner tomorrow?
Drinks?
I'm starting to feel like that chick again.
I won't be here tomorrow.
I'm leaving for Paris tonight.
Paris?
- You're finally taking that vacation?
- It's not a vacation.
I'm going there with a man
that I'm in a relationship with.
He's wonderful, and I'm happy.
So please don't feel bad about anything.
Goodbye.
Wait. What do you mean, "goodbye"?
I have to go.
Carrie, stop!
What are you doing, saying goodbye
and jumping out of the car like that?
Are you moving to Paris?
When were you going to tell me?
- You're not even going to tell me who he is?
- His name is Aleksandr Petrovsky.
You're moving to France with a Russki?
- Come on, it's a joke, Carrie.
- You do this every time!
Every time!
What, do you have some kind of radar?
Carrie might be happy,
it's time to sweep in and shit all over it?
What?
No, look, I came here to tell you something.
I made a mistake.
- You and l...
- You and I nothing!
You cannot do this to me again!
You cannot jerk me around.
- Carrie, listen, it is different...
- It's never different!
It's six years of never being different.
But this is it, I am done.
Don't call me ever again!
Forget you know my number!
In fact, forget you know my name.
And you can drive down this street
all you want...
because I don't live here anymore!
Sure, now that I'm with someone else,
now that I'm leaving, it's "different."
- You know who he is?
- Who?
The boy who cried love, that's who.
And just like in the fable,
it's too little, too late.
Love? He said he loved you?
No, it's...
It's an allegory. No, look, my point is,
he's been doing this for years. Years!
And I'm done with it.
- Then just put it all behind you.
- It is behind me.
I'm mostly upset about
him ruining my last night in New York.
Well, fuck him!
And, you know, I never say that.
- Would you like another cocktail?
- No, I can't be drunk on the plane.
I want to arrive stunning
and impossibly fresh-looking.
Okay.
Ladies...
Stop, really, you're going to make me cry.
She didn't even say anything yet.
I know what's coming.
I want to thank you all
for wishing me well tonight...
in spite of some of your personal opinions
about my leaving.
Me? I've never had an opinion in my life.
You guys, stop. Please.
Easy there, waterworks.
Today, I had a thought:
What if I had never met you?
Let's pull it up, shall we?
- I'd like to show my face here again.
- Yes, the tears have to go.
All right, someone say something
not sentimental.
Chemo might have kicked me
into early menopause.
Task accomplished.
You cannot believe the hot flashes.
I can barely keep my clothes on.
Really, what was your excuse
before the chemo?
I'm going to miss you, you cunt.
Wow, even "cunt" didn't stop her.
It's me, leave a message.
Manhattan Towncar for Bradshaw.
Car number 221, downstairs in two minutes.
Ladies, I know it's getting late,
and we all need to get up for our pilates.
- More hot decaf?
- Are you insane?
But hang in...
and I know we can make
this breast cancer benefit our best ever.
Mona, the goody bags, tell us.
Thanks, Sheila.
Okay.
First, we have the pink-ribbon
breast cancer cookie.
- Oh, Jesus.
- What's wrong with the cookie?
For the past five years, every fucking
breast cancer benefit I've been to...
has had that fucking breast cancer cookie.
I don't care about a breast cancer cookie,
and I had breast cancer!
Point taken.
And?
Some of the women coming to this event
are battling cancer.
They need something more inspirational
or outrageous than a fucking cookie.
Is it hot in here?
Well, the cookies are donated,
so we're having them, but you're right.
We do need something inspirational...
and outrageous to give to these women.
So, I'm giving them you.
Excuse me?
I'd like you make a little speech
before you bring me up.
- But what would I say?
- Something inspirational.
Something you think they'd like to hear.
But...
my husband's parents, the Liebermans,
are coming...
so please try not to say "fuck" so much.
Could I get some water, please?
Fill it up.
A little slower, s'il vous plaît.
- But of course. American?
- New Yorker.
Je m'appelle Carrie Bradshaw.
I'm staying here with Aleksandr Petrovsky.
Very good, Miss Bradshaw.
I believe Mr. Petrovsky is
in the salon right now.
Yes.
The luggage?
Thank you.
- Carrie, you're here.
- Hi.
So nice to see you.
I want you to meet my daughter Chloe.
I'm sorry, all I got was, "It's 10:30."
- You don't speak French?
- Well, I'm learning, but...
Chloe was saying
that she's having a bad day...
and she wants to kill herself.
She's a bit dramatic.
Boyfriend troubles.
Well, that's my department.
So tell me all about the bum.
Papa tells me this is your first visit to Paris.
Well, not if you include movies.
But I can't believe I'm finally here.
I almost screamed when we
drove by the Eiffel Tower.
Terrible.
It was tolerable before,
but now with that light show at night...
hideous, just hideous.
I wanted Chloe to meet us
for drinks tonight...
but the only time
she could give her old papa...
is from now till this afternoon, so...
You two should have your day alone.
Interpreting for me
is going to cut your time in half.
I can unpack and take a nap...
and try to get on Paris time. Okay?
Also, I have to meet some people
from the museum for an early dinner.
But I'll eat light,
so we can go out then, okay?
I'm in Paris. Don't you worry about me.
See you.
- It was nice to meet you, too.
- Thank you.
- Where am I going?
- 625.
Ten hours later...
all dressed up, and no Petrovsky to go.
Where is the recommendation
from your friend, the judge?
Here.
And Carrie left hers at home,
so I can pick it up when I get her mail later.
It's amazing, with all the unwanted children,
we have to do this.
This private adoption
is a very competitive market.
More competitive than China?
We've got a year's wait on that list.
Honey, God is going to send us a baby
from somewhere.
And it's just our job to file all the papers...
and to just be as aggressive as we can,
up to the point of obnoxious.
Amen.
I'm sorry I'm late.
This museum dinner
turned into this big, long thing...
with the exhibit sponsors...
and other patrons, riffraff, blah, blah.
Sorry.
- Why didn't you call?
- I did.
You had the "do not disturb"
on your phone.
Right.
I forgot.
Did you sleep?
- Did you get enough sleep?
- Yeah.
It's dinnertime in New York.
You look like dessert.
What's under your millefeuilles?
Millefeuilles.' a thousand layers.
One, two, three...
four, five, six...
seven, eight, nine, ten...
Oh, my God! Stop!
"If you want to see the face of breast cancer,
look around you.
"It's the woman next to you
at the dry cleaners...
"the nurse in pediatrics...
"the single mother
picking her child up from school."
Are you sure the heat is off?
Fucking chemo.
Where was I?
"She's the woman with the knowing smile.
"A smile that says:
"'I beat cancer, I can take on the world!"'
It's good?
What is that?
It's kind of stiff.
- I thought it would sound more like you.
- It's an inspirational speech.
At AA, the most inspirational speakers
are the ones who keep it real.
Keep it real?
I'm speaking at a black-tie benefit,
not chilling at P. Diddy's crib.
I'm just saying, the truth is powerful.
Look, you may know AA, but I know PR.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I simply must stick my head in the freezer.
After a week in Paris, I'd decided
my French was now strong enough...
to brave the ultimate test.
A day of shopping.
Fine, I'm fine.
Oh, my purse.
I'm fine.
Someone has been shopping.
I fell. I fell in Dior.
So I decided that the more I purchased...
the less they'd think of me
as the American who fell in Dior.
- They don't think like that.
- Not anymore, they don't.
This is the shopping equivalent
of a lobotomy.
Poor baby.
My purse went flying.
I had to scoop everything up.
I came all the way from New York
to squat and scoop in Dior.
I didn't even bother to check and see
if I had all my credit cards.
Well, apparently you had one.
One that I won't be using again
for many, many years.
Oh, no.
- No, oh, my God.
- What?
My Carrie necklace was in here.
I put it in here, and I don't see it.
It's not in here.
God, no, I can't have lost
my Carrie necklace, no!
- Was it insured?
- No, it's not like that.
It cost nothing, but it's...
It's priceless.
I've just had it forever, so...
Hello?
Is it too early?
Carrie, hi! How's it going?
I'm really upset.
- What's wrong?
- It's nothing serious, I just...
I lost my Carrie necklace.
It's gone, and I'll never be able to replace it.
I got it at that street fair
when we were all together.
It just makes me so sad.
Sure, I understand.
Well, no one in Paris seems to understand,
or at least they don't understand me.
Come home.
I can't come home.
I've only been here a week.
So, aside from the necklace, how's it going?
Well, you know, it's hard.
It's harder than I thought.
I don't speak the language.
And it's too cold and rainy
to walk around all day.
I've been to every museum twice.
I don't know, I'm just sort of lost.
Where's Aleks?
Well, the exhibit is taking much more time
than he thought...
so I'm alone a lot.
Come home.
That's ridiculous, I just got here.
I'm serious, you sound really upset.
No, I'm just being a baby.
You know, I lost my necklace...
and I saw these girls having lunch and...
I just thought how much I miss you guys.
We miss you, too.
This is absurd. I'm in Paris.
I've wanted to come here my whole life.
I just have, you know,
too much time to think.
What does that mean?
Can I tell you something
you won't use against me...
when I feel better and everything's great?
Yeah.
I keep thinking about Big.
About...
what it would be like
if I'd come here with Big.
Hello?
I'm still here.
But that's just something I do...
when things aren't going perfectly
with any guy.
I compare him to Big.
God, this French phone
is saying something that I don't...
Listen...
If you want to see the face of breast cancer,
look around you.
It's the woman next to you
at the dry cleaners...
the nurse...
in pediatrics...
the single mother
picking her child up from school.
I said inspirational, not perspirational.
She's brave...
she's capable...
she's you.
Oh, fuck it, she's me.
And if any of you are
having hot flashes like I am...
you deserve a fucking medal.
Bad enough I lose my hair, now I have
my face running down my couture.
Oh, to hell with it.
That's better.
Hey, it's me, leave a message.
It's me.
I know you said you never wanted me
to call you again, but I'm still in town...
and I don't know if you're even calling
this number, but I had to call.
I figure at this point I've got nothing to lose,
except you.
I can't lose you again, Carrie. I love you.
Hi, it's Charlotte.
And her computer
was just sitting there on the bed.
Well, I know I haven't been your favorite
over the years.
- I wouldn't say that.
- I would.
Well, God knows
I've made a lot of mistakes with Carrie.
I fucked it up many times.
I know that.
Look, I need your advice.
You three know her better than anyone.
You're the loves of her life,
and a guy's just lucky to come in fourth.
But I do love her.
And if you think
I have the slightest chance...
I'll be on the next plane to Paris,
I'll roam the streets until I find her...
I'll do anything.
But if you think...
that she really is happy...
well, I wouldn't want to wreck that for her.
And I'll be history.
Go get our girl.
And what is that?
Oh, my God.
I know this is not the Carrie necklace,
but it's a necklace for Carrie.
These aren't diamonds?
Let's just say I wouldn't throw it around
in your old purse.
I hope this will cheer you up.
- Want to try it?
- Yes!
Okay.
- It's all right?
- It's lovely.
Listen, I know I've been busy.
As soon as the exhibit opens...
it'll be just you and me, I promise. Okay?
Carrie, this is Andre, my best friend.
- Remember, I told you about him?
- Oh, yeah.
Ripped by RavyDavy
part of the [RL] Crew