Okay, this here's the dough mixer.
You gotta get in there, really scrub it...
...hose it down every night.
Keep the bugs out.
Because someone found a roach in
a loaf of wheat once and sued.
- Can't you just spray it with Raid?
- Then you got poison in bread, kill 100.
Is that good?
Oh, Jesus.
I gotta get to my chiropractor.
Hey.
Think anyone's
ever had sex in here?
Now, why the fuck would
you even think that?
Romano?
Romano, are you okay?
That was...
You made the weirdest noise back there.
If I were you, I would not
get into a weird-noise contest.
Oh, yeah?
Oh, boy.
I love this song.
This, really?
Yeah.
My dad had all these
old big-band records.
It always reminds me of...
I don't know, being a kid.
Still being blissfully ignorant
about what a sick joke life can be.
I would've pegged you
as more of a fan of...
What? Sting?
U2? You know, grew up in the '80s
but too straight to be into the really...
...hard-core punk stuff.
- Oh, yeah?
I suppose you were into
the hard-core punk stuff.
I think it was just the heroin talking.
Oh, man, I love that look.
No, I really should go.
Mom and David and I are having
some sort of family meeting...
...to discuss whether we should
sell the business to Kroehner.
God, I hope we will.
Why?
So that I can get the hell
out of here and go back to Seattle.
Why don't you come with me?
Why on earth would I do
something like that?
Because you are my woman.
- You're out of your mind.
- Oh, yeah?
How come my name is
branded on your ass?
I love that look.
You don't understand
how serious this is.
We're under siege by
a major corporation.
- Stop being so dramatic.
- Mom, it's a fact.
David, we all have problems.
This oat bran is stuck on here
like cement...
...because you didn't soak
any water in it.
Listen to me.
Kroehner is pressuring our suppliers...
...to demand money upfront.
Now Continental Caskets wants us
to pay...
...for anything we put in the show room
before we sell it.
That's thousands of dollars.
Your father never let these things
get to him like you do.
He never had to deal with
this kind of situation.
I'm sure things will work out.
They always do.
- No, they don't.
- Good morning.
What's going on with you?
Nothing.
You're not leaving here until you
put some food in your stomach.
I'm starving.
Are you bulimic? Is that what we're
going to have to deal with now?
Mom, apparently you want a child
with an eating disorder.
Morning.
How was your run?
I haven't gone yet. I stayed over
at Brenda's last night.
No one cares where you were.
Why do you have to tell people
every single thing you do?
Sorry, I forgot we're all supposed
to live under a shroud of secrecy.
So I think we should sell.
I'm not saying that just because I don't
want anything to do with this business.
Have you looked at their offer?
A lot of money. Stock options?
Do you have any idea
how arrogant you are?
You don't get to decide
what we're doing.
I own half, Dave.
You haven't spent the last
11 years working here.
You didn't give up
anything for this.
Is this really what you want...
...or are you trying
to make a dead man happy?
We should have this
conversation later.
- Why can't she be a part of this?
- Thank you.
Nate, this is all I know.
Stay and run the place for Kroehner.
Go to law school like you wanted.
Take my trust fund.
I'll take the cash.
I think Nate's right.
Who knows how long any of us has left?
We should do what makes us happy.
Fine, sell, what do I care?
- You mean it?
- Sure.
Let's just invalidate my entire life.
I'll go to Gilardi today
and tell him our decision.
Oh, I don't know.
I guess the one with the satin interior.
Ma, there were five with satin interior.
Let's just go with the Classic Regal.
- I liked the White Pearl.
- The Classic Regal will be fine.
Who cares anyway?
My Tommy was cut up into 50 pieces
by a big, giant dough mixer.
Oh, Ma, Pop wasn't
in that many pieces.
Ma, he's gonna look just as you
remember him. Right?
It says in your brochure you have
a gifted restorative artist. Whatever.
Can he make sure Pop look good
enough for an open casket or not?
Because you know,
we'll go elsewhere.
You'll be completely satisfied
with our work. I guarantee it.
Humpty Dumpty, huh? Train tracks?
Dough mixer.
Can you go to St. Joseph's
to pick him up?
Not today.
It's my cousin Ramon's baby's
christening. I told you.
I'll give you 50 bucks extra.
A hundred.
I'm the godfather, David.
Shit. I can't go because
of Mrs. Bond's viewing...
...and Kroehner told Marty
if he does our pickups...
...he'll lose all their business.
- So send Nate.
You know, I know he hates this shit,
but he's your partner now, right?
- He's, like, in a lot of pieces.
- Humpty Dumpty, I know.
Careful, that could be his head.
- Jesus.
- Or his pelvis.
It's probably his head.
- What happened to Rico, he get canned?
- No, he's just busy.
You new over there?
No, I'm just a temp.
I heard old man Fisher kicked.
You know him?
Not really.
Hey, no offense, pal,
you might want to call your agency...
...and ask for a new assignment.
- I'm already on it.
Hey, Gabe. I looked for you in the quad
this morning, but I didn't see you, so...
Maybe you stayed home because
you were tired or something, but...
Anyway, I just wanted to let you know
I was thinking about you and...
Not in any serious way,
I was just thinking about you casually.
Okay. Bye.
I wanna kill myself.
Hey, Morticia!
Foot slut!
It's such a fucking easy decision for him.
And then Mom takes his side.
Big surprise.
It's like I don't even exist.
Like me giving up law school
meant nothing.
So fight. If you really want to keep
the business, don't give it away.
See, that's just it. All day long, I've
been feeling this incredible sense of...
Relief.
I don't know if I want to keep it.
I could do anything. I'm still young.
- Right?
- Are you kidding? You're still a baby.
What about that one?
That's a little Mayberry for me.
Something simple and clean.
Like the ones that hang
in a deserted truck stop...
...when that handsome
drifter blows into town.
Of course.
What about that one?
Not bad.
I could see Ava Gardner
lying beneath it...
...plotting to steal Clark Gable
from Grace Kelly.
People start their lives
over all the time, right?
- That guy just cruised you.
- Really?
Bitch.
Right in front of me,
like I'm not even here.
He did?
And I missed it?
Oh, sorry.
- Oh, Ruth.
- Amelia.
Another casserole.
Lemon bars.
The kids will love them.
Don't you have candy striping today?
I did, but I told them
my best friend needed me.
- You've made the right decision.
- I know.
I never realized how much money there
was to be made in the funeral business.
Death-care industry.
And it's only gonna grow,
with all the baby boomers and all.
- Gee, there will be bodies everywhere.
- Hopefully.
And all in final resting places
provided by Kroehner.
With a little help from Fisher & Sons.
You know, we've had our eyes
on your operation for some time.
Your father was a nice guy, but he
didn't know how to run a business.
Well, my dad was never
in it for the money.
I think he was more concerned about,
you know, helping people.
You wanna help people,
join the Peace Corps.
- Yeah.
- Greedy little Nazi fuck.
So how exactly will this work?
We won't change the appearance
of your unit at all.
Maybe a little cosmetic upgrading,
perhaps.
But preparation of loved ones
will now take place...
...at a centralized location,
which services several other units.
Technicians on staff,
constantly producing.
So it's like a little factory.
Of embalming.
Preparation for visitation.
- We maintain a small fleet of vehicles...
- Hearses?
- Funeral carriages.
- Dead wagons.
Removal vans.
Once you centralize operations, you'd be
amazed how you maximize profits.
So in the end, we're all just
human McNuggets.
Just as we began.
I like you, Nate.
You hear that, buddy-boy?
He likes you.
Wow, you are so cool.
Your initial payment, sir.
The rest will follow after both our
lawyers have held up the process...
...Iong enough to justify their fees.
In the meantime, we'd like to send
a facilities inspector out to...
...take a look at things
as early as next week.
You know, like the president.
- I'll see you later.
- Yeah, all right. Later.
Hey.
What's going on?
You fucking asshole.
Why is my car covered with
words like "toe sucker"?
I... I don't know. L...
You didn't, for instance, blab to
your friends that you bagged me...
...and that I sucked your toes?
I might have told one person.
Andy. He just... He asked me what I did
the night before, so I told him. I mean...
It's not like I thought this
was gonna work out...
...because I know nothing
ever works out...
...but I guess I just wanted
to enjoy this for a little bit.
Instead, the whole world's calling me
"this little piggy lover."
I'm sorry.
I mean, come on. So what?
- So it got out. Who cares?
- Know what I wish?
I wish that just once people wouldn't
act like the clich'es that they are.
This can go to Goodwill.
And this...
And this one too.
Maybe Nathaniel's clothes
are too dull for Goodwill.
- Does Goodwill ever refuse anything?
- Ruth. If you want to cry, cry.
- What are you talking about?
- Just let it out. That's why I'm here.
For the last time, I'm fine.
I just think it's very interesting. You're
supposed to be making two piles.
One for Goodwill
and one for memories...
...and yet you have not
held on to one thing.
The memory pile was your stupid idea.
What can I do with Nathaniel's
old clothes?
Make pillows, a quilt?
I ought to just burn them all.
How can someone with so little
clothing have so much clothing?
What is this?
Nothing.
It's stupid.
Something about visiting the pyramids,
taking ballet lessons?
I wrote down things I might
want to do now that I'm...
- I have more time.
- Well, I think that's wonderful.
No, it's not.
It's stupid. I don't even want to do
any of these things.
I just did it because
some book told me to.
- What am I, gonna be in Swan Lake?
- Why not?
You see stories like that on the news
all the time. It's inspiring.
It's depressing. It seems so desperate.
Maybe it's a little desperate.
Besides, who knows?
It's always possible
you might meet a man.
That part of my life is over.
You're supposed to flip this mattress
every two months.
I do mine every 14 weeks.
Well, I can't remember ever flipping this.
It's probably been 20 years.
Come on, get up.
You haven't finished going
through Nathaniel's clothes.
Ruth.
Ruth, how can I help you?
You can lift this up with me.
An uncovered mattress is so sad.
Help me turn this over!
All right.
Okay.
Does it feel any different?
No.
Save our park!
No more money for politicians!
Money for parks!
Save our park!
What are you doing?
You have a gift.
You can help people.
Fine.
Go back to peddling soy milk
and nailing waitresses.
What do I care? I'm dead.
Move it, asshole!
Save our park!
So now you don't want to sell.
- I know it sounds crazy.
- No, not at all.
We'll keep the business for the rest of
the day, then sell it again tomorrow.
- Hear me out.
- This is a good system.
We'll sell in the mornings,
keep it in the afternoons.
Sometimes, we sell again in the evenings
when we can't make a decision.
David, you're not being fair.
When I didn't want to sell,
you could've cared less.
When Nate doesn't, you listen.
Okay, I'm a terrible mother, who's
responsible for all your problems. Happy?
So you had some revelation, and
now you wanna be a funeral director?
- How long is that going to last?
- He does have a point, Nate.
- You don't always stick with things.
- You can't be in the same room...
...with a dead body.
I know, but there's a reason for that.
This is what I'm supposed to do.
Which is why I've spent so much time
running away from it.
My whole life, I've been a tourist.
Now I have the chance to do some
good instead of just sucking up air.
I know it's a lot to ask of you, I know,
but I just really think that we can do this.
You and me, together.
Brothers.
Like we used to be.
We could still sell to Kroehner
and both manage Fisher & Sons.
Yeah, but then we're just
spokesmodels...
...working to make fat Republican
stockholders richer.
Kroehner doesn't give a shit
about people. We care.
- We can help them through their grief.
- This is a business, Nate, not a charity.
Of course it's a business, but...
...it's more than that, and you know it.
Okay.
Great.
I'll call Gilardi and tell him
he can kiss our collective ass.
Language.
Maybe Dad knew what he was doing.
You did not have to waste this stuff
on me.
Oh, please. My parents got a case of it...
...from some TV movie they
were technical advisors on.
Some serial-killer thing for cable.
Oh, they're such whores.
They'll do anything.
Gosh.
Can you believe this
stuff is expensive?
You know, I've always wanted to tell off
some corporate suit, some...
...greedy little
Nazi fuck, you know?
That's very hostile.
No, I was very diplomatic. I just said,
"Thanks, but we changed our minds."
What did he do?
He didn't do anything.
What's he gonna do?
- This is completely unacceptable.
- The Baxters changed their mind.
- They're going with the Unger Mortuary.
- Was there a reason?
They probably just underbid you.
Hal Unger never underbid anybody.
He moved to Florida. They were
bought out by Kroehner months ago.
Sign here.
You know...
...I didn't just decide to stay in
Los Angeles because of the business.
- I had another reason.
- Oh, please. Don't ruin this.
- I've got such a nice buzz going.
- It was you.
Nate, get serious.
- It's true.
- No, it's not.
You're staying here because
you found something you want to do.
I am the extra bonus
that probably won't work out.
Sometimes your honesty
gets really tiresome.
- I don't want any children.
- Who said anything about children?
I was referring to you.
I got something for you.
Open it.
Glenn Miller Orchestra
at the Hollywood Palladium.
Brenda, this is so cool.
I've never been to the Palladium.
You grew up in L.A., and you've never
been to the Palladium? Pathetic.
These are for three weeks from now.
How'd you know
I wouldn't be in Seattle?
I didn't.
Morning, Rico.
Just what I need, another boss
breathing down my neck.
Put me to work.
Hello?
Pregnancy's kicked Vanessa's hormones
into overload. I gotta talk her down.
If you wanna help, take Mr. Romano
out of the bag and put him on the table.
Remember, breathe through
your mouth, man. He's pretty ripe.
Oh, Christ.
- Nate.
- Great, look what you made me do.
Oh, gross.
I want to talk to you
about something.
I don't know if you noticed, but I'm
a little busy swimming in a man's guts.
I don't know what this is.
I'm picking up a part of a person,
and I don't even know what part it is!
Fine, I'll talk to you later.
Oh, God.
Sorry.
What the hell are you doing?
I work here now.
I have to be a part of things.
Let Rico take care of him.
I have a job for you that's much better
suited to your particular talents.
Morning, Nate.
Lovely day, isn't it?
I've seen better.
I only wanted to say hello,
seeing that I'm your new neighbor.
We just bought that house
across the street.
Got it for a song too.
Oh, and by the way, we're planning to
put you out of business in six months.
They're opening a Poseidon Society
across the street?
That's right.
What is a Poseidon Society?
They sell cremations, cheap cremations.
Now, for a fraction of what we charge...
...you can dump off the relative
you never really liked...
...at the Torch Mart across the street.
I guess we have to just
continue to do our best.
And how exactly do we do that?
You know Lou the florist,
that sweet old guy?
He just upped what
he charges us by 200 percent.
And that chemical dealer
on Figueroa is now suing us...
...over some nonexistent
shipment of cavity fluid.
Every other supplier that we have
in common with Kroehner...
...suddenly developed
some problem with Fisher & Sons.
For some reason,
by the name of Kroehner...
...the Health Department
is going to inspect us next week.
Yeah, so what? Isn't everything clean?
Yes, but any inspection means
we have to update something.
If it's the ventilation system, we're sunk.
We should've sold.
Nate? I'm having a problem.
You don't happen to have
Mr. Romano's foot on you, do you?
Do you remember picking up the foot?
I think so, but my eyes were shut,
and I was trying not to vomit.
I'm not happy.
Well, that's very interesting, David,
because I'm ecstatic.
Maybe the morgue
never gave us that foot.
Both feet are listed
in the paperwork, Nate.
Just think, Nate. Is there
any other point you could've lost it?
- Lost what?
- Nothing.
If you lost something, look under the
bed. That's where things always turn up.
- I doubt that applies in this case.
- That's what people always say...
...then they find what they're
looking for under the bed.
- Mom, we're really busy down here.
- The upstairs machine is broken.
I called the repairman but...
Oh, my God, what is this?
Someone left a Kleenex in their pocket,
and now it's all over everything.
It's disgusting.
Nate, retrace your steps.
Is there any other point
you could've lost the foot?
I almost dropped him at the morgue,
but the bag didn't open.
I tripped on the stairs,
but nothing fell out.
Banged into the freezer.
Spilled him onto the floor...
- And I picked him up from off the floor.
- It should be here.
I'd say it's an $8 million lawsuit.
At least.
- Here she comes.
- Like my new shoes? They're size 12.
Toe slut.
Amelia?
It's me, Ruth.
Your best friend needs help.
Is he all put together?
- Oh, he's 100 percent there.
- Absolutely.
I'd like to see him.
I'm sorry, our embalmer
is a little on the artistic side.
He gets crazy if he has any input.
It's best to wait until
we're completely done.
One more thing.
His shoes.
- What are you, an idiot?
- Those are his favorite shoes.
He has perfectly comfortable loafers,
which would be much more appropriate.
Yes, I myself have loafers
which are just like walking on air.
We should've just
told her the truth.
"Sorry, Mrs. Romano, but my idiot
of a brother lost a part of your husband."
Yeah, that would've worked.
Where are you going?
I have someplace I have to be.
When I return, I hope to
be greeted by a foot...
...a solution as to how to stop
a billion-dollar corporation...
...from putting us out of business
and pruned hedges.
- Aren't you glad you're out of the house?
- Yes, this is just what I needed.
We should try and get a seat
right in front.
- I'm placing a bet.
- We should just try and enjoy the day.
I don't see why we need to gamble.
That's sweet.
You both look so happy.
It's just an act.
Just enjoy it while it lasts,
which isn't very long.
Excuse me?
You think you have forever,
but you don't.
Soon you start to get on each
other's nerves...
...then you don't tell the other person
as much as you used to.
What's the point?
You thought they understood you.
- But they never did, not really.
- Ruth.
Finally, not only do you not
tell him anything real...
...you actively start lying to him.
Then when you think it can't get
any worse, he up and dies.
- I think I see a shorter line over there.
- Bye.
No matter what you do,
you end up alone!
Not knowing who you are
or what you really want!
Ruth, Ruth, why did we
come here today?
To have fun. Aren't you having fun?
I think it's wobbling.
It just looks like it's wobbling because
you've been staring at it for so long.
It's definitely wobbling.
You're hallucinating.
Life is strange.
If one of those tiny screws
isn't screwed on tight enough...
...that thing could fall
and kill us instantaneously.
Just chop us to bits like a Cuisinart.
And an assassin with a semiautomatic
could walk through the door...
...and spray our brains all over the place.
The sun could become a supernova
and engulf the entire planet in flames.
David Fisher.
We just got a call from Claire's school.
She's in trouble.
- Can't Mom handle this?
- She's MIA.
And besides, I think you might be
interested in what they told me.
What? Start from the beginning.
Jesus.
Okay, I'll be right there.
Until then, tell Nate to...
Oh, great, he's MIA too?
All right, bye.
There's a rumor going around school
that my sister put a dismembered foot...
...into some boy's locker.
- Shut the fuck up.
She did it. I know she did.
Where's the foot now?
I don't know.
The student who found it...
...denies that it ever happened.
- Okay, where's your sister?
No one knows.
A police report has been filed...
...and now Mom is supposed to meet
with the principal.
I don't understand kids.
When I was her age, I never
would've taken a foot.
David, I can help. I'm a cop.
That's what I do for a living.
You find feet?
What the fuck am I gonna do?
Tell me who lived here again.
The Fritzens.
I have totally fucked things up.
Kept us from selling.
Now we're gonna go under, and it's
because of me. I'm a fucking moron.
You used to hang out over here?
Jeannie Fritzen and I used to play in here
after school. Both her parents worked.
Brenda, this is serious.
My entire family could go bankrupt.
So swallow your pride,
go back to the corporation and sell.
They'll cut their offer in half now,
knowing we're so quick to buckle under.
Plus, I really don't wanna let
that greedy little Nazi win.
Oh, so this is a pissing contest?
Nate, I'm going to kiss you!
I lost someone's foot today.
Sorry.
I really thought I had, like, this...
...profound revelation.
Fuck, if this isn't what I'm supposed
to be doing with my life, then what is?
Living it.
And you're doing that, so relax.
You don't give a fuck about
what I'm going through.
Sure. As much as I can, given we've
known each other less than a month.
There's no big investment. I mean, that's
part of the appeal for both of us.
Right?
Jeannie Fritzen tried to kiss me
in this room. I wouldn't let her.
- You can't control things. Nobody can.
- Shut up.
There's only one thing that's certain.
- Everything changes.
- Shut. Up.
I already talked to the cops.
I don't understand why
I have to go through this again.
- Because this time I want the truth.
- Man...
A witness already said she saw you
running down the hall...
...screaming the crazy funeral-home
girl put a foot in your locker.
It was a joke. It was just a joke.
She's kind of a loser,
and we all pick on her.
- She totally asks for it.
- Modern technology is really something.
- I don't care, man.
- You should.
We have chemicals we put on your hands
to see if you've touched human remains.
No way.
You want to tell me
what really happened today?
L...
Who's that?
That's my partner.
You better be glad you don't have to
mess with him.
That guy's into some crazy-ass shit.
Now, either you can tell me
where you put the foot...
...or you're gonna be dealing with
that crazy-ass motherfucker.
Big Shirley by a nose!
She won!
Oh, God, I just can't believe it.
I won $ 16.
I told you this would be fun.
- How much did you win?
- I don't know.
- Four thousand.
- Four thousand what?
Dollars.
And by the way, I had an affair
with a hairdresser last year.
- You did?
- Yep.
Are you a cup?
How many cups are you?
I'm a loaf of bread.
Hello?
Okay. Talk slowly.
I'm gonna see you in a few hours.
Slow down. Slower.
Well, you're gonna have to wait.
- Because you have to.
- Brenda.
Just stay there.
I'll call you in a half-hour.
- Promise?
- I promise.
- Who was that?
- Nothing to worry about.
- I gotta go.
- Brenda, who was it?
Just someone else, okay?
Just back off.
I can't deal with this right now.
I'll call you.
I'm glad you're staying in town.
- He threw it out of his car?
- He was taking it to show some friends.
Then it hit him,
he might get in trouble.
What with people not supposed to
be in possession of others' feet.
- He tossed it out.
- I've gotta get home.
Just drop me off, and I'll
pick up my car later.
All right, I'll take a look
where he said he tossed it.
- You don't have to do that.
- Hey, how can I sleep?
Knowing that there's
a foot on the loose?
- You lost $25,000? It's just gone?
- I suppose it still exists.
It's just not mine anymore.
- I'm waiting for an explanation.
- Don't talk to me like a child.
I was on a...
What do you call it? A roll.
So I kept betting more and more,
and I just felt so good...
...like I was living someone else's life.
I was up $9000!
And then I started to lose.
And then I started to feel like me again,
and so I kept betting more and more...
...and losing more and more.
- You should've been more careful.
I don't want to be careful.
I want to feel alive.
There should be a way to do that
that's a little less expensive.
I have a right to make mistakes, Nate!
You of all people shouldn't
begrudge me that.
What?
I lost $25,000. Okay, you got it
out of me. Now leave me alone!
Hey.
Claire?
- You're David's friend.
- Keith.
What's going on?
Not much.
So where's Claire now?
I gotta say I'm totally relieved.
That I didn't lose it.
Hey.
Nice job, Rico.
- Thank you.
- Boy, they did do a marvelous job.
They ought to, they charged a fortune.
Can I assist you, Miss Romano?
I know it's silly...
...but I just wanted to see with my own
eyes that Pop's all put together right.
We get to do that, don't we?
Okay. Good.
I think I'll be able
to sleep much better now.
- Rico, you gave him a foot?
- Yeah. Yeah.
I thought it was for the best.
Remember that leg of lamb
that your mother had...
...in the back of her freezer for forever?
- Okay, stop.
Embalmed, wrapped in latex
and duct tape.
I was following him home
to get it back when I saw him toss it.
Now I've been here for
hours, and I can't find it.
- Describe it to me again.
- It's a foot.
Why did you take it in the first place?
Well, at the time, it seemed like a good
way to pay him back for something.
I just wanted to shake him up.
I don't understand how guys
can be so unshakable.
I know what you mean.
Did you ever suck a guy's toe?
Yeah.
Me too.
Have you been
watching Mrs. Romano?
Yeah.
Been watching her all night.
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
Casket climber.
Her? She doesn't look that energetic.
Yeah. Those are the ones
that really go for it.
So we should probably have
a conversation with Rico...
...about what's going on with Kroehner.
Okay.
So there was no baby christening
the other day. I lied.
But I only took one
meeting with Gilardi.
- You met with him? Why?
- Hey, Gilardi called me, okay?
I have the right to consider my options.
My father put you
through mortuary school.
- I wanna go with you!
- Mrs. Romano! Mrs. Romano!
- It's okay.
- Mommy!
Grab her legs! It's okay.
It's okay. Here we go.
- Here we go, Mrs. Romano.
- I'm sorry.
I give up.
It's not here.
This probably isn't over.
If there's a lesson to be learned, it's
that your actions have consequences.
Yeah, well, Gabe should learn that.
I know you and my brother are,
like...
...gay.
Okay.
What do you see in him?
- He's just David, you know?
- I know. That's why I'm asking.
He is smart. He's kind. He's funny.
I know he can be a little uptight,
but underneath that, he's...
...such a little boy. Innocent.
And I like that.
Most of the men I meet, well...
...they kind of just want me
to be one thing.
What, like, big, black sex cop?
"Sorry I was speeding, officer, I guess
you'll have to punish me now."
Yeah.
And I don't want to be that.
Rent a video.
David...
...he gets me.
When someone sees you as you
really are and wants to be with you...
...that's powerful.
Whatever.
I wish I could know
the David you know.
You could be a little nicer to him.
He's under a lot of stress...
...with that cremation place
opening across the street.
What cremation place?
She stole a foot?
From a person?
Yes. Would it have been better
if it was an animal's?
A little bit.
You wake up one day
and your baby's stolen a foot.
- Where have I been?
- Losing $25,000.
Hey.
Okay, I've had a long day.
Oh, David, I ran into your friend Keith.
- Who's Keith?
- You met at Dad's thing.
- I never met a Keith.
- Yes, you did, the cop.
I asked him to help out.
He'll see what he can do
about there not being an official report.
Why does this person have to be
so involved in our life?
Claire, we should probably talk about
getting you some help.
You are not my father.
If you need a project, get a dog.
Keith says the school's probably
gonna make me see a shrink anyway.
Oh, dear.
By the way, that house
across the street?
It's on fire.
I guess this should solve
all your problems.
Freckles!
Here, girl!
Subtitles by www.tv-series.nm.ru