Sleek, Sophisticated, Seductive,
The new Millennium Edition
Crown Royal funeral coach,
Because your loved one deserves
the very best in style and comfort,
- Nathaniel Fisher.
- Nathaniel?
It's Ruth. Did you take your
blood pressure medication today?
- Yes.
- Don't lie to me.
I took it, What do you want
me to do, OD on it?
Oh, and I just realized we don't have
any of that soy stuff Nate drinks.
You know, since he gave up milk.
I don't know what it's called.
Why not just cut some milk with tap
water? He'll never know the difference,
Look, if you don't want to go, I'll go.
It's not as if I don't have enough
to do already.
I'm kidding, I'll get some.
But it has to be after I pick up Nate
at the airport. I'm already running late.
Nathaniel!
- Are you smoking?
- Nope.
- Yes, you are. I heard you.
- I'm not, No, I'm not.
Look, forget you'll give yourself cancer
and die a slow and horrible death.
You should not be stinking up
that new hearse,
- I told you not to let him take it.
- Like I could've stopped him.
He's as proud of that thing as your fool
brother was of that damn motorcycle.
And who still has a pin in his foot?
Nathaniel, people want things
to be nice when there's a funeral.
They don't want their loved ones riding
in something that smells like an ashtray.
All right, look. I'm quitting right now.
I promise.
Okay? I'll see you tonight.
That new hearse
was a total waste of money.
There was nothing wrong
with the old one.
I think your father's having
some sort of midlife crisis.
It would've made more sense
to invest in repaneling the chapel...
...or adding coffee bars
to the slumber rooms.
Well, I'd much rather he buy himself
a fancy new hearse...
...than leave me for a younger woman.
Or a woman my age,
for that matter.
Or heaven forbid, a man,
like my cousin Hannah's husband did.
God sure has dealt that woman
some blows in this life.
Mom.
Can I do anything to help?
No, no, honey. I'm fine.
Besides, don't you
have a viewing tonight?
- You should probably be getting ready.
- Right.
So I enjoyed talking to you
about that whole shiatsu thing.
I really hope that pans out for you.
You should let me
work on you sometime.
Here's my cell number.
I'll be here until the 29th.
Here you go.
My dad was supposed
to meet me here.
- I could give you a ride.
- I'm sure he'll be here soon enough.
I wasn't talking about that kind of ride.
You've done a nice job.
- She looks so peaceful.
- Well, she is at peace now.
If there's any justice in the universe,
she's shoveling shit in hell.
Excuse me.
- David Fisher.
- David, it's Claire.
- Is Nate there yet?
- Nope.
I thought he was coming
so we could do,,,
...the forced Christmas Eve family thing.
- Well...
There are some really excellent parties
I could be going to.
Claire.
This is one of the few times
we're all together.
Don 't get all Pat Robertson on me,
I'll be there,
I have to drop some stuff off at a friend's
house before I head over, okay? Bye.
Fucking Boy Scout.
Attention, passengers of flight 71,,,,
This is kind of disgusting.
- Disgusting good or disgusting bad?
- Disgusting very good.
I know.
- You are so fucking hot.
- You're so sweet.
I'm a sweet guy.
Shut up and fuck me.
Hello.
This is Ruth Fisher.
Yes, I'm his wife.
What is this about?
What?!
Excuse me.
Mom, what the hell are you...?
There's been an accident.
The new hearse is totaled.
Your father is dead.
Your father is dead,
and my pot roast is ruined.
Oh, my God.
You carry a lot of tension
around in your lower back.
Not as much as 20 minutes ago.
Just so you know...
...I never do this.
Oh, yeah. Me neither.
So...
...were you ever gonna
tell me your name?
Probably not.
Why not?
Because I'm a realist.
That's my father looking for me.
Hey, Dad.
Oh, Dave, hey. Merry Christmas.
Of course I'm okay.
Couldn't be better in fact.
What?
I'm so sorry, Nate. I hate
to have to be the one to tell you.
This is just speed, right?
Promise me this isn't crack.
I'm having Christmas Eve dinner
with my demented family.
It'll be weird enough
without being high on crack.
No, it's just crystal meth. It just makes
everything burn a little bit brighter.
And it makes sex, like, totally primal.
Here. It's all right.
Oh, well, it's too late now.
It's mine.
Hello? David, hi.
Hang on a second.
So is Nate there yet?
No, he's still at the airport.
Claire, I've got bad news.
What?
Yeah, sure.
Okay, I'm on my way.
I have to go.
- No fucking way!
- Excuse me.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
- You're coming back, right?
- I don't think so.
My dad just got hit by a bus,
and it broke his neck, and he's dead.
I gotta pick up my mom and bring her to
the morgue so she can identify his body.
No, I'm not kidding.
This is actually happening.
And now I'm high on crack!
- Crystal.
- Whatever!
So I guess this whole hellish experience
I'm about to go through...
...is just gonna burn
a little brighter now, right?
Great! Thank you! Fuck!
You really didn't have to do this.
I could've rented a car.
It's okay.
You're in no shape to drive.
I'm in no hurry to get home to my
family's annual Christmas Eve massacre.
Parents who stayed together
for the children...
...but really because they got off
on tormenting each other so much.
Manic-depressive brother...
...who always chooses the holidays
to go off his medication.
And an ancient springer spaniel who's
completely blind, deaf and incontinent.
What about you?
Actually, we're pretty normal.
My mom's a control freak.
My brother...
...well, he's a control freak too.
And my sister...
Well, I left home before she was born
so I never really knew her that well...
...but she's kind of wild like I was.
- Was?
My dad really rode my ass
when I was a kid.
I couldn't go rafting because
he buried a girl who drowned.
He buries this dipshit loser who OD'd
at a Flock of Seagulls concert...
...and I'm not allowed to go
to concerts for a year.
Your dad worked in a cemetery?
How could a man who's so scared of
everything, who never had an accident...
...or a speeding ticket in his entire life,
how could he have a car wreck?
Are you mad at him,
or the fact that we're all gonna die?
- Are you a shrink?
- No! God, no. No!
Both my parents are.
So, what else do you
want to talk about?
The weather?
Or the fact that we both
just fucked a perfect stranger?
And that we both lied
when we said we never did that.
- Wonderful service.
- Yes, it was. Very nice.
She looked so peaceful.
Thank you so much.
- You're welcome.
- Wonderful job.
Did you know that
before you were born...
...funeral homes
ran the ambulance business?
No.
Hearses were the only vehicles
that could transport people lying down.
Your father used to joke about that.
"Just drive him around the block
a few more times.
We won't need to stop
at the hospital."
You're kind of freaking me out
right now.
Claire...
...are you having sex?
- What?
Or doing drugs?
Why are you asking me this right now?
Your father is dead.
I can't even remember the last time you
and I talked about anything important.
I need to know you're okay.
Oh, yeah.
Believe me, I'm okay.
You know, considering.
- Do you work here?
- Yes.
I wanted to compliment you
on the music.
I've been to three funerals this year.
Cancer, stroke, pediatric leukemia...
...and the music is always
that same sad organ music.
It reminds me of soap operas
my mom watched...
...before I started kindergarten. Oh, God,
you're probably too young to remember.
Anyway, I so prefer this light classical,
you know, chamber orchestra stuff.
It's still spiritual, but doesn't
seem so dated or depressing.
I studied music appreciation.
You think I'm really boring, don 't you?
Well, get used to it,
Now that your father is dead,,,
,,, you can forget
about going to law school,
It's just you and dead people and freaks
like me for the rest of your life!
Mom.
Mom, I'm so sorry.
Who's she?
- This is...
- Brenda Chenowith.
Brenda Chenowith.
Brenda, this is my mom,
Ruth Fisher.
And my sister, Claire.
- Nate, can I talk to you for a second?
- Yeah, just give me a minute.
- Mom, did you already do the...?
- I can't.
I've seen too many dead people
in my life. They're work.
I won't see your father that way.
I need you to do it.
Nate, I need to talk to you now,
please. It's urgent.
- So how did you and my son meet?
- In cooking class.
I have to tell somebody.
I am tweaking.
- Yeah, we're all upset.
- No, I'm high on crystal.
I smoked some with some friends
before David called me.
- You did what?
- Don't worry, it's the first time.
But I think I'm having a meltdown...
...and I can't tell if it's Dad being dead
or the crystal, but...
I'm really scared.
You cannot do this to me right now.
Don't be a narc.
We smoked pot at Thanksgiving.
Look, I have to go identify
our dead father's body.
I'm sorry you're having
a bad drug experience, but deal with it.
Well?
Well, well,
The prodigal returns,
This is what you've been running away
from your whole life, buddy-boy.
Scared the crap out of you
when you were growing up, didn't it?
And you thought you'd escape,
well, guess what?
Nobody escapes.
- Well?
- Yeah, that's him.
Okay, let's get out of here.
How'd he look?
Dead.
Will there need to be
a lot of reconstruction?
David's not that skilled
at the really hard stuff.
Federico usually does that.
He's quite gifted.
You don't think we'll have
to have a closed casket, do you?
- I would hate to send that message.
- What message?
That we're not equipped to handle
a major restoration...
...or that we're not proud of our work.
- Can we talk about this later?
We should really get Nate home.
He's probably exhausted. Let's go.
Thanks for driving me here.
Please. I'm just avoiding my own hell.
I'm a big coward.
Me too.
I don't know if I can handle this.
Well, you're about to find out.
I wish you the best, Nate.
Goodbye.
Claire.
- You're driving too fast.
- This isn't fast. You wanna see fast?
Pull over!
Listen, do you do a lot of drugs?
What? No.
And it's none of your business.
Yes, it is my business.
You were driving like a maniac.
You could've gotten us killed.
What the hell is this?
You're not my father.
You split as soon as you could.
You don't even know me.
So don't start thinking you can
tell me what to do, okay?
So where's Dad, downstairs already?
He's still in the morgue.
You didn't bring him back with you?
Oh, dear.
That didn't even cross my mind.
We should've taken the van
so we could bring him home.
I'm sorry.
That was very stupid of me.
Nice going, Dave.
Like she doesn't have enough
to feel bad about right now?
Things have to be done.
Federico's downstairs, ready to start.
Every second we wait will only make
Dad's restoration more difficult.
But you wouldn't know
about that, would you, bag boy?
"Bag boy"?
I'm assistant manager of organic produce
at Seattle's highest volume food co-op.
Jesus, pull your dicks out and measure
them. Let's get this over with.
Were we supposed to throw Dad
in the back of Claire's car?
It is a hearse!
Yeah, hi. It's David Fisher.
Yeah, so I need to come
pick up the body.
These people mean nothing to me,
Know you not the family of the man
who has slaved for you,,,
,,, from dawn to dark
these many years?
They appear to be so happy,,,,
- I made you some dinner.
- I'm so not hungry.
We have to eat, Claire.
We didn't die.
What is that?
- For your father,
your brother, Tiny Tim,
On three. One. Two. Three.
Really sorry, man.
Thanks.
For a body that's firm, yet flexible,
For skin that begs to be touched,
For the velvety appearance
of actual living tissue,,,
,,, top morticians rely on Living Splendor
embalming fluid,
Living Splendor,
Only real life is better,
Hey, buddy-boy.
Come on in, it's okay.
Say hello to Mr. Bloomberg.
There isn't anything to be afraid of, Nate.
Mr. Bloomberg's dead.
I'm getting him ready so his family
can see him for the last time...
...and say goodbye to him.
It'll make them feel better.
That's what Daddy does.
What do you got?
You got me.
You can touch him
if you wear one of these.
Believe me, he won't mind.
He won't care.
Nate!
What's up?
- Hey, Rico.
- It's good to see you.
Really sorry about your dad, man.
But, well, you know,
when your time's up, it's up, right?
How's he doing?
So far so good.
I really appreciate you coming in
on Christmas Eve, Federico.
It's the least I could do for Mr. F.
Everything he did for me.
I was gonna be up all night anyway,
putting together useless shit...
...Santa Claus is bringing my kid.
We don't use that kind of language
in here. Show some respect.
- You need something?
- No.
I just...
David Fisher.
Hey, I just want to remind you, don't
eat too much with your family tonight...
...because I am making you something
totally decadent and fatty for dessert.
Hold just a second, please.
Hi.
Keith, I'm sorry, I can 't make it,
Why not?
My father was just killed
in a car accident.
Oh, shit. David, I'm so sorry.
What can I do?
Nothing, thanks.
But I have to stay here.
Listen, if you need anything,
don't hesitate to call me.
Sure,
I mean it, David. You don't
have to go through this alone.
I gotta go.
Okay, here it goes.
This is the one I'm most proud of.
The husband, okay?
He got fired, flipped out...
...shot his wife point-blank in the head,
then shot himself in the mouth.
Some seriously closed-casket shit, right?
Now look at this.
Like the bride and groom
on top of a cake.
And then we cremated them.
What a fucking waste.
Actually...
...this right here is...
This is my best work.
Wait a minute, this kid
was born just last month.
He'll be 4 fucking years old in April,
can you believe it?
Vanessa's pregnant again.
You stud!
Hey, it wasn't planned. You know what?
Neither was this one.
And he's the best thing
that ever happened to me.
Keep an eye on those chemicals,
Federico. We don't want him to burn.
Hey.
- Where's Mom?
- She went to bed.
Was she feeling any better?
Yeah, Nate, she was on top
of the goddamn world.
- Where's David?
- He's downstairs, working.
On Dad?
Yeah, well, him and Rico.
He said not to wait up for him.
We should try and sleep.
Yeah, as if that were a viable option.
- You want to go to the grocery store?
- Yes. Anything to get out of here.
Well, it's about to start
raining frogs here.
How are things on your end?
- God, I'm glad you called.
- Really, why?
I don't know.
Because you...
You have a calming effect on me.
Are you familiar with the psychological
term "projection"?
term "blow me"?
Come on, You grew up
with all that psychobabble,
You rebelled against it
every chance you got, Still do,
And that includes having sex
with strangers in closets at airports.
And you think you're
not easy to read?
Coasting by on your looks and charm
isn 't working like it used to,,,
,,, but you have no idea what else to do
because you've never had to learn,
Any woman with half a brain
looks at a guy like you and thinks:
"Good for a hot fuck."
But believe me, that's it.
L...
Nate, can we go home?
I really gotta take a shower.
Oh, God, Jesus Christ! Am I not allowed
to have even a single moment to myself?
Okay.
It's okay.
What can I do?
Nothing. No one can do anything.
- You'll have to pay for that cantaloupe.
- You fuck off!
She looked her best
every day of her life,
Don 't let one horribly disfiguring
accident change that,
Use new Wound Filler
cosmetic molding putty,
Now faster setting and self-sealing,,,
,,, to help make masking
unsightly wounds a breeze,
Ma, you remember that stuffed dog
I used to have?
I dragged it around until its ears fell off,
then you made new ears out of a towel.
I hated that dog after that.
And I threw it up on the roof.
No.
I wanted it back and begged Dad
to get it, but he said no...
...if I really wanted it, I'd never
have thrown it in the first place.
Your father did so many wonderful things
for you, and that's all you can think of?
- I just remembered it.
- He was a good man!
I'm going running.
Oh, no, you're doing me?
You're the worst one we've got.
- Thanks, Dad.
- Where's Federico?
It's Christmas morning. He's with
his wife and kid. He'll be in later.
Couldn't this wait?
I don't want you ruining my face.
- It's a little late for that.
- Not funny.
- I need to stay busy right now.
- So go reorganize some files.
Or develop a new bookkeeping system.
That's what you're good at.
You never really had any aptitude
for this stuff.
I know.
And what did I do with my life?
I went to school to learn
exactly how to do this stuff.
Other kids my age were going
to frat parties, I was draining corpses...
...and refashioning severed ears
out of wax.
Thank God I didn't lose an ear. I can
only imagine what you'd do with that.
And I did it all for you.
I did it to make you happy,
you ungrateful son of a bitch.
Dave?
I just wanted to let you know
I was here.
We'll deal you in next hand.
- I'm about to jump out of my skin.
- Don't.
I'm just barely holding it together.
Are you still high?
- I don't know. Am I sweating?
- I know I am.
This is too fucking weird.
It's been three days...
...and I'm still trapped in zombie world.
- This is all happening to you.
Fuck off!
I'm sorry, but you're not the only one
who wasn't prepared for this.
I came expecting to sleep late and chow
down on Mom's cooking for six days.
And now I find myself feeling like...
...I'm not even a part of this family.
- I'd trade places with you in a heartbeat.
At least you got out of here.
I live in a shitty apartment
which was supposed to be temporary.
I work at a job,
also supposed to be temporary...
...until I figured out what I wanted to do
with my life, which apparently is nothing.
I have lots of sex, but my relationships
don't last more than a couple months.
I don't even have the self-discipline
to floss daily. I've had four root canals!
I'm 35, I've had four root canals.
I'm gonna be a loser who ends up
in his deathbed saying:
- "Where'd my life go?"
- No, you won't.
You'll be saying,
"Where the hell's the morphine?"
I'm just trying to cheer you up.
I've spent my whole fucking life
being cheerful.
I'm sorry about your father,
but he's in a much better place now.
You are so right about that.
Who the hell is that?
I know, Ruth.
I know everything.
I've known the Fishers
for years from church.
- You know them too?
- Yes, yes. I work here.
Oh, you work here.
- What are you doing here?
- I just got off duty. I came...
...to pay my respects to your father.
- You never even met my father.
Exactly. And you've met my parents
how many times now?
- We spent the weekend at their house.
- Don't do this to me.
- This is not your high-school reunion.
- I'm sorry.
This is not the time to be political.
- You think I'm here to be political?
- Keep your voice down.
What is this? We can fuck, but I can't
be a shoulder for you to cry on?
- I'm not crying.
- So, what am I? Am I just sex to you?
Jesus!
Do we really have to have
this conversation now?
Oh, shit. Here comes my mother.
- I'm so tired.
- I know, Mom. It's exhausting.
- Is something wrong?
- No, nothing's wrong.
This is Keith Charles, a friend of mine.
He came to pay his respects to Dad.
It's nice to meet you, Mrs. Fisher.
I'm really sorry about your husband.
- You're friends with a cop?
- We play racquetball together.
Nice to meet you.
I'd like to see your father now.
Who's that cop?
- My Aunt Shirley was laid out here.
- Aunt Shirley, huh?
Shirley Hamilton.
Terrible accident, lost her ear.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, I know Shirley.
I remember Shirley.
- Really?
- Yes.
I was the person who sewed her ear
back on. That was me. That's my work.
What? She's sad,
so he has to get her out of sight?
They always do that.
The second someone starts to lose it,
they take them off into that room.
It makes the other people uncomfortable,
I guess.
This is not about the other people!
Volume.
When I went backpacking through Europe
after I quit school...
...I went to this island
off the coast of Sicily.
It was this volcanic island,
And on the boat over,
there was this pine box,
Somebody from the island
being returned to be buried there,
And there are all these old Sicilians
dressed up all in black...
,,, waiting, lined up on the beach,
And when they got
that coffin to the beach,,,
,,, those old Sicilian women went apeshit,
screaming, throwing themselves on it,,,
,,, beating their chests, tearing
at their hair, making animal noises,
It was just so,,,,
So real,
I mean, I'd been around funerals
my entire life,,,
,,, but I had never seen such grief,
And at the time,
it gave me the creeps,
But now I think it's probably
so much more healthy than...
...this.
That cop is hot.
- Oh, David, David.
- I know, Mom.
It's going to be okay.
It just takes time.
- I've done a terrible, terrible thing.
- What?
I've done a terrible thing.
- How's she doing?
- She's fine.
I'm not fine. I'm a whore! I was
unfaithful to your father for years!
And now he knows.
He knows.
I met a man at church once
when your father didn't come with me.
- Mom...
- And he invited me for coffee...
...and he said he liked my hair.
He's a hairdresser, a widower.
Well, they divorced before she died,
so technically I guess he's divorced.
He invited me to accompany him
on a hike.
This is really not the time.
- Maybe she needs to get this out.
- I don't want to hear it.
I used to love hiking when I was
younger, and being outdoors.
I always wanted
to take you kids camping...
...but your father would never
leave the business!
Well, I can tell you. I went camping
with this man from church several times!
Told your father
I was visiting my sister.
If he'd ever thought to call...
Can you even begin to fathom
the impropriety of this?
Your husband is lying
in a casket.
David, she's grief-stricken, okay?
Fuck propriety.
We don't say that word!
Did you know him?
No.
Did you?
He was my father.
You're Claire?
- Yeah.
- Keith Charles.
I'm a friend of your brother's.
- Of Nate's?
- No, David's.
- David's friends with a cop?
- We play racquetball together.
- David plays racquetball?
- Excuse us.
You want me to cry
on your shoulder? Fine.
My mother just confessed
she was having an affair.
- Wow.
- Yeah, with some hairdresser...
...who likes to hike. Now Nate is in there
playing Mr. Sensitive with her...
...while her dead husband
lies in the next room. It's disgusting.
- Breathe. You're gonna get through this.
- Oh, I know.
I'll be the strong, stable, dependable one,
because that's what I do.
Everyone around me will fall apart
because that's what they do.
Don't you get exhausted being so hard
on everyone? And yourself?
Oh, shut up.
- She met him at church.
- You met me at church.
Hands.
I didn't even realize how lonely I was...
...or how long it had been
since a man touched me like that.
Well, loneliness is a terrible thing.
I'm still a woman, you know.
Yes, I know.
And now your father sees me.
Like God sees me.
He knows everything.
I'm so ashamed.
You didn't do it to hurt anybody.
You were lonely.
I'm sure Dad forgives you.
- And God doesn't?
- Oh, yeah, yeah. I'm sure he does too.
Look, it's okay.
Everybody forgives everybody.
For everything.
Fuck.
If you're looking for the olives, honey,
they're right here.
Ashes to ashes and dust to dust,,,
,,, is easy as pie with Franklin 's
new leak-proof earth dispenser,
Say goodbye to soiled fingers forever,
Only from Franklin Funeral Supplies,
We put the fun back in funeral,
In the midst of life,
we are in death.
Of whom may we seek for succor,
but of thee, O Lord?
Who for our sins art justly displeased?
Thou knowest, Lord,
the secrets of our hearts.
Shut not thy merciful ears
to our prayer.
But spare us, Lord most holy,
O God most mighty.
O holy and merciful savior,
thou most worthy judge eternal.
Suffer us not, at our last hour...
...through any pains of death,
to fall from thee.
In the sure and certain hope
of the resurrection to eternal life.
Through almighty God
we commend our brother...
...Nathaniel Samuel Fisher...
...and we commit his body
to the ground.
He looks like he's salting popcorn.
Earth to earth,
ashes to ashes...
...dust to dust.
The Lord bless him and keep him.
The Lord make his face to shine
upon him and be gracious unto him.
The Lord lift up his countenance
upon him and give him peace.
- Nate...
- No!
I refuse to sanitize this anymore.
- This is how it's done.
- Yeah? Well, it's whacked.
What is this stupid saltshaker?
What is this hermetically sealed box?
This phony AstroTurf around the grave?
Jesus, David, it's like surgery.
Clean, antiseptic, business.
- He was our father!
- Please don't do this.
You can pump him full of chemicals,
you can put makeup on him...
...and you can prop him up
for a nap in the slumber room...
...but the fact remains that the only
father we're ever gonna have is gone!
Forever.
And that sucks.
But it's a goddamn part of life,
and you can't really accept it...
...without getting your hands dirty.
Well, I do accept it, and I intend
to honor the old bastard...
...by letting the world see how fucked
up and shitty I feel that he's dead!
Goddamn it!
Amen.
Wait.
Let her.
Let us pray.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name...
...thy kingdom come, thy will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day, our daily bread.
Forgive us our trespasses...
...as we forgive those
who have trespassed against us.
Lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom and the power
and the glory, forever and ever. Amen.
Amen! Amen!
The Lord be with you.
Mom, Federico's gonna
drive you back, okay?
I just need to go over a few details
with Nate. We'll be right behind you.
Put her there, Mrs. F.
You have such delicate hands, Federico.
Like a statue.
Or an illustration in an antique book.
Or one of those little ceramic hands
they use to display gloves.
You want to be the alpha dog,
Nate, is that it?
Coasting toward mid-life
with nothing to show for it.
You wanna come back and be the rock
for this family to lean on?
- Fuck you.
- That is not what I'm...
You want to get your hands dirty?
You sanctimonious prick.
Talk to me when you've had to stuff
formaldehyde-soaked cotton...
...up your father's ass
so he doesn't leak.
- Jesus!
- Yeah.
Well, I'm sure you just would've
tossed him out with the garbage.
It may seem weird to you...
...but there is a reason
behind everything that we do here.
We provide people
with a very important...
...and sacred service
at the darkest time in their lives.
Because maybe they don't wanna
make a spectacle of themselves.
Because maybe they'd prefer
to grieve in private.
Why?
Why does it have to be such a secret?
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
- Dave, please...
- You know nothing!
Nothing!
You had a responsibility
to this family...
...and you ran away,
and left it all for me.
Don't blame me if you're
not living the life you want.
That is nobody's fault but your own.
Okay, fine.
Just do me a favor, okay?
You got out...
...stay out.
Excuse me, Mr. Fisher, sir?
If I could get a moment of your time.
- What?
- I'm from Kroehner Service International.
I'd like to talk to you about joining
our family of death-care facilities.
- I cannot believe this.
- Lf you'd just hear me out...
We're not selling.
Get the fuck out of here!
We wouldn't change
the name of the business.
We would retain you
as a salaried manager.
Look, I really want to hit somebody
right now, and it might as well be you!
I'll call you when you've had some time
to recover from your loss.
- You're really lucky, you know that?
- You kidding? It was over in a second.
I didn't have to be afraid of it
or even think about it.
- No more bullshit.
- No more responsibility.
- And no more having to care.
- No more boredom!
No more waiting to die.
Hi.
Well, after four days with my family,
I'm ready for shock therapy.
I'm just waiting to see
if my HMO covers it.
- How's it going with you?
- Oh, it's great. Great.
My father's dead, my mom's a whore,
my brother wants to kill me...
...and my sister's smoking crack.
I think I win.
Four days ago,
I was a relatively happy guy.
Now it's like I don't even know
who that guy was.
I'm a fucking mess.
If you want to know the truth.
But I think you're already aware of that.
Well, here's my number.
If you ever want to, I don't know,
go out on a real date?
You know, where you buy me dinner
before I put out.
Maybe I'm a woman that meets a man
who seems emotionally conflicted...
...no relationship skills, and I figure,
"Hey, that's for me."
- I don't even live here. I live in Seattle.
- That makes you more attractive.
- Really?
- Oh, yeah.
Well, I also happen to be a serial rapist.
I've got 10 nurses
buried under my house.
Now you're making me wet.
I... I need...
I need...
It's okay. It's okay.
Good morning.
Thank God you're here.
Yeah, well, of course I'm here.
- What do you want for breakfast?
- Oh, I'm gonna go for a run.
- I'll eat when I get back.
- Nate?
You don't have to go back to Seattle
right away, do you?
I guess not.
I could make a few calls.
- Thank you.
- Yeah, sure.
Just for a few days.
Okay.
Subtitles by www.tv-series.nm.ru