I just remembered, I owe you money.
Well, thank you for sparing me
the awkward confrontation.
- Are you starting to feel exploited?
- Yeah, but in a good way.
- Go ahead.
- Yeah.
- Are you looking at my balance?
- It's okay. Size isn't everything.
Funny.
So does bad music make people deaf...
...or do deaf people have
really bad taste in music?
Well, there is Beethoven.
- Come on, let's go.
- What the fuck is that shit?
- Hurry.
- My receipt.
- Come on, that's all right, just...
- Look, it's all yours.
Do you think you can do
that kind of offensive shit in public?
- We're sorry, man, we didn't...
- Oh, he's sorry, huh?
Look, Pete, let's go.
- Fuck you, man!
- Fuck you!
Fuck! Run!
Help!
The other one got away.
Fucking freak!
Fucking pervert!
Read a Bible, you pervert!
Johnny, come on. Come on,
let's go. Come on.
Okay, here we go with Uncle Nate.
- You got him?
- Just about.
- Put your hand under there. There we go.
- All right, I got him. I got him.
Okay, but don't hold him
like he's a football.
It's more like you're carrying
a watermelon.
- All right.
- See?
- Okay.
- Adjust, adjust, adjust. There you go.
Hey, there, little guy.
Who looks just like his daddy, huh?
When a baby's born
it always looks more like its father...
...which is nature's way
of establishing paternity.
We're hoping he grows out of it.
Oh, don't worry, I'm sure he will.
Oh, yes, yes.
David, come meet Augusto.
I just have to get Mr. Perlmutter
dressed for his viewing.
David, please, come take
one look at him.
Nate was an extremely gassy baby,
always crying.
David, on the other hand,
hardly ever made a peep.
When are you guys gonna grow up
and make this woman a grandmommy?
Well, certainly not until after
Mr. Perlmutter's got some clothes on.
You know, it's kind of funny,
me coming back to school in a hearse.
It's hilarious.
This sucks.
Does everybody know?
I don't know. Who'd you tell?
No, I mean, like, did they make
an announcement or something?
Don't you think you would've gotten,
like, a couple of cards if they had?
No.
It's not cool to OD.
Freaks people out.
Who gives a fuck what
these people think?
Everyone's too obsessed with
what people think about them...
...to think about anyone else.
You're a freak.
Yeah, well, so are you.
Is that supposed to make me feel better?
- That's the guy who OD'd.
- Yeah, it is.
What the fuck are you looking at?
What, you called me over here to show
me a picture of you and the gravedigger?
I need your key back,
because you've crossed a line...
...and I don't feel like
I can trust you anymore.
- You think I took that picture?
- I will not play this game with you!
I won't deal with you
when you're off your meds...
...because I don't even know
who you are.
For someone with so much animosity
towards the psychiatric profession...
...you sure love to push pharmaceuticals.
Makes sense, as you're no stranger
to medication yourself.
You're sick, Billy. You have to
stay on your medication...
...or you get scary, okay?
You're not scared of me.
I'd never hurt you. You're the most
important person in my life.
Yeah, well, did you ever stop to think
that maybe that's fucked up?
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be sorry. Just...
Just take the meds.
Okay. I promise.
Now give me the key.
I just told you I'd take
the medication, Brenda.
I just... I just told you I'd take
the medication!
Jesus Christ, you don't have to be such
a bitch! When did you turn into Mom?
Okay. I don't give a shit.
You want your fucking key?
Great. Here, take all the fucking keys.
I could have an extra copy at home.
Yeah, I could always change the locks.
Do you know how easy it would be
to break into this place?
I'd like you to go now.
Get your wet suit, clothing, robes.
Take them.
I just told you I'd take
the medication, Brenda!
I told you I would take
the medication, please.
You have to take care of yourself now.
I can't do it, not anymore.
Please, Brenda, you're the only person
I can talk to.
You're the only one that hears me.
Billy, you have to get a life
of your own, okay?
Please.
You probably read about it.
It was on the news...
...what happened to Marc.
Yes.
The coroner still has his...
They still have him.
In situations like this,
when there's been violence...
...the family may prefer
a closed casket.
- No.
- Honey, I think he looks pretty bad.
I have to see him.
I brought some pictures,
so you'll know what he looks like.
Wasn't he such a beautiful boy?
Why does a thing like this happen?
Come on, now, we all know
why this happened.
That is not a reason.
It's the only reason.
If he wasn't...
He'd be alive today.
You know, I was always
so worried about AIDS.
I never even thought that just being
out on the street...
What is wrong with people?
Could've told him this happens.
I would've too if he'd ever just
talked to us about it, ever come out...
...and told us what he was.
- Well, what do you expect, Marcus?
You can't even say it.
Hey, Dave.
I'll be right with you.
Okay, okay.
- Jesus.
- Oh, boy.
Okay, Cinderella...
...we're gonna have to work overtime
to get you ready for the ball...
...because men don't make passes
at girls with big gashes.
That was funny, right?
Daddy's Mr. Funnyman.
Let me just run Augusto upstairs,
and I'll be right back down to do him.
I can handle this, Federico. Why don't
you take the rest of the day off?
That's a pretty tough job, Dave.
The skull's all shattered up there.
You might have to rebuild
the tissue on his cheek.
I can do it.
Hey, thanks, man.
I'm so damn tired I can barely
see straight.
- Get some rest.
- You bet. Good luck.
Let's go, buddy. Let's go, buddy.
Let's go.
And I told him not to come around
for a while.
- That's it?
- Oh, what else could I do, Nate?
You could talk to the police.
You could get a restraining order.
I don't need you to tell me how to handle
this. That is so arrogant and patronizing.
I just need you to listen to me.
You can't just wait for the next
fucked-up thing Billy does.
You need to do something now.
Do you think that was easy for me,
just cutting him off like that?
Do you even comprehend
what it's like...
...to be responsible
for someone your whole life?
Do you even get the concept
of loving somebody that much?
Yes, I get that concept.
He's sick.
He's not just sick, he's dangerous.
He built a bomb. He broke into our hotel
room and took pictures of us in bed.
- What's he gonna do next time?
- I took his key away from him.
Yeah, well, he didn't have a key
in Vegas. That didn't keep him out.
I'm sorry. I know you don't trust
your parents...
...but I really think they're right on this.
He needs to be somewhere.
This is so not how I need you
to be right now.
- What are you doing?
- I don't wanna discuss this with you.
In fact, you know what?
Why don't we just take some time off?
You dump Billy,
so now you're gonna dump me?
Don't you fucking analyze me!
You might as well throw away your key,
because I changed the lock.
Where's Claire?
Well, she claims to be at a movie,
but what do I know?
Nobody ever tells me
what's really going on.
That boy who got beat up
on the street...
...was he doing something?
He was getting cash.
Didn't you read the paper?
Yes, I just thought you might
know more about it.
Do you like the hen?
Yeah, very much.
What did you stuff it with?
Chestnuts, bread crumbs, celery.
Do you wanna know
all the ingredients?
No, thanks.
Are you going out tonight?
No, not tonight.
Are you?
Me? No.
But, you know...
...sometimes I do see Hiram
on occasion.
And I know you don't like that...
...but I also know you love me
no matter who I see in my private life.
Well, that's good, Mom.
Why'd you drop jazz vocals
sophomore year?
Because the music teacher
was a crackhead.
I'm serious, Claire.
So am I. He got busted and fired,
and then jazz vocals was discontinued.
Do your homework.
What happened
with the literary magazine?
Censorship. I wrote this totally,
like, harmless...
...like, cartoon story about this girl
who can make people's heads explode...
...and apparently it was
too disturbing to publish.
The debate team?
They debated what the prom theme
should be.
I mean, God, the people in this school,
they have the mentality of teenagers.
- You are a teenager.
- Yes...
...but I actually think about things
beside trying to figure out...
...how to puke after lunch
without anyone noticing.
So, what do you do for fun?
I don't know. What do you do for fun?
I go bowling with my friends.
I take hikes with my girlfriend.
- I bake.
- You bake?
Your turn.
I read.
I go online and make up
freaky cyber identities.
You know, sometimes
I'm a Scientologist.
Sometimes I'm a young, Christian wife.
What about friendships that are
based on the truth? Any of those?
Sometimes I hang out with
Parker McKenna. I kind of like her...
...even though she's pretty much
a split-personality freak.
Dating anyone?
Dating? You mean, like,
getting drunk and screwing?
- Lf that's what it is.
- Yeah, that's what it is. No, I'm not.
Keith, got a minute?
Yeah, sure. What's up?
I wanna put you on security
for the Marc Foster funeral on Thursday.
Okay, why?
The wackos turn out for these things.
- Why me?
- Come on, Keith.
You're a good, smart cop,
and you use your head...
...before you use your gun, all right?
So it has nothing to do with the fact
that I'm gay, right?
What do you wanna do,
sue me for discrimination...
...or show up and protect
this kid's family?
Oh, God, I look like something
Chef Boyardee makes.
So you never told your parents
you were gay either?
Oh, please, they knew.
I just didn't want my dad making me
feel guilty about it all the time.
Maybe he could've accepted it
if you'd given him a chance.
You heard him.
He thinks it's my fault I'm dead.
That's not what he was saying.
He was saying it's a sick world.
- I'm the one who was sick.
- Shut up.
So I liked men.
I never should've given in to it.
It's not what God intended.
I could've had a family and a normal life.
You could've too.
That life would've been a lie and
unfair to your wife and children...
...who would've hated you.
Not if I never looked back.
Not if I had faith.
God challenges us like this,
so we'll choose good...
...so we'll triumph over evil.
Only thing is, so few of us do.
It's not a choice.
God already made the choice for you.
That's just liberal propaganda
to justify your own depravity, Jim.
No matter how nice you fix me up,
I'm still going to hell, and you know it...
...because you're going there too.
Brenda, pick up the phone.
Don't just lay there and say, "Fuck you."
Okay, I'm sorry I pissed you off.
I know you're under a lot of pressure...
...but so am I.
So let's talk about it, okay?
Call me.
Hey.
Yes, this is Fisher & Sons.
Can I help you?
I'm terribly sorry.
Yes, we can pick up the body...
The deceased.
Which morgue?
A residence, okay.
What's the address?
- Robbie?
- Oh, I'm sorry, did my tree hit you?
- Do you have a moment?
- Well, I don't know, Ruth.
I got a whole big bunch of ferns
out back I gotta cut up...
...so you can make some more of those
beautiful, one-of-a-kind arrangements.
How did you tell your parents
you were...
Into flowers?
Well, it was obvious from the beginning.
My first word was "perennial."
How did you tell them you were gay?
What makes you think I am gay?
Just because I have
a refined aesthetic...
...you make assumptions
about my personal life?
I'm so sorry. You're not gay?
Yes, I'm gay.
But I certainly don't see
how that's any of your business.
Do I ask you about
your intimate sexual life...
...even though it is on full display
in the workplace? No, I do not.
I tolerate the repercussions,
but I don't pry.
I'm sorry. I'm asking because my son...
Oh, dear Lord, save it for Geraldo.
Someone in the family shows signs
of homosexuality...
...and suddenly it's a national crisis.
Coming out to my parents.
Honestly, why don't you tell me the most
horrible moment from your intimate past?
- It was horrible?
- It's none of your business.
I'm sorry I offended you, Robbie.
That is a shitty place for the lily.
Mr. Jacoby?
Oh, fuck.
Jesus, Billy, you fucking psycho.
Did I get you?
Come on, man, it's paint.
Why aren't you laughing?
I don't think it's funny.
Oh, no, it's just plain fun.
You know, if you mix up the letters
in "funeral," you get "real fun."
How much do you love that?
You stay away from my sister.
She's just a kid.
Now, that's kind of ironic,
don't you think? You telling me that.
What'd they tell you?
They tell you I made a bomb?
They tell you who it was for?
I know you wrote things
about your family.
Liar!
Don't fucking lie to me.
He thought he was such a genius,
everybody thought.
He even had Brenda fooled,
which blows my mind.
Well, okay, she was young.
- Are you talking about Dr. Feinberg?
- No, Trevor, you fucking moron.
Trevor. Perfect fucking Trevor.
He thought he was the king of Brenda,
which is such adolescent shit...
...as if you could know somebody for a
few months and replace their whole life.
Their family.
Brenda's not allowed to love anyone
as much as she loves you?
Able.
She's not able.
You know what? You're right.
Bren never even told me about Trevor.
She doesn't trust me.
You don't get to call her that.
You call her Brenda.
You know, she broke up with me today.
- Really?
- Yeah. Took away my key.
Well, it's probably for the best.
You and Brenda was never a good idea.
Yeah, tell me about it.
Listen, I gotta go, so you take care.
Hey.
- Ready to go?
- Yeah, just...
...give me a second to recover.
Still bad, huh?
It's just fucking tiring
trying to act normal all day.
I know what you mean.
So, what's the stupidest thing
anyone's said to you today?
Packy Walker told me that he once
had to get his stomach pumped...
...because he ate his dog's
deworming pills.
He thought they were ludes.
Well, isn't it comforting to know
that being miserable...
...is still better than being an idiot?
All right.
You wanna hear the most horrible
moment from my intimate past?
No, sister, I do not.
I was married to my husband
for 30 years.
I never slept with another man until I
started having sex with my hairdresser.
And the first time my hairdresser
friend and I had intercourse...
...he asked me to pleasure
myself, so he would know...
...you know, how I did that.
And I couldn't.
Because I had never pleasured
myself in my life.
I was 52 years old.
And I had to learn how to...
Masturbate.
From a hairdresser.
Oh, my.
Well, Ruth, thank you for sharing that.
But I'm still not gonna tell you
about coming out to my parents.
- Why not?
- Because I never did, cupcake.
My daddy would've never spoken
another word to me...
...and my mother would've just gone
insane, right there on the spot.
How do you know?
A child knows what his parents
need him to be.
My mother is one of those women that
never did anything but raise children.
So, if you came out wrong,
like the opposite...
...of what she was trying to make
you into, then, you know...
...her whole life is a failure.
I'm not like that.
Did he ever actually threaten you?
Telling the new boyfriend you wanted
the old boyfriend dead...
...while you're playing with a knife.
Yeah, that seems like a threat to me.
How come you never told me
about Trevor?
It's such ancient history.
You said you'd never been
serious about anyone.
I was 18.
- Did you love him?
- Yes.
So, what happened?
Billy got sick.
Trevor went to Yale without me.
Billy got rid of him
because he was jealous.
Everyone was jealous of Trevor.
He was ridiculously gifted...
...one of those people everybody
secretly hates...
...because he's good at everything
and always gets what he wants.
- Well, he didn't get you.
- Oh, please. He could do better.
He did, actually. The woman he married
won the National Book Award last year.
You know, you're
ridiculously gifted too.
You could be one of those people
who has everything.
If you don't wanna deal with this,
I might have to wanna call your parents.
Well, you might have to wanna call
my parents...
...but unfortunately, they're
in South Africa at the moment.
I have absolutely no idea
how to contact them.
Would you stop fucking around?
I love you, and I'm sure
whatever you feel about me...
...you don't wanna see me dead.
Are you okay?
No.
Do you want me to take you
to a doctor?
What, now you think I'm crazy too?
No, no.
Goddamn it, why are you
shutting me out?
I just wanna be alone, okay?
I just wanna go to sleep.
Well, good night.
Why didn't you tell me about
your relationship with Gabriel Dimas?
I guess I just wasn't in the mood
for a lecture on inappropriate friends.
What makes you think I'd do that?
Well, some people don't think
he's the greatest influence.
And what do you think?
I think that I'm as much of an influence
on him as he is on me...
...so it's not like it only goes one way.
Right.
Relating to another person is a way
that we relate to a part of ourselves.
It's like, he's, like, an extreme version
of me, you know?
I can see that.
But what he's going through,
it's so much more.
But I understand, you know?
Feeling like you've got this shadow
over you all the time.
What's your shadow?
Death, I guess.
Death and silence.
Is that crazy?
What's the silence?
I don't know.
It's, like, sadness...
...or fear, maybe.
It's, like, you know, everybody's
so scared...
...that they're gonna say
the wrong thing...
...because, like, you know,
when you bury someone...
...that's, like, the most sensitive time
in a person's life.
So it's, like, my family,
they're just so careful.
It's like they almost become invisible.
That was heavy.
What's going on?
Nothing. I'm just being a freak.
You don't have to be afraid
that you'll say the wrong thing.
That's just it. I'm not.
I mean, I do say the wrong thing.
But, it's, like, this is gonna
sound stupid...
...but, like, I talk so much shit
all the time, you know.
And that's just another way
to not say...
Whatever.
To not say what?
I'm not here for the school
or for your mom.
I'm just here for you.
This is confidential, right?
Gabe didn't OD by accident.
He did it on purpose, I think.
Well, most ODs aren't really
just accidents.
Right, so, what can I do
as the friend of a person...
...who would do something like that?
Like, I know all the "I can't save him"
stuff, and I went to the websites.
And it's all, like, what you can't do.
So, what can I do?
Try not to make yourself invisible.
This isn't about me.
That's not a very good start, is it?
At least my tie can be straight, right?
You should've left me
the way I was.
Let the world see me
for who I really am...
...an abomination of nature.
Shut up.
Who you are is nothing
to be ashamed of.
That's a little hard to buy,
coming from somebody...
...who cruises for dick on the Internet
and has unsafe sex with prostitutes.
They made a shrine at the place
where you died...
...with pictures of you and flowers.
People go there and hold candles
in your honor.
- What people?
- Your friends, your community.
Bleeding-heart faggots
with nothing better to do.
Guys who fucked me when they were
drunk and then never called me back.
There are people who love you.
But not as many as hate me...
...and you.
Nice job.
Man, that is the best work
you've ever done, David.
- Thanks.
- Nice, very nice.
Hey, there's, like, 200 homos
outside. Oh, shit.
Already? It's only a quarter of.
You'd think the family wouldn't want
all of that coming in here, you know?
All of what?
There's this one guy,
he's dressed like Jackie Kennedy.
You think this guy's mother
really needs to see that today?
How'd you get those abrasions
on his cheek so smooth-looking?
I used diaper rash cream.
You left some.
You know, Rico, I'm a homo.
I may not dress like Jackie Kennedy,
but I have sex with men.
Don't... Don't talk to me
about that. All right?
Why should I hide it from you? You
change your baby's diaper in my house.
You show me a videotape
of your wife giving birth.
Where I come from...
...if men need to do that sometimes...
...they don't talk about it.
They don't leave their families.
They're men.
I am a man!
So I took the height of tree A and
divided it by the length of shadow B.
So do you see how I got
to tangent C?
Since when were you such a trig bitch?
Don't get me wrong.
I know it's totally pointless.
Just somehow, teaching you
makes it seem more interesting.
It must be the power.
Well, you are...
...a very stimulating teacher.
I love your grasp of the material.
Well, maybe we should grasp
the next one.
Which one?
Number five.
Come on.
- What is it?
- Oh, nothing.
Allergies.
Hey, come on.
I'm scared.
It's okay.
I'm scared too.
I'm scared you're gonna disappear.
I'm not gonna disappear.
What are you scared of?
I'm scared I'm not gonna finish
my math homework.
Hey, I told you.
I'm scared that you...
...are too good for me.
Oh, you're crazy.
I finally find a woman I wanna commit to,
and she makes it totally impossible.
You think that's a coincidence?
What is that supposed to mean?
Maybe if she made it easier,
you wouldn't be so eager.
I need more garlic.
You've always been bored
with the girls you could have...
...and fascinated with
the ones you couldn't.
Yeah, well, whose fault is that?
Your brother's gay, isn't he?
I think that's a question for him.
Has he told you?
No, he has not told me.
But it's obvious. Everyone knows.
Am I supposed to say something?
I tried to discuss it. He wouldn't let me.
I guess he doesn't wanna talk about it.
It's not good for him
to skulk around like that.
He's very tense. It's not good for him.
- Breathe, Mom.
- I know how to breathe!
I don't appreciate you blaming me for
all your problems, thank you very much.
Your carrots are burning.
Haven 't you seen a little girl
called Bunny?
- About your age,
- No,
- A new girl,
With a dress, just like yours,
Look, there's no point
in questioning the children,
What are you doing here?
I know what to do.
I know how to fix it.
Yeah? Fix what?
Oh, it was a big mistake.
But I'm gonna fix it, okay?
Oh, my God, Billy, what have you...?
- Did you hurt him?
- No, no, no, I fixed it.
- Oh, God.
- See, I can't be him anymore.
He's somebody else now.
I did it for you.
Now we can bury him.
And the best part is...
...now the nurse won't
ever be able to find him.
You've lost a lot of blood.
- Let me get a towel.
- We just have to get yours now.
This way, you'll be safe from her too
for the first time.
Then we can bury them,
and you and I can be new people.
And we can forget about everything
bad that they wrote.
I don't want us to be new people.
I like us the way we are.
Well, I already did it, Brenda,
so you have to do it too.
Okay.
Give me the knife.
- I wanna do it.
- No, you did yours. I should do mine.
Nathaniel saved Isabel on the sailboat.
It's a book. It's fiction.
He saved her for the first time.
She always saved him before.
Nathaniel and Isabel are not real.
I need to do it.
Billy, get off!
Billy, get off me!
I'm warning you. This is gonna hurt.
Yes, hello. I need an ambulance.
- It's in the Bible.
- Your son's burning in hell.
- God hates fags.
- God hates morons.
- The wages of sin is death and AIDS.
- Amen.
You leave these people alone,
or so help me...
- It's my right to be here.
- This is America.
It's my right to tell the truth. God killed
Marc Foster, and I'm here to celebrate.
God just shoved your stomach into
your lungs, and I'm here to celebrate!
- Look, God just got you in the face.
- What's wrong with you?
He started it.
- You all right?
- That man ought to be arrested.
- We'll take care of it. Watch yourself.
- I demand that man be arrested!
This is a funeral. Show some respect.
- What happened? Did something happen?
- No, nothing happened.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't apologize to me.
Damn, you messed that guy up.
No, I'm sorry for how I've been.
I'm just...
I'm sorry.
You know, I have to work not to be
worrying about you all the time.
You could get yourself killed if...
- lf what?
- Lf that's what you want.
- That's not what I want.
- Are you sure?
Yes.
I'm sorry for how I was with you
when we were together.
I don't know why it's so hard for me.
It's hard for all of us.
But you know that you're right, that
you're a good man. For me it's like...
...I agree with them, you know?
Like it is my fault,
and I should be able to fix it.
- There's nothing to fix.
- But it's not who I wanna be.
I wanna be the guy at church
with the kid on his knee.
You can have a kid
on your knee, David.
That guy probably hasn't slept
with his wife in five years.
I feel like my father would hate me
if he knew.
You told me he did know.
And he never said anything.
Did you?
Would you shut up? My mother'll
fry your balls for breakfast...
...if she catches you in here.
Nice.
So is that pretty much what you eat
in a funeral home?
Yeah, why?
Hey.
I had Billy committed.
Mom?
Are you okay?
I have a terrible headache.
- Well, maybe we can talk later.
- What?
What?
I'm gay.
Why didn't you ever tell me?
- I am telling you.
- Before, before.
- Don't you trust me?
- What do you mean? I'm telling you.
But I've tried to discuss it with you
several times.
Look, I just wasn't comfortable, okay?
- What does it matter now?
- Why not?
- When I was clearly trying to be open?
- You know, Mom...
...you may be trying to be open now...
...and that's great.
But that's not how you've been
for all my life.
You and dad, no one talked
about anything.
None of us are like that, except Nate...
...and that's just because he has
no other way to distinguish himself.
I've always loved you.
I know you love the part of me
that's your son.
What part of you isn't my son?
You're all my son.
I don't think you know me very well.
Well, whose fault is that?
I'm sorry.
And, you know, when you've tried to
bring it up before or now even...
...it's like you've decided
you should know who I am.
You're willing to see me how
you look at something horrible...
...like a corpse, because it's
your job, your duty.
It revolts you,
but you make yourself bear it.
Well, you're wrong.
You don't revolt me!
I don't choose which part of you I love,
like some kind of chicken!
It was just so much easier
when you were little...
...and you would tell me everything.
And when you were upset,
I could always fix it.
I don't know how to take care
of you anymore.
Just let me...
Just let me take care of myself.
But do you? I'm afraid that you don't.
I do.
I will.
Well, that's all that I wanted to say.
All right.
We're having veal.
Well, Mommy still loves you.
Does that make everything better?
- Yeah, I didn't think it would.
- What are you still doing here?
I could've come out to every mother
in the world, and I'd still be dead.
Oh, what, you're gonna interrupt him
and his matching love stud?
Both of them will be in hell
with us, by the way.
But something tells me they're gonna
have a lot more fun.
Stop, stop.
Make me.
Please, God, help me.
Take this pain away, please.
Fill this loneliness with your love.
Help me, God. Please help me.
Subtitles by www.tv-series.nm.ru