So I want you to meet this guy
I'm going out with tonight. Okay?
He's kind of a dork,
but in a sweet way.
He seems real, at least.
And he's kind of rich, I think.
Kind of.
Of course, so was Kadeem, and that was
a fucking waste of two years of my life.
And you know what?
I knew you never liked Kadeem.
So I'm gonna bring this guy
home to meet you.
And this time...
...I swear I will pay attention
to what you think.
Because I am
one fucking hot-shit bitch...
...and he'd be fucking lucky to have me.
Oh, does that feel good.
Hey, Tito!
Come hang with me. Okay?
Thank you.
Who's my lover?
Yes.
Yes. Aren't you glad I rescued you?
You better be fucking glad.
Cost me 800 bucks in vet bills...
...at a time when things were particularly
tight for Mommy, I might add.
One good thing about this guy tonight...
...is, he's got a big, fat dick,
and he fucks like a jackhammer.
Those never last.
David, I'm so glad to see you here.
It's always nice when someone
comes back.
Oh, I've been going to church.
I was just going to a different church.
- Really, which one?
- St. Stephen's.
- In the Palisades?
- No, St. Stephen's in West Hollywood.
Well, I hope you always feel
as welcome here as you did there.
- Thanks.
- Your father was a deacon here...
...and we still haven't replaced him.
I think it would be good for this church
to listen to a younger voice.
If you're at all interested,
I could submit your name.
Me? A deacon?
David, that's wonderful.
Your father would be so proud.
Well, sure, I'd be honored
to be considered.
- Ruth, how are you holding up?
- I'm doing okay, Father.
- Each day is just a little bit easier.
- That's what I love hearing.
Wow, what a small world!
Do you go to this church?
I just joined. I was raised Catholic,
so I like the whole ritual part of it.
You smell good. What is that?
Who are you?
Oh, my God. I can't believe
I never introduced myself.
It seems like we've known each other
forever. I'm Tracy Montrose Blair.
- Hi, I'm David...
- Fisher, I know. I know who you are.
Okay. Why?
Because my Uncle Walt
was buried at your funeral home.
Old guy? Cancer?
Had a tattoo of a roulette wheel
on his back?
Oh, yes.
I have a tattoo.
A butterfly.
I think that you should know
that I'm not really available.
- You have a girlfriend?
- Yes.
- Serious?
- We're engaged.
Well, good for you.
Most men your age are so
commitment-phobic, it's pathetic.
- Yes, men are pigs.
- Or they're gay.
Well, I'm certainly glad
to find out you're not gay.
I have to go. My mother's waiting.
Bye-bye!
- She seems nice.
- She seems nuts.
Hello?
Out here!
Hey.
- This is the life, huh?
- Apparently.
So how often do Mommy and Daddy
go away?
Oh, constantly.
They're very important people...
...with very important places to go.
Lucky for them, I have
absolutely nowhere to go.
- How are you?
- I'm good.
- It's chilly today. Aren't you cold?
- Nope.
Jesus, it's like a hot tub in here.
Mommy and Daddy keep it
this hot all the time, even in summer.
They're very wasteful.
That's just wrong.
Oh, man, you are...
What?
You're unlike any woman
I've ever met.
Good.
- You scare me a little.
- Why?
I don't know.
It's just...
...so much I don't know about you.
Me?
I am an open book.
I'm so glad you're bringing
your friends home.
You know, you haven't
done that in years.
You said you'd be gone
through the weekend.
Yes, it's Sunday.
It's the end of the weekend.
Nate, these are my parents,
Margaret and Bernard Chenowith.
Margaret and Bernard, this is Nate Fisher,
the man I am having sex with.
Hello.
Brenda has told us absolutely nothing
about you.
You know what? I'm not surprised.
I'm not sure there's that much to tell.
Oh, don't be so modest.
Nate's studying for
his funeral director's license.
Well, Nate, you'll have to tell us
all about that.
- Will you stay for lunch?
- At least a drink or two?
I'd like to, but...
...I really have to study.
Well, then you'll have to join us
for dinner sometime.
That sounds great.
Great!
Okay, Mrs. Fisher.
I asked you here today so we could
talk about your relationship with Claire.
- I told her it wasn't my idea.
- No.
Claire feels that,
being the youngest child...
...perhaps she might have missed out
on a time when the family was happier.
No, you said that.
I don't think there was a time
this family was ever happy.
That is not true.
There was lots of happiness:
When the boys were young,
when you were young, Claire.
You were a very happy little girl,
and you know it.
That's because I was too young
to realize what freaks we were.
Why would you tell this man
we were never happy?
Because I grew up in a house that was
usually filled with total strangers...
...who were crying all the time?
- Oh, boo-hoo.
I grew up in a two-room apartment
over a barbershop...
...and I spent my teenage years
taking care of my grandmother...
...after her legs were amputated.
Life's hard!
You had a roof over your head.
You didn't go hungry.
She gets up on this cross,
and then there's just no talking to her.
You did not have to go begging
for food on the streets of Calcutta.
Because I wasn't dropped in a dumpster,
I shouldn't want things to be better?
This is good. This is good
for you two to talk like this.
These are obviously things
you need to say.
So we're just supposed to fight
and get on each other's nerves?
I prefer the not-talking thing.
I think you should try to
have more of a dialogue.
Make time for it. Schedule it.
Remember, any relationship is work.
Okay, excellent session.
- That's it?
- That's up to you, isn't it?
He does this for like
five different schools.
She should look spectacular.
That's the most important thing.
We'll make sure that she looks her best.
She was the real deal, you know?
She was a star.
And I can assure you
we will give her a funeral...
...that befits the star that she was
and always will be.
- You know who she was?
- Absolutely.
And I'm a big fan of hers.
Hey, Rico.
- Holy moly.
- Feel them.
- They're really hard.
- No, thanks.
Like a rock.
See how they're all cockeyed?
They got this low-cut thing they want
her in, and they said absolutely no bra.
Shit, I don't know what
the heck I'm gonna do.
Maybe I could, like,
tape them together somehow.
You know where this goes? I put it
in the wrong place, David will bitch.
Top left, above the purple stuff.
Well, boys, this just might be our
highest profit margin funeral this year.
- She's rich, huh?
- The guy who's paying for it is.
- She looks so familiar to me.
- She's an actress. Viveca St. John.
Oh, my God, you're right.
That's her!
- Apparently, she was quite talented.
- She was a porno star.
- What?
- She was huge in the mid to late '80s.
You never saw any of her videos?
- No, Nate, I missed those.
- This chick fucked a snake.
- This chick fucked 30 guys at one time.
- I saw that. I saw that!
My cousin Ramone showed me
when I was like 12.
On the diving board. Okay?
They were wrapped around the pool.
Did you see the one where the guy's
riding this motorcycle, so he's...
...fucking her while riding in circles?
- Oh, shit!
Nate.
Could I speak to you
outside for a minute?
Damn it, Nate! The woman on that table
is just as deserving of dignity...
...as anyone else we prepare.
And Federico is an employee.
It's up to you and me to set
an example for him, all right?
- All right, I'm sorry.
- Show some respect.
These are human lives
we're dealing with here.
These are not organic blackberries
or granola in bulk.
- I said, I'm sorry.
- I don't want you to be sorry.
I want you to remember
that what we do here is serious...
...because it really sucks for me
always having to be the spoilsport.
Okay.
Thank you.
- Hello?
- Nate, Bernard Chenowith,
Hi.
Margaret and I were wondering if you
would join us for dinner tomorrow night.
- We won't take no for an answer.
- You hear that?
Well, actually I have a lot of
studying to do for this exam...
Nate...
...we'd really love to be able
to get a sense of who you are...
...and I'm sure you're curious
about us as well, right?
Good. Shall we say 7-ish?
Can I bring anything?
Hello?
Suck on that, you ugly fuck!
Hi.
There's this thing called knocking. It's,
like, protected in the First Amendment.
I rented some videos.
I thought you and I could
watch them tonight.
Remember when you
were in middle school...
...you and I went to the movies
every Monday night?
Remember how much fun we had?
I remember seeing a lot
of really bad movies.
What'd you get?
Runaway Bride
and The Nutty Professor.
Cool.
Oz didn 't make you a bitch,
You were born one,
lt'd be good for business too.
Dad was a deacon there.
It's a big congregation. People die.
Their families don't know where to go,
and the church sends them our way.
They know you're gay?
I think Father Jack
has a pretty good idea.
- You think he likes you?
- Keith.
Does this mean you're not gonna be
going to church with me anymore?
Well, if they make me a deacon,
I'd have to go there all the time, yeah.
I'm sorry. I know.
Sundays have sort of been our day.
I think it's great. I really do.
One of the things I love about you...
...is the fact that your religion
means so much to you.
Besides, I think it could be
kind of hot, you know?
Dating a man of the cloth?
- But I need you to do something for me.
- What is it, my son?
You know the gay firemen
and police officers club I belong to?
Well, we're having a party
in Laguna this weekend.
- I want you to be my date.
- Your date? Will I get a corsage?
I want you to start meeting
some of my friends, David.
I'd like that.
Forgive me, Father,
for I am about to sin.
This is an entire movie
about expelling gas.
I think that's why people like it.
- I don't want to watch this.
- Good, because neither do I.
Claire, look...
...I know you probably think
I'm old and stupid.
No, Mom, I don't.
But I love you just as much
as I ever did...
...and I'm worried about you,
and I don't know how to help.
I don't need help.
Why is everyone acting like
I'm in the Trenchcoat Mafia?
- You stole a foot. A human foot!
- Okay, you want to know why?
Because some guy who scammed me
into having sex with him...
...because I thought he cared about me,
told the entire school I sucked his toes.
And then when I confronted him,
he showed entirely no remorse.
I saw Nate drop the foot on the floor.
I grabbed it to get back at that asshole.
It wasn't premeditated.
I'm not Jeffrey Dahmer.
- I don't get off on hacked-up body parts.
- You're having sex?
No. Jesus. No, I'm sorry. I cannot have
this conversation with you.
And I'm sorry, but I don't think
we're ever gonna have...
...a touchy-feely, mother-daughter
relationship like on TV and the movies...
...because you know what?
They don't exist!
Here's our guest...
...and he brought us a bottle
of Louis Jadot Pinot Noir.
- 1997, no less.
- Okay, a man who knows his wine.
I'm liking you more and more, Nate.
Well, I worked at a food co-op in Seattle
for a long time. Learned a little bit.
A co-op? So there's a little hippie
in there, huh?
That makes sense.
Brenda would find that attractive.
She likes to think of herself
as being wildly countercultural.
I think she's actually
just jealous of the fact...
...that Bern and I really were hippies,
briefly.
- Can I offer you a drink?
- Sure, do you have any beer?
No, we have vodka, scotch, bourbon.
- I'll have a little bourbon.
- Manly, but not elitist. Just her type.
Down, girl.
So where is Brenda?
Brenda?
Oh, Brenda's not coming tonight.
- Really?
- She felt, and I have to agree with her...
...we'd have a better chance of getting
to know each other if she weren't here.
She does tend to take
center stage, so to speak.
- I wish somebody had thought to tell me.
- I'm sorry. I assumed she did.
There you are.
David was raised in this church.
He was christened and confirmed here,
he served as an altar boy...
...and he was president
of the youth ministry in high school.
- How old are you, David?
- I'm 31.
- What do you do for a living?
- I'm a funeral director.
His father served as a deacon for over
a decade. He just recently passed away.
So you see this
as a sort of passing the torch.
No, sir, I see it as a chance
to serve God.
Well, I'm glad to hear you say that.
Because that's what it is.
Being a deacon is more than just having
access to the church mailing list...
...and passing out your business cards
after Mass.
Sir, I won't deny that I run a business...
...providing service to people
in times of need.
But I would never exploit my relationship
to the church for marketing purposes.
Frankly, I consider that to be
a pretty grave sin.
No pun intended.
St. Bartholomew is an old church...
...a conservative church...
...a church that doesn't need
to have its boat rocked.
Which is precisely why I feel
David is a good candidate.
How many men his age
have values as strong as his?
I think he would be
an excellent role model.
- Are you married?
- No, sir. I was engaged, briefly.
Is there anything else you'd like
to tell me about yourself...
...before I consider this?
No, sir.
Is there anything specific about me
that you'd like to ask?
No.
I'll let you know my decision
in a few days.
- You impressed him.
- You think?
Yes.
Oh, by the way, one of our parishioners
recently lost her father to liver cancer.
Sharon Murdoch. I gave her your name.
You may be getting a call.
Thank you.
- Again with the not knocking.
- Pack some things.
- We're going to San Bernardino.
- What?
We're spending the night
at my cousin Hannah's.
- Mom, I'm doing homework.
- Well, stop!
- I have school tomorrow.
- I'll write a note!
It's been a long time since Brenda's
wanted us to meet...
...any of the men in her life.
- What was that last one, chiropractor?
- He was a Rolfer.
He was an idiot.
Well, I'm not sure Brenda
ever meant for us to meet.
I don't think she expected you guys
to come home that day.
Oh, Nate.
Where Brenda's concerned,
there are no coincidences.
- You think she planned all this?
- Of course.
She's a master manipulator.
I love her dearly, but you really ought
to know what you're getting into.
Would you like another bourbon?
No, thanks.
Can I ask you guys something?
As long as it doesn't involve
asking us for money.
No, it doesn't.
Does the name "Nathaniel"
have any significance to you?
Well, sure. Nathaniel and Isabel.
Brenda adored these books as a little girl.
She could read by the time she was 3.
- What are they about?
- Two orphans who had adventures.
They ran away from an orphanage.
There was a malevolent nurse
who was always hunting them down...
...but they always managed
to outsmart her.
Typical infantile wish fulfillment.
- I've never even heard of them.
- They're British, quite dark.
People die in them all the time.
When Brenda's brother was born...
...we expected serious displacement
anxiety from her, but there was none.
She would sit next to his crib
and read him these stories for hours.
- She was what then, Bern, 4?
- 5 at most.
It's all in the book.
This book?
You mean, she didn't tell
you about that either?
I feel terrible,
- I'm sorry I snapped at Grandma,
- Yeah, huh?
That was a pretty Freaky Friday moment
we had back there,
Ruthie, I am so glad you called.
Ginnie and I would never allow
ourselves this kind of food...
...unless it were a really
special occasion.
We are definitely gonna have to do
an extra spinning class this week.
Tomorrow morning?
- Who's teaching?
- Derek.
I'm so there.
Mom and I have the hugest crush
on this spinning instructor at the Y.
He is hot, hot, hot.
So, Claire, have you thought
about college?
Yeah.
I'd love to go to, like,
NYU or Columbia...
...but I don't know
if I could ever get in, so...
Well, there are some great schools
in L.A.
Why would you want to go to school
in the same town you grew up in?
I go to Cal State
right here in San Berdoo.
- Well, whatever rocks your boat.
- Claire.
Hey, I love it.
By living at home, I'm saving
a ton of money for grad school.
I'm not stuck in a crappy dorm
where everyone's smoking pot...
...and playing loud music all the time.
And I don't have to call campus police
every time I walk home from the library...
...so that I don't get raped.
- And I like to stay close to my mom.
- That translates to: I do her laundry.
Oh, that's not true.
I love my mom,
and I'm not ashamed of it.
Thank you, honey. I love you too.
Okay, anybody want more?
- So how was it?
- Oh, it was quite informative.
I know what Nathaniel means now.
I know you have an IQ of 185.
I know you had a book
written about you.
Here, I signed it for you.
Why didn't you just tell me about this?
People always change after they read it.
I was trying to make the fun part last.
Oh, God! So you're kind of
scarily brilliant, I can handle that.
What I can't handle is the way
you keep mind-fucking me...
...for your personal entertainment.
It's really starting to piss me off.
I'm sorry I'm not a well-behaved,
little nothing that never challenges you...
...but if that's what you're looking for,
you might as well just leave right now.
So, what, you're trying
to drive me away?
Yeah, Nate, I'm trying
to drive you away.
It was my mother's idea
that I not be there...
...which is fine by me.
I don't really enjoy their company.
She said it was your idea.
Yeah, she would. She probably
believes that. She's out of her mind.
You could've warned me
what I was walking into.
You wouldn't have gone.
I just wanted to get it all
out of the way.
Them, the book, everything.
Yeah, well, I felt like a fucking lab rat
over there!
Yeah, that's what they do!
I'm 6 years old, I score through the roof
on some standardized, biased test...
...and it all becomes about them!
They hand me over to strangers,
experts, a bunch of academic fucks...
...who scrutinized everything I did
or said or thought even.
It is a fucking law of physics
that the very act of observation...
...changes that which is being observed.
And now you're gonna read that book
and think that you know me.
- Well, you know what? You don't.
- Yeah, because you won't let me.
Okay, fine.
What do you want to know?
Ask me anything.
Did you burn down that house
that we made love in?
You think I burned down the house?
Really? That is so weird!
Well, what am I supposed to think?
You put my brother and me
in the bus that killed our father.
You get weird phone calls from
screaming people you won't explain.
Now you wanna make me
feel stupid for being suspicious?
Give me a fucking reason not to be!
I just want to know what this is...
...for you.
Am I just another step along your way?
Okay, look...
...we obviously have
an intense sexual connection...
...and yes, I would like for there to be
something more than that.
But that can't ever happen until you
trust me, which apparently you don't.
Should I trust you?
Yes.
Come here.
R-A...
...K- E.
Triple letter score for K.
Good one, Mom.
H-E-L-L.
H-E-L-L...
...O.
Hello.
D...
...E...
...F...
...T.
Deft. What is deft?
Well, it's a laundry detergent
from when Ruth and I were kids.
No, it's a word.
It means skilled.
Really? Use it in a sentence.
He deftly juggled his responsibilities.
Deft.
Or "Deft, where ith thy sting?"
So how you both doing,
you know, with Nathaniel passing?
- Better every day.
- You know, shit happens.
You know, it's such an awful thing,
losing someone you love.
In terms of stress, it's right up there
with moving and getting fired.
I know when Ed and I split up,
I was devastated.
I didn't even want to get out of bed.
I just wanted to curl up and die.
And all I can say is, thank God
for my precious daughter.
Well, I just wouldn't let her mope.
Just wouldn't let her.
Dragged her ass,
pardon my French, out of bed...
...and took her to spinning class
with me.
And I hated her for it at the time,
but it really got me back on track.
You know, endorphins really are
nature's antidepressants.
Life goes on. It doesn't go on by itself.
Sometimes you just gotta
kick it in the butt.
But Ed didn't die.
He's still alive. You can still see him.
When Ginnie gets married,
you'll both be there.
When she has children,
they'll be able to know him.
He's not gone forever.
Yeah, well, sure, but...
...in terms of the impact
it had on both our lives...
...it's similar.
Okay, I have the greatest idea.
You guys are coming to spinning class
with us tomorrow, bright and early.
No offense, but I'd rather drive
a rusty railroad spike through my skull.
Oh, just try it once.
You might be surprised
how it changes the way you feel.
- I feel fine.
- You know what, Ginnie?
That is absolutely an inspired idea!
Okay, ladies, let's get to bed. Because
if your butt isn't on that bike by 6 a. M...
...Derek doesn't let you in.
So these tits do nothing for you, huh?
Well, I can appreciate
that they are beautiful...
...in their own completely artificial way.
Men loved them.
Well, real men.
You think God cares that you're gay?
You think God cares
that you fucked 30 guys at once?
Oh, so you equate being a fag
with being a whore?
- No.
- One's okay, but one isn't?
I think God appreciates it
when love's involved.
Oh, honey.
I loved every man I ever fucked
while I was fucking him.
- What are you doing?
- Watching you.
Claire, wake up. Get dressed.
- Why?
- We're leaving. Hurry.
Jesus, Mom, I'm starting to feel
like Anne Frank.
If we don't get out of here fast,
we'll have to go spinning.
Oh, my God.
- Let's go.
- Wait.
What are you doing?
Thanks for buying me breakfast.
Thank you for finding
my G-spot this morning.
Anytime.
Oh, I have something for you.
Wow.
- Oh, come on, it's just a key.
- No, this is great.
I'm a little surprised, that's all.
I'm too nervous to eat.
I'll just drink coffee
until I start twitching and sweating.
Why does being a deacon
mean so much to you now?
- It wasn't a consideration a week ago.
- I know you think it's naive...
...but I see it as a chance
to make a difference...
...make the world a little more tolerant.
David, we have our own church
in West Hollywood...
...which means the other churches
and dioceses don't have to tolerate us.
Frankly, I resent the notion
that I need to be tolerated.
So, what, we should just allow
ourselves to be ghettoized?
Why do you embrace an organization
that doesn't embrace you?
- The church embraces everyone.
- Right. Hate the sin, love the sinner.
- The operative word being "hate."
- What is with you?
The other night you said
you liked the idea.
I had a chance to think.
Isn't that your brother?
Okay, look, can we just have breakfast...
...without me feeling like I'm George Will
and you're Cokie Roberts with PMS?
You probably like George Will.
Dave.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Keith, you remember my brother Nate,
don't you?
- How's it going?
- Hey.
This is Brenda.
My...
- My girlfriend.
- I prefer the term "fuck puppet."
So, what are you guys doing here,
you just play racquetball?
- No. No, we just worked out.
- Oh, so you guys work out together?
Yeah.
Yeah, we do.
Oh, well, that's great.
Okay, great.
Okay, you guys have a great day.
You too.
Bye, David.
Oh, my God, I think David is gay.
I think David is lucky.
Did you get a look at that guy?
Claire.
I had an affair.
For the last two years
I was seeing someone.
Your father never knew about it.
At least, I hope he didn't.
And I called it off after he died.
It's not something I'm proud of.
- Why are you telling me this?
- Because it's the truth.
And whatever relationship
you and I have, I want it to be honest...
...even if you hate me.
Mom, I don't hate you.
I remember going to the movies
on Monday nights...
...but I'm 17 years old now,
and I have my own life.
And there's things I have
to figure out on my own.
And that's, like, normal.
And I know stealing a foot is weird...
...but hello, living in a house where
a foot is available to be stolen is weird.
I gotta get to school.
- Did you see his face?
- Oh, man.
I know I shouldn't be laughing,
but he looked so stupefied.
The way he was all,
"Great, great. I'm hip, I'm cool."
Proud of you, man.
So listen, this thing in Laguna
is Saturday night.
I got us a room at the Surf and Sand.
You ever been there?
- No.
- Man, it's gonna be great.
We got a fireplace
overlooking the ocean.
Keith, I don't think I can make it after all.
I shouldn't miss church, not while
they're considering me for a deaconship.
- I'm sorry.
- Fine.
We'll come back Saturday night.
- That'll work.
- I can go to church with you on Sunday.
That's not a good idea.
This hasn't been a good idea
from the beginning, has it?
Fine, why don't we cut our losses...
...and call it quits right now?
- What?
Look, as long as you feel the need
to keep our relationship a secret...
David, you're ashamed of it!
I'm not having any of that, not anymore.
- I just came out to my brother.
- One step forward.
Now you want to take a giant leap
backwards into the arms of the enemy.
So now I'm a Nazi collaborator?
A lot of African-Americans might say
the same thing about you...
...being a member of the L.A.P.D.
You fucking coward!
Keith, please don't...
It works.
I must have left the stereo on again.
So you are not too freaked out?
A little, maybe.
It makes David more interesting.
No, I mean about me giving you
a key to my apartment.
What do you think I am, an aging
Peter Pan who's gonna disappear...
...at the sign of something permanent?
- Well, yeah.
You're one to talk. You couldn't even
allow me to refer to you as my girlfriend.
Don't mind me.
I thought we agreed that you would call
before you came over.
I did. The hot water's out in my building.
I needed to take a shower.
Don't be mad at me.
You know I hate it
when you're mad at me.
Hey, it's me,
I need to use your shower, okay?
Besides, I haven 't seen you in a while,
and it's a fucking gorgeous day,
- Satisfied?
- I'm going to make a cup of tea.
Hey...
...I'll take one of those.
- Hey, you behave yourself.
Hi. What's your name?
- Nate.
- Nice to meet you. I'm Billy.
Hi.
So how long you known Brenda?
A few months.
So...
Who am I and why am I in your
girlfriend's house practically naked?
- Yeah.
- She's my sister.
She's my mother. Sister. My mother.
Sorry. Nobody's ever laughed at that.
I should know better.
It's nice to meet you.
- So you met the parents yet?
- Yes, last night.
Wow.
You've made it pretty far.
So why haven't I heard about you?
No idea.
Well, I guess I better go
put some clothes on.
How'd you get her breasts synchronized?
Some sort of industrial epoxy?
Would you ask Colonel Sanders
for his secret recipe?
Oh, come on, I'm not gonna tell.
I stuck a can of cat food
under each one.
My sister-in-law did
a cat food commercial.
We've got like 10 cases.
Hey. I'm Larry Wadd.
You know...
...I met Viveca St. John
before she even did her first video.
Yeah, she was...
She was the fluffer
on the set of Dirty Larry 3.
She was...
...friendly. She was eager.
I can honestly say I've never received
a better blowjob in my life.
And nobody was even filming it.
When I first met Viveca,
I met her on Deep Diving.
Thank you.
And I had never gone down on a girl
before. So naturally, I was nervous...
...but Viveca was so warm
and relaxed about it.
She really put me at ease.
Well, her and the two Xanax
she gave me.
And when I first had to do
a double penetration...
...I was, like, a total wreck.
But Viveca came through
like such the pro she is.
I mean was.
- Nate, what the hell is going on in there?
- A funeral.
For whom? A prostitute?
A woman who was a star
of adult videos.
Mom, we're gonna clear
8 grand from this.
We can finally pay for all that
air conditioning work.
I'm just glad your sister is at school.
It was awful.
They're like best friends.
They're both like cheerleaders
with this totally plastic way of life...
...like spinning class solves everything...
...and they're both hot
for the same guy. It was creepy.
My mom's...
My mom is just so fucking sad.
And I wish I could help her.
So help her.
Now, Mrs. Murdoch, some people
prefer the solemnity of a church...
...and St. Bartholomew
is a beautiful setting.
Here, however, one is more free
to customize the service.
I'm sorry to interrupt.
I just had to tell somebody.
Viveca looks so great.
Her tits have never looked better.
She was like a sister to me.
I'm so glad that you're pleased.
We want to remember her
at her very best, don't we?
Now, I'm sorry, but I'm helping
some other people right now.
- Okay.
- I'll talk to you after the service?
Okay.
I think we'll have Dad's service
at the church.
Fine.
I'm not a religious man,
but I do believe in God.
If I were to make a list of the things
I thank God for the most...
...fucking Viv would be
at the top of that list.
She was a goddamn force of nature.
And I loved her.
And I know God loved her too.
I know he knew
just what he was doing...
...and how much joy...
...she would bring to the world.
For David James Fisher,
chosen deacon in your church...
...we pray to you, O Lord.
- Lord, hear our prayer.
That he may faithfully fulfill
the duties of this ministry...
...build up your church
and glorify your name...
...we pray to you, O Lord.
- Lord, hear our prayer.
That by the indwelling of the Holy Spirit
he may be sustained and encouraged...
...to persevere to the end...
...we pray to you, O Lord.
- Lord, hear our prayer.
For all who fear God
and believe in you, Lord Christ...
...that our divisions may cease
and that all may be as one...
...as you and the Father are one.
- We pray to you, O Lord.
- Lord, hear our prayer.
Way to go, Dave.
All I have to do is join the Kiwanis club...
...and Fisher & Sons will have
all our bases covered.
Where's Keith?
He's just a friend, Nate.
- Very good to see you.
- Hello.
So, Mom, what are you doing
tomorrow night?
Nothing as far as I know. Why?
I thought maybe you'd want to go see
a movie or rent a movie or something.
Okay, but if you cry,
the whole thing is off.
Thanks for coming today.
- I know you must've found this a little...
- Are you kidding? I loved it.
All that pageantry, it's so trippy.
It's like a Fellini movie.
Well, it was kind of cool being with you
here in front of God and everybody.
- You don't really believe in God, do you?
- Well, yeah.
I mean, I don't believe in some bearded,
old, white man up in a cloud...
...but I believe in something.
Some sort of undefinable creative force.
I think it's just all totally random.
Really?
Yeah.
We live, we die.
Ultimately, nothing means anything.
How can you live like that?
I don't know. Sometimes
I wake up so fucking empty...
...I wish I'd never been born,
but what choice do I have?
Subtitles by www.tv-series.nm.ru