Do you guys not see the problem here ?
Vince said she was stayin' a couple nights, right ? A couple's two.
Except in Utah.
Look at him, she's got him doing fuckin' yoga, man. It's embarrassing
She thinks she's his trainer.
So do you.
What ? I'm not ?
What the fuck did I get certified for then ?
Relax, Drama, you're his trainer.
Hey, it's all a big joke to E. 'Cause he's been
sleepin' off campus at Emily's.
What do you got a lojack on me, Turtle ?
You guys are both gonna get girlfriends and
you're gonna fuck everything up !
Quiet, here they come.
How was yoga ?
Great.
Fiona's a great teacher.
Thanks, baby.
Alright, you ready for a real workout Vince ?
Nah, no weights. I just had a mean stretch.
Hey, Vince, you gotta hit the weights if you wanna put on size, man.
Bulk is so '90s, johnny. It's all about flexibility,
don't you think ?
Um... no, I don't.
We'll catch you later. We're gonna go grab breakfast.
Bye, guys.
I don't trust that "new-agey" bullshit.
Me neither. Even if it is attached to an ass like that.
Yo, E., What up, dawg ?
Not much. How 'bout you ?
Never better.
Who's that jerk-off ?
No clue.
Yanks are playing the Angels tuesday.
I got the company box if you want to roll with.
Got the gals from "the L. Word" coming.
Trust me, they're only acting.
Not trying to be an asshole or anything, but ah,
do we know each other ?
E., You kiddin' me ?
Josh Weinstein, Triad, we met at the fight.
Oh, yeah, okay. Alright, Josh, do me a favor,
put a towel on or something, cover up.
Not a locker room guy. No problem.
So listen, E, I didn't want to interrupt Vince's workout,
but I got a great piece of material.
Could you do me a favor and have him take a look ?
Josh, you got to understand, the guy, he gets
hundreds of scripts a week, you know that right ?
Yeah, but this is something special. Kick's ass.
It's gritty as shit.
You'll love it, I guarantee you Vince will flip.
Tell Vince it was a great movepassing on "Matterhorn", too.
You think ?
Oh, yeah, script's a piece of shit. It's not a
movie, it's a theme park ride... there's no characters.
That's what I said.
I bet Ari pushed hard for that one, huh ?
Yeah.
You know he doesn't read, right ?
Anyway, man, this one's different.
Takes place in your old neighborhood.
Queens, right ?
Yeah.
Hey, how are you ?
Hi, sweetheart ?
Oh my god, I'm sorry.
I, um, I thought you were someone else.
come on, Monica.
I'm done talking to you, Turtle.
You were supposed to hook me up with some weed two days ago.
The whole town's dry. Believe me,
I'm not holding out on you.
What are you looking at ?
These uggs, they're great, but... I can't find them anywhere.
I can get those for you in two seconds, alright ?
Just gimme the size and the style number.
Oh ?
Hey, Shauna, what up ?
Yeah, I have an apparel request for Vince.
He needs a pair of uggs for his lady friend, ASAP !
Yeah.
Hey, you don't have a weed guy, do ya ?
Hey.
What are you doing ?
Just reading a script.
Any good ?
Ah, it's great, so far, yeah.
So, that's your job ? You just read a bunch of
scripts and tell Vince which the good ones are ?
Yeah, something like that.
Wow, that's a really cool job.
So did you go to school for that ?
No.
I love to read. I read all the Harry Potter books, and...
I don't know, if you need a second opinion,
don't hesitate.
okay, cool.
- Alright.
- Thanks.
Don't get mad, but I think she's stealin' food.
She's not stealing food.
Well, shit keeps disappearin' out of the fridge.
I did have an ivy meatloaf vanish.
I know how these kleptos work.
First it's the food, then it's the plasma.
Alright, she didn't steal it, she threw it away.
- Throwing it away, why ?
- She's vegan.
What the fuck does that mean ?
It means, she's into a cruelty-free lifestyle.
It's cruel to throw away a $65.00 steak from Morton's.
Look guys, just do me a favor.
And keep the meat out of her eye-line while she's around.
Look, she's already got him wearing cloth shoes.
These are my slippers, idiot.
And they're the ones that he stole
from the Four Seasons mall.
Oh, those are the slippers ?
Where's the robe ?
Fiona just dropped the robe at the pool.
And had nothing on underneath.
She's naked at the pool ?
Yeah.
And you were looking at her ?
She's naked at the pool.
How'd she look ?
Good enough to eat, I bet, huh ?
Yeah.
Too bad Vince can't eat animal products anymore.
I'm goin' up, you mind ?
Yeah, I mind.
Sue me, I'm goin' !
Did you call the hack ?
Ah, yeah, he's got nothing.
How can the whole town be out of weed ?
Hack says the drought dried up the crops, man.
It ain't on me, peace.
Three days, Vince. You're bending the rules.
I made the rules.
Can we talk about something important here ?
This is important, it's a lifestyle issue.
Did you see the picture of the swami in the bathroom ?
It's her guru.
Well, I don't like the way he looks at me when I'm pissing.
I found your next movie, Vince.
Yeah ?
Yeah, this script is awesome,
you got to read it now. Now.
Vince, I need you.
I'll read it later.
All she wants to do is fuck.
The plan is to get as close as possible
without actually touching.
How long do we have to go for ?
The longer we hold out the better the sex.
Some tantric masters hold out for years.
Yeah, but they're up in a mountains somewhere
by themselves. They're probably whacking off like crazy.
Vince, you reading that script ?
I'm sorry, babe, I'm on a tight schedule.
Alright, here you go, Turtle.
Now you can stop bothering me.
Thanks, Shauna.
Vince's lady friend's really gonna love these.
- These aren't taiwanese knock-offs, are they ?
- Would I do that to you ?
Nah, those are real goods.
Look at the sheepskin.
You can tell these babies were born and raised
in the outback.
- Yeah ?
- Yeah, absolutely.
Thanks a mil, Shauna.
Don't thank me, thank Christy.
Christy.
Christy, thanks.
Oh yeah, no problem.
If you ever need anything, concert tickets,
pedicure, full body massage...
How 'bout a stun gun ?
Alright.
Shauna, what's with the photographer ?
I thought I told you I don't want Vince posing
on one of these things.
Yeah, then I called back and said if he still wants
the Harley, he's gonna have to take a picture on it.
Yeah, but we never had that discussion.
- You're right, I had it with Turtle.
- And I spoke with Vince.
And that's all I give a shit about. What Vincent wants. So don't fuck with me like you're fucking with Ari, Eric !
Hey, Eric, I read it, it's awesome.
- You read what ?
- The script, it's so good.
- You read it ?
- Yeah, god, it even made me cry, right, Vince ?
Yeah, it did.
Hey, shauna.
Yeah ?
Just so you know, look, you know I love you,
but... I can't take a picture on that thing.
Turtle said that you would do it.
No, I know, it's just my girl, she's really
conscious about the environment.
And she thinks it sends the wrong message.
Really, I mean she doesn't mind riding around in
your hummer... What is she thinking ?
Look, I don't know what she's thinking,
but you know, I can't be hassled.
Vince, you're totally fucking me on this.
I'll take the picture.
What am I supposed to do with your fucking picture ?
And you, gimme back those uggs.
I know they're not for him, you fat midget.
Shauna, you're gonna have to pull 'em
from my cold, dead hands.
Oh, really ?
Good boy, Arnold.
- What the fuck, what are you doin' ?
- You didn't call bank shot.
I did too, you didn't hear me !
- You got to learn to project.
- You hire a vocal coach, become a real asshole.
E., Script's great.
- You read it ?
- Yep.
How many pages ?
The whole thing.
Yeah, right, how does it end ?
What are you an asshole ?
I'm just saying, I tell you I got your next movie,
you ignore me.
Fiona likes it, you read it in an hour ?
I read it, what's the difference ?
I don't know, but there is one.
You know, don't worry about that. Let's get it
together. Call Ari, find out why he doesn't know about it.
Yeah, E., Go call Ari. Get us paid.
Shut up, Turtle.
Vince, you see any juicy parts for me ?
Yeah, maybe you could play his father.
Fuck you.
Ari Gold's office.
- Hey.
- Hey. You left your wallet at my house.
- Did I ?
- Yes. Is that your way of saying you want to come back ?
Sort of, yeah.
So, we read a script that we love.
Anyway Ari's free for lunch ?
Ah, like in december.
Hold on, let me just take care of something for you.
Alright, I just rescheduled Anthony Lapaglia.
- Oh, thanks.
- I'll see you tonight.
- Okay.
- Bye
- Pussy.
- Fagget.
Um, yeah, I'll get the faux mung bean meatloaf.
Okay.
What the fuck are we doing here, man ?
I'm on atkins, I need protein.
Come on, there's plenty of protein in mung beans.
No, no, I'm talking about real protein. I mean, like man
protein. You know, from the flesh of slaughtered animals.
I want to have war paint on, I want to have blood
dripping. That's what I need.
Have you seen a video of a slaughter house, Ari ?
Meat is murder.
Even broccoli screams when you rip it from the ground.
Alright, enough about the fucking menu. Can we talk about "Queens Boulevard" for one second ?
- I really want to do this one.
- It's the best script I've ever read.
- She's reading your scripts now ?
- Vince asked me to.
Oh, he did ?
Do you guys have a problem with that ?
Not if you don't mind it not being printed on recycled paper. It's all good.
What's the matter, E. ? The big words overwhelm you ? You had to, pass it along ?
Well, I read it.
- You don't even know about it.
- Oh, I knew about it.
- You think that you knew about it and I didn't know about it ?
- I think so.
You think there's anything in this fucking
universe that you know about that I don't know about ?!
- Vince, can I talk to you, please ?
- Yeah.
First rule of being a manager, is control the star's fucking girlfriend.
'Cause Yoko Ono, is macro-psychotic.
- What's wrong ?
- You heard what he said about meat.
I know, I know, babe, I'm sorry.
God, man, I'm going to wait outside. Your agent is a karmic disaster.
Okay, babe, I'll see you out there.
I'll be like, five minutes.
Excuse me ?
I was wondering, if maybe, you would take a picture with us ?
Sure, why not.
Thank you so much.
Hey, idiot, do you know that Scott Wick is my best friend ?
Who's Scott Wick, asshole ?
He's the producer of the movie, you dumb fuck.
Oh, okay, well this should be pretty fuckin' easy,
don't ya think, douchebag ?
No, Eric, it shouldn't.
Because what you don't know, you little garlic knot making motherfucker, is that Wick hates Vince.
So, now that you've gotten him all excited about
the script. How would you like to break that news to him ?
Okay, I'll do that. Hold on, watch this.
Hey, Vince, the producer of the movie thinks you suck !
Do one more.
Now what, Ari ?
Hey, is it alright if I hang out with you guys ?
It's a free sidewalk.
What ?
Bite ?
No, thank you.
You trying to tell me you can't find one person in
the entire West Coast that has a joint ?
You're slackin', hack.
Alright.
He's sendin' a recon team up to Humboldt county.
But, ah, he's not hopeful.
You guys in need of weed ?
What do you know about it ?
I got a sherpa who grows 100% organic.
No herbicides, no pesticides.
Yeah, like we're goin' all the way to Zverest to
score weed from your sherpa.
Come on, guys, he doesn't live in Everest
anymore. He lives in Bel Air.
What the fuck's a sherpa ?
This guy sells weed out of this house ?
Yeah, even the carpet's made of hemp, it's cool.
I just stepped in shit.
Whoa...
Come on, guys.
Holy shit.
A field of fucking dreams.
I said check the fluorescents in the vegetation
chamber. It's the little thingy with the lights on it.
Hey, baby.
Dakatoka.
How are you doing ?
That's her channeled name. Fiona's channeled name is Dakatoka.
I missed you.
Oh, you're an ancient wisdom giver.
Who, Fiona is ?
Dah.
Johnny Drama ?
I'm Johnny Drama.
I'm a fan, man.
When's the next season of "Viking Quest", dude ?
It got cancelled seven years ago.
- Bummer.
- Yeah.
Eurydice, ina, we're gonna have a little tea.
Make some ancient mayan mule shit. It's a hybrid.
Drama.
Earth is moving.
Did you feel that ? Everything all the time.
There are dimensions we can't even see.
Everything is evolving...
Turtle, you're a dove.
That's cool, could I hit that... chirp, thanks.
Aren't you afraid of getting busted ?
Busted, I'm entrusted.
I don't steal. I heal.
We're not getting stoned, we're getting honed.
My probation officer's one of my best customers.
I'm a prisoner. I'm a prisoner of war... the war on drugs.
It's all so negative, man.
I mean the man's most positive, positive 'tiv,
is the negative. He's a mega-negative.
Right ?
"Viking Quest" !
Let them be low. We are getting high.
We're not getting fucked down. We're getting fucked-up.
That's awesome.
Yo, I think that went out, though.
Don't touch it !
No, it's cool, it's cool, Finley. It's a cell phone.
Okay.
Is it cool ?
Please, enjoy.
Put it on vibrate.
Hello ?
Call me Helen Keller 'cause I'm a fucking miracle
worker. Seven o'clock at Mastro'S. You're gonna
break bread with wick. And don't be late !
And tell Vince to wear something tight.
Yeah, okay.
Sorry about that. Ari delivered Wick.
We have dinner at Mastro's at seven.
I'm over that project, E.
What are you talking about ?
I thought you love the script.
I'll love another.
I'm not gonna waste my time with some guy who doesn't like me.
Vince, there are no others, trust me, I know.
I'm the one who reads them.
If this guy meets you, he'll love you.
Oh, yeah ?
Free steak, what the fuck ?
I'm dying for some red meat.
Hey, anybody need some clean urine ?
You're fuckin' whipped, bro.
God, would you stop it already ?
- Jesus.
- It's true though, I mean this girl tells you
what pictures to take.
What scripts to read, what dinners to go to...
I mean, come on. Where you're fucking balls ?
Alright, E., Don't freak, alright.
I love her, I want to marry her.
- I'm fucking with you, relax, bro.
- That's not funny.
Dude, look, she's leaving on friday, she's going
to an ashram in India for four months.
Well, in that case, I love her.
- No problem, she's gone.
- Good, get her out of here.
- I know...
Gentleman, Scott Wick.
Hello.
Let's make this snappy.
Be nice.
Mmm, beluga.
Excuse me ?
Caviar. Reminds me of a cold winter night in Novgorod.
Where is...Nov, Novgorod ?
It's in Russia.
E. didn't know that 'cause he dropped out of college.
So what'd you do in russia, scott ?
My father was an american diplomat.
Oh, that's nice.
My father was a douchebag.
Okay, I am gonna get the New York strip, 'cause
it reminds me of my childhood... in New York.
That's funny, that's funny.
So, Scott, listen. We want to talk to you about
the script. Vince wants to do it.
Yeah. I read it and I loved it.
I appreciate that, boys, but, unfortunately,
I just don't see you in it.
You know, this movie is about a guy from
Queens. It's a kid from the neighborhood.
Vince is a guy from Queens. He is from the neighborhood.
Well, he doesn't feel like he is.
Where does he feel like he's from ?
I don't know, the Appalachians ?
Come on...
You know what, with all due respect
I grew up a block from where this script takes place,
in a shitty little apartment with five brothers and sisters and a psychotically drunk father.
I am this part.
Yes, but you know that even the truth sometimes
seems fake, right ? Wouldn't you say ?
This doesn't seem like it's going anywhere, does it, Scottie ?
Not really.
I'm gonna order a little extra.
Maybe I'll get this rib eye, to go.
Bring a little doggy bag home for the boys.
Do I look like goodwill to you ?
What are you, high ?
Actually, Scott, I am.
Is that a problem ?
Where did you get it ?
Oh, a friend of mine. Some of the best shit I've
ever smoked. Are you in need ?
I am. My guy says the town is dry...
something about a drought.
Is your guy black hack ?
My guy spoke to another guy, but I don't really have a guy.
I could hook you up.
Fellas, c'mon, what are we doing here...
we talkin about the script or we talking about weed ?
Maybe both, E. Maybe both.
oh, Christ, I'm going to have to lie at my
N.A. Meeting... again !
Scott, can I ask you a question ?
Mm-hmm.
Why do you have to be such a hard ass all the time ?
I don't know. 'Cause it... I don't know,
I guess it's just fuckin' fun.
You think I'm a hard ass ?
Oh, shit, oh, shit.
This should be fun.
Give me one of those, cocksucker, motherfucker.
Scott, relax, you said your dad's a diplomat, right ?
That was 50 fucking years ago, asshole.
Just roll down the windows.
I'm on fucking probation.
For what ?
It was nothing, it wasn't anything. It wasn't even true.
Hello, officer.
License and registration.
Sure.
Here you go.
Is there a problem ?
Yeah, um, mr. Wick.
You're parked in a red zone.
Oh.
Would you step out of the car, please ?
I could just move it.
Sir, out of the car.
Excuse me, officer. Hi, how are you ?
You know officer Hecht ?
His daughter Melissa's a good friend of mine.
I know you.
Saw the new trailer, movie looks good.
Yeah. It's a good film.
It is good. It's real good.
Not only does this guy not bust us for smokin'
weed or parking in the red zone.
He asked this guy for his autograph.
Awesome.
What can I say ? I'm above the law.
Let's toast.
What is this stuff ? Is it wheat or is it grass ?
Whatever, it's good for you.
Nah, I don't trust this shit.
I lived on this stuff in '93.
By the end of the year I was sleeping standing up.
Come on, guys, a goodbye toast.
Aw, you're really gonna leave us ?
I could cancel my trip.
- No, no.
- Bad idea.
- Don't do that, we wouldn't want you to bum out rammed ass.
Ram dass.
Whatever.
Alright, on the count of three.
Three.
That's disgusting.
Hello ?
Mini-Vince.
Hey, ari.
I don't know who blew who, but Wick's got
a crush on your boy Vince, wants him to star
in his vanity project.
Alright, I'll tell him.
Prepare to enter the poor house, you little bitch.
Wick wants you in the movie.
I don't know.
You think I'm Queens enough ?
We'll see.
Synchro par zed22
www.forom.com