[eerie music]
(Arlene)
Mark?Mark!
Mark, would you please
ask your father
if he wants a burger?
I know, you're defending
the free world.
Please ask your dad
if he wants a burger.
[crackling sounds]
Dad.
[muffled radio transmission]
(Mark)
Dad.
Mom wants to know
if you want a burger.
[static]
Mom, I don't know
what he wants.
[throbbing]
[static]
[increasing noise]
You want a burger?
[muffled voices and static]
[wheelchair whirs]
[rumbling and throbbing]
[Massive Attack's Teardrop]
* Feel good *
* *
* City's breakin' down
on a camel's back *
* They just have to go
'cause they don't know whack *
* So all you fill the streets *
* It's appealing to see *
* You won't get undercounted *
* 'Cause you're
damn [bleep] free *
* Feel good * *
The guy drove his wheelchair
into a pool.
House would love that.
He'll be bored.
It's a great visual,
but it's diagnostically boring.
What about post-hair-transplant
aphasia guy?
Infection throwing clots.
House'll shoot it down
and call you an idiot.
Oh, well,
I wouldn't want that.
What about yoga girl?
It has a good hook.
Should we lead with it?
His first day back
he might want to flex
his sarcasm muscle.
Maybe we open with one
of the weaker pitches.
You ran here?
[out of breath]
It's just eight miles.
Why did you--
Why does a dog lick its
workplace-acceptable euphemism
for testicles?
Because he can.
What do you got
for me, boss?
I thought you said you needed
eight weeks of rehab.
You should've
been back here--
If I'd come back sooner,
then I'd only be able
to run six miles.
I never would've made it in.
What do you got for me?
You're completely
pain-free?
The ketamine treatment
can wear off.
It's been two months.
It's not wearing off.
What do you got
for me?
It can take
as long as--
Why are we having
this discussion?
Thank you, Dr. Cuddy--not just
for removing the bullet,
but thank you for putting me
in a ketamine-induced coma
and changing my life.
Happy?
I am.
Middle-aged man
had a hair transplant
about two months ago--
Infection throwing clots.
You're an idiot.
Except you're not an idiot.
And she's holding a file
for a 26-year-old female.
What do you really got
for me?
Girl was doing
an inverted yoga pose.
Neck snapped.
Paralyzed from the neck down.
Except the X-rays show
no evidence of spinal injury.
And she's cute.
Oh, well played, sir.
What about Stephen Hawking
trying to do
the 500 butterfly?
Forget it.
Brain cancer, brain surgery.
I would take
the other one.
Mm...
I'll take 'em both.
You don't think
he had brain cancer?
Course he had brain cancer.
Even oncologists don't screw up
for eight years.
So if there's no
diagnostic issue,
why are you taking
the case?
Treatment can be interesting.
Not to you.
I've changed.
No, you haven't.
No, I haven't.
So why are you taking
the case?
Guy tried to kill himself.
The guy had cancer.
He's a lump.
He hasn't been able
to touch his wife,
speak to his kids.
He's been in that chair
for eight years.
His muscles have atrophied.
Maybe I can help him
with the pain.
Isn't that enough of a reason
to want to help?
Not for you.
I've changed.
No, you haven't.
Then why am I taking
this case?
[sighs]
Let's start
with the cute paraplegic.
Welcome back.
Hey.
You look--
Healthy.
[slaps House on back]
Quad with no broken neck.
Struck me as odd.
Uh, you could take
a whole two minutes
to ease into being back.
Wouldn't taken a whole month
to ease back.
But eight weeks is
the maximum rehab time
for a gunshot wound
to the stomach and neck.
So go.
We heard they never
found the guy.
There's no new leads?
What, you think
he might've shot
this patient, too?
That would explain
her symptoms.
Could be M.S.
See?
It's not so difficult.
It's not M.S.
She had no symptoms before
she climbed onto her head.
Unless she's been upside-down
for the last ten years,
M.S. ain't it.
Could be transverse myelitis,
swelling in the disks
choking off nerve function.
(Chase)
MRI was negative for that.
[mysterious music]
When did this turn into
"What did you do
over your summer vacation?"
(Foreman)
It's a little weird
to discuss the case
while you're staring
at your blood on the floor.
I asked Cuddy
to replace the carpet.
I like the carpet.
What did you do
over the summer?
I--
Redo the tests.
Let's see if the source
of the problem
is in the limbs
or the spine.
Do an EMG.
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
Got a whole other quad
to cover.
This guy's still got fluid
in his lungs.
You don't think that's
from the pool he drank?
Get him an O-2 mask.
His leg muscles
have atrophied.
Tendons have shortened
from disuse,
causing intense pain.
Tendon surgery will make him
more comfortable.
(Foreman)
Comfortable?
Scoot.
(House)
Not a problem.
My dad wouldn't kill himself.
You haven't spoken to him
in over six years.
I know my dad.
Mark, the doctor's
just trying to--
He wouldn't kill himself.
Fine. I'm wrong.
You obviously have
a better understanding
of this man who drools
in front of your TV set
24 hours a day.
Dr. House.
(Mark)
He must have been confused.
All right?
It must have been
an accident.
Hope it was
a suicide attempt.
If he was trying
to kill himself,
then he knows how miserable
his life is.
It means there's still
something there to kill.
It means your dad's
still there.
[knock on door]
Sorry. Need you.
Thank you.
We were doing the EMG,
but we never got past
the insertion
of the conduction pin.
Did she just say
"thank you"?
I loaned her some money.
What went wrong?
Nothing went wrong.
If nothing went wrong,
then something went right.
You're not gonna tell me
why she thanked you?
what went right?
You did something
for which she is grateful,
and you're...
embarrassed?
For you.
She saw you coming up,
thought you were
a 14-year-old boy.
I set her straight.
I am not telling you
what went wrong.
Or right.
Until you tell me
why she said thank you.
Oh, you've got me.
You know I need to know.
I am so gonna fold.
Except you're forgetting
there's one thing
I can do now.
It's either that
or a reflex response or--
What happened?
Okay.
This is Dr. House.
House, this is Caren.
Pleasure's all mine.
What happened?
When we inserted
the conduction pin,
she flinched.
She flinched!
Did you hear?
Does that mean
I'm getting better?
How big is a flinch?
Bigger than a twitch?
Smaller than a spasm?
[Caren gasps]
You smoke?
Socially. Not a lot.
You do yoga
and you smoke?
I know.
It's hypocritical.
Not at all.
The world sees your legs.
No one's checking out
your lungs.
How would smoking--
It wouldn't.
I just needed a lighter.
[screams]
House!
Oh, my God!
The case was looking
so promising.
Hey, I'm not faking.
Get this lunatic
out of here
before she bores again.
I'm not faking!
I heard you
were watching surgery
with a patient's family.
Talking
to a patient's family.
It's because of your
hallucination, isn't it?
After you were shot.
You chose life.
You decided
you wanted meaning.
So you took a case
with no mystery.
Something any doctor
could do.
A case with no upside except
She thanked me.
And...you felt nothing.
I wasn't even sure
what I was supposed to feel.
It's like your leg.
It's atrophied.
Keep working it.
The feeling will come.
Sorry. Need you.
Again.
I told you
to get rid of her.
It's a good thing
we didn't.
Tightness in her chest.
She can't breathe.
It could be
a pleural effusion.
Right.
Either that
or she's holding her breath
like a four-year-old.
[gasping]
Relax.
I'm not gonna
burn you again.
I'm going to stab you!
[gasping]
Look, either you're faking
or you've got
a pleural effusion.
That's a buildup of fluid
around the lungs,
which is very serious,
and I'd have no choice
but to stab you in the back
with this needle
and suck all the fluid
out of you.
[gasping]
So.
(Cameron)
We should give her a local.
That would defeat the point
of me being nasty.
Ready?
Down.
She can't breathe
if she's down.
Down.
She can't--
Down, down, down!
That's not
a pleural effusion
in the last two hours.
So either we figure out
what's causing blood
to build up
around her heart,
or I follow her around
with a needle
for the rest of her life.
Echo was clean.
No structural abnormalities.
Could be an
infectious process, TB.
(House)
But not the paralysis.
Let's assume
that she wasn't faking it.
(Cameron)
She moved.
Therefore, she could move.
She wasn't paralyzed.
Doesn't mean she was faking.
Could have been a delusion.
Either she was faking
and coincidentally
got a real cardiac problem
at the exact same time,
or it's a delusion.
And the fake paralysis
is a real neurological symptom.
You thinking vascular tumor
in her spine?
Her platelets are normal.
And she's been scanned
up and down.
It was all clean.
So open her up
and find it.
(Foreman)
So what do you want us to do?
Start at her neck
and just keep cutting
down her spine
until we stumble on something?
That should work.
[heart monitor beeping]
His heart rate's
a little high.
Should I be worried?
Probably just means
he's still in discomfort
from the surgery.
I'm gonna up his morphine
a little.
You've been so nice to us.
That's the job.
No, I mean,
all the other doctors,
all they did was obsess
on the cancer, the treatment,
the damage.
Just trying to fix him.
You're the first doctor
that's ever given a damn
about the quality of his life.
His heart rate's
come down.
Morphine worked.
I was right.
What a touching moment.
That's why
we become doctors.
One of those rare moments
when our hearts are warmed--
Would you like
to get a drink?
Are you serious,
or are you just trying
to change the subject?
No, I'm serious.
I drink.
You drink.
We could do it
at the same time.
At the same table.
Do you eat?
We could do that, too.
I mean, if the answer is no,
that's cool, but--
No, it's just--
You're just coming
off the surgery,
and you're not yourself yet.
And I work for you,
and even though last year's...
[sighs]
You're smiling.
I'm saying no,
and you're smiling.
Oh, don't take it
personally.
It's just 'cause
you're full of crap.
You have no interest
in going out with me.
Maybe you did...
when I couldn't walk.
When I was a sick puppy
that you could nurture
back to health.
Now that I'm healthy,
there's nothing in it for you.
You are not healthy.
Cuddy wants to see you.
You've been back at work
24 hours,
and you're already
playing hide-and-seek
in a woman's spine.
Who won the pool?
There's no tumor.
Her platelets are normal.
The scans didn't--
What's the worst
that can happen?
I paralyze her.
She wouldn't even notice.
Her lawyers might.
You're not doing the surgery.
And lower the morphine
on your other patient.
Fine, I'll lower it.
If you'll let me do
the surgery.
What?
You want to trade?
We're not swappin'
a couple of goats
for your help
puttin' up a barn.
You want something.
I want something.
We compromise.
It's the grownup way
to resolve our differences.
There already
is a mechanism for that.
It's called the employer-
employee relationship.
You tried to swap?
Ran a few more tests.
Came back negative.
Surgery's on.
[thump]
You really don't
give a crap, do you?
Does that make me evil?
Yeah.
The girl's life
is at stake.
All we're talking about
with the guy is--
is the reason you took the case.
To help someone.
Too bad for them.
Too bad for you.
The reason we crave meaning
is because
it makes us happy.
The first level
of happiness is--
I'm not going away.
(Wilson)
The fifth level of happiness
involves creation.
Changing lives.
(House)
The sixth level is heroin.
The seventh level
is you going away.
You're saving lives.
Which is tantamount
to creating lives.
But all you're taking
away from this
is the game.
You don't have to listen
to them thanking you.
You don't have to change
the cases you take
or even how you handle them.
You just have to know
that you made a difference.
[mysterious music]
* *
[door bangs]
House, you're not--
I'm not an idiot.
(surgeon)
House, leave her alone.
(House)
Close her up.
Wanna know why?
The room's no longer sterile.
True, but that's not
the most interesting reason.
That is not a sexy
big toe.
You would never
put that in your mouth.
What the hell
has that got to do with--
Told you
it was interesting.
It gets even better.
[slurping]
Scurvy?
Yeah. Drink.
Like what sailors get
when they don't eat right?
Aye-aye.
Your arms and leg tissues
are choked with blood.
Makes it hard to move.
Also damages your hair
and toenails.
But I'm on this great diet.
Lots of protein, lots of--
No vitamin C.
Now drink.
Well, thank you.
And thank Dr. House.
Send him a note.
The nurse changed
his morphine.
I thought you were
worried about the--
It's just post-op
discomfort.
He's ready to go home.
So he won't have
any pain?
Eventually.
Thank you.
Everything else
will be the same.
Well, you took away his pain,
and that--
that changes a lot.
Why don't you put him
in some sort of facility?
Someplace without a pool.
Yeah, I could dump him there.
Except...he's my husband.
He's my son's father.
Right.
Kids need a dad.
Someone to play catch with,
talk about girls.
Mark's learned that you don't
have to abandon someone--
Get a dog.
I'm taking care of him
for the same reason
you helped us.
Some guy shot you,
and you hallucinated?
I have a responsibility.
So he's just an anchor weighing
you and your family down.
Sapping your energy,
wasting your life.
That's the meaning
you take from this.
I want to take care of him.
You enjoy this.
I can't abandon him.
So you don't want
to take care of him.
Taking care of him
doesn't fulfill you,
make you happy.
But not taking care of him
would make you miserable.
Hmm.
Okay.
Here we go.
Huh.
[makes gurgling sound]
I don't need your help.
I've done this
a million times.
Lay him back down.
Do that again.
Make that sound.
[makes gurgling sound]
What was that?
That...
was talking.
You guys
are lousy doctors.
You're in such a rush to make
the patient feel better,
you forgot to check
what was wrong.
Yoga girl walked out of here
two hours ago.
You fixed her.
Not her.
The other guy.
He had brain cancer.
They removed it
eight years ago.
His condition's been the same
ever since.
Until last night.
He spoke.
What'd he say?
[imitates gurgling noise]
He...grunted?
You want us to dissect
eight years of medical history
with grunting
in the differential?
Sounds good.
Call me when you're done.
You're fabricating a mystery
because you're bored.
I am not bored.
Ow.
Damn it.
You didn't tell the wife
it was only a grunt?
Of course not.
Because then she never
would have consented
to a bunch
of dangerous tests.
I don't remember you
being this bitchy.
The Vicodin dulled it.
In the sober light of day,
I'm a buzz-kill.
You're giving false hope to
a family that's been wrecked.
Tell the wife
it was only a grunt.
Tell her to go home.
I can't let her down
like that.
Pumped her up
with too much false hope.
Oh, I stuck that primo!
How rad am I?
[tense music]
* *
2002, patient had dry eyes.
Dry eyes plus a grunt.
[clicks tongue]
It all makes sense.
Could be
a neurological issue.
I get hay fever,
I put drops in my eyes.
I don't go
to a neurologist.
Dry eyes could indicate
an autonomic dysfunction.
What about coughing?
Or boogers?
Should we include boogers?
I'm happy we're doing this.
I'd much rather do this
than lengthen
some guy's tendon.
Patient's headaches
increased.
Doc scanned his head,
found a tumor.
You like wasting your time?
I'm learning.
To do what?
Reconsider solved cases
because you don't want to deal
with the real world?
He's pushing
where there's nothing.
Cameron, you are
an excellent doctor.
You'll get lots
of tearful thank-yous
from grateful patients.
Yeah, am I such a bitch
for wanting that?
Well, it's not a bad thing.
But it's not
why I'm here.
I took this fellowship
to learn from House.
He's teaching you
to be a masochist.
Dry eyes goes on the board.
(Foreman)
In eight years,
the patient experienced
214 symptoms,
many of them repeating.
Any patterns?
(Chase)
Fever plus frequent urination
could mean prostatitis.
Or a urinary tract infection.
White count was normal.
No infection.
(Foreman)
If you add pain
into the mix,
fever, frequent urination
could indicate
a kidney problem.
I like it.
No.
Creatinine and BUN
were both normal.
Not the kidney part.
The pain part.
Abdominal pain
plus all that stuff
could equal
pancreatic cysts.
(Cameron)
Perfect.
You've managed to pick
the one symptom
he never had.
Abdominal pain.
It's the first symptom
on the board.
Grunt.
Grunting isn't pathognomonic
for abdominal pain.
No.
The traditional
diagnostic marker
is compression
of the diaphragm
and vibration
of the larynx,
leading to the audible sound.
"I have a pain
in my abdomen."
(Cameron)
Richard's symptoms are culled
from eight years
of medical history.
They're not patterned.
These are random,
individual events over time.
Illnesses have
incubation periods.
Do an upper endoscopic
ultrasound.
(Foreman)
His throat will collapse.
Muscle degeneration
in his neck
won't tolerate the scope.
It's an automatic trach.
You're talking about him
like he's an invalid.
We're insensitive.
Does he drool?
Can he hold
his neck straight?
Does he choke
on his food?
His neck's fine.
His throat's
not gonna collapse.
Cameron, get consent
from the wife.
Open.
I need you to swallow.
[gulps]
Sorry about that.
Here we go.
Passing through the lower
esophageal sphincter,
into the antrum
of the stomach.
There's the tail
of the pancreas.
Looks clean.
Moving medially,
the body and the head
of the pancreas look clean--
Get it out.
It's stuck.
I can't move it.
His throat's collapsed.
[sucking air]
Vitals are all over
the place.
We're losing him.
I'm cutting.
We trached him, endoscopically
removed the probe,
and he's breathing again.
So, all in all,
great idea.
Did you get a look
at the pancreas
before the world ended?
It was clean.
Which means,
barring anything else,
meaning you,
he can go home tomorrow.
This man nearly died.
How can you discharge him?
His throat collapsed because
of what we predicted.
(Foreman)
You stick something
down someone's throat,
they gag.
Spasm.
Which he did.
It took us a half an hour
to get that thing out.
Except our patient's throat
was sedated.
Which means the brain
should have sent a signal in
not to do anything.
This could be cancer.
Even a new type
of vacular--
Stop it.
You're enjoying this.
I find it interesting.
It's interesting
only if you're right.
If you're wrong,
we're torturing this guy
to amuse you.
Half hour
to remove the probe?
House.
It's not a spasm.
His throat didn't collapse.
It locked down.
Brain is supposed to tell
every muscle in the body
to relax and contract
at the same time.
This muscle was only
contracting,
which means a signal from the
brain was not getting through.
Nothing to interrupt
any orders.
All it takes
is one wire down.
A few microtumors
on the meninges,
suddenly you're choking
to death.
You wanna look
at the lining of his brain?
(Chase)
The amount
of contrast material
you'd need to pump up there
just to see--
He'll bleed into his brain.
No, he won't.
Because that wouldn't
be interesting.
You can get permission
this time.
The brain is enclosed
in a sack called the meninges.
Does this mean
the cancer's back?
No, no, no, no.
House.
If we found cancer,
it wouldn't be
the original cancer.
It'd be new.
So what?
More surgery?
More radiation?
Might not be
the worst thing.
If this isn't
just ancient history,
maybe it's something
we can correct.
Might even get
some brain function back.
He could get better?
No.
But understanding what
you're saying would be nice.
Maybe you can figure out
ways to communicate.
Thank God he spoke
to you.
Mrs. McNeil.
The test to do this
is very risky.
He could die.
He's already dead.
[tense music]
(Foreman)
Contrast material entering
into the fourth ventricle.
No parietal bleeds.
Blood pressure's high.
But it's holding.
(Foreman)
Meninges are intact.
No bleeding.
Surgeon repaired
the CSF leak.
You're lucky he didn't die.
I'm lucky?
He's the one
who didn't die.
We told you
he'd hemorrhage.
You told me he'd bleed
into his brain,
not out of his ear.
You've gotta drop this.
We're missing something.
We did
a dangerous test.
And something
bad happened.
That's all this is.
Give me a tour
of the brain, Foreman.
Walk me through the scans.
1998.
What happened?
5-centimeter, grade IV
astrocytoma
between the parietal--
Nothing. Next.
Speck on the superior
temporal region.
It's a regrowth.
Benign.
Star thingy next to
the Rathke cleft?
Scar tissue
from a biopsy.
House, every speck
is not a suspect.
It's years of surgeons
digging around
in his head.
Let him go.
Redo every blood test
he's ever had.
Re-scan his head.
No.
He's been sick and suffering
for eight years.
I'm not gonna
help you make it worse.
I'm not gonna help you
make it interesting.
[sighs]
That's okay.
Foreman's better at that stuff
than you are.
We need 5-millimeter cuts
through the occipital
and hypothalamic regions.
No.
How many millimeters?
I can help him.
This is it?
That's your argument?
Seems like a good one.
If I thought for a second
you wanted to help him,
you'd have carte blanche.
You're doing this
because it's fun.
Does nobody
in this hospital
have anything better
to talk about
than my motives?
My motives have nothing to do
with the case.
Your motives have everything
to do with your judgment.
For the first time in years,
I've got no opiates in my body.
Now you question my judgment.
24 times a year you come
storming into my office,
spouting that you
can help someone.
Only you never say
those words.
You say something like,
"His pancreas
is gonna explode
because his brain is on fire."
You come here with medicine,
not with platitudes.
I didn't want to bore you
with the details.
There are no details.
You have a hunch.
House, you don't use hunches.
You always have reasons.
This hospital doesn't exist
for your whims.
I'm sorry.
As of 7:00 A.M.
tomorrow morning,
I'm sending your patient home.
The answer is no.
Cuddy called 30 seconds
after you left
and said you'd try
an end around.
My leg hurt.
How bad?
Enough that I'm
telling you.
Did it go away?
Ached for a while.
First time I've felt anything
there since the surgery.
But it went away.
[sighs]
It was muscular.
There was some cramping.
What are you smiling about?
You're 40-something
years old.
You've been running God knows
how many miles a day.
Fallen 100 times
off that skateboard,
and you're shocked
to have some soreness?
Just give me
a prescription.
For Vicodin?
House, people get
aching joints,
cramps, they put on
an ice pack.
They take some ibuprofen.
I know what the pangs
of middle age feel like.
No, you don't.
Because you've been stuffing
Vicodin every five minutes
since you turned middle-age.
The surgery didn't work.
Don't play me.
Oh, you think
this is a scam?
I think you want me
to feel sorry for you
and either do the end around
on Cuddy
or give you the drugs.
Either way, you get the high
you think you need.
House, your surgery worked.
You're fine.
It's just gonna take time
for it to feel good.
[suspenseful music]
* *
[knock on window]
[knocking]
[clatter]
[gasps]
The circumventricular system
senses cytokines released
in the early stages
of the immune response.
But CVOS releases prostaglandins
that reset the hypothalamic
set point upward,
unless it's countered
by anti-pyretic therapy.
So yeah, his brain
is on fire.
The suicide attempt
He drove that wheelchair
into the pool
because he couldn't regulate
his body temperature.
He had hypothalamic
dysregulation.
And you discovered this...
when you stepped into the...
university pool?
Fountain.
I can cure him.
Cure him.
[laughs]
Even if the fountain
proved anything,
fixing hypothalamic
dysregulation
isn't gonna regenerate brain.
No, but if the scar tissue
on his hypothalamus
is resting
against the pituitary,
the adrenals would shut down.
Addison's disease.
You didn't see any
scar tissue on his MRI.
His CT scans--
His brain is functional.
His temperature's normal.
There is nothing wrong
with his hypothalamus
or his pituitary.
I can make him walk.
I can make him talk.
This is a wild guess
that came to you
because you were sweating.
Inject him with cortisol.
The guy'll have sex
with his wife again.
He'll hug his kid again.
Hopefully that's
the combination he was using.
Be a shame
if I cured a pedophile.
You're smiling.
That's a bad sign.
You're high.
I told you I haven't had
anything in three months.
This is as high
as you get.
A theory that ties
your case up
in a neat little bow.
But you don't have a lick
of substantiating proof.
[bangs head on frame]
Your decision
doesn't make any sense.
There is no risk
to a cortisol injection.
If I'm wrong, big deal.
He goes home a vegetable,
like he already is.
But if I'm right--
This is not about downsides
or risk management.
It is a big deal for you
to understand the word no.
[Cuddy sighs]
He's on his way
out of here.
Figured you'd be
on your scooter
racing down the halls
to stab the patient in the neck
with cortisol.
She was right to say no.
I had no objective reason
to think
that I was right.
Just needed the puzzle.
Hold on a sec.
Is everything all right?
Yeah, it's just something
I forgot.
What's that?
This is cortisol.
And it's to fight infection.
Wanna hold onto that?
Put a bandage on it.
Let's see.
Is he okay?
Yes.
Can we go now?
You can go.
Excuse me.
[gasps]
[suspenseful music]
* *
[grunts]
[mumbles]
Richard.
Dad, you okay?
[gasps]
[exhales sharply]
Richard?
Richard!
[sobbing]
Richard.
(Arlene)
[whispering]
You're standing.
[laughs weakly]
Huh!
[Richard laughs weakly]
Thank you.
(Cuddy)
He got up.
I have to go tell House.
No.
Cuddy.
You can't tell him.
I have to tell him.
He was right.
Why did you do it?
Why did you think
he might be right?
Because he's House.
Medically.
What made you think
he was right?
Nothing.
He got lucky.
That's all that happened.
Telling him no
was a good thing.
Because next time,
he won't get lucky.
He'll kill someone.
Just because
he was right
doesn't mean
he wasn't wrong.
I see him every day.
I can't just...
Everybody lies.
[soft trumpet]
* *
* You can't always get *
* What you want *
* But if you try sometimes *
* Well, you might find *
* You get what you need *
* Oh, yeah *
* And I went down *
* To the demonstration *
* To get my fair share *
* Of abuse *
* Sing it to me now *
You can't always get *
* What you want * *