Wait.
We shouldn't--
We shouldn't be doing this.
What? You're not having fun?
It's not that, I just--
Rather be with the boys?
No.
Well, then. Come on.
- You kids need any help?
- No. No, we're fine.
Car trouble?
No.
Then, why are you here?
We're just talking.
And she do all the talking?
Most of it.
I know what it's like.
I'm gonna come back
through here in ten minutes.
Ans if you're still here,
I'm gonna call your parents.
Yes, sir. Thank you.
Now, where were we?
We were going.
Nine minutes.
Wait a minute.
Stevie? What's wrong?
Oh, my God!
Help! Someone help me!
Transcript: swsub.com
Sync: jh26
16-year-old with respiratory arrest.
The only thing I hate more
than a thief is a crippled thief.
Yeah, me too. No sign of trauma.
No history of asthma or allerg--
- Who the hell is J. Whitner?
- No idea.
Stevie Lipa's EKG and
echocardiogram were normal, but--
Normal is good. Send him home.
J. Whitner! Doctor.
Who is he and where do I find him?
She's a new researcher,
works with Ereshevsky.
Is she hot?
- She's in a wheelchair.
- Doesn't mean she's not hot.
Just means she can't bend over,
so Cuddy has to bend over backwards.
16-year-old kid. E.R. work-up
revealed a bloody pleural effusion.
- That's odd.
- Yeah, that occurred to me.
- What took you so long to mention it?
- No tumors or pneumonia on the CT.
He passed out while making out.
If he's into sex,
drugs and rock and roll can't
be that far behind I'm guessing cocaine.
Tox screen was clean.
Just means he wasn't on drugs,
not that he hasn't been using drugs.
Looks like a plumbing problem to me.
Leaky pipes.
If he popped an aneuvrysm,
he'd be in the morgue, not the E.R.
That's why you're gonna do
a venogram instead of an arteriogram.
This is not a high pressure burst,
it's a low-pressure leak.
Still could've been drugs that caused
the pipes to corrode in the first place.
So go look under his mattress.
See if he's go any pills or
powder stashed with the hand lotion.
Sweet ride.
I asked for the one with
the sissy bar and the banana seat,
but Santa gave me this instead.
Guess that's what
I get for being naughty.
You must be Dr. House.
Oh, looks like there's been some
sort of mix-up at the parking office.
They had to move me closer to the door.
Had to? You don't look
like the type to pull a weapon.
- Wheelchair.
- Cane.
I think you should do the honorable
thing, let me have my space back.
Oh, well, uh,
since you asked so nicely-- wheelchair.
Cane. Walking long
distances makes my leg hurt.
And it's easy for me?
Of 'course not.
Pushing that little lever,
your thumb muscles must burn.
I'm sure the last ten
yards are pure torture.
Crossing the parking lot's dangerous--
cars can't see me.
Did you ever hit a patch
of black ice with a cane?
No, gosh, on account
of the fact that I can't walk!
Maybe you should ask the
parking office for some crampons.
This is about who can most easily cross
the parking lot. You're the winner.
Oh, and the prize is
apparently a parking space.
There's still no answer at either
one of your parents' cell numbers.
Is there any other way
we might be able to contact them?
No.
They're in a conference.
They probably had to
turn them off or something.
What does it matter where they are?
I mean, he's in pain.
You gotta do something.
We need them to sign this.
Why can't he just
sign the papers? He's 16.
Still not an adult.
Then call my parents. They know him.
They'll take responsibility,
do whatever you need.
I can't. It won't--
You can't just l him sit here in
agony until his parents finally decide--
Leah. It's okay.
No, it's not.
I feel like there's an
anvil sitting on my chest.
You win.
We're doing the venogram now.
We'll deal with the fallout later.
My fingers feel wet.
That's just the dye. Your nerves
can't tell the difference between
the cold inside your body
and the wet outside your body.
The nerves can't tell the difference,
or the brain can't
interpret the difference?
It's a little of both.
You like science?
It looks like a diffusion pattern.
That's because it's the venous side,
low pressure.
So Graham's Law applies?
You've taken physics already?
No. Just sort of read up on my own.
I had to teach myself a lot of stuff
too Schools sucked where I grew up.
You go to public or private?
Public.
Leak has to be in the pulmonary
veins to get in my lungs, right?
Yep.
I don't see anything. Do you?
No.
It doesn't make sense.
How can I have a bloody
effusion without any bleeding?
This is putrid.
Put food-borne parasites and
infections on the list to check on.
I'll take the bedroom.
I'm sorry,
I didn't know there was anyone--
We were just--
I have a gun.
Look, you can take whatever you want.
My wallet's in my suit.
Freeze!
I'm calling the cops.
Okay, you don't have a gun.
And you're not calling the cops.
Oh, no, I'm calling the cops,
unless you two get
out of here right now.
Unless? Who calls the cops
unless a burglar does something?
You don't want to have
to explain the affair.
We're not having an affair.
He's got a ring. You don't.
And judging from the state
of the kitchen downstairs
and the half-vacuumed bedroom,
I'm guessing you're a better
lover than you are a maid.
Maid?
You son of a bitch.
I'm not a maid, okay?
This is my house, not his.
Oh, sorry.
And what's wrong with my kitchen?
Nothing. We're sorry.
We're just here to help Stevie.
Who's Stevie?
Your... son?
It was the address you gave.
The E.R.
must have written it down wrong.
Or you lied cause you don't
want us to talk to your parents.
I gave you their phone numbers.
You gave us some numbers.
We haven't been able to reach anyone.
I told you,
they must be in a conference.
- He's lying.
- Leah.
He's Romani.
A gypsy.
So you don't have a home?
Of course we do.
Next you're gonna ask me
about dancing around campfires and--
stealing children?
This is why I don't tell people.
They share everything with
each other and nothing with the gadje--
the outsiders.
Sharing information with outsiders
has not gone so well for my people.
But right now you're making
yourself more vulnerable by lying to us.
You can't go to my house.
You'll pollute it.
- All we're gonna do is look around.
- Your presence is enough.
My parents take it seriously.
It's spiritual as
much as it is physical.
- You know where he lives?
- Don't.
Look, I'll tell you
whatever you need to know.
If we can't trust your answers--
I drink sometimes, okay?
I've smoked pot.
I'll tell you anything. The truth.
You just--
You can't go in my home.
The pot wouldn't cause
a bleeding problem.
A pesticide on the pot could.
Where did you get it?
Some kid at school.
He got the pot from me.
He doesn't even go to school.
His parents made him drop out.
- I'm home schooled.
- He reads books.
What else are you lying about?
Is your father really a professor?
He's a salesman.
They buy and sell anything
they can get their hands on.
They-- so you're with your
dad when he's making these deals?
He was just in Chicago a week ago.
- You fly?
- No.
My dad's got a truck.
- You can't be serious.
- Actually, I can.
See?
It's my space. I want it back.
It's not your space. It's the
hospital's space. And the hospital
thinks that the person who's
worse off should get the better space.
Your application for a handicapped
space says you can walk 50 yards.
And Whitner says she can
roll 50 miles between oil changes.
I can't change my leg.
The space I moved you to is
only 46 yards away from the front door.
I measured. You'll be fine.
Great, so I can collapse
four yards into the lobby
instead of outside in the cold.
As long as it's not in my office.
You know who won the New York
City Marathon six years in a row?
Guy in a wheelchair.
Then go get yourself
one and leave me alone.
Gimme my space,
I'll be happy to roll around all day.
You couldn't last
one week in a wheelchair.
Wanna bet?
What's wrong with you?
Nothing that a week
off my feet won't solve.
Venogram's negative. No leak.
You mean you couldn't find the leak.
- Is your leg worse?
- No, but my parking spot is.
Blood is only made inside
the circulatory system,
which means when we find it outside
There's no leak.
I even checked lymphatics.
You're spending a week in a
wheelchair to get a parking space
- closer to the door?
- Easier than chopping off my legs.
- We've ruled out toxins and drugs.
- Kind of. He Romani.
Apparently,
they feel the need to keep secrets, so
it's hard to know anything for sure.
Yeah, he's also a human being,
which means you shouldn't
be trusting him to begin with.
Stop relying on his answers
and find some on your own.
It's a deep vein thrombosis.
The kid spent 16 hours
in the backseat of an old pickup.
Causes a clot and makes
its way to his lungs.
We should do an arteriogram,
find the clot, bust it with TPA.
- Or we could find the leak.
- There's no leak.
You can't yell at a guy in a wheelchair.
It's a slow leak. You gotta speed it up.
Thin his blood. Redo the venogram.
That could cause a massive bleed.
Excellent-- massive'll
be even easier to find.
Pardon me.
Guess you guys are gonna
have to get the next one.
I thought you were redoing the venogr.
As soon as we're done
with the arteriogram.
Okay, you're gonna feel a little poke.
- Can you maybe do that?
- Don't worry. It's just your leg.
I don't have to go
any further than this.
Take a look at this.
Bones of your forearm.
Uh, radius and ulna.
How 'bout the wrist?
Lunate...
hamate... the...
Scared lovers try positions
they can't handle.
It's anemonic for the wrist bones.
It's the only way I can remember them.
Are you okay?
Ow, my stomach.
- You hit something?
- I barely started.
- Lie flat.
- No, I can't. It hurts too much.
I'm getting out.
It's our only chance
to see what's going on.
If he moves, I could shred his artery.
Just get it out! Now!
It's gonna be okay, Stevie.
Just inject the dye.
Dye's going into his liver,
but it's not coming out.
The clot's gonna be constricting
the flow in the hepatic vein.
It's not constricting it.
It's completely blocking it.
His whole liver's fried.
Kid's liver's failing because of
massive clots blocking his hepatic vein.
How can he have a bleed and a clot?
It's not a clot. Must have
blocked a vein with a catheter wire.
Not a chance.
Increased pressure downstream
could also stop the blood.
There's no heart failure or cirrhosis.
Means it has to be a clot.
Massive clots block veins.
They don't make them leak.
And since he clearly has some kind of--
You having a little problem?
Would you mind?
Boy, that was humiliating.
How does Whitner
make it through the day?
"Pride goth before the fall."
Lucky for me,
I'm sitting in one of these babies.
So, what other theories
can I shoot down?
DIC would explain both--
His platelets are normal
and his PTT isn't eleved.
- Leukemia?
- Normal CBC and differential.
You guys are still thinking like doctors
when you should be
thinking like plumbers.
Come on, I wanna see some butt crack.
Something inside the liver
is punching holes in the pipes.
Blood bleeds through the opening,
sticks to the intruder, forms mass.
- A clot.
- A mass.
Cancer. A tumor could
erode a blood vessel.
Well, so could a granuloma
from tuberculosis or scoidosis.
Do a CT,
MRI, a sputum, and an ACE level.
Excuse me, sorry.
Cripple coming through.
He says his throat hurts.
That phrasing means
you think it doesn't.
No, I don't.
Good enough for me.
- Where are you going?
- Mothers know best.
Get yourself a sucker on the way out.
Look, I think he's just faking
so he doesn't have to go to school.
How did you know I was a truant officer?
I told him he had a choice,
go to school or the doctor.
Right-- he's wasting your precious time,
so you decided to waste mine.
How thoughtful.
I'm in a wheelchair, so I can't examine
him all the way up there. Hop down.
My life is just one
horror after another.
Open.
Does it look like it hurts.
Nope.
What's that?
It's a syringe.
I'm with you,
make him hate the doctor's
office more than he hates school.
That's okay.
I don't-- I don't think that's--
It's just saline--
hurts like hell when it's
injected directly into the muscle.
So what do you think? Arm or ass?
- I think he's learned his lesson.
- Oh, I don't know.
We better check. Jack,
is your mommy a big fat idiot?
Well, what do you know?
Guess you we right.
Just hold still, Stevie.
This shouldn't take long.
Sorry, I'm guessing the mike
in this thing doesn't pick up nods.
- Smart kid.
- Too bad it's all gonna go to waste.
Nothing wrong with being a salesman.
He should be able
to pursue his own life,
not be stuck helping
his parents sell old toasters.
He's still young, you never
know what he'll end up doing.
Unless he goes back to school,
I know exactly what he'll end up doing.
Wait.
Is that a lesion?
Magnifying times five.
It's a granuloma.
Means Wegener's is most likely.
- Stevie!
- Mom, is at you?
- Get him out of this now!
- Your son is sick.
- The sign on the do
- The sign says no metal.
- We took everything off.
- It says no admittance.
- What's wrong with our son?
- We don't know yet.
He not gonna die, is he?
Your son is very ill.
We're still trying to figure out why,
which is why we need
you to leave the room.
What are you going to do now?
Oh, now I've gotta slide my
butt from one padded seat to another.
What if I bump my knee?
MRI showed a granuloma in his liver.
Fantastic.
- Wanna give me a hand here?
- No--
Clotting, bleeding,
and a granuloma equals Wegener's.
I know. That's why I said fantastic.
I was being sincere.
- Now give me a hand.
- It wouldn't be fair.
We're gonna biopsy the liver to confirm.
Wouldn't be fair not to.
People are good and kind and
gentle and help people in wheelchairs.
- You don't believe that.
- But you do.
No, I don't.
Forget the biopsy. His liver'll
be gone before you get the results.
Start treatment with cyclophosphamide
before Wegener's punches
a hole in another pipe.
What's with the clothe.
You're not being discharged.
I know. It--
It's my parents.
They insist that I wear this stuff.
We insist on our own food,
gown, and furnishings for a reason.
Hey, my-- my chest burns.
Are you sure the treatments are working?
Wegener's causes the
body to attack itself.
It doesn't get undone overnight.
Be patient.
- Where's your soup?
- It's in the garbage.
It has willow bark extract.
Willow bark extract
is basically aspirin.
Yes, for the fever.
He's already on meds-- our meds.
We can't risk any adverse interactions.
We need all this stuff to go.
We need to control this environment.
So do we. People get sick for a reason.
'Cause something in their
life is out of balance.
Dad, he's a doctor.
He doesn't want to hear your talk.
Balance is just starting to
be restored now that that girl is gone.
That girl took pretty good
care of your son while you were away.
Yes, we can see that.
All this stuff may make him
feel more comfortable, but it's not--
How long is this treatment gonna take?
We should start to see some
improvement in his liver function soon.
"Soon." Very scientific.
I'm sorry.
Be back in a little bit to check on you.
Ah, yes. If it isn't Dr. Ironside.
Ah, if isn't "Dr.
I had no friends when I was growing up,
"so all I did was watch TV by myself,
which is why I can now make constant
"pop culture references
which no one understands but me."
That's my name. Don't wear it out.
Safe from Cuddy, but I guess
not from her trusted rat-complice.
Reasonable people don't debate
the relative merits of their handicaps.
Reasonable peoe rules
based on evidence--
like difficulty covering a distance,
say 50 yards,
not on some pre-ordained
pathetic-ness scale.
Last I checked, pigheadedness
was not the eighth heavenly virtue.
It's only pigheaded if you're wrong.
If you're right,
they call it sticking
to your principles.
Give it up. You're demeaning yourself.
That's what they told Rosa Parks.
Don't stand up in there.
I'm watching your feet.
Get out of our home.
This is not a home. It's certainly not--
It's our home as
long as our son is here.
Mom, Dad,
will you just please just calm down?
You're not family.
You have no right to be here.
What are you gonna do, throw me out?
You can't even touch the gadje.
- I'll touch you.
- What is going on?
I'm the one who brought him here.
I should be able to see how he's doing.
He wouldn't even need to
be here if it weren't for you.
Right-- I'm so unclean,
I caused his liver to shut down.
Enough. No one is leaving.
He's our son,
and we want her out of here.
- It hurts.
- Your stomach again?
- No.
- What?
His liver's actually improving. We
plug one hole and end up poking another.
We talking about the patient
or how to get a raise from Cuddy?
The Wegener's treatment gave
him a massive hemorrhage in his bladder.
Which means...
- it's Wegener's.
- What did I just say?
We were treating him for Wegener's
when it went wrong.
Not everything.
Yeah, it was a very lovely day outside.
On the other hand,
the treatment made him worse.
Treatment made his bladder worse,
not his liver.
Clot in the liver's breaking up.
And the MRI, sputum, and ACE
ruled out TB, sarcoidosis, and lymphoma,
- which leaves us with...
- Still could be a cancer with multiple
A cancer we can't see on MRI,
CT, or blood tests?
It's Wegener's.
It's not the wrong diagnosis.
It's the wrong treatment.
We could increase immunosuppression.
Add methotrexate.
We can't give methotrexate to
a kid who's already had lung problems.
Methotrexate is carpet bombing.
Hits everything.
We need a smart bomb.
So we don't suppress the immune system--
we change it.
Immune modulation.
FT-28. His antibodies are
attacking his blood vessels.
The irritation causes
them to bleed and clot.
We change his immune system
so the antibodies don't interact
with his blood vessels
but work fine everywhere else.
FT-28's still experimental.
It's not FDA-approd.
It's worked for Crohn's
Disease and rheumatoid arthritis.
He doesn't have Crohn's or arthritis.
Let's say that he does...
and start the treatment.
Absolutely not.
My people have been experimented
on before. Never again.
Mr. Lipa, with all due respect,
comparing this hospital to Auschwitz,
it's ridiculous.
- FT-28's been proven safe in hundreds--
- People always say you can trust them.
Why'd they say anything else?
Why do they think we'd listen
You think I don't understand
what it's like to come from a people
who've been enslaved,
mistreated, and experimented on?
Tuskeg went on for 28
years after World War II.
And the laws that made
it illegal for the Romani
to even set foot in this state
were still on the books until 1998.
It's not ancient history.
Conventional therapy hasn't worked.
Your son may be dying.
He needs a targeted approach,
and you need to trust us.
I'm sorry. A lifetime of experiences
tells me I can't trust you.
And the past three days
have done nothing to change that.
We want our son treated,
not experimented on.
If you don't know how to do that,
then just tell us so we can
take him someplace where they do.
They're absolutely right.
Stay away from that unproven,
experimental stuff.
Much better to stick
with the "moving of furniture
until he gets better" approach.
You're right. We're gonna have
to come up with something else.
You mean another last-ditch
desperation move? You got anything?
Go back and don't take no for an answer.
- What kinda salesman are you?
- The kind who avoids the house
with the crazy couple who
put tinfoil over their windows.
They got money for tinfoil, they
got it for whatever you're selling.
What's that mean?
Means that if they don't trust you,
you should earn that lack of trust.
What does paying for tinfoil mean?
Why should I have to
answer all the questions?
Sorry.
Still getting used
to the power steering.
- I assume you've heard the news?
- I'm not worried.
From what I hear, what you lack
in shame you also lack in willpower.
My will may be weak,
but my backbone is strong.
And pain-free,
now that I've stopped using the cane.
Of course,
it's harder to look down Cuddy's shirt.
Then, the vantage point
on her ass is much improved.
That's just me-- always
looking on the bright side.
I'm the guy who said
that her C cups are half-full.
They are nice, aren't they?
No.
You're not gonna
win me over that easily.
You may have a wheel.
It doesn't mean you get the grease.
You gotta squeak.
What's that?
Cyclophosphamide. We're continuing
the standard treatment as you requested.
I have to ask everyone to
leave the room for a few minutes
while I apply some bandages.
Why do we have to leave?
For his penis.
You lied to them.
The bleeding stopped.
I don't need any bandages.
We need to change your treatment, but
your parents won't let us. They've got
it in their minds that we want to try
some sort of inhuman experiment on you.
The treatment's experimental?
FT-28's been through
extensive clinical trials.
It's also been used successfully
for other conditions.
The fact that you're recommending...
experimental treatment
means you have no other options?
Sorry.
We stop the pleural effusions,
your liver almost fails.
We save your liver, the bladder fails.
If we don't get ahead
of the curve on this
What do you need me to do?
Take the medicine,
but don't tell your parents.
I don't like lying to my parents.
The rest of the world, though--
The rest of the world I can't trust.
You can trust me.
How do I know?
Because if you do this, then
tell your parents, I lose my license.
You okay?
- God!
- Get in here!
Spleen basically exploded, huh?
Got another bleeder.
2-0 silk on a stick.
Got it.
I believe you ordered your meat rare.
Keep him open--
if I confirm Wegener's,
might as well stage the disease
while he's still on the table.
What's taking so long?
External capsule's
ruptured but still intact.
No signs of a clot or bleed.
Normal follicles.
Normal lymphoid tissue.
His spleen is ripped to shreds. There's
gotta be granulomas. Keep looking.
Come on. Can't leave Humpty
Dumpty like this forever.
I don't see anything but normal spleen.
No granulomas.
Means no Wegener's.
That's all I need to know.
Let's go, people.
Run his bowel.
No need. I'm closing.
Suture.
- Run his bowel.
- Nothing suspicious in the spleen.
Get him out of here.
You missed it.
He had a gnuloma in his liver.
No, it was just scar tissue.
Looked like a granuloma on the MRI,
but it's not.
Don't know why I'm debating this.
Pass me the Kelly clamp.
I'm closing.
Not unless you're gonna sew
my hand into this kid's stomach.
Get out of there. He's unstable.
He's got Wegener's which
means he's got granulomas.
I'm calling my lawyer.
It's only 26 feet.
If he were an ostrich,
you'd have a 46-foot wait.
Blood pressure's dropping.
Hang another bag of Ringer's Lactate.
I'm having nothing to do with this.
- Foreman, hang another bag--
- Ringer's Lactate.
Got it.
Come on, come on. It's gotta be in here.
It's gotta be in here.
But it's not.
Mind if we close?
Well, it's a good thing
we never sold him on FT-28.
His parents were right.
There's no way his parents
are gonna let us near him again.
They won't be able to transfer him
until he's recovered from the surgery.
Add the surgical team to the list
of people who won't let us near him.
Bleeds, clots, bleeds, clots.
Spleen explodes.
We should test him for Von Willebrand's.
Or we could just play tic-tac-toe.
Okay, Xs are bleeds. Os are clots.
It started in the lungs, right?
What did we do?
CT, sputum, two venograms.
That's one bleed, one clot. Then what?
Liver shut down. MRI,
labs, treated with cyclophosphamide.
Whereupon, he peed out 3
units of O negative. Another bleed.
- Where is this going?
- I don't know yet.
- What's next?
- Bladder, kidneys.
High resolution CT scan.
UA and urine sediment.
- GI tract?
- You ran his all bowel in the OR.
The large bowel is fixed to
the abdominal wall. I didn't run that.
Because there was no reason to.
He hasn't been having
any symptoms in his bowels.
Do a colonoscopy.
- Because he's had no symptoms?
- You lose your keys,
first thing you do is look everywhere
you might logically have placed them.
You don't find them,
then you start looking in other places.
The medicine cabinet, freezer, mailbox.
We need to look in this kid's mailbox.
Why don't we x-ray his feet?
They're fine too.
Because we need to take
the center square to block.
Okay, even if that did make sense,
it's kind of hard to do a colonoscopy
on a kid you can't get near.
He's in the ICU now. His parents
only have limited visiting privileges.
I like that kid.
He's got spunk.
Can't talk now. On guard duty.
- You're still in that thing.
- What thing?
Oh, this. Forgot it was even there.
You know, even if you manage not to
get struck down by a bolt of lightning
and make it a week, Cuddy's
not gonna give you the space. She can't.
Bet's a bet.
Yes, and that rule outrank
the Americans with Disabilities Act.
You think you've got logic on your side,
but Whitner's got the legal system.
And legal beats logic
every time-- just ask O.J.
You're right.
- I am?
- Yeah.
So you're doing this
even though you know you've
got no legal leg to stand on.
Who needs legs when you got wheels?
I'm gonna get that spot.
No way Cuddy is going to gyp me!
What'd you say?
I'll see you later. Gonna have them
yelling at me for the next 20 minutes.
Mucosa looks normal, healthy.
No lonely diverticula.
Blood pressure's dropping.
- He's bleeding again.
- Not in his colon.
- Hurry up.
- I am.
- There's nothing there.
- Wait, wait, what's that?
- A reflection?
- No, it's something...
Looks like a...
- toothpick.
- Are you sure?
He must have swallowed it
accidentally and just figured he'd
digest it eventually.
When you two were making out in the car,
it must have folded awkwardly and
pushed the toothpick through the
wall of the intestine and into the lung.
And it moved on to his liver and
made its way to his bladder and spleen.
So that's it. He's gonna be okay.
Yeah. Small holes.
He shouldn't take that long
to heal now that we've got it out.
See?
- See what you did?
- Me?
- If you hadn't been kissing him...
- That's what you heard?
It was the toothpick!
It was that disgusting habit--
It would have just passed right through
him if he hadn't been writhing around.
Isn't that right--
That's it?
Yeah. That's it.
Wood absorbs water, becomes the
same density as the tissue around it.
That's why it didn't
show up on the CT or MRI.
That's cool.
I mean, not cool for me, but...
lot of damage for something so small.
You know, the lab here,
they have a paid intern position.
It's usually given to one of
the kids from the universities, but
if you want,
I could probably get you an interview.
There's some entry-level stuff,
some gopher work, but
you'd also have access
to a lot of cool things.
Thanks, really, but...
I can't.
Yes, you can.
Stevie, you're bright.
You have more curiosity than
90% of the doctors on the staff.
It's not that. It's just...
I go to work every day
with my family, you know?
People I've known my whole life.
- I don't want to lose that.
- You can have both.
No, I can't.
Because they don't want to let you.
They shouldn't be making you choose.
Maybe not, but they are.
And I'm choosing them.
Look, change
is hard.
Trust me, I know.
But it worked out for me.
You're a successful doctor.
Your name is on journal articles.
I would love that.
It's just...
I see you with Drs.
Chase and Cameron, and...
you all got empty ring fingers.
You're alone.
This is my last day
living a life of leisure.
So are you gonna tell Dr.
Whitner she's outta my space or can I?
Why would I do that?
Because you said that you would.
And lying is wrong.
I said I would give you the
space if you made it a whole week--
- Which I--
- Didn't.
The bet didn't stipulate that you
had to be the chair for a week unless
you had to barge in an operating room
and shove your hands in a kid's bowels.
You know about that.
You lost.
I saved a life.
Two minutes out of the
chair to save a kid's life.
You lost, House.
- I earned that space.
- No, you didn't.
I earn that space every day I limp
into that building and do my damn job.
You lo-ost.
You were never gonna
give me that space, were you?
I saw Whitner the other day.
She knew about the bet.
Didn't seem that worried.
- She knew I'd win.
- But she doesn't know me.
In fact, she doesn't know anything
except what you tell her, and
you told her that you were never
gonna give me that space, didn't you?
Just tell me.
Do you at least feel a little guilty?
If you wanna teach me lessons,
don't make commitments you can't keep.
How's it going?
How guilty does she look?
About an eight.
That space is mine.
Veni, vidi, vici.
Transcript: swsub.com
Sync: jh26