Fran?
- I'm Robin.
- Please come in.
Cute home.
- Two bedroom, one bath?
- Yeah.
A guy I know collects those.
He says they're worth
a fortune on the internet.
Yeah.
You've never used our agency before,
have you?
Is it that obvious?
As you can see,
we offer a full range of services.
- "Round the world"?
- Our Deluxe package.
Offers all the services of A, B, and C.
How much?
$1,000. And satisfaction's guaranteed.
Twice.
- I'll get the money.
- I'll get ready.
Harrington?
What are you doing up there?
All right, now.
Don't take this personally,
but you're gonna have to go...
Fran?
Is this okay?
Are you all right?
Oh, God.
Yeah, I... I need an ambulance
at 500 North Sycamore.
I don't know. My... friend collapsed.
Transcript: swsub.com
Sync: jh26
And what were you
doing when you fainted?
- We were just...
- Looking for her cat.
And have you banged your head recently?
No.
Is this a motion sickness patch?
I must've forgotten to take it off.
I just got back from a trip.
Scopolamine can cause
dizziness and blurred vision.
You probably hit your head when
you fell and that caused the blackout.
I thought those patches were supposed
to prevent you from getting sick.
Every drug has a side effect.
But it might be a good idea
to keep your eye on her for the
next few hours to make sure she's okay.
- Oh, actually I...
- She has to get back to work.
Is it important?
We just don't like people
to be alone after they leave here.
I'm fine. Really, I'm...
I got a seizure. Code cart!
- What's wrong with her?
- I have no idea.
Where's House?
Antique vintner's cane. It cost me $900.
It had a corkscrew in it.
Ah, that would explain
the "vintner's" reference.
Could be used as a
weapon against the pilot.
Only if you stuck it
in a bottle of Zinfandel.
You'll get it back when we land.
I want my blankie!
Give her 20 milligrams of antihistamine.
It could save her life.
Cause if she doesn't shut up,
I'll kill her.
Delivering good will
to yet another continent.
You only forced me to deliver a speech,
not good will.
You gave a three-minute speech.
You know how much WHO accreditation
means to the hospital?
May have been short, but it had girth.
And the room service
thing was just spiteful.
- I was hungry.
- $300 for a bottle of wine.
- I was thirsty.
- $120 on video services.
I was lonely.
That's $500 in expenses I can't justify.
Don't worry. I'll take care of it.
Right.
Welcome aboard.
Mr. House, you're right here in 2A.
Ms. Cuddy, you're in the
next cabin and to the left, 9C.
No, I booked two first-class tickets.
This must be a mistake.
No mistake.
Just arranged for a $500 fare reduction.
Expense problem solved.
Where did you travel?
Duluth. To visit my sister.
Really?
Is this her artwork?
Fire... butt?
I was a little drunk.
Where were you a little drunk?
I turned 58 last March.
Same age my mother was when she died.
Next week I packed a bag.
I went to JFK. Looked at the big board.
Took the first plane
that went to a warm place.
Caracas.
Oh, my God.
Did you drink the water?
Eat salads? Any raw foods?
Yup.
And?
I also did mescal shooters, and snorted
cocaine from a homosexual man's stomach.
- Did you have sex?
- No.
Not with him.
I had sex with El Gordo.
- He was a large man.
- Oh, my God.
I never do things like that.
I should have gone to visit my sister.
It was stupid.
That's why I'm sick, isn't it?
It's... possible.
Here you are. Rib eye, medium rare.
Thank you.
Some more Pinot Grigio?
Uh, no. I think I
will switch to the Syrah.
- Sir, are you all right?
- He's drunk.
See?
Does anyone speak Korean?
Is anyone a doctor?
Yes.
I'll go get her.
What do you want?
Did you really think I was gonna
leave you stuck back here for 18 hours?
Go on. Enjoy.
The Vicodin and the wine.
I could sleep anywhere.
Thank you.
We should put her back
on the scopolamine patch.
She can't wear motion sickness
patches for the rest of her life.
No, but if it does relieve her symptoms,
it'll narrow down our search.
Anything else you two
guys want to agree on?
- You have a problem with us agreeing?
- No, I have a problem with the other
thing you're doing which makes
me question your motive for agreeing.
I'll put her back on the patch.
What else?
It's got to be something neurological.
We should do a CT and
look for a brain tumor.
It can also be an allergy or something
environmental. We should check her home.
Bit more likely she got sick
in Caracas than in New Jersey.
Right, I forgot there
are no toxins in the U.S.
I think I'm starting
to feel sorry for House.
Get a tox screen, chem 20, STD panel,
blood cultures, then you run a CT,
and you check her house.
Please.
- Not funny.
- Wasn't supposed to be funny "ha ha."
Fever, headache, severe abdominal pain,
and a rash all over his lower back.
It's serious. It may be contagious.
We just attended
a symposium on pandemics
and you run right into one on the
flight home. Talk about a small world.
If it's meningoccus, half the passengers
on this plane could get infected
and die before we reach New York.
- Is someone sick?
- No.
Someone has a hangover.
He had a snoot-load of
Bloody Marys before dinner.
Watch the movie.
That booze did not give him the rash.
It is textbook meningoccus.
It's also textbook allergic
reaction to pollen, peanuts,
semen-stained polyester
blanket he's lying on.
Mr. Peng's throwing up again.
We have to turn around.
What? Why do we have to turn ar...?
We don't. You misunderstood.
Dr. Cuddy just meant
that he might feel less nauseous if
he was facing in a different direction.
She didn't mean to panic
a planeload of people.
We're about to head over the North Pole.
We don't turn back now,
the next ER's 15 hours away.
He'll be fine. I'm a doctor too.
You haven't examined him.
Korean male, mid-thirties, 5'9, 160,
bald, scar on the right side of his jaw,
medic alert bracelet
on his left wrist indicating
that he is allergic to at least,
penicillin.
Without any way to do an LP,
or rule out meningoccus,
our only choice is to assume the worst.
Good point.
On the other hand,
I am a board certified
specialist in infectious disease.
She assigns parking spaces.
Please let me know if he gets any worse.
Think we should feed the cat?
Bowl's full.
If he wants it, he can get it.
Cadmium yellow?
Heavy metal poisoning would
explain the ataxia and the seizures.
Not unless she was
painting with her tongue.
Is Foreman right? Did you agree
with me because of our relationship?
- Relationship?
- You know what I mean.
You mean because of
our lack of a relationship?
I mean because we're having sex.
Yes, Foreman's right. I thought you were
completely wrong about the medicine,
but agreed with you anyway,
because I figured then you'd
do me in some old lady's home.
Then well played.
Come on, we're supposed
to be looking for toxins.
We agreed it was a brain tumor. What?
He's watching.
Haven't you had anybody watch before?
- Is that guy really sick?
- No, he's all better.
I don't believe you.
Look that way.
Why?
Cause you're gonna throw
up and I don't want it on me.
I'll get some towels.
Give her a banana. Monkey see,
monkey barf. You smell vomit...
Okay. I wasn't expecting that.
- I need help.
- Who doesn't?
I need someone to talk to.
Can you say...
- "Crikey, mate"?
- Crikey, mate.
Perfect. No matter what I say,
you agree with me, okay?
- O- kay.
- Nicely done.
You disagree with everything I say.
Sorry. Not understanding.
That's close enough.
And you... get morally
outraged at everything I say.
That's permanent marker, you know?
You guys are good.
We are looking for the simplest
way to explain these symptoms.
Organophosphate poisoning. Some
international flights spray pesticides.
Could be.
Sorry, English not so nice.
Is this a joke?
Just passed the halfway mark.
Can't turn around. Nice call.
No worries.
- We think it's pesticide poisoning.
- We don't spray these flights.
- Dramine overdose.
- Wouldn't explain the fever.
- Jet lag.
- Wouldn't explain the abdominal pain.
- Deep vein thrombosis.
- Wouldn't explain the nausea.
Food poisoning. What was on the menu?
Steak and sea bass in first class.
Fettuccini and seafood
kebabs in economy.
Since when does food
poisoning cause a rash?
Sea bass, seafood kebabs?
He had the sea bass.
Please tell me she had the kebabs.
I think so.
Ciguatera poisoning.
It's an instant onset toxin.
Symptoms include 'E' all of the above.
It's only found in certain
kinds of tropical game fish such as...
Sea bass?
Make sure you get a resume from him.
- Hello.
- Excuse me.
Ladies and gentlemen, I have a brief
announcement concerning your meals.
If you ate the sea
bass or the seafood kebabs,
you have ingested a dangerous toxin.
However,
if you proceed to the restrooms,
both on your left and right
and in the rear of the plane
and vomit as soon as possible,
the toxic effect should be minimal.
Thank you and have a pleasant flight.
- Meningoccus makes just as much sense.
- I know.
What'd you find?
Nothing in her house. Big waste of time.
- Medically.
- CT was a complete waste.
She was negative for tumors, her blood
was negative for drugs, heavy metals,
tropical diseases,
food poisoning, and STDs.
Also no sign of lead
poisoning or sepsis.
Apparently, Venezuelan tattoo
parlors have standards after all.
Good to know.
We sure she's even sick?
Two more seizures in the last two hours.
Which is slower than she was having
them before you put the patch back on.
I'm an idiot.
She's exposed herself to so much crap,
I just assumed it was a zebra.
It's breast cancer.
Since when is breast cancer
treatable by motion sickness meds?
It's not. But the inflammation
caused by the paraneoplastic syndrome
caused by the cancer can
be reduced by anticholinergics.
Is he gonna die?
We're doing all we can.
We don't know what's wrong with him yet.
Am I gonna die?
No. Here, chew on these.
Good news is all the
pilots are red meat men.
Although I was kind of looking
forward to landing this puppy myself.
- Peng's getting worse.
- That makes sense.
First class ate before coach.
He digested more of
his food before he threw up.
Or you're wrong and we're gonna
start seeing neurological symptoms soon.
Seizures, paralysis, ataxia.
We're not gonna see ataxia.
- You're so sure you're right.
- No, it's just hard to show clumsiness
when you're lying moaning
in the fetal position.
Stand up!
- Nobody speak Korean on this flight?
- I assumed you did.
I know how to ask him
if his sister's over 18.
I don't think that's gonna help.
Stand up!
Don't play the cripple card with me.
I'm leaving.
Work.
Important client.
Sure.
Listen...
are you close?
Why?
She needs a mammogram.
Oh, God.
I know I'm throwing a lot at you.
She just has no family in town.
And I really think she
could use a friend right now.
Okay, put your hand here.
You don't have to stay.
No, it's... no problem.
But why?
You don't even know me.
You gotta be scared.
- I almost hope it's breast cancer.
- No.
- Then it wouldn't be my fault.
- Whatever it is, it's not your fault.
That's not true.
You can control things.
Not everything.
But you don't have to take stupid risks.
- I was being an idiot.
- You were having fun.
You have regrets?
Yeah.
Robin.
Hold still.
Good.
Okay, we're gonna get just one more.
Sorry, I know it hurts.
It's not that.
It's my eye.
My right eye, I...
I can't see.
It's definitely ataxia.
It's definitely a rash.
You want to look at it for
five more minutes before concluding
it's also definitely a leg.
- Thin leg. It's been in a cast.
- So?
- So it could be radiation poisoning.
- From a broken leg?
- From the X-rays they took of it.
He could break every bone in his body
and still not have enough
X-rays to cause radiation sickness.
Unless those X-rays were
performed in "Wankoff", North Korea
by a third-grade dropout
with a 50-year-old imager.
Which accounts for the absence of fur.
Radiation poisoning accounts
for all the symptoms.
I have hair. I haven't had
an X-ray since I got my teeth whitened.
You're pregnant.
I'm what?
Explains the nausea,
abdominal pains, fever.
And why you're stuffing
your 36Cs into a 34B bra.
- And her rash?
- PUPPS.
- A common pregnancy rash.
- I can't be pregnant.
- You a virgin?
- No, but...
You're pregnant. Mazel tov.
Let's get him into the chair.
Two different diagnoses.
I thought you didn't
believe in coincidences.
I believe in statistics.
200 passengers on the plane.
10 should be gay,
two should be with child,
and one should be incredibly
annoying with an extra ass chromosome.
Get him some iodized salt to
protect his thyroid. I'm going back...
You're wrong.
I said we should've turned back.
You should have listened to me.
Now we're eight miles over the Arctic...
I'm trying to listen to you now,
so shut up.
Heart's fine.
Breasts are firm.
Is it contagious?
A lot of the passengers are scared.
Tell them there's
nothing to worry about.
- Is there something to worry about?
- Yeah.
Tell them there's
nothing to worry about.
Get me a flash light.
Cover your left eye with this.
Photophobia!
Symptom of meningitis.
We need antibiotics.
I'll call down to the pharmacy.
You're creeping me out.
Then get me a lab.
Pseudomonas smell yeasty.
Staph smells musty.
Some liver diseases smell of ammonia.
House, I'm not in heat.
Citrusy on the nose,
with a blush of toasted coconut.
I need to get a better
look at your rash.
Use your imagination.
Fine, shall I go with lifeguard
Cuddy or Mother Superior Cuddy?
Three more passengers are sick.
If we don't get drugs, we're
gonna have a lot of dead passengers.
Blindness in her right eye
indicates it's not breast cancer.
- It's likely neurological.
- I just met her today.
- You should go.
- She needs someone here.
That's not your job.
Please let me know that she's okay.
- It's just sex.
- There's no such thing.
Other eye.
Are you saying women can't separate
the physical from the emotional?
No one does it well. Women do it worse.
You just want us to stop,
because you think it's affecting...
Me. Yeah.
- Polyspikes over 01 and 02.
- That's her left eye.
Burst suppression on every lead.
She's comatose.
Nothing...
Come on, nobody has no meds.
Excuse me.
Open your mouth.
- Where is the acyclovir?
- I'm not on any meds.
Well, you'd better get some.
You've got herpes.
Oh, what do you know? He's got some.
This must be your lucky day.
This is for real! People are sick.
Some of us will be deplaning
in body bags unless you cough up.
Thank you... thank you.
God bless you.
Her brain is shutting down
because of intercranial pressure.
Or her nerves are dying.
Because of the increased pressure.
She has a bleed in her brain.
- You said the CT showed...
- No tumors.
But if she has an AVM leading
to a cerebral hemorrhage,
we could have missed it.
She needs a burr hole to relieve...
You want to drill in her brain
because of an invisible
bleed the CT couldn't see?
We should do an LP to confirm
the presence of red blood cells.
And her brain herniates
and then she dies.
Right, better to kill her in the OR.
Chase, what do you think?
Here's a cliffhanger.
I think it'd help to know what she has
before we start digging into her brain.
Might be better to
play it safe to start.
Do an LP.
Sex better be damn good.
Lotta apples, not many candy bars.
- Any antibiotics?
- Three caps of augmentin.
There are six patients.
Give them to Peng.
He's allergic to penicillin.
The first aid kit has two epi pens.
If he has a severe reaction, ten epi
pens won't save him, you take the pills.
- He's worse.
- He's a guy who doesn't speak English.
- Give him the meds.
- If it's not meningitis,
we're risking his life and
flushing meds down the toilet.
Then do an LP on him.
If it's clear, you win.
If it's cloudy, he gets the
augmentin and we risk a reaction.
Sounds like a plan.
Oh, except for the part
where we don't have an LP needle.
Oh, and the shaking of the plane means
I'll probably pierce his spinal cord
and cripple him for life, but,
I mean, it totally soundslike a plan.
You're right.
Let him die. Give me the meds.
Got it.
Damn.
- What is it?
- Shut up.
- Don't get hysterical.
- Just tell me what the hell it is.
We should have turned back.
We should have turned back!
Hold this.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have a passenger with a
confirmed case of bacterial meningitis.
And even if we land as soon as possible,
the passenger will not survive.
It's very likely that some
of you have been infected as well.
As soon as you start feeling symptoms,
we need to isolate you
in the first class cabin.
Fever, rash,
nausea, and in the late stages...
tremor in the left hand.
I have that.
Oh, God.
No!
What do we do?
Break out the bubbly.
Yo! Listen up!
Bad news is you have an illness.
The good news is,
it's not meningitis.
It's not fatal.
It's just embarrassing.
It's conversion disorder.
Or commonly known as mass hysteria.
It happens often in high anxiety
situations, especially to women.
I know it sounds sexist, but
science says you're weak and soft,
what can I do?
House, you're wrong.
Look at my hand.
Yeah, look at her hand.
Shaking left hand.
What is that a symptom of?
Not meningitis.
It's basically a symptom of nothing.
She put the idea into their
head and watched it happen.
Same thing that Peng cruelly
did with the puking and the rash.
- The rash is in my head?
- Your mind controls your body.
It thinks you're sick,
it makes you sick.
If... If you'll all just calm down,
your symptoms will soon go away.
And to facilitate this process, your
flight crew will move through the cabin
with a complimentary bar service.
Thank you and,
as always, have a pleasant flight.
- Still feel like puking?
- No.
How did you know?
LP was negative.
I came up with an alternate
theory and I tested it.
Couldn't have done it without you.
Rage is a symptom of mass hysteria.
Just one more thing to clean up.
Peng set off the mass hysteria.
What set off Peng?
- He really is dying.
- Yeah.
And I haven't the faintest idea why.
What's extension pastoring?
It's when you're molested
by a priest's cousin.
Do we really need these three?
Worried they'll make you look bad?
Could be symptomatic of head trauma.
Cerebral infarction or
intercranial hemorrhage. Thoughts?
- How long till we land?
- Too long to wait.
His head's as smooth as a baby's bottom.
No bumps, so I think
we can rule out head trauma.
So you gotta choose between what's left.
Clog or a leak?
Uh, you're talking of toilet?
Is this actually helpful?
Not so far.
What about syphilis?
First of all, he apparently speaks
a language that no one else speaks.
Which makes talking up
the ladies a little rough.
We're flying out of Singapore.
If he has a credit card and a condom,
he can get anything he wants.
What?
Condoms.
He has focal limb paralysis.
- His legs got paralyzed by a condom?
- No, by cocaine
that was inside the condom, and is now
spreading through his digestive tract.
- You think he's a mule.
- I think he's a jackass.
- We're gonna have to operate.
- Cool.
They're gonna kill her.
We were wrong.
Which means Foreman was right.
Maybe Foreman's right about us too.
Maybe we should just stop all this.
- I mean, if it's affecting our jobs.
- It's not affecting our jobs.
We had sex in a patient's bedroom.
A bedroom we were examing for toxins.
Yeah, our judgment's right on the mark.
All right, no more sex at patient's
homes. No more sex with cats watching.
Anywhere else you want
to cross off the list?
- The bowl.
- What?
- Has she eaten since she's been here?
- She's been sick since she's been here.
- What if it's a symptom?
- Why would you think...
The bowl was full.
You're gonna need to hold him down.
He's not gonna like this.
- Do you really think he's a mule?
- It fits the symptoms.
- You sure he's not contagious?
- Pretty much.
Can't be "pretty much" sure.
It means you're not sure.
Oh, aren't you clever?
Well, I know you're
"pretty much" unconscious,
but as it's been pointed out to me,
"pretty much" doesn't mean squat.
Okay, hold him tight.
The faster we do this,
the less likely he is to die of shock.
Tighter.
- Sorry.
- Do that again.
Ease off, then press down.
Pressure on his joints
relieves his pain.
- Okay.
- Wrong again.
Where's his wallet?
SCUBA certification card.
Big deal. I have one of these.
Yeah.
Do you also have a receipt from
Tekong's scuba rental dated yesterday?
Tell the captain to drop
as low as he can under 5,000 feet.
- We're at 38,000. We can't...
- Peng's got the bends.
He went diving yesterday, and
like an idiot, he surfaced too quickly.
And like a bigger idiot,
he boarded a flight which is pressurized
to 8,000 feet above sea level.
Low pressure is killing him.
Tell the pilot to dive until we
can club baby seals out of the window.
And get him some oxygen.
Fifty years ago, it was one estate. The
two homes shared an electrical system.
Unfortunately the exterminator
didn't know that, so when they fumigated
next door, the poison gas flowed through
the old pipe and into your house.
The scopolamine patch was
masking the effects of the poison.
You'll have to stay here for a few more
days, but after that you should be fine.
I'm sorry about your cat.
And your hair.
For 12 years,
Harrington never left the property.
I thought I was being
punished for going away, but
really...
I was being punished for coming home.
Have a safe trip home.
Thank you.
I saved your life. You owe me.
- I wasn't sick.
- But you didn't know that.
- You owe me.
- I know it now.
Your mind convinced your body
to get a rash, photophobia, and vomit.
How do you know it wouldn't have
shut down your cold, cold heart next?
I don't owe you.
You're mean.
That's how I compensate
for being weak...
and soft.
I just wanted to say thank you.
- You're extremely welcome.
- And I'm in New York every Monday.
Are you handicap accessible?
Hi, Robin?
This is,
Dr. Wilson, F-Fran's doctor.
James.
It was a toxin. We caught
it on time and she's gonna be fine.
Yeah, it is.
Listen, I was just wondering if
you were coming back in again to visit.
- Nice catch.
- Thanks.
- Think even House would be impressed.
- I don't know about that.
Any idea how you want to celebrate?
What?
I want more.
I thought you were getting
a little worn out, but...
That's not what I meant.
I know.
I was just hoping you'd take the
hint and pretend you never said that.
- I want this to be more than it is.
- I thought we were clear.
In the beginning,
but you can't tell me you...
Yes, I can. And I don't.
It was... fun.
That's it.
And now it's over.
Transcript: swsub.com
Sync: jh26