My offer's withdrawn,
you can walk to work.
Got it, you're morally outraged.
Now can we get through this part
'cause the next part's awesome?
How do you rationalise
something like this? You broke
into Stacy's therapist's office...
Borrowed a key.
...and stole her treatment notes!
Nope! I made copies.
Mark is, and I quote,
[Wilson groans]
"Withdrawn, passive-aggressive,
won't communicate, like he resents me
because I can walk"
I don't want to hear this.
Dishes in the sink,
toilet seat up.
Meanwhile, she can't
stop thinking about...
I can't read that,
is she obsessed with
a Grey Horse? Or me?
It says she thinks
you're an annoying jerk.
It's a pet name.
Here's the kicker.
They're not having sex?
Doctor cleared him,
but no liftoff.
She's frustrated
so she's doc-blocking me.
Paperwork, seminars,
meddling with my patients.
Great, now you've got
the proof you need. Just...
take those personal psych
records to Cuddy, that'll show
her Stacy's out of control.
You ignoring me?
While looking for my newspaper,
efficient huh?
Kalvin:
Over here!
[Sighs] Dr. Wilson,
I want you to meet my stalker.
Your waiting room sucks.
I am not treating you.
What, because
you're a closet-case?
Err...we're not...
err... together.
He is so self-loathing.
Well, we've got to go now,
so maybe see you after work...
No no no! Ah...
Nobody can figure out
what's wrong with me.
Well, your shirt is gaping
at the collar, means
you lost weight, you're flushed,
that's fever, and
you're short of breath.
And finally there's
the KS lesion on your face.
Means you're HIV positive,
you've progressed
to full-blown AIDS.
So you're sick because
our immune system is shot
and someone sneezed on you.
am I excused now?
Brilliant, but,
my immune system is fine.
Your concentration camp
physique begs to differ.
Get your T-cell count re-checked.
I've already done that.
They test for
T-cell lymphoma?
It was negative.
All of this will be fascinating
to an HIV specialist.
Now let go of my cane before
it becomes your new boyfriend.
Honey, I will marry it
if you would look at my file.
Congress says you can't, so...
[Car alarm goes off]
[Wheezes]
I didn't touch him.
He's going into
anaphylactic shock.
2x07 - Hunting
Original Airdate (FOX): 22-NOV-2005
- Go see Stacy.
- We gave him epi, he's fine.
You need a lawyer,
go see Stacy.
You hit a patient.
Four words, two mistakes.
He's not a patient,
and I didn't hit him.
Of course you didn't.
Go see Stacy.
I didn't cause
the anaphylaxis.
It's probably one of
his HIV meds abacavir.
I'll pass that along,
make sure
the ER takes him off it.
Go see Stacy.
You have to treat him.
Medically this case
is a snooze-fest.
AIDS plus infection.
You don't treat him,
he charges you with assault.
Just 'cause he says I hit him
doesn't make it true.
Watch, I am surrounded
by naked cheerleaders.
See?
Although I like my chances
of some action this morning.
I forgot
Wednesday was hooker day.
This could've waited!
You make me meet you
at your house,
your husband is
conveniently absent.
Mark's at physio.
I'm stuck waiting
for the exterminator.
I saw a rat last night.
Well, I'm surprised
your feet are touching the floor.
I barely slept.
What was Mark up to?
Memory serves,
quick climb up Mt. Gregory and
you dozed through a seal hunt.
Clubbing, shrieking.
What're you doing?
Sorry, it's driving me nuts.
You hate washing dishes.
People change.
I could make sure you
sleep like a baby tonight.
Rather take care of that myself.
I was referring to the rat.
Trenton Pests is sending a guy.
Mark:
What's going on?
It's not what you think.
I know it looks like
we're cleaning dishes but
actually, we're having sex.
We're working.
Wow, wish
I'd become a doctor.
Place would be spotless.
Take ten minutes,
cure the guy, and stop whining.
I give you Kalvin Ryan.
So flamboyant in person,
so boring on paper.
Obviously got an
opportunistic infection,
probably TB or PCP.
Have you read his file?
I started, but I found
the characters two-dimensional.
He went to
a HIV clinic last week.
Tested negative for
TB, PCP, MAC, CMV, HSV.
It's not an infection.
HIV clinic.
So few patients, so much money.
Re-do the tests.
The results make sense.
Kalvin's T-cells are at 200,
that's strong enough
to fight infection.
Fine, parasite.
Nope, stool sample
was negative.
Two months ago,
he was down to 30 T-cells,
then he changed his meds,
his immune system rebounds,
his viral load drops,
everything's getting better
but he's getting sicker.
Face it, this might be
an interesting case.
What if his immune system
is too strong.
An auto-immune disease
with HIV, that's impossible.
His new HIV meds kicked
his system out of a sound sleep.
Wakes up hungry,
cranky, spoiling for a fight.
When it doesn't find
an active infection,
starts attacking
the harmless remnants
of old infections.
Immune reconstitution syndrome.
His meds made him
so much better,
he made himself sick.
- Sounds pretty...
- BORING!
This is so not interesting.
Chest X-ray and
find the old infections,
start him on steroids.
If you're wrong,
steroids will tank his immune system.
He'll get worse.
Now THAT would be interesting.
Where's the coumadin?
If your patient's got
a blood problem then
blood thinners aren't exactly...
It's for Stacy's rat.
Death by anti-coagulation.
Trying to win Stacy back
by killing an animal...
very caveman.
I don't want her back.
I just want her to
admit her feelings for me.
I go to Cuddy,
Cuddy fires her or re-assigns her.
Either way, I'm happy.
If you want her back,
either tell her,
or, better yet, shut up,
and cry yourself to sleep
like everybody else.
Hi, this is Mark Warner,
1724 Spring street.
Listen, you don't need
to send that guy down,
we caught him.
No, you should send the bill to
Princeton-Plainsborough hospital.
Attn: Dr James Wilson.
Yeah.
Your lymph nodes ren't swollen.
That's good.
Maybe Dr. Chase should check.
Sorry mate, hands full.
He's too pretty to be straight.
You ever done any modeling?
Does anyone actually
fall for that line?
Everyday.
Why do you think
I became a photographer?
I'm guessing
you guys didn't think
about dating on career day.
- I love my job.
- Really?
You seem more the
'find it exceptionally satisfying' type.
I'm not sure
there's a difference.
Your mom died of diabetes,
how's your dad's health?
Last I heard,
he had cirrhosis.
Love is love,
satisfying is social validation,
fun can wait.
I have fun.
Yeah, she's got
some scheduled for February.
Chase:
Last you heard?
Your father?
He threw me out
when I was 16.
It's just as well, I got tired of
getting BB guns for my birthday
when I'd asked for a Barbie.
Dads can be real sweethearts.
Mmm, sensitive, AND cute.
He's cute.
It ran into that
heating vent right there.
Hopefully Mark's anger
will go away eventually.
He's not angry,
just doesn't like you.
Nothing unique there.
Didn't seem really
wild about you either.
He's fine with me.
He's angry.
Said so in group.
Of course he's angry,
he's looking at months
of painful physio.
[Sniffs]
He's mad at you.
There's no way he said that.
[Sighs]
No, but it's true.
He resents you
for being able to walk.
I've been there.
I resented you
for hell of a long time.
Past tense?
[Phone starts to ring]
Might be the hospital.
What!?
[Phone is on speaker]
Bad time? Where are you?
Hosue:
At your girlfriend's place.
Ignore the moaning and squeaking.
His lungs are too scarred to tell
which infection triggered
the immune reconstitution.
He a smoker?
Cameron:
Yes, and possible
more than cigarettes.
His tox screen came back
positive for recreational drugs.
House:
Not surprising.
Not medically relevant.
His heart looks
a little enlarged.
House:
That's a typical
side-effect of AZT.
House:
What are Kalvin's
most recent infections?
Toxo, CMV and PCP.
[Squeaking]
[Whispers]
Well let's assume
it's one of those.
House:
Give him Ganciclovir
for the CMV...
Woah,
we can hardly hear you.
Where are you?
House: In a closet.
Your girlfriend's other
boyfriend showed up.
Ganciclovir for the CMV,
Sulfadiazin for the Toxo,
Bactrim for PCP.
Gotta go, it's killing time.
Cameron:
Your tox screen
came back positive for...
Crystal meth
and...ecstasy.
Recreational drugs are
dangerous to begin with,
but for someone with HIV...
I didn't mistake them
for vitamins.
[Whispers]
I'm a P&P boy.
Party and Play.
Drugs and sex.
[Coughs]
You don't approve?
Does the sex include condoms?
If he's negative, sure.
If he's positive...
why put on a raincoat
if you're already wet?
You could get hepatitis
or another strain of HIV.
Or I could get hit by a bus.
AIDS isn't a
death sentence anymore.
I don't want to
have any regrets.
[Starts coughing again]
How long have
you been coughing?
Ah...about an hour or so.
[Coughs]
Try to take a deep breath.
What is it?
I think its blood.
[Starts coughing again]
I recommend
post-exposure prophylaxis.
Your chances of conversion are slim,
but I'd like to put you
on three antiviral medications.
Finavir, zidovudine and lamivudine.
There are side-effects;
headache, nausea, vivid dreaming.
You'll be tested for HIV
in 6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months...
Very interesting.
He coughs infected blood
in Cameron's eyes and mouth,
that's interesting?
The coughing part,
not the in Cameron part.
New symptom,
blood vessel ruptured in his lung.
I closed the tear.
Well it takes
immune reconstitution
off the table.
What's it put on the table?
Its ok, she's not here.
You can skip the nice guy acts.
You know some human beings are
actually capable of human feelings.
My giving a damn or not
is not going to change
what happened.
Could be Kaposi's Syndrome.
No edema,
no blood in urine.
KS on his face could mean
KS in his lungs, with
bleeding from the lesions.
I would have seen them
when I repaired the tear in his lung.
Wegener's granulomatosis?
Wegener's would have
responded to the steroids.
Maybe you should go home,
take the rest of the day.
I'm fine.
Oh this is good,
he's pretending to care,
you're pretending not to.
I think we should
reconsider drugs.
Kalvin uses crystal meth.
Concerned enough
about his health to stalk me
while indulging in
deadly street drugs.
Study in contradictions.
Interesting.
Still not medically relevant.
It could be,
if his drugs were tainted.
They cook meth with
battery acid, lye, lantern fuel...
Find Kalvin's pills,
test for toxins.
Foreman, you're with me.
I need a consult
on another case.
You have another case?
It's a hip-pocket deal.
Patient presents
with a distinct neck tilt.
*****
Is he an athlete?
He's a regular runner.
Any pain associated
with movement.
None that he's complained of.
Best case scenario,
an infection in the ear or lungs.
Worst case,
brain stem tumour.
Should do an MRI,
CAT scan, full work-up.
Uhh..I don't think so.
No insurance.
No drugs in here.
I'll take the bathroom.
How about a drink after work?
Take your mind off what happened.
Cameron?
I might have HIV,
a drink's not going to wash it away.
There's like zero chance of
you contracting the virus.
Big difference between
'like zero' and 'zero'.
What did the infection
control guy tell you?
He was very reassuring,
kept reminding me that
the hospital covers all my medical costs.
Apparently forgot to mention
that if I do test positive,
that they'll pass it on to legal
and legal will dig up any dirt
they can trying to prove that I'm a...
drug user or tramp, and
that's why I have HIV.
It's not like they're going
to find anything, right?
Right.
Check this out.
Chase:
Kalvin's a photographer.
The broken bulbs were props.
Glass is from
1930's fluorescent.
Some of the bulbs
have date stamps.
Pre-World War II fluorescent bulbs
contained large amounts of beryllium.
Beryllium dust inflames the lungs,
they get rigid, patient can't breathe.
My father co-authored a paper
on acute berylliosis.
Phew! For a moment there
I thought you were smart.
Cameron, get a biopsy of
Calvin's lung tissue.
I want a spectrographic analysis.
I can handle it.
No reason to risk
exposing the entire team.
Then who would I torment?
I'm sorry.
About what happened.
It's best not to talk.
You're going to
feel a sharp pinch.
This actually is going to
grab a piece of your lung.
What were you guys
looking for at my hotel?
Your drugs. Thought maybe
you'd used toxic meth.
We'll know if you're exposed
to beryllium in a few hours.
Well if you're still curious, it's...
in my bag over there on the chair.
You brought drugs
into the hospital?!
Glad I wasted my time
at your hotel.
I told you I used,
you didn't ask me for a sample.
You're not pissed about this,
you're mad because
I coughed blood on you.
That was an accident.
Oh, would you stop being nice!
It's useless and worse, it's boring.
Get angry!
I had one stupid night,
I end up with HIV,
do you have any idea
how pissed off I was?
This wasn't your fault.
You broke into my house?
Why I had to,
Mark isn't here.
He has physio.
Oh really?
How's he doing?
What happened
with all the cheese?
I had to get rid of it before
Steve McQueen ate any coumadin.
I named your rat.
Steve's tilting his head.
Any neurologist will tell you
that suggests an infection
or brain stem tumour.
Death cures both those things.
Well we can't kill him.
If it's an infection,
it could be caused by
something in your house,
something that
could affect you guys.
Smell this.
[Sniffs]
- Does it smell like urine?
- Oh!
[Sniffs]
You missing any asparagus?
Ok, stuff these,
he doesn't get better,
then it's a tumour.
Then what? Chemo?
Steve McQueen without hair?
It's a blessing
he died young.
[Phone rings]
Hello.
Oh, hi honey.
I'm sorry I missed you,
yeah, I came home.
Alright, I'll see you
in a few minutes.
Okay, bye hun.
Chest hurts!
[Monitors are beeping]
He's a hundred and climbing,
could be an allergic reaction.
Neck pains are out,
must be pericardial effusion.
No wheezing.
Tear in his lungs
must have re-opened.
Kalvin, you're bleeding into
the area around your heart.
I'm dying?
I can't breathe!
The blood's crushing your heart,
once we remove it, you'll be fine.
If I die, please tell my dad...
You're not going to die.
...tell... him... sorry.
[Monitors are beeping]
Where's the blood?
It's clear.
Only one other thing
could cause this.
Tumour in his heart.
Wilson:
CT confirmed a mass in Kalvin's heart
and several smaller ones in his lungs.
That's why his heart's
enlarged, not the AZT.
You ok?
She's fine, probably getting
bored with the question.
Masses in the heart and lungs,
what kind of cancer are we looking at?
They may not be cancerous.
This is classic
Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma.
HIV positive patient
with a primary heart mass.
It could be sarcoidosis.
His lung tissue is negative.
Lymphoma's a death sentence,
sarcoidosis is treatable.
So's an ear infection,
but since he didn't test
positive for that either...
I wanna do the
Kveim-Siltzbach test.
[Splutters] Do you have any idea
how much paperwork
Cuddy is going to need signed?
Do it.
So...
how is the patient's father?
Uh...
Tell my dad I'm sorry?
Might as well wave
the red flag at a bull.
He's not coming.
Well it's not a tragedy,
dad doesn't want to see him,
he doesn't want to see the dad.
You're the only one
who wants them together.
- He asked!
- He thought he was dying.
Dying people lie too.
Wish they'd work less,
they'd been nicer, they'd
opened orphanages for kittens.
If you really want to do something,
you do it, you don't save it for sound byte.
What did you say when
you thought you were dying?
On the other hand,
his dad tossed him out.
So what's our guy
want to apologise for?
Everybody has regrets.
Cameron:
The growths in your lungs
and heart are sarcoid,
your body will
recognise this material
and we'll see
a reaction on your arm.
Did you really
want to see your dad?
Did you call him?
Thanks.
He would have come,
try to straighten me out.
How are you holding up?
- I'm fine.
- Convincing.
What did you do with my drugs?
The lab disposes of them
after analysis.
Too bad.
They could have
done you some good.
Not really my thing.
You know I hope
you don't have it, but...
getting HIV
might have been the best thing
that ever happened to me.
I used to be a good boy.
Never wanted to
piss anybody off...
playing by the rules
makes everybody else happy.
Now I'm happy.
So you just show up
every time he's at physio?
Off course not!
Also when he's at group therapy,
or out for dinner with friends.
And when she happens
to mention to Mark
that you dropped by...?
You tell your wife everything?
It's a... process. [Sighs]
But Stacy doesn't have
any reason to hide this from Mark.
As far as she knows,
Mark's okay with you being there.
My bet is she mentions me
to Mark as little as possible,
'cause she thinks that he thinks
that she still has feelings for me.
And you know
why she thinks that?
Because she still has
feelings for you? [Elevator dings]
If you're right, she did tell him,
and I don't get through the door tonight.
But if I'm right...
So how long
do we stay here?
'Til something happens.
He's not going to come out
with us right here.
We are downwind, and
he seems to have hearing loss.
He's not blind.
Steve McQueen
does not run from danger.
Antibiotics on the other hand...
He ate around the pill? Smart!
Admit it, you like him.
He's alright...for a rat.
You wanna know
how cool he is?
His urine showed
traces of hydrogen cyanide,
formaldehyde, lead.
He's a smoker.
Your husband's been lighting up...
which is particularly stupid,
it could cause his AIP to...
Okay, I blow my smoke
into the vents
so Mark doesn't know.
I always knew it.
Bluffing!
You started
two weeks after my surgery.
Menthols, then
lights after a month.
Why didn't you say anything?
'Cause it helped me
monitor your misery level.
One trip outside was a good day,
upwards of six you were in hell.
You could have
asked me how I was!
I already knew.
Sorry you were miserable.
Sorry I caused you
so much pain.
[Clangs]
[Squeaking]
Aha.
[Music from inside the room]
[Knocks on the door]
Glad you changed your mind
about that drink.
Come on in.
You should get changed,
there's this new place
on campus that...
- Are you high?
- Uh huh.
I thought
you disposed of the drugs.
Not all of it.
Uhh, slow down...
Your pupils are dilated!
Come on Chase,
don't turn into a
good guy on me now.
You're late.
And hungover.
Or maybe not.
Why do you have a rat?
Jealous?
[Elevator dings]
Kalvin:
[Shouting] Out of my room!
Don't you dare put this on me!
Kalvin:
I'm not going to grovel, dad!
That's not what I'm asking for.
Like hell it isn't!
You said you didn't call!
Don't mind me.
Just here for the show.
Yeah well, there's
not going to be any.
What happened to the big apology?
Yesterday he was all
"daddy, I'm so sowwy".
This is none of your business.
You should have thought of that
before you stalked me.
Now I'm interested.
So what's he got to apologise for?
You're the one who tossed him out.
Now why would I do that?
I don't know.
'Cause it's tough to brag
to your hunting buddies
that your son knows
all the words of the whiz.
That's a lie!
- 42nd Street?
- Oh, tchick!
Much easier to just
get drunk and beat him.
Explains his hating you.
Also your cirrhosis.
Also why the more I talk,
the more you sweat.
What it doesn't explain, is
why he's gotta apologise to you.
Residual guilt for
sharing your special toy
with other boys?
Just leave it alone.
Just want to leave the bigot
with some peace of mind
after you're gone?
Look, this has got nothing,
and I mean nothing
to do with him being gay!
Now Kal brought this on himself,
with what he did to his mother!
He steal her signature look?
No, no. He killed her.
Kalvin lied!
Yeah, that certainly is shocking.
Mom's kidneys were failing,
she needed a transplant,
they tested Kalvin, he was a match.
He was also positive for HIV,
mom never found a qualified donor,
she dies.
Tragic tale.
Undercut slightly
by the rapid fire delivery
and constant movement.
Too much coffee
this morning?
He didn't kill her.
Our bodies aren't donor farms
for our parents.
It's not 1980. We know
how HIV is transmitted!
If Kalvin got HIV
through unprotected sex,
dad has every right to be pissed!
So you always use a condom?
Uhh... yeah!
Brother's
on the down-low, got to.
Huh, not ready for any
Foreman Juniors yet.
You?
Working girls are sticklers.
You're not going to pull Chase?
I'm not an idiot.
Obviously not.
Who doesn't sleep with
a drugged out colleague
when they have a chance?
Where's Wilson?
We got the result
for the Kveim test.
[Sighs]
So... I have cancer?
In all likelihood, yeah.
Non-Hodgkins Lymphoma.
And I am... dying?
We need to biopsy the tumour.
It's near your aorta so...
getting that sample
carries serious risks.
Is my dad still here?
He hasn't been in?
We'll inject a dye around your heart
to make the tumour visible on the CT,
then a surgeon
inserts a guide wire,
runs it up into your heart
where he takes a small piece of
that tumour so we can look at it
under the microscope.
Chase: Ativan
will help settle you down.
Why are you so calm?
Not coming off meth helps.
Last night probably
shouldn't happen again.
Do you think I want it to?
When two people have had sex,
unless it sucks,
if they can do it again,
they're gonna do it again.
And that's when
things get complicated.
And it didn't suck.
So now you've got to drum up
another excuse to be
around the love of your life.
Could hit another patient.
Nyah, don't like to repeat myself.
People will say I'm formulaic.
Well that rules out
letting the rat go so
you can catch him again.
I can't do that.
Steve needs
two weeks antibiotics and
a smoke-free environment.
Cigarettes
aggravated his infection.
The rat is actually sick?
That thing could
infect the entire hospital!
Steve's infection is
not contagious to humans.
I'm an idiot.
How did I miss micoplasmosis?
Was that the kid's father?
Yeah.
Remember the black death?
Started with rats.
What's he doing in the hallway?
His kid getting his biopsy already?
He just won't go in the room.
Who knows what else he has?
Parasites? Bacterial infection?
- Kid doesn't have parasites.
- Not the kid, the rat!
Was he still sweating?
Rats only sweat
through their tails.
Not the rat, the dad!
Where are they from?
Err...Montana.
What's going on?
You were right,
it's a parasite.
Cancel the biopsy.
It'll kill him.
[Bangs]
Hey daddy, come with me!
Yeah, uhh...
I'm not going in there.
[Sighs]
Your son asked to talk to you.
Why is he here?
He wanted to talk to you.
Aha.
Did you two use to
hunt together?
Foxes. Did you kill foxes?
It's Montana.
Those masses in your chest
are not tumours.
They're parasitic cysts
from a bug called equinococosis.
Touch a dead fox, they jump aboard,
they can hunker down for decades
- growing, spawning,
shopping, putting on plays.
I've been tested
for parasites.
Okay, it's cancer.
You happy?
The cysts isolate the parasites,
keeping them from showing up
in stool samples,
even in blood tests, cardiac...
All right,
you don't need me for this.
But you've got
the same things in your liver.
I have cirrhosis.
Liver cysts have
identical symptoms
with one addition, fever.
Now liver cysts
we can test for.
Your diagnosis
could confirm Kalvin's.
So, option A,
we draw some blood...
No, look,
you're not touching me.
You see, this is
why I need you here.
I want you to tell your son that
you won't take a simple painless
blood test to save his life.
You err... never expressed
a shred of regret for
what happened to your mother.
Geez dad...
Dad:
If you'd've worn a damn rubber,
you'd've been fine.
Dad:
Could have saved her life.
You wouldn't be lying here!
House:
Yeah yeah yeah, I get it!
You're really mad at him
for killing himself and
for destroying everything you love.
I don't have time for this,
are you going to apologise?
I'm living my life
the way I want.
Are you going to
give me some blood?
Look,
if he doesn't give a damn
then neither do I!
Okay. Option B.
Why did your wife kill herself?
Did she hate you?
She was a diabetic!
You know, you don't know
a thing about my Suzanne.
Either Suzanne wanted to die,
or she was both fat AND stupid.
Used a twinkie instead of a gun.
And girls with big appetites, well
they just can't get enough of anything!
Shut up!
Probably nibbled on
every devil dog in the county!
SHUT UP!
Just in case I'm not
making myself clear,
I don't mean the delicious snack...
You son of a bitch!
Yeah? Come on!
Thank you,
means I can do this.
We're going to need
some epi in here, stat!
Are you out of your mind?!
You said you didn't care.
[Choking]
Notice how you can't breathe?
Now either that's the cane,
or I just ruptured one of those
liver cysts we were chatting about
and you've gone into
anaphylactic shock,
exactly the same as your son did
when he accidentally tripped
against my friend's car.
I'm just SO excited
to find out which!
[Choking and wheezing]
I'm gonna schedule surgery.
Nurse: Clamp.
Surgeon:
Pressure's holding.
Two successful surgeries,
two lives saved.
I'm over my quota.
Can I have next week off?
Two family members assaulted.
- It was self defence.
- You baited him.
You're right.
I was asking for it.
The low-cut blouse,
the 'Do-Me' pumps.
You flooded his gut
with a parasite, he could sue.
Go see Stacy.
Okay.
That's it? Okay?
No name-calling? No squawking?
No rending of garments?
I like this T-shirt.
You lied to me.
If this is about my mom...
This is about your
lonely, miserable life.
I'm not miserable.
And as long as
there's a gay bar around,
I'm never lonely.
You haven't had a single visitor
except for your dad.
Drugs are great,
HIV freed you,
your dad hates you,
you're so happy.
Everything's a lie!
You blame yourself
for your mom's death,
you're not trying to have fun,
you're trying to self-destruct.
You wanna kill yourself?
Fine, but stop recruiting!
Heard you hit another patient.
Yeah, sure. Why not?
He hit me first.
Cuddy didn't mention that.
Let me see.
I'm the doctor.
My concern is purely legal.
Looks okay, does it hurt?
A little.
You need some ice.
There's no way that
Mark doesn't know...
about the smoking.
He would have
said something.
Then he hasn't been
near you in months.
We're fine.
Can't be easy.
Stop squirming.
Why would you
lie about this?
I'm not lying.
I don't care if you're
sleeping with him or not,
but you're not, so...
I am.
You're lying.
You know when I have sex?
You can smell that on me too?
The only people who know
about what's going on between
me and Mark, are me and Mark.
I just know you.
And I know you.
You're confident, arrogant,
but you're never certain unless
there's a reason to be certain.
One other person knew,
I told you I was seeing Dr. Harper.
You can easily get into her office,
you read my file.
You read my file?
The dishes,
the concern, the oh...
acting like a human being?
You have...
This whole time
you've been manipulating me?
You knew that
I had an angle the moment
I poured soap on to a scrub brush.
You could have
thrown me out,
or ignored me, or
found another exterminator.
You didn't even tell Mark
that I kept coming by.
You LET this happen
because you wanna be with me.
I don't know anymore.
Get out.
["Colors" by Amos Lee]
I'm sorry.
# Yesterday I got lost in the circus #
# Feeling like such a mess #
# And now I'm down
I'm just hanging on the corner #
# I can't help but reminisce #
# I know we all
We all got our faults #
# We get locked in our vaults,
and we stay.. #
# When you're gone #
# All the colours fade
When you're gone #
# No new years day parade
You're gone #
# Colours seem to fade #
Synchro : Vaccine
www.forom.com