- You okay?
- Yeah, I just got clipped with a beam.
What the hell do you
two think you were doing?
We thought we heard someone in there.
You never go in without authorization.
Captain, this is all me.
Amy just followed me in.
So torching your ass
last year wasn't enough, huh?
You need to stop trying
to prove how tough you are
before you get yourself killed.
Yes, sir.
Go have the paramedics look you over.
Come on, Derek, let's get
this ladder to the second story.
Let's go.
Derek!
What's happening?
I'm...
freezing.
Transcript: FRM - Synchro: jh26
www.sub-way.fr
- I'm fine.
- ER docs don't think so.
Your temperature's been going
up and down like a rollercoaster.
- How old are these skin grafts?
- Last one was about six months ago.
Gonna run some tests,
and we'll get a consult with Dr. House.
I'll be fine.
You'll be doing what
the doctors say. Got it?
I'll check in later.
The way you covered for me last night.
He's my brother.
I know how to eat it from him.
I'm gonna stop after my shift, okay?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
So where is this Dr. House?
Speaking engagement.
Not guilty.
And on the charge of gaining
control of said medication by fraud,
- how do you plead?
- Not guilty.
Very well. Preliminary hearing is set
for the 19th at 10:00 AM, at which time
I'll determine whether there's
enough evidence to proceed to trial.
Next case on the calendar, People v.
Williams.
You're gonna go talk to him?
I was just gonna ask him
where he gets his hair cut.
They have your signature
in a prescription log,
a security camera video,
and a pharmacist's sworn statement
saying you stole the dead guy's pills.
You're already looking at ten years.
You want to add witness
intimidating charge?
Go ahead. Ask him about his hair.
He suffered third degree burns
over 54% of his body a year ago
and arrived in the ER last
night disoriented and shivering.
For 12 hours his temperature
was bouncing between 96 and 102.
Why don't you contest the
search of the pharmacy records?
Yeah, you could argue it violated
doctor-patient confidentiality.
Except he wasn't the
patient or the doctor.
He was the guy who stole
from the patient and the doctor.
This was the third time he had
been disoriented in the last two weeks.
Running into smoke-filled burning
buildings can be a bit disorienting.
Fortunately, I have the cure.
Stop doing it.
He's not in a burning building anymore,
and he's still shivering.
A hypothalamic tumor could
cause a vacillating temperature.
So could ER nurses who are
too busy to notice that a patient likes
both hot coffee and cold sodas.
He tested negative for Hep C, TB,
HIV, Lyme, and his tox screen's clean.
In case you hadn't noticed,
not exactly in the mood to dance.
I'm not asking you to dance.
I asking you to do your job.
EKG showed arrhythmia.
Probably just a mild heart attack.
No chest pain. And smoke inhalation
already explains the arrhythmia.
The guy was in the burn unit for
six months and had multiple surgeries.
Could be a hospital-acquired infection.
Maybe MRSA.
Works for me.
Draw blood cultures.
Start him on antibiotics.
Vancomycin plus broad
gram negative coverage.
If you called to see the design for
my prison tats, they're still in R&D.
- You need to talk to Tritter.
- Not according to my lawyer.
Your lawyer isn't gonna be able to get
the DA to the drop the case. Tritter can
Yeah, you know what else Tritter can do?
You are not impressing anyone.
You may call yourself principled,
but what you really are is stubborn,
adolescent idiot.
- This isn't his fault.
- I'm not the one--
You used the rectal thermometer on him.
You insulted him instead of apologizing.
You flaunted your drug use in his face.
And you refused to accept a deal--
I accepted the deal.
Not until after you
stole a dead guy's pills.
Allegedly.
Tritter has been opening
doors for you every step of the way,
and you keep slamming them shut.
There are no more
openings to give, House.
If you want to stay out of prison,
you gotta make one for yourself.
It's Vicodin.
You function better on it.
Talk to him.
MRSA's a bacteria that
often infects hospital patients.
The burns on your chest and arm
exposed raw flesh that
made you a wide open target.
But the antibiotics
will take care of it, right?
Depends on what strain it is.
We'll know more once we get
the results back from these cultures.
So this...
MRSA thing...
Would it make everything look blue?
He's seeing blue.
Who'd you get the scrip from?
Cuddy.
You want to know what I gave her?
MRSA wouldn't change his ocular palette.
Heavy metal poisoning
could cause vision changes,
particularly thallium.
If it was thallium,
he'd be losing his hair.
So maybe it's menopause.
He's 28 years old.
Yes, his age is the reason
it's weird that a man has menopause.
Male menopause.
High estrogen, low testosterone.
Explains the temperature swings,
disorientation.
Endocrinologically
similar to female menopause
but without the vaginas
and mah-jongg tiles.
Male menopause doesn't
explain the blue vision.
The blue vision isn't a symptom,
it's a side effect
of Viagra.
It's right there on the label.
Which I have no reason to
have read except that I'm a doctor.
He's not taking Viagra.
You mean he didn't tell
you he was taking Viagra.
I don't care how sick he is, trust me.
He still thinks he's got a shot.
Menopause causes temperature swings,
limpness.
Limpness causes pills,
pills cause the blues.
He's presenting no other
signs of premature aging.
Aging's not the only cause. You said
that's he got burns on 54% of his body.
Sure it's not 55%?
Burns to his genitals
could cause testicular trauma.
Which in turn could cause?
Run a hormone panel.
Comes back positive, pump him
full of testosterone and send him home.
And stop following me.
Thank God my parents are dead.
If the old man had heard I
had menopause, I'd never live it down.
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
Once these testosterone
pellets dissolve,
your system will be back to normal.
Yeah, but till then I'm an old lady.
Okay to come in?
It's not MRSA.
He's not being isolated anymore.
Anyone not in a white coat is welcome.
You're looking better.
- How you feeling?
- I'm good.
Turns out I got some hormone thing.
They're fixing it right now.
You okay?
Yeah, I think so. I just--
Derek, you in pain?
- You need to get these out.
- Hold on. What's wrong?
- What's going on?
- Looks like an allergic reaction.
Hold on, we're gonna
get you something to stop it.
- No, just take 'em out!
- You gotta calm down.
- Get 'em out!
- Derek!
Derek, let her go!
I need two milligrams IV lorazepam stat!
Get 'em out!
Complaint department's across the hall.
I'm busy.
Can I just assume that you
told me how unfair I'm being and--
I'm sorry.
You could throw a dart at all the
adjectives between arrogant and unhinged
and I'm sure you'd
hit one that describes me.
There's a reason I operate that way.
I live in pain.
Pain that on good days
is merely intolerable,
but on bad ones will suck
the life force right out of you.
Doesn't mean that
I've handled this right.
Actually...
means I was wrong.
Thank you.
I know that couldn't have been...
easy for you to say.
Even if you don't mean a word of it.
I'm sorry.
You can hook me up to a damn polygraph.
And I'm sure you'd pass.
The thing is, I've never been
interested in what you have to say.
All I care about is what you do.
I'll see you at the hearing.
It wasn't the medicine.
Contamination and allergy
tests both came back negative.
There was nothing to
suggest a pulmonary embolism.
And his EKG showed
the expected tachycardia
from the exertion of the attack.
And I'm fine by the way,
thanks for asking.
Aggression comes on that fast,
it's gotta have a neurologic basis.
We should do a CT for a frontal
lobe tumor and an LP for meningitis.
Great.
Have at it.
That's it?
No challenging our theory?
No tearing us down?
No need.
You've got it under control.
Where are you going?
Upstairs this time.
To do what?
Check myself into rehab.
- Did Tritter offer you another deal?
- Nope. This is all me.
So, no slaps on the back,
encouraging words?
We're just trying to
understand what this is.
I hope it's me detoxing.
Otherwise I soiled a perfectly good pair
of underwear last night for nothing.
So this is for real?
It's not just a show for Tritter?
Absolutely it's a show for Tritter.
And the judge.
Unfortunately,
unless it's real, there is no show.
Hey, if it doesn't help my case,
then at least I can go
to prison with heightened senses.
All the better to enjoy
my strolls around the yard.
Time's up. Group's starting.
Gonna need to check that stuff.
When I lead the big patient rebellion,
Voldemort here is first to go.
CT was normal. No frontal lobe tumor.
LP was negative for meningitis.
We're back to square one.
What about something vascular?
Polyarteritis nodosa?
Brain lesions would've
shown up on the CT
Legionnaire's explains
the chills and temperature.
Altered mental status
causes the aggression.
We would've seen respiratory problems.
We're throwing darts.
We need to go to House.
We need to deal with this ourselves.
He can make the time.
Derek's still his patient.
The man's life as he
knows it could be over.
I think you of all people
would want to cut him some slack.
We're treating a man who runs into
burning buildings for perfect strangers.
He didn't ask for what's happening
to him. House did everything to himself.
He's been cut more than enough slack.
Right now, House has more
important things to deal with.
It was the first time
I'd seen him in months.
I guess I was hoping he'd put his arms
around me and tell me he understood.
But he said he wasn't
ready to forgive me.
He may never be ready.
You're doing the only thing you can do.
You're trying.
How about you, Greg?
You thought about how to
fix things with people in your life?
No need.
People in my life have
no expectations of me.
- Makes all our lives easier.
- Apparently not.
- The first step in recovery--
- Is admitting I have a problem.
I've obviously done that,
or I wouldn't be here.
I've even embraced step two. I've
accepted that there is a higher power.
Maybe not a god per se, but
that Andre the Giant guy was powerful.
Where I start to butt
up against it is step three,
surrendering my will
to this higher power.
I'm sure Andre's ghost has
my back and all, but my free will?
- I never leave home without it.
- Kind of like your pills.
If you could do this on your own,
I assume you wouldn't be here.
True.
Everybody lies.
- His tox screen.
- It's been clean every time.
Exactly. It shouldn't be.
He's had extensive skin grafts,
which hurt like hell.
Not everybody's House. People
can handle pain without medication.
But they do have pain.
This guy's worried about losing his job,
so he's hiding the pain.
We find out where the pain is,
maybe we find out where the problem is.
- Or he doesn't feel pain.
- Either way, it's something.
- When?
- Two minutes ago.
Pulse is 137. Respiration 42.
He was fine, just telling me a joke.
Get her out of here.
No fluid in his lungs.
O2 set's 85. He's hypoxic.
We're gonna have to intubate.
It's not his lungs.
He's got marked S-T elevation.
He's having a heart attack.
Pick a color.
Medication time.
You are a ray of
sunshine on a cloudy day.
- He's stable.
- Won't stay that way.
His blood tests show
troponins and CKMB up.
Chase was right.
He was hiding chest pain.
He's been having a whole
series of heart attacks.
Heart attacks can't cause
to reach out and choke someone.
Lack of oxygen to the
brain causes disorientation.
Increased adrenaline causes rage.
More important question is,
what caused the attacks?
Where you going?
To see House. We have a
28-year-old with clean arteries,
no valvular abnormalities
having multiple heart attacks.
I'm not gonna wait for Chase
to give us another breakthrough.
Maybe we should go.
We don't have an answer yet.
I'm fine by the way, thanks for asking.
Whoever came up with buprenorphine
to wean off Vicodin should be shot.
Then stabbed in the eye.
Think someone needs to adjust my meds!
The heart shows no
signs of inflammation or--
The cause of the heart
attacks isn't internal.
It must be external,
something environmental.
None of the attacks
happened in the same place.
Still must be something in common.
First one happened in
a flat building fire.
Fire, water, smoke, oxygen masks.
And the 2nd and
3rd ones happened here.
There's no fire, no water, no smoke.
His clothes are all different.
He'd been cleaned.
That's the what's. How about the who's?
His partner Amy was
at all three attacks, but--
- Anyone else?
- People don't cause heart attacks.
Well, you should be worried
about proving me wrong.
Would you come with me, please?
Anything new on my brother?
We're not quite sure yet.
Could you come with me?
Yeah.
What's this all about?
I don't know.
They wanted to talk to us together.
House was right.
I don't get it.
How can I be causing his heart attacks?
You may be carrying an agent that
triggered them. It could be anything.
Mold spores, poisonous plant residue,
something you picked up at a fire site.
Until we identify the agent,
we can't allow you near Derek.
I can't believe that
I'm doing this to him.
You can't blame yourself for this.
- You know how he got those skin grafts?
- He was trapped in a fire.
We were clearing rooms
in an office building fire, and
the ceiling collapsed.
And it cut me off from
the rest of the group.
And I kept yelling that I was fine, but
Derek refused to wait for the
team to clear the debris, so he took off
looking for another access point.
He got caught in a back draft.
He almost died because of me once.
And now it's happening again.
You're not my mom.
You don't have to
keep checking up on me.
- How you doing?
- Not bad.
Considering I've just learned
I'm completely powerless.
See this big fancy wing?
It was built because this program works.
Faulty logic.
This big fancy wing exists because some
people with money think that it works.
They want to believe
they can buy a better world.
This is nothing short
of idealized despair.
- Let other people wallow in it.
- I don't even know what that means.
None of this means anything.
It's just nonsensical
slogans and platitudes.
- Meaning takes time. It takes work.
- What do you think I've been doing?
You've been here for two days.
Talk about wallowing in it.
We all get it.
We know how much pain you have.
You're here to deal with
that and get on with your life.
Right.
I should have an affair with
a dying patient and move into a hotel.
You're a coward, House.
You find fault in everybody, because
you're afraid to look at yourself.
Thanks.
I was running short on platitudes.
You can leave now.
We tested Amy for about
a dozen different agents,
- but they all came back negative.
- So she's not causing the attacks.
Are you in love with her?
What does that have to do with anything?
Amy told me how you
got those skin grafts.
And the way you're always
watching out for her.
And I see the way you look at her.
Have you told her how you feel?
She has a six-year-old daughter.
Women with daughters
can still fall in love.
I know.
Because she did.
With my brother.
They're engaged.
Broken Heart Syndrome.
He's in love, and it's killing him.
Thought that only happened
to 80-year-old widows.
Thanks to his menopause and estrogen
level he basically is an old woman.
BHS is an acute physical
response to an emotional experience.
Stress triggers a
flood of catecholamines--
That's a plain old stress
cardiomyopathy, not a heart attack.
But if you're too worried about
losing your job to get it treated,
they can devolve into
full-on heart attacks.
You think it's a coincidence
this started when Amy got engaged?
No, I don't.
But now that you know the why,
what are you gonna do to stop the how?
We already put him on beta
blockers and nitroglycerine, no effect.
We need to put him on anti-depressants.
Not if you're right.
Anti-depressants would inhibit
his autonomic nervous system,
which would only speed
up the heart attacks.
We could try propylthiouracil.
Slow down his metabolic rate.
Thyroid effect would
only weaken the heart.
The only other option is blood thinners.
This is not a fat guy with plaque-filled
arteries and a swollen heart.
He's a guy whose brain
is trying to his heart.
So buy him a girlfriend. Make him happy.
That might make you happy. The only
thing that'll make him happy is Amy.
So keep him away from her.
He has a myocardial infarction
every time she walks in the room.
What will happen when we'll
tell him he can never see her again.
- He needs a shrink.
- Chase's idea is as good as any.
Because short of frying
his brain and wiping Amy out,
he's screwed.
We need Cuddy.
Why?
So you can tell her why
you need to fry a guy's brain.
The guy's heart isn't working,
and you want to shock his brain.
Electroshock therapy is the
only way to erase his memories of Amy
and stop the brain's
chemical attack on the heart.
This isn't 1940. The problem
can be controlled with anti-depressants.
Cameron?
Anti-depressants would inhibit
his autonomic nervous system,
speed up the attacks.
LMNO, PTU, blood thinners,
none of them will solve this problem.
The man's got a real-life
Harlequin romance in his head.
We're gonna pull out the 1940 playbook.
Bilateral electrodes,
high stimulus sine-wave intensity,
turning that dial all the way to 11.
It's basic brain chemistry.
We interrupt protein synthesis,
altering the neurotransmitter system.
End results: no memories,
no Amy, no problem.
Go ahead.
You heard the lady. Go plug him in.
Am I really that pathetic?
What are you talking about?
If I had pitched electroshock therapy
as a cure for Broken
Heart Syndrome any other time,
you'd have dug in and maybe try
a hundred other useless things first.
So either you're actually
beginning to trust me, or
you just feel sorry for me.
You presented a reasonable argument.
You were clear-headed
and non-impulsive about it.
Never once used the word "moron."
The rehab's working, House.
You'll still be able
to perform routine functions
like walking, talking, tying your shoes.
The treatment targets
the anterior cingulate cortex.
It should only affect
your experiential memories.
So my parents? My childhood?
If this works, you won't remember them.
Or your firefighting training.
And Amy.
Are you okay with that?
I wouldn't miss her, right?
Tell Amy how you feel,
because if she loves you--
No.
I won't do that to her.
Or to my brother.
You're effectively killing
who you are just to keep this secret.
She doesn't love me.
Caterpillar?
Lower intestine with ulcerative colitis.
You crash art therapy classes
just for the adrenaline rush?
Cuddy wouldn't get off the phone until
I promised I'd come and see for myself.
I gotta admit,
this move I did not expect.
Well, don't tell anyone, but the photos
of smiling people in the brochures,
it's just marketing.
Well, you're obviously making an effort.
So I suppose the next
step is for me to...
talk to the DA.
Which you have no intention of doing.
No.
So words mean nothing,
actions mean nothing.
What the hell is left?
You son of a bitch!
What about your words? Your actions?
"Gotta get House cleaned up.
Gotta get him to show some humility."
But when it comes to actually
doing something, you've proved that
all you care about is bitch-slapping
a guy who refused to kiss your ass.
You ever trust an addict?
You ever give one
the benefit of the doubt?
- How many times that works out for you
- Yeah, I get it.
So you were screwed over by your wife,
your mother, your partner.
But you keep sending
them Christmas cards
while you take it out on everyone else.
No more Christmas cards.
No, I learned...
people like you...
even your actions lie.
I'm scared.
I know.
I'm gonna give you a muscle
relaxant so your body doesn't convulse.
Count backwards from ten.
Go.
What's your name?
Heart sounds good.
Do you know what city we're in?
No.
Would you be okay with
a couple of visitors?
It's me. Brock.
I'm your brother,
and when you get out of here,
you'll be staying with me.
I'm Amy.
I'm your friend.
I'm sorry.
But I don't remember either of you.
We've give him four
rounds of electroshock.
The charge made his voice a little
higher, but the EKG and BP are good.
Good.
We're gonna give him
his last round in the morning,
then be in court for your hearing.
Thanks.
I'm gonna stay here.
Monitor Derek.
Thanks for the update.
My next condolence call is arriving.
I'll see you guys tomorrow.
I got you something.
Nice.
I figured it might help make
a good impression on the judge.
It's not that nice.
I had no business blaming
you for any of this.
I know you were just trying to help me.
Protect me.
That's what friends do.
Is this
an apology?
Part of the program.
You don't like it, I can stop.
Not at all. It's just so...
unfamiliar.
Please, keep going.
He looks lost.
It's gonna take him a while.
Brock's pulling a double shift.
He can't stand to see him this way.
Derek's gonna need him, Amy.
I know the timing isn't
great with a wedding coming up.
What wedding?
Yours.
You and Brock.
We're not getting married.
We don't even date.
Why would you think
we're getting married?
When you first offered Dr. House
the chance to check into drug rehab,
- how did he respond?
- He told me to get out of his office.
I warned him that...
he could end up in prison
and lose his medical license.
If he was concerned,
he didn't show it.
- So you continued your investigation.
- Yes,
which is what lead me
to the hospital pharmacy.
Turn it off.
I thought I told you never
to call me when I'm on trial.
The memories were false.
We fried his brain for nothing.
Whatever was killing
him before is still there.
We did an MRI. There's a slight
hypoperfusion in the anterior cortex.
What did you find when
you checked the pharmacy log?
Hold on, Mr. Vickers.
Thanks, Your Honor. Hard to hear.
Did you test for clotting
time and LV function?
I believe this is a medical emergency,
Your Honor.
His blood's normal, and his
heart's pumping it up to the brain.
But it's not all getting there.
Something's obstructing the blood flow.
You were given adequate notice
to make arrangements for your patients.
There's no hyperintensity to
suggest a foreign body near the region.
And no signs of infection
or vascular malformation.
- It's lower down.
- Dr. House, hang up.
The cytology on the
LP doesn't suggest a tumor.
Now!
Hang on a second.
Does your voice always get that
high and annoying when you're angry?
- Do you want to go to jail?
- No thank you.
Set him up for a selective
vertebral angiography. I'm on my way.
Dr. House--
Sit down!
Why?
I'm bored. There's nothing I can say or
do that's gonna make a difference here.
If you leave this room,
I will find you in contempt.
Get a recess.
Are you out of your mind?
They said they wanted me there,
but I don't think they liked me.
His voice isn't high because
of the electrical charges.
It's another symptom of menopause.
His system keeps getting
hit by women's issues.
So let's follow the pattern.
What might obstruct the blood flow
that's more common in women than men?
- Is the catheter in?
- Go back to court.
- We'll let you know the results.
- Shut up and wire him.
Center the image on
the interpeduncular cistern.
Keep it moving at 30 frames per second.
If you think the arteries are narrowing,
we're gonna need still shots,
which we can do without you.
The problem is not how wide the road is.
There's a guy with a squeegee
on the sidewalk flagging cars,
that's what's causing the slow down.
We find him, we find the problem.
- He's wired.
- Go.
Injecting the dye.
Blood's in the capillarieses.
There.
Mr. Squeegee.
Spinal meningioma pushing
on the nerves to the vocal chords.
Creates the voice change.
And that nerve just happens to live
right near the meningeal
branch of the vertebral artery.
Obstructs the blood flow to the brain.
Brain malfunctions,
creating false memories.
Memories cause love.
Love kills.
And we didn't completely screw up.
Cleaning the slate bought
us time to find the real problem.
On the other hand, if we'd been better,
we wouldn't have needed the time.
Schedule him for surgery.
Dig that thing out.
He can start enjoying real
misery instead of the fake stuff.
I just heard that
you apologized to Wilson.
Detoxing.
I didn't know what I was saying.
Excuse me.
I have to go to jail.
What is your position
at Princeton-Plainsboro?
Chief Administrator
and Dean of Medicine.
And you're responsible
for oversight of the pharmacy?
Yes.
Sorry, didn't mean to interrupt.
I hope you don't mind that
we continued on without you.
I said I was sorry.
There's no need to be sarcastic.
What is this?
That's our prescription
sign-out log from December 24.
Does that appear to be Dr.
House's signature?
Yes. What has he signed for?
A prescription for oxycodone
in the name of patient Larry Zebalusky.
And did those pills
ever reach that patient?
- No.
- Why?
He was already dead.
- And Dr. House knew this.
- Yes.
So...
Dr. House had no legal or medical
basis for acquiring that oxycodone?
Dr. Cuddy?
He never got the pills.
It's his signature.
The log is strictly controlled.
Dr. House did pick up a prescription,
but it wasn't for oxycodone.
It says oxycodone.
- You testified it was--
- I know.
But it wasn't oxycodone.
Dr. Wilson informed me that Dr.
House already tried
to steal the pain
medication of this patient,
which made clear to me that Dr.
House was in
a particularly vulnerable
and desperate state.
So I went to the pharmacy
and I swapped bottles.
Dr. House only got
a bottle with placebos.
I understand your impulse
to protect a valued colleague.
I have it right here
on the inventory report--
Your Honor, she's lying.
She's obviously forged that report.
In light of this evidence...
If this is real,
why didn't she mention it earlier?
- I move to dismiss this case.
- There is other evidence, Your Honor.
Everyone shut up and sit down.
Dr. Cuddy, why are you only
now coming forward with this?
I guess I never expected
it to go this far.
The witness is excused.
Your Honor,
you can't seriously believe--
Dr. House, please stand.
My suspicion is your boss--
My suspicion is you have
better friends than you deserve.
Rules and laws apply to everyone.
You are not as special as you think.
But Detective Tritter
chose to make you so.
Detective, I don't know
exactly what's going on here,
but I am sure that this man is
not flooding the streets with cocaine.
I'm also certain that,
knowing Dr. House,
he must've done something
to set you off. But
you're gonna have to live with it.
Given Dr. Cuddy's testimony, I'm not
going to allow this to proceed to jury.
Case dismissed.
Court is adjourned.
You're still guilty of contempt
for that little walkout earlier.
You'll be spending the night in jail,
and after that,
you're going right back to your rehab.
Bailiff,
take Dr. House into custody.
Dr. House.
So should I be looking
for you in the shadows?
Flinch every time a car backfires?
Good luck.
I hope I'm wrong about you.
We got the meningioma.
Your brain should start
generating real memories again.
What do I do when I get out?
You have people who love you.
They'll take care of you.
You start over.
Surprised to see you're not
spooning your way through the walls.
So, what do you say?
How about a conjugal visit to celebrate?
There's nothing to celebrate, House.
You made me perjure myself.
Fabricate evidence.
You make everyone around
you worse for being there.
The only bright spot
is that now I own your ass.
When you get out of rehab,
you're gonna be pulling
double clinic duty,
giving lectures to students
helping me find donors,
and pretty much anything else I ask.
You got it?
Your buprenorphine.
You get these from the
pharmacy or from Voldemort?
Voldemort.
Why, what difference does it--
That's Vicodin.
- He's been slipping you Vicodin?
- No!
He'd be risking his
minimum wage job to do that.
The whole time?
My higher power said it was okay.
Nothing's changed?
Nothing's changed.
The apology.
You didn't need to
do that to make this work.
Believe what you want.
Good night, House.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Good night, Wilson.
Transcript: FRM - Synchro: jh26
www.sub-way.fr