He's got a temperature of 103.
And why do we care?
Because we're human beings.
It's what we do.
He said he was
at a luncheon memeeting.
You took his history?
Guy looks like Harpo.
You should see him.
You asked him what book
he's currently reading.
It's hilarious to
watch him try and talk.
I asked him
anything I could think of.
Favorite color:
"Bwoo."
Favorite dessert topping?
Trust me, you never know
what fact may prove the key
to saving your life.
Whipped cweam.
House:
I asked him if he was sure.
Where are you going?
You're an ass.
I know.
Where are you going?
This is either a toxin,
an infection, or an allergic reaction.
I assume you gave him epi,
so that rules out allergies.
Put him on antibiotics
in case it's an infection.
And if it's a toxin,
we'll keep him here overnight,
let the swelling go down,
send him home.
I'm going to the movies.
Which one of you is House?
The skinny brunette.
No, that's Dr. Cameron.
I'm skinny.
How do you know her name?
I was a patient of yours.
Oh, well, if you want to leave
the chocolates downstairs--
Bang!
Stay!
Stay away from him.
Shocking, isn't it?
Who'd want to hurt you?
Bang!
2X24 - No Reason
Original Airdate (FOX): 23 MAY-2006
You're pathetic.
Judging by the growth,
I'd say I've been unconscious
for two days.
- Have you been sitting
there the whole time?
- No.
Judging by the oily buildup
in your hair, I'd say you're lying.
I was scared.
Pardon me for caring.
Did I lose any organs?
The bullet to your abdomen
pierced your stomach,
nicked the bowel,
lodged in the posterior rib.
Well, I always say,
if you're gonna get shot,
do it in a hospital.
The one in your neck--
I don't remember that one.
Went right through,
severed your jugular.
- The shooter turns out
to be a guy who--
- Don't care.
You don't care why a guy walked
into a hospital and shot a doctor?
Shot you?
I assume
his reasoning was faulty.
So what was it?
Infection?
The surgery went fine.
- You've had no post-op--
- Not me. Patient.
- Harpo.
- You just got shot, House.
You should rest.
I got shot.
Diagnostically boring.
Big fat tongue, on the other hand...
endlessly entertaining.
We biopsied his tongue.
House:
And it was negative.
And the blood tests were negative.
I didn't say
we did blood tests.
You don't biopsy a tongue
unless you have to biopsy a tongue.
And you don't have to biopsy a tongue
unless you've already come up with
nothing on a routine battery of tests
which don't involve
torturing your patient.
Any new symptoms?
Other than the increased
intracranial pressure?
Any guesses on how
I figured that one out?
You knew the next step
would be a lumbar puncture.
A lumbar puncture would almost
certainly give us a definitive answer.
Since we don't have a definitive answer,
we must not have done an LP,
and the most common
reason to not do an LP is
increased intracranial pressure.
He was shot by security trying to--
House, what are you--
House.
I'm talking to Cuddy.
Lie down.
You've got to be in pain.
Not today.
Today I'm on morphine.
You're going to rip your stitches out.
- Check Harpo's trash.
- Forget about the patient.
Come on.
You're curious.
T rash?
You don't know
what I'm talking about,
but you know it's good.
You can't just be walking around.
Well, then stop me.
- You've lost blood--
- Physically stop me.
- You could damage--
- You can't.
Because that would involve
physically touching me,
and then things would
get so sexually charged--
I'm twice your size.
Get your hands off me.
Everything that lives, eats.
Everything that eats, poops.
That's why every organ has
a sanitation department.
The lymph system.
Whatever's doing the damage
is dumping its waste in there.
That's what you meant by trash.
Biopsy the lymph node
under the jaw.
I'm sorry,I know it's crazy,
but there's no other place.
It's the ICU. It stands for intensive care.
He needs intensive care, so do you.
He needs to be shot again.
He is handcuffed to his bed.
He is sedated.
He's not going to hurt you.
If your security was any good,
I wouldn't have been shot
in the first place.
He is where
he's supposed to be.
- Where you're supposed to be--
- Who did my surgery?
Gillick, why?
You going to send him
a fruit basket?
He screwed up.
It's annoying enough dealing
with your Vicodin habit.
Quit upping your morphine.
I'm not.
I'm reducing it.
And you're not in pain?
I'm feeling better.
Gillick is very good.
Your recovery time--
My stomach kills me,
my neck is throbbing,
but my leg feels better.
- That's amazing.
- It's unbelievable.
Since getting shot is not
an FDA approved treatment
for anything,
it means something must have
gone wrong in the surgery.
Yes, terribly... tragically wrong.
Enjoy the mistake.
He must have nicked something
in my peripheral nervous system.
If it's alleviating pain,
who knows what else it's doing?
Get back to the ICU
before you rip out your stitches,
and I have to chain you to your bed.
Why did you try to kill me?
I didn't.
Then the gun thing
might have been a mistake.
If I'd have killed you,
it would have been over.
I needed you to live.
Because I want
to see you suffer.
[Moriarty  groans out]
Get the needle out of there.
[Alarm starts beeping]
He can't breathe.
House.
The test was negative.
Are you sure
you want to be doing this?
I'm fine. I think.
Cameron,
you got my records?
They don't like to release
patient's operative notes.
And yet you're holding them.
And whispering.
He's sleeping.
Yeah.
Killer needs his rest.
Otherwise
he's grumpy all day.
Hey! Wake up!
Watch me save a life.
Almost for sure
it's some sort of infection.
We've got him on broad-spectrum antibiotics,
but it's not even slowing the thing down.
Unless we figure out what type of infection,
we can't treat, and we can't figure out
what type because we can't do an LP.
Do an LP.
See what I did there?
Couldn't have done that
if you'd killed me.
We would have done an LP
2 days ago if we could have.
But that much pressure,
something's bound to go--
We would have done an LP 2 days ago
if the risks hadn't so obviously
outweighed the benefits.
We just cut a hole in his throat.
The equation has changed.
Couldn't have put it better myself.
Pressure...
120 millimeters H2O,
with small visible excursions
related to respiration and pulse.
- Well within normal, that's good.
- No, that's weird.
You want to hear a story?
I have a rule.
- People who shoot me
forfeit the right--
- My wife was sick.
- None of the doctors could figure out why.
- Oh, I know this story.
She died.
So you selected one of her doctors to kill,
because that wouldmake everything right again.
She lived.
You cured her.
I'm truly sorry I did that.
In the course of
investigating her illness,
you convinced me that
everything was relevant.
You needed the truth.
I confessed to you
that I'd had an affair.
But it turns out that it had nothing
to do with why she was sick.
Genetic predisposition
to brain aneurysms.
You told her that.
You also told her
about my affair.
And you caught crap,
she left you,
and now I've got to pay
because you couldn't keep
your little killer in your pants.
She killed herself.
What sort of hospital
has glass walls?
That's my husband.
Really?
You thought
I just liked watching people
get needles poked in the back?
Nope.
I figured a coworker
or a sister. Not wife.
Why?
Don't worry.
It's not insulting.
At least not to you.
You're satisfied
by that answer?
You're Dr. House, aren't you?
You're not going to
shoot me, are you?
You treated a friend of mine.
She told me
you only talk to people
if you have to.
And then you insult them
while showing off
how insightful you are.
Sevens marry sevens.
Nines marry nines.
Fours marry fours.
Maybe there's some wiggle room
if there's enough money, or
somebody got pregnant.
But  you've got at least
3 points on your husband,
and your frock says
you didn't do it for the money.
And your breasts say that
you haven't had any kids.
So you figure my marriage
is a mathematical error?
Numbers don't lie.
We're having trouble finding out
what infection your husband has.
The most likely culprit is an STD.
You want to know
if I've had an affair with
someone closer to my integer.
And I have to tell you the truth,
or my husband will die.
Is your friend single?
No.
And I've always been faithful.
Wow. I would've bet money
something would go wrong.
Let's rotate him back.
He's  bleeding
into his ocular orbit.
LP wouldn't do this.
Lots  of pressure behind.
Gotta relieve it.
[Alarms starts beeping]
What's going on?
What--what are they doing?
I should go.
I seem to have torn my stitches.
You collapsed in the hall.
Tore your stitches.
I remember.
I was there.
How's your gut?
It's hurting?
You shoot the guy
who sold her the gun?
She locked herself in the garage,
and she started the car.
You shoot the guy who
sold her the garage door opener?
You're an ass.
That is a bold position to take,
given that I shot you.
The shooting just makes you an idiot.
You're an ass because you're
trying to wrap it in the flag,
like you did a good thing.
You're an assand a hypocrite.
You don't believe in rules.
You do whatever you think is right.
That's all I did.
You were my role model.
Watch out. You're
getting crumbs on the flag.
I didn't commit to honor her.
I didn't commit to never lie to her.
Well, if you'd kept your mouth shut,
she'd be alive, and you wouldn't be shot.
If you'd kept
your pistols in your pants--
It's my fault she's dead.
I know it.
But why can't you admit that
it's maybe just a little bit yours too?
That maybe it's
not just medical mistakes
that screw things up.
Here's how life works.
You either get to ask for an apology,
or you get to shoot people.
Not both.
House:
Infections don't make
your eyes pop out.
Chase:
We should get back. You're
supposed to be chained to your bed.
House:
I'm not done eating.
There's got to be some sort of
bleeding disorder.
This is really stupid.
Look, if my stitches pop out again,
I got 3 doctors to save me.
Could be some sortof weakness
in the lining of the ocular veins.
Okay, I'll be you guys.
[as Chase] No way, mate.
Too much blood to just be a vein.
[as Foreman] No way is he!
If it was an artery,
he'd still be bleeding.
[as Cameron]
Actually, he'd be dead.
He could have had a granuloma
in his sinuses that bled,
which could have been
caused by Wegener's.
I think the surgeon would have
noticed a giant growth while
they were sticking the eyeball back in.
Tongue and eyes are sick.
What about the nose?
It's right in between.
Why isn't it sick?
So it's not spreading.
It's got a common source.
Which can only be what?
The brain,
except the CT was clean.
Check the brain's trash,
see what it's hiding.
- The brain doesn't
have a lymph system.
- I know.
All its garbage just blows off,
gets caught in the snow fence
by the side of the road.
You're referring
to the blood-brain barrier.
What else?
Biopsy the barrier.
Wouldn't it be safer to make
a few educated guesses first?
Try some relatively
safe treatments?
Biopsy the barrier. But first,
start him on mebendazole
in case it's a worm.
And levofloxacin
in case it's an infection that
slipped by the first antibiotic.
And azithromycin for STDs.
I really don't think the wife is
the kind to be messing around.
If I was married to her,
I certainly wouldn't--
House.
The patient isn't married.
He's a widower.
Really, it's more helpful
if you do the prescribed rehab yourself.
My body is fine.
My mind, on the other hand...
Maybe she was a girlfriend.
Maybe she was just trying
to jerk you around.
I spoke to every one
of the nurses on that floor.
The patient had only had 6 visitors.
Two females, no babes.
His mother and his aunt.
So they missed someone.
They're not security.
My posse never saw her or me
talking on the other side of the glass.
They were a little busy
trying to save the guy's life.
There's only one
possible conclusion.
It was a hallucination.
What does that look like to you?
Point-six?
Anesthesia? No.
It's got to be six and a smudge.
Let's say you're right.
It wouldn't be
that uncommon after trauma.
After that much blood loss?
If my perceptions are compromised,
then my judgmentis compromised.
What if his wife told me
that the patient just got bit
by a rabid Vietnamese leper?
So pull yourself off the case.
And the next case?
You take two weeks.
You recover.
What if I don't?
What if it wasn't the shooting?
The guy who sees connections
between everything sees no connection
between being shot and minor brain disruptions?
What if it was the surgery?
What if it was the fact that
you tore out your stitches
and lost two pints of blood?
Why did Gillick give me
ketamine during my surgery?
Working.
We need to talk.
Get back to the ICU.
Who un-cuffed you?
Why would a surgeon
administer ketamine?
Who showed you
your surgical file?
How do you know it's mine?
Because your patient hasn't had surgery,
and you don't care about anybody else.
My anesthesia was almost nonexistent,
and yet I wasn't awake.
For some reason, somebody decided
to put me in a dissociative coma
instead of just putting me out.
There are plenty of reasons to use--
- Fine.
I'll go beat the truth
out of my surgeon. Gillick, right?
It worked.
There's a clinic in Germany.
They've been treating
chronic pain by inducing comas,
and letting the mind
basically reboot itself.
There's about a 50% chance
your pain will come back.
Which of course means there is
a 50% chance that it won't.
- You had no right--
- To heal you?
- You messed with my brain.
- Why are you so upset?
Are you experiencing
any neurological symptoms?
Dizziness, tremors,
hallucinations?
No.
It's a point of principle.
- Test was negative.
- No trash against the fence.
Is your leg really better?
Don't worry, I'm sure
something else is wrong.
We did find blood.
- On which side?
- The wrong side.
First thing that makes sense.
The wrong side's the wrong side.
It can't make sense.
It'd mess with his brain.
Wouldn't cause fever.
- He's been sleeping a lot lately.
- You worried?
I marked a change of meds
on his chart.
Foreign object.
Body wants to get rid of it.
It causes the fever.
Blood's a foreign object?
In the brain lining, it is.
Blood dyscrasia means cancer.
Find it.
- All the tests--
- Have been negative.
What do you do
if your trash cans are full?
You use your neighbors' trash cans.
Except it's still light outside.
Your neighbor will see you.
So you go out the back way,
into an alley, and drop off
your trash by their garage.
We'll check
the lymphatic system in the chest.
You got that from
trash cans in the alley?
The saliva glands from the tongue are
connected to the lymphatic system in the lungs.
It's the next lymphatic system over.
Yeah.
Go get lung lymph.
How did he know that?
I wouldn't have hired him
if he wasn't smart.
Right.
Because you have
nothing but respect for him.
Maybe he knew the answer
because the question wasn't
nearly as trickyas you thought.
Maybe he's not getting smarter.
You're getting dumber.
You pretend
to buck the system.
Pretend to be a rebel.
You claim to hate rules.
But all you do is
substitute your own rules
for society's.
And it's a nice, simple rule.
Tell the blunt, honest truth
in the starkest, darkest way.
And what will be will be.
What will be should be.
And everyone else is a coward.
But you're wrong.
It's not cowardly
to not call someone an idiot.
People aren't tactful or polite
just because it's nice.
They do it because
they've got an ounce of humility.
Because they know that
they will make mistakes,
and they know that
their actions have consequences.
And they know that
those consequences are their fault.
Why do you want so bad
not to be human, House?
Oh, he's awake.
House, we need
to talk to you.
How the hell did you know
I was awake?
Your nostrils flare
when you sleep.
- No, they do not.
- Fine, I'm lying.
- Test was negative.
- You knew?
- Force of habit.
- Showed no cancer.
No reason why
he's got a fever of 103,
and no reason why
his tongue won't fit in his mouth.
He's post-op. Chase is
getting him up and around.
It's important that
you're up ASAP after surgery.
You think you can urinate?
It's getting bigger!
What, you're...
getting aroused?
No! Not that part.
Oh, God, it hurts.
It's not stopping. Aah!
Surgeons found
no evidence of a burst artery.
The blood had to
come from somewhere.
You took a shower in it.
Trauma?
You think someone snuck in here
just to kick him in the jewels?
And poke out his eye,
and swell up his tongue?
Keep riding.
I got a bet with my physio
that I can do 100 klicks by Friday.
What  about blood
from the kidneys?
Kidneys drain into the bladder,
which drains into the ureter.
There's no way it would
mess with the scrotum.
Yeah.
Basic human anatomy.
Therefore, I think it's safe to assume
that the problem lies elsewhere.
But given that this case doesn't
make any kind of sense whatsoever,
maybe we should
even question the basics.
Maybe he's not human.
An anatomical defect
would seem more likely,
but let's not rule that one out.
Even more likely, he is human,
his anatomy is where it's supposed to be,
but he has testicular cancer.
Cameron:
We tested for cancer.
Foreman: We tested
the lymph system in his chest.
Chase:
Surgeons found no growth.
Foreman:
Surgeons were just trying to
put everything back where it was.
They weren't doing an inventory.
May have been lucky.
If you don't catch
testicular cancer early, it kills.
- Probably eroded some vessel.
- Yeah, I know.
The question is
why I didn't think of it.
Eyes popping out is
a rather odd presentation.
Sack blowing up,
on the other hand...
If you could think of everything yourself,
you wouldn't need a team to annoy.
I screwed up some basic anatomy.
And I missed connecting
a testicular explosion
with a testicular problem.
You think there's any way
I would have done that before
Cuddy messed with my brain?
She was trying to
help you, and it worked.
Yeah, I can run like the wind,
but I can't think.
And seeing as how I'm too old
to become a professional athlete,
it looks to me as if
she screwed me over big time.
You don't want
a healthy leg.
Oh, here we go.
If you've got a good life,
if you're healthy,
you've got no reason to bitch.
No reason to hate life.
Here's the flaw in your argument.
If I enjoy hating life, I don't hate life.
- I enjoy it.
- I didn't sayit was rational.
HIV testing is 99% accurate,
which means there are
some people who test positive
who live with their own impending doom
for months, or years, before
finding outeverything's okay.
Weirdly, most of them don't react
with happiness. Or even anger.
They get depressed.
Not because they wanted to die, but
because they've defined themselves
by their disease.
Suddenly, what made them
them isn't real.
I don't define myself
by my leg.
No, you have taken it
one step further.
The only way you could come to terms
with your disability was to somehow
make it mean nothing.
So you had to
redefine everything.
You have dismissed
anything physical.
Anything not coldly,
calculatingly intellectual.
Why are you protecting her?
Because she's done
nothing wrong.
You're completely comfortable
with what she did to me?
Yeah, I am. Yeah.
You agonize
over moral choices.
You're not completely
comfortable with anything until
you've taken days to get your head
around every possible side.
I've known
what she did for 6 hours.
How come you're acting
like you've known for days?
What do I have?!
- You're not sick.
- What do I have?!
- You need to calm down.
- I have my brain!
- And that's it!
- We were trying to help you.
Yeah, nobody tries
to screw up! They just do.
You were out of control.
You were shooting morphine--
I can make people better!
And you two decide to
trade that for jogging shoes.
If you're suffering from side effects,
then we can look at that--
You value the physical so much.
Let me put this in terms
you can understand.
You're unbelievable.
Even when you're out of your mind
with anger and fear,
you still couch it in logical terms.
- Are you hallucinating?
- Yeah, I'm hallucinating!
No, I mean right now.
[Moriarty's voice]
Are you hallucinating?
How did you know I was...
You were yelling at me.
You were calling me Wilson.
No.
You're losing it, House.
I never call Wilson by his name.
Oh, yeah, right.
The hallucinator is going to tell
the hallucinatee what happened.
You're not the hallucinatee.
Wilson was the hallucinatee.
You think maybe you're focusing
on the wrong thing here?
Cuddy's office was the hallucinatee.
The bathroom was the hallucinatee.
Bathroom. It figures.
What figures?
You wet your bed.
Damn it.
Test was negative.
No.
AFP and Beta HCG
say no testicular cancer.
So, let's recap.
We've just ruled out everything.
Which doesn't make sense.
So the answer has to be
something that doesn't make sense.
Do a cystoscopy.
Make sure he's human.
Test was negative.
For him being human?
Everything was right
where it's supposed to be.
All the tubes go
where they're supposed to go.
Most likely scenario is
some kind of bacterial prostatitis.
Hmm.
Find out
if his father hunched?
His father have
trouble peeing?
His father have sex
with his own mother?
If the answers to
any of these questions is yes,
assume you're right.
If the answers are no,
assume you're right, but
biopsy some prostate lymphs
just to be sure.
But...
Then we'd have to cut through his stomach.
And since he's clearly got a bleeding problem,
- this kind of surgery might--
- He doesn't clearly have anything.
How did I get here?
What are you talking about?
I was in the ICU.
And then I was coming down
these stairs with you guys.
What happened in between?
I don't remember
how I got here.
I'm taking myself off my case.
Your patient's in critical care.
He's had a fever unabated for two--
I'm losing my mind.
I'm having blackouts.
- You said you weren't having any--
- I lied.
If you are doing this to scare me,
you made your point.
Next time you get shot, I promise
to only treat the bullet wounds.
I'm off the case.
Why did you jump up
when I came in?
I thought you were
going to attack me again.
Again?
Yeah, you were in my face.
- You were--
- No, I wasn't.
- You came in here with Wilson and--
- That was a hallucination.
- No, you--
- Which means this is a hallucination.
How can I tell
what's real and what's not?
Everything looks the same.
Sounds the same.
Tastes the same.
Seems like
I'd be the last person
you'd want to ask.
Why not?
You're obviously not here.
I'm obviously not here.
Which means this is a creation of my mind,
which means I'm really just asking myself.
Well, if you're talking to yourself,
that's a lot of unnecessary explanation.
Hey, I'm trying to work this out.
That requires give and take,
even in my own mind.
What was the question?
How can I tell what's real?
Does it matter?
That doesn't sound like
something I'd ask.
All right. Your concern is that
if you act in the real world
based on information that's not real,
the results are
impossible to foresee.
With you so far.
But information is
incapable of harm in and of itself.
Ideas are neithergood nor bad, but
merely as useful as what we do with them.
Only actions can cause harm.
That sounds like me.
So you do nothing.
You refrain from taking any actions.
You continue to throw out your ideas
as you always would, but
if they're based on faulty assumptions,
your team will point that out.
They won't do anything
that could hurt him.
So I trust my team.
Test was negative.
No blood in the prostate.
No structural abnormalities.
If something
doesn't make sense,
what does that mean?
It's not rhetorical.
I need your input on everything I ask,
no matter how obvious it might seem.
It means you're wrong.
It means one of
your assumptions is wrong.
Because if something doesn't
make sense, it can't be real.
So, what are our assumptions?
We don't have any.
We're just guessing on testing.
We assume
the tests are right.
We've already
redone them. Twice.
Let's go more basic.
What's more basic
than the test results?
The tests themselves.
What does a biopsy consist of?
You take a sample.
Define sample.
It's a small representative piece
of whatever you think is the problem.
House:
You go down to the shore,
you fill a cup of water.
It's got no fish in it.
Does that mean
no fish in the ocean?
- We can do another biopsy.
- We could fill another cup of water.
We gotta dive in. We gotta see
what's actually in there.
We can't operate.
He's got a bleeding problem.
We ASSUME
he's got a bleeding problem.
Yeah, because he bled from
where he wasn't supposed to bleed,
causing parts of his body to blow up.
Assuming that
crazy assumption is correct,
if we operate on him, we'll kill him.
What if we could find
a way to do this surgery
without giving him
more than a paper cut?
You want to let a robot
operate on me?
The technology is amazing.
It magnifies everything ten times.
It's ten times the accuracy.
No way. I want a person.
- A personwill be controlling--
- People suck.
People have turned you from a guy with
a swollen tongue into a guy with one eye,
one ball, and a stapled-on face.
If you want someone to hold you
while you cry yourself to sleep at night,
choose warm and soft.
If you want
someone to write you a poem,
pick the sensitive loner.
But if all you care about is that
something's done right,
pick the guy with the metal head.
No way.
No way, no way.
You gotta see this thing in action
before you say no way. Come on.
House.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
I'm not doing anything.
Just throwing out ideas.
I think
you should put him in a wheelchair,
take him down to the O.R.
But I may be out of my mind.
Relax, Cameron.
I'm not going to cut you.
I just want to show
what this puppy can do.
It can make
1mm incisions.
You know how small that is?
It's small even in metric.
If I do something
that doesn't make sense,
even to you, stop me.
Delicate, no?
House.
Does that hurt?
Seen enough?
No.
That wasn't a question.
You either do this, or you die.
You've wasted your life.
Yeah.
If only I'd spent more time
dedicating myself to finding
someone worthy to shoot.
If I had killed you,
would it have mattered?
Not to me.
Have you got a pen?
You don't care
if you live or die?
I care because I live.
I can't care if I'm dead.
I don't want to
hear semantics.
You anti-semantic bastard.
Would anybody care that
the world lost that wit?
Working here.
That's all right.
You don't have to say anything.
Just let me soak
into your subconscious.
You think that
the only truth that matters
is the truth that
can be measured.
Good intentions don't count.
What's in your heart
doesn't count.
Caring doesn't count.
But a man's life can be measured by
how many tears are shed when he dies.
Just because
you can't measure them,
just because you don't
want to measure them,
doesn't mean it's not real.
That does not make sense.
And even if I'm wrong,
you're still miserable.
Did you really think that
your life's purpose was to sacrifice yourself
and get nothing in return?
No.
You believe there's
no purpose to anything.
Even the lives you save,
you dismiss.
You turn the one decent thing in your life,
and you taint it, strip it of all meaning.
You're miserable for nothing.
I don't know
why you'd want to live.
I'm sorry.
I know what's wrong.
House, get out of here.
You're not sterile.
He'll be fine.
Chase:
Great.
What's he got?
How come you guys have
never tried to yank me off this case?
I'm having hallucinations.
Blackouts.
But you're always insane,
and you're always right.
I'm almost always
eventually right.
You have no way of knowing
when "eventually" is.
Every time I've had
an epiphany on this one,
you guys were right on board.
No challenges,
no need to explain.
No offense, but either
you guys are getting smarter,
or I'm getting dumber.
We've worked with you
long enough to know--
I know the test results
even beforeyou enter the room.
We have identical knowledge.
How is that possible?
You're wrong.
If something doesn't make sense,
one of your assumptions has to be wrong.
Because if something
doesn't make sense,
it can't be real.
But what if the faulty assumption
is that it's real?
House, you're losing it.
I've lost it.
Why did you stop me?
Because I think
you're going to kill him.
No, you don't think that.
You know it.
Because you're in my head.
As long as the delusion makes sense,
my mind lets it go on.
I have to make it
not make sense. I have to...
push it past the point
where it can trick my mind.
Hey, hey.
If this is a nightmare,
you're gonna wake up.
If it's real,
you're killing a man.
It's also possible that
I may already be dead.
But I don't believe
in the afterlife.
House, go back to your room.
If this is a hallucination,
it's a good one.
You're pain free, you can walk--
It's not real.
Therefore, it's meaningless.
I want meaning.
[Alarms start beeping]
[Monitors flatlining]
Oh, God.
Goodbye.
- Foreman: He was shot.
- Twice.
Once in the abdomen, once in the neck.
Hello.
It's going to be okay.
You're gonna be okay.
You don't know nothing.
Tell Cuddy...
I want ketamine.
Transcript : Raceman
Synchro : Vaccine
www.forom.com