Hi, kids.
- Mommy, look what I made.
- Oh wow.
It's a farmer and
a cow and some horses.
It's beautiful.
It's for Ted's office.
Oh, he's gonna love it.
And it would be nice
if you called him Dad.
Give me a big hug.
Secret is the Haas avocados.
I can e-mail you
the recipe if you want.
[Cell phone ringing]
Oh. It's the third time
they've changed plans since Friday.
These idiots think
you could just add the 14th floor
and the mayor won't notice.
I thought turning the garage
into a nursery was complicated.
Any luck on your end yet?
Not for luck of try.
Ted.
Oh, come on, Margo.
I have to go Teleclient.
He is an idot.
Go kick some ass.
I have to take Stella to karate by 3:00
and birthday party at Julia's after.
You okay?
Yeah, I'll be back.
Just make sure
she's dressed.
[ A crow cawing]
[A dog barking]
[Unlocks her car]
Ow!
[Starts the engine]
Ah. Oh.
[Tires screeching]
[Crash and screech to a halt ]
[Honks a horn with her head]
[Groaning with pain]
Honey!
[Whimpers in pain]
2x11 - Need to Know
Original Airdate (FOX): 7 February-2006
Cuddy:
He's actually on time.
He's six minutes early.
- Something's hapened.
- I'm on it.
Morning, Jimmy.
Anybody die while I was gone?
Did--did you iron your shirt?
Thought about shaving.
Couldn't find a razor.
What the hell
happened in Baltimore?
Sorry, chief.
Never kiss and tell.
I think you just did.
[Elevator dings]
There's no such thing
as "Just a kiss".
Did you iron your shirt?
Everybody's flash today.
Has she left Mark?
Is she going to?
I think I can hear
cancer kids calling.
Are you planning on
asking her to leave Mark?
Not sure.
- Cameron keeps my calendar.
- Hey.
This is a big deal.
This is an affair.
Have you even talked to Stacy
about what the hell this means?
*** a lot of time for talking.
- If you know what I mean.
- Great.
Breaking up a marriage.
Fertile ground for high comedy.
We need to talk about this.
Gosh, wish I could.
How did the HIV tests go?
Did you study up?
I rescheduled for this afternoon.
We have a new patient.
34-year-old female.
Movement disorder.
Movement disorder?
Fascinating.
[Gives a deep sigh]
This isn't just gonna go away.
No. But maybe you will.
Probably suffered head trauma
in the car accident.
Trauma leads to the dyskinesia.
According to her husband,
the flailing started before
she got anywhere near that car.
What does the flailing look like?
Arm spasms, uncontrollable way
and there's a mild facial twitch.
Demonstration?
You want to know what it looks like, go see the patient.
Oh... Snarky.
Was he like this
the whole time I was gone?
Patient's been a fertility regiment
for the last 13 months.
Cameron:
Excess estrogen in her system
could explain--
We finish the animal crackers?
Sudden movement disorder could be
a symptomom of Huntinton's.
If you finish something,
don't just put back the empty box,
throw it out.
Huntington's takes a day to confirm.
We should put her on Tamoxifen
in case it is the fertility meds.
- Counteract the estrogen.
- It's a great idea
if you want to kill her baby.
Movement disorder can present
in the first trimester.
She's not pregnant.
Peeing on a stick is
only 99% accurate.
Get a real pregnancy test.
You know, the one with
the blood hormones and the rabbit.
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's still your limo.
What do you say, Miss Daisy?
Whatever you want.
- Lame duck's done quacking.
- You quack, people shoot you.
Cuddy just put me here
to make you miserable.
Another two days,
you can go back to
making yourself miserable.
Okay. Get an MRI.
See  if it's in her head
or in her uterus.
You're gonna want to paralyze her.
You run tests on a flailer,
somebody's gonna lose an eye.
Ow. Sorry.
You think I'm pregnant?
We need to find out for sure.
Would all this go away
once she delivered?
It could also be neurological.
We need to get an MRI.
Can she do that
if she's pregnant?
The risk to the fetus
is extremely low.
But there is a risk?
I-I don't think we should do it
until we're sure.
Ah.
Ted, I think you should
take Stella home.
I  want to stay here.
We should be with you.
You should take her
out of the room.
We're going to temporarily
stop Margo's spasms.
- You can do that?
- Vecuronium.
It's a paralytic.
Essentially cuts off the brain
from the muscles.
Don't worry.
Your mom'll be just fine.
It'll make running the tests easier.
And it won't be dangerous for the baby
if you are pregnant.
Let's go, Stella.
- I wanna go with Mommy.
- We'll be just outside. Okay?
We gotta let the doctors
get her that. Alright?
It's okay, sweetie.
- Love you.
Your vitals will be watched closely.
I'm going to close your lids
so your eyes will dry on***.
Just try to relax.
What the hell did you do?
Were you just
cold and lonely?
[Sighs]
Of course he told you,
he's a 8 year old boy.
Hey, you're the one
who kissed him.
Why are you so
worked up over this?
- Because you're married.
- Not to you.
This is none of your business.
The last time you left,
I was the one stuck
picking up the pieces.
Oh, right. He cried himself
to sleep every night.
That so sounds like him.
He's been pining for five years!
- You're being dramatic.
- No. Actually, I'm underplaying.
- This is me being restrained.
- It was one kiss.
Are you being
intentionally thick?
This was not just
a one-night stand.
- You can't toy with him.
- I'm not.
He's probably toying with me.
I do--
I don't know what I'm doing.
Oh, boy.
Welcom back to the world.
You're off the vecuronium.
Could you wiggle your toes for me?
The MRI was clear.
Whatever this is isn't in your brain.
MRI. So I'm not pregnant?
I'm sorry.
So what do we do next?
It could be a variety of things.
Some treatable.
Others more serious.
Open up.
We're gonna run a genetic test
for Huntington's.
That one of more serious ones?
Yeah.
It's also possible that this is just
a symptom of the fertility treatments.
Now that we know you're not pregnant,
we're gonna start you on Tamoxifen
to counteract the estrogen.
Will that undo
all the fertility treatments?
For the time being, yeah.
But it could cure you.
You can start trying again
once we get you healthy.
Damn  it!
The spasms are going to get worse,
now the vecuronium's wearing off.
What are you so scared of?
I'm still your mother.
I'm just a litte sick.
Why did you even bring her here?
I told you to leave her at home.
Foreman:
Hypervigilance, sudden irritability...
Symptomatic of...
lunch with Cuddy?
The patient now defines Huntington's.
Then what do you need me for?
Start her on Huntington's meds.
Before we get her test results back?
If we start her *****
it could destroy her liver.
Could stroke.
If we wait she could progress
full blown psychosis.
Then her kid will never get
the chance to say good-bye.
Want to tell her the class of that feels?
Huntington's patients don't
progress to psychosis in a day.
Shcwen from 0 to 600
in world-record time.
[Beeper goes off]
Indicating it might be something
other than Huntington's.
We got a problem.
Stay away from me.
- Where's my daughter?
- What's happening?
- She's having a psychotic beak.
- No!
She is not yours.
What do you want with her?
Calm down.
- Margo, you're gonna hurt someone.
- No!
- Push two milligrams of Ativan!
- I want my daughter!
She's not yours.
I want my daughter.
No more experiments.
No!
How can her Huntington's test
be negative?
All the signs are there.
Movement disorder, psychosis.
It should be Huntington's.
Yeah. That'd certainly
make your job easier.
Well, good news for Margo,
it's not Huntington's.
Bad news for us.
Her psychotic break
eliminates fertility meds.
Which means we have no idea what's wrong with her.
We give you so much.
You give us so little.
You know, patient is prime age
to develop spontaneous schizophrenia.
Almost impossible.
No family history of mental illness.
Chase:
How about toxins?
None of her family members are sick.
Nobody at her office,
her volunteer group, kid's classes,
and PTA members. All fine.
So she raises a daughter,
runs a business,
she does charity work.
She volunteers at school.
Attends PTA.
- What makes mommy run?
- You thinking drugs?
Cocaine.
Explains the psychosis and the flailing.
And the uncanny ability to bring home the bacon, fry it up in a pan, and never ever let Teddy forget that he's a man.
I'll go look for her stash.
Take Foreman.
There's gotta be a reason
for the stereotype.
I know you're in there.
I can hear you caring.
The door was locked.
Means I didn't want to see anyone.
High school reunion?
It's for a patient.
She can't roll.
Now lock that door too.
Paranoia.
Must be the good stuff.
Times like these,
I wish I had cancer.
So what did she say?
That depends.
What did you do, and
who are we talking about?
We both know that
as soon as we talked, you ran to Stacy
so you could gossip and giggle.
I need to know what she said.
I have a crazy idea.
Why don't you go talk to her?
Because  my bestest buddy says
that could lead to trouble.
She sounds confused,
but I don't think she is.
I think she's waiting
for you to do something.
Show her you're serious.
Wow.
It's a big jump from infidelity
is morally wrong to do her.
I didn't say do her.
I said do something.
What exactly did she say?
She  didn't say it was a mistake.
She's not gonna leave Mark in the middle of his rehab.
Too much guilt.
She left you.
Harsh toke, dude.
House.
Killjoy.
I could've covered this.
You need to get that test today.
I wish you guys remember
my birthday instead of my HIV test.
Forgive us for being concerned.
I got a bet with House.
He says you're too scared to get it.
I say you're too anal not to.
I'll cut you in.
Cameron:
That was a colossal waste.
Foreman:
Who would've known?
Searching a high end family home
for illicit narcotics was
such an obvious choice.
Working moms practically
live in their cars.
- Little bump on the run?
- You were a car thief, right?
Ha.
Mama's little helper.
House. Ritalin.
- Cocaine with a PG rating.
- Prescribed to her daughter.
Mommy does everything
for her family these days.
Even swallows their pills.
It's possible
the kid's meds are the kid's meds.
Pop enough Ritalin,
it can explain everything.
Well, Ritalin maybe explains
some tics, some involuntary--
Case reports have referred to chorea.
She's been cut off from her stash,
so the flailing's tapered off and
the psychosis hasn't returned.
- It's perfect.
- Tox screen will confirm that.
Half-life's 12 hours.
The drugs'll be out of her system.
- We're done. Get rid of her.
- We're not done.
We have to confirm the diagnosis
before we send her home
to die of something else.
Oh yes, the power tastes so sweet.
You just can't resist.
You're like a diabetic
at the ice cream counter.
You want to say no,
but you need that
chocolaty goodness.
Yeah. Well, I'm still
signing the charts.
So until tomorrow,
you're not allowed to kill anyone.
Wuss.
We've asked her three times
if she's on any meds.
So we don't ask her.
Candy striper.
[Hooks chair, pulls to himself]
So you like dogs?
That's not a dog.
Smart kid.
Are you always such a good little girl,
or does mommy sometimes say
you're the reason
she needs a double martini?
Who are you?
Over here, kiddo.
I'm talking to you. Focus.
It must be because
you're off your meds.
- Who are you?
- Doctor and candy striper.
She's not on any medication.
Well, that's strange
'cause this bottle has her name on it.
And I think these are
medical pills inside.
What's he talking about?
Doctor prescribed Stella...
a few months ago.
I never told you about it
because I never gave her any.
Hmm. That's funny
'cause the bottle's almost empty.
You missed a couple of days.
- Take five.
- Stop.
Why?
Unless they're not hers.
- Do you need some water, sweetie?
- I'm not taking Ritalalin.
Come on.
All the cool moms are doing it.
And tox screen says you're cool too.
You were on drugs
while taking care of Stella?
I'm sorry, Ted.
It's a cafeteria menu.
It should take
a couple of hours to process her.
Then you can take her home
and divorce her.
Working late?
Or you just avoiding Mark?
It was one kiss, Greg.
So far.
I'm planning on keeping a chart.
I'm moving back to Short Hills.
I think it's time.
You're leaving?
It's never meant to be permanent
now that Mark's getting better.
Yeah. Much better.
Except for the whole walking thing.
He needs to get back to work.
Right.
Saving the next generation
from making bad choices
about acne cream.
You're running away because
the kiss meant something.
I'm not running away.
I'm going home.
With Mark.
I love Mark.
You love me more.
I don't want you to leave.
Are we okay?
I'm sorry.
Let's just get you home.
That's a good idea.
- Mommy!
- Hey!
Call the code.
- What's wrong, Mommy?
- What's going on?
[Phone ringing]
This better be important.
You've gotta come back in.
- No, I don't.
- Margo's stable, but--
Oh, my God.
Well, I'll be right there.
She had a stroke.
Perfect.
Gotta go back to work.
Right now?
Well, patient's stable.
Could maybe wait a half hour.
He should've been here 20 minutes ago.
Doubt if he makes it all.
I saw him leave with Stacy.
He's probably just
walking her to her car.
Oh, yeah.
That sounds like House.
He's not an idiot.
He's not going to hook up
with a married woman.
I hope he is getting some.
Maybe he'll mellow out.
# Overhead, the moon is beaming,
White as blossoms on the bough. #
What took you so long?
It's midnight.
Traffic.
Cinco de Mayo.
You owe me 100 bucks.
You didn't take the test?
Fear trumps anal every time.
It's not a big deal.
I had the viral load and antibody tests.
99.9% that I don't have HIV.
And if you had the test
and it's negative,
you gain a tenth of a point.
But if it's positive,
you lose...nearly 100, right?
No arrhythmia.
So Ritalin isn't the big problem.
Something else is going on.
Fine.
Let's play doctors.
I removed the clot
which caused the stroke.
Problem is, we don't know
where it came from.
Did ultrasounds of her heart,
arms, and legs. All clear.
Could be a protein C deficiency.
Wouldn't explain
the movement disorder.
Nothing  explains everything.
What if it's a crime syndicate?
Let's say Ritalin and the
fertility meds plotted a caper.
Ritalin takes care of
the psychosis, the flailing.
I still don't think Ritalin--
Fertility meds are competitive by nature.
They gotta do something bigger.
Something really unexpected.
Fertility treatments have been known
to cause endometrial cancer.
Which could cause clots.
Which could've caused her to stroke.
So ultrasound her uterus this time.
See if there's something
growing in there at
doesn't look adorable a onesie.
Cameron.
I love you.
Get your test results tomorrow.
The prescription
for my heart condition.
A bit on the cheesy side.
I was trying for romantic.
- Still fits.
- Hmm.
Did you tell Mark?
I told him I had to work late.
You going to tell him?
How am I going to tell him?
Still working on that phrasing.
How about,
"know all the stuff you worried about
when we first came here,
honey, you were right."
Pithy.
Everything's easy
when you don't care
if you hurt anyone.
You already did the hurting part.
- He just doesn't know yet.
- If I never tell him, it'll never hurt.
I want not to love Mark.
I want to hate you.
I want all of this to be simple,
but it's not.
You can either have a life with me,
or you can have a life with him.
It can't be both.
It's not easy.
But it is simple.
[Elevator dings]
No endometrial thickening.
No masses.
No cancer.
She's on fertility treatments.
She had a blood clot. It's there.
Millions of women are
on fertility treatments,
and they don't get cancer.
Right.
They get babies.
She had a blood clot
and a stroke.
She'll get another one
and probably die
if we don't find that tumor.
Do an endometrial biopsy.
Biopsy's painful and unnecessary.
We just did an ultrasound.
- What?
- Ssh.
If you have a person issue that's interfering with--
Ssh, ssh, ssh.
What are we waiting for?
Your four weeks just expired.
Your reign of terror is over.
Mine is just begun.
No go stick a needle up
her hoo-hoo and find that cancer.
Hoo-hoo?
He went to Hopkins.
[On TV]
...has got 1,500 horsepower blown
and injected with alcohol.
- Yeah, that baby really moves.
- Oh yeah, the transmission...
What are you watching?
TV.
What are you doing here?
Ted's with my mom.
He asked the nurse to watch me.
What nurse?
She's not really watching me.
I got that.
Do you still have the balloons?
No.
D'you want play something?
When can mommy come home?
Don't know.
What's wrong with your foot?
- War wound.
- Does it hurt?
Every day.
Is that why you're so sad?
Oh, aren't you adorable.
I'm not sad,
I'm complicated.
Chicks dig that.
One day, you'll understand.
That's what my parents say
when they don't want me
to know something.
They say that a lot?
Only when they're talking
about making babies and stuff.
When you catch them fighting?
They don't fight.
Not ever?
People who love each other don't fight.
Right. [Elevator dings]
Forgot that.
What floor was that nurse on
who was watching you?
Two.
Good talk.
At your age, the type of uterine cancer
that develops is not likely to metastasize.
It's very treatable.
Hold still, Margo.
I'm--I'm feeling a little bit dizzy.
Oh, my God.
[Monitors start beeping]
BP's dropping.
What's going on?
Get him out of here.
- What's going on?
- Nurse: Heart rate's 98 and rising.
We gotta find that bleed.
What'd you do?
Hit an artery?
With what?
I hadn't even started the procedure.
Oh!
I need some advice.
Whatever it is, can it wait?
Yeah.
What was Greg like after I left?
Uh, an egomaniacal
narcissistic pain in the ass.
Same as before you left.
Do you think he's capable of
having a real relationship?
- What happened in Baltimore?
- Nothing.
- Right.
- Maybe something.
Right.
Technically,
most of the something
happened after Baltimore.
Oh God, Stacy.
I don't know what to do.
Are you seriously thinking
about leaving Mark?
No. I don't know.
I can't.
And you want me
to tell you it's okay?
It wasn't all bad with Greg.
I was with him for a reason.
You left him for a reason.
I could swear
I remember him being fun.
Sorry for the scare.
Just tell me she's okay.
Ultrasound showed the bleed
was coming from her liver.
It's rare, but the blood got
into her Fallopian tubes.
In a way, it was lucky.
Let us know we were
looking in the wrong place.
The tumor's in her liver.
Is it cancer?
We're running some more tests.
There it is.
It's a liver tumor.
If it's malignant,
at least she's only gonna
leave one child without a mother.
Do a biopsy.
We can't.
It's vascular.
House.
What?
I'm here about Stacy.
What about her?
I think I'm losing her.
Your wife, your problem.
She won't talk to me.
So what, you're gonna
talk to me instead?
Talk to your shrink.
She keeps saying
everything's fine.
Find a bar and
talk to a stranger.
You're the only one
who's been through this.
I'm shutting her out.
I'm saying things and then
hating myself for saying them.
- How did you get past that?
- Didn't.
Can you please be a human being
for one minute and talk to me?
Sorry. Gotta go.
People dying.
You're not gonna outrun me.
House.
You're not ready for this.
I've seen the way
you and Stacy talk to each other.
You're an idiot.
You probably just
set your rehab back three months.
Let go of me!
Get off of me!
Liver tumor doesn't make sense.
Are you saying
the CT was wrong?
I'm saying
the symptoms don't add up.
"A" plus "B" does not
equal liver tumor.
We gotta solve for X.
We gotta look at this differently.
What do we know about her?
Side effects of Ritalin
caused the--
No. We've examined
the file up and down.
Come here.
Give me that.
Why do you people always
overlook the human element?
What do we know about her?
Margo...
Dalton.
The woman.
She's a people pleaser.
She doesn't like to let people down.
Who never fights
with her husband.
She went to drugs instead of
asking for help to manage her life.
So if she can't manage now,
why does she want another kid?
Foreman.
Need your help here.
You want to pull a bank job.
Would you go it alone?
If you're gonna rob a home, sure.
It's a one or two man crew.
But a bank...
Lookout, getaway driver.
I'm not saying anything
until the metaphor plays itself out.
So here's the caper.
Fertility meds
create a distraction.
Mommy had
three refills on the Ritalin
in the last three weeks.
That team goes straight
for the top floor.
Has no problem
taking out communications.
But they also
need  a specialist.
Safe cracker.
All this guy does is stroke,
blood clot, liver tumor.
Foreman was right.
This bad ass even does flailing.
Come on.
Only one guy I know
does that kind of work.
Birth control pills?
[Bam!]
While the surgeons are
cutting out a chunk of your liver,
should I have them
do a hysterectomy too?
A hysterectomy?
I'm trying to get pregnant.
You don't have to lie to me.
We're not married.
You're super mom.
You can do anything.
You work seven days a week.
You volunteer.
Raise a kid.
Yet you still somehow find the time
to lie to hubby number two that
you really really want to give him a child
with his chin and pretty brown eyes.
- What makes you think that I--
- Because it fits.
Birth control pills caused
hepatocellular adenoma.
Explains all your symptoms that
aren't explained by your other lies.
That's it?
Also.
I'll have the tuna on rye.
Would you like to
leave my room now?
Tumor is benign.
Stop taking the pill,
and it'll go away on its own.
I'm canceling the surgery.
What are you going to
tell my husband?
That I'm canceling the surgery.
You can do the explaining.
It's tricky, huh?
It's one thing to say
you can't have a baby.
It's another to say
you don't want one.
Personally, I'd make up
some other lie.
Could--
Could I die on the table?
Could you die
if you tell him the truth?
I need the surgery.
I'm not on the pill.
You can't cancel the surgery.
If she goes off the pill,
the tumor goes away on its own.
You have no proof
the birth control pills caused this.
she's even taking them.
Well, if we do the survey,
maybe we'll kill her on the table.
Then I can prove
I'm right at the autopsy.
Or we can forget the surgery,
let the tumor grow, and kill her.
Why don't you
take it up with Stacy?
See which option
minimizes your risk.
Here's what I think
she's going to say.
Oh, I love Greg.
But if you go
against a patient's wishes,
you're calling her a liar.
And if something goes wrong,
I end up in court having to
defend the big, mean doctor
albeit with dreamy eyes
who wouldn't believe
the nice suburban mom.
And even though
his cane makes me melt,
do the damn surgery.
Shocking.
It's benign.
People do crazy things for love.
No. Crazy is
hanging out at the park
all day talking to pigeons.
Margo knows what she's doing.
She gave up half her liver
to save her marriage.
No. She surgically removed her fingerprints to cover her pathetic lie.
It's twisted and manipulative,
I get that. But it's also...
romantic.
I'm barely willing to
put the seat down after I pee.
- Do we need to talk?
- Nope. I'm fine.
So the surgeon got
the whole tumor.
And it was benign.
- That's good, right?
- Yeah. Benign is good.
How could a benign tumor
have caused all the symptoms?
We believe
all your wife's symptoms
will go away now.
Oh. Thank God.
Look. I'm gonna pick up Stella.
I'll call you after
I get the baby-sitter.
Dr. Foreman,
you can help me.
You could tell my husband that...
because of all this...
I can't take any more
fertility treatments.
Confidentiality rules
stop me from telling
your husband the truth.
But my obligation to lie
ends there.
Are--are there--
is there a birth control method,
something that won't make me sick?
Margo, you're gonna have
risks with everything.
Especially if you're not
telling your fertility doctor.
If you keep doing this,
it's gonna kill your marriage
and kill you.
You don't know.
In a few years, we'll give up, stop trying to get pregnant.
We'll hug, cry.
Eventually, Ted will stop
thinking about it.
And he'll appreciate
Stella even more.
And we'll live happily together
for the next 50 years.
Something you need to see.
Knowing is always
better than not knowing.
It's a referral request.
Right.
HIV thing came in earlier.
You're fine.
You won't read your mail,
but you'll open mine?
It said confidential.
I wanted to know.
The most important letter of my life.
And you're still an ass.
Comforting, isn't it?
Hey.
Hi.
I'm going to
talk to Mark tonight.
Then I'm going to
stay here with you.
Don't do it.
This isn't funny, Greg.
I know.
You...
spent all these months
chasing me.
Now I'm here and
you start running.
What the hell changed?
Nothing.
Nothing changes.
- I'm not going to change.
- Who asked you to?
Mark is willing to
do whatever it takes.
I'm not.
Never was.
Now you're introspective?
Weren't so analytical
the other night.
You were happy with Mark.
You'll be happy again.
Shut up about Mark.
What the hell's wrong with you?
I can't make you happy.
What?
How do you think
this is gonna end?
We'll be happy for what?
A few weeks, few months.
And then I'll say
something insensitive,
or I'll start ignoring you.
And at first it'll be okay.
It's just House being House.
And then at some point,
you will need something more.
You'll need someone who
can give you something I can't.
You know I'm right.
I've been there before.
Oh.
It doesn't have to be.
It does.
I don't want to go there again.
I'm sorry, Stacy.
50 bucks says
they're divorced in a year.
Six months tops.
I'll take that bet.
It's the perfect marriage.
There nothing to fight over
if you never talk about anything.
What did you tell her?
I told her she's
better off without me.
Huh.
That's probably true.
You're an idiot.
You don't think she'd be
better off without you.
- Right. I set her off on a whim.
- You have no idea why you sent her off.
- Don't do this.
- This was no great sacrifice.
You sent her away because
you've got to be miserable.
That kind of psycho-crap help
get your patients
through the long nights?
Or is it just for you?
Tough love make you feel good?
Helping people feel their pain.
You don't like yourself.
But you do admire yourself.
It's all you've got,
so you cling to it.
You're so afraid if you change,
you'll lose what makes you special.
Being miserable doesn't make you
better than everybody else, House.
It just makes you miserable.
Transcript : Raceman
Synchro : Vaccine
www.forom.com