I'm okay, let's just go home.
You're getting checked out.
I tripped on the ice. Eight other
kids tripped. This is embarrassing.
You said you were just
gonna hang with your friends.
I turn around and you're
out there on the ice.
- I'm fine.
- You don't know that.
You fell. Awkwardly.
No, I didn't.
You don't know how to fall.
I'm 16, I've been falling a lot.
I think I'm getting the hang of it.
And I checked.
And now the doctors are gonna check.
You don't think that
you're overreacting?
I don't need you to fix every boo-boo.
Then stop getting them.
I was just playing around
with my friends. I was having fun.
You know you can't do that.
- Oh, I can't have fun?
- You know what I mean.
I'm gonna have a talk with your friends
- No!
- they need to stop--
No. I don't want you freaking them out.
Fine. I'll go to the hospital, but
they're gonna tell you that I'm fine.
And they're gonna tell you
that you don't need to worry about...
Mom!
Mom?
Hello!
Mom, you gotta wake up.
No one's coming.
911, what is your emergency?
We got into an accident along
the canal road just outside Kingston.
My mom's unconscious.
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
Transcript: FRM - Sync: jh26
www.sub-way.fr
- Where's Foreman?
- He's down here somewhere.
Somewhere. Very helpful.
Do you have any idea
when he's getting out tonight?
Sometime.
I realize you can't predict, I just
thought you might be able to estimate.
It's Valentine's Day.
I've planned a surprise getaway.
Getaway.
Get away.
- Is my mom okay?
- She's gone to surgery.
Your girlfriend wants to know
if you're available for Valentine's.
Act surprised.
What are you doing down here?
There's a snowstorm.
E.R.'s short staffed.
We're all supposed to be here.
You're supposed to be here.
And you're an ass. Act surprised.
This could sting a little.
Can we hurry this up?
- Make sure that--
- Take your time.
What's your name?
Hannah Morganthal.
You have CIPA, Hannah Morganthal.
No, I don't.
We have to do x-rays to make
sure you don't have internal injuries.
Blood tests to make sure no infections.
EEG for neurological anomalies. And...
biopsy a spinal nerve.
Congenital insensitivity to pain is one
of the rarest conditions on the planet.
There's only been about...
60 documented cases...
Yeah, and I have seven reasons
to think she's one of them.
- She says she's not.
- That's reason number one.
She knew what it was
without us telling her.
Two, she's still wet from the snow,
but she's not shivering. That's odd.
Unless she can't sweat
or feel hot and cold.
The ambulance was warm.
I want to see my mother.
Three, scarring around
the lips and tongue.
When she was a baby, she chewed
on herself without feeling it.
I fell through a
window when I was a kid.
Four, when you cleaned the wound,
she flexed into the cleaner
instead of away from it.
It's hard to fake pain
when you've never felt it.
Takes an imaginative leap, Ms.
Morganthal.
That's one of them Jew names.
Ashkenazis are a higher risk group.
One the other hand,
she says she doesn't have it.
And she'd be dead by now
if she'd never been diagnosed.
They killed our Lord.
You gonna trust them?
She wants to see her mom.
If she admits having CIPA,
she knows we're not letting her
go anywhere without a battery of tests.
- You said you had seven reasons.
- I pulled a number out of the air.
- What, five isn't enough?
- Five lame reasons aren't.
I'm taking her to
see her mom as soon as--
I can hit her again if six isn't enough.
Do the tests.
Need to bail on the E.R. I got a case.
Why are you wearing perfume?
Is this a real case or
one of those imaginary cases
that happen when you're bored?
CIPA.
CIPA is a diagnosis.
Diagnoses happen at the end of cases.
She's got no idea what's going on in her
body. There's gotta be something wrong.
In other words,
she could be perfectly healthy,
but you're curious about
someone who can't feel pain
because you always feel pain.
So you wanna go exploring.
She was in a car accident.
She needs x-rays,
blood tests, EEG, nerve biopsy.
I also note that, although snow
was coming down in sheets this morning,
you left your hat at
home and used ear muffs.
Do your tests except for the--
So while everyone else was
just worrying about getting in,
you were concerned with hat-head.
Blind dates are never a good idea.
Only reason to wear a scarf like that is
as a beacon to identify you in a crowd.
Do your tests. Except the nerve biopsy.
- I need the nerve biopsy.
- You'd risk paralyzing her.
- But it's neurological.
- You have no evidence of that.
She tripped.
Do you have any evidence
other than the fact
that a typically clumsy CIPA
patient tripped on an icy day?
If the EEG reveals a problem,
we can talk then.
You could have left the
scarf at home and just told him
you'd be wearing a look of desperation.
Spiking on leads C3 and O2.
She could be going into a seizure.
I think there's a simpler explanation.
You're not gonna find anything.
I'm fine. I wanna see my mom!
- So sedate her.
- She won't consent.
- She's a teenager.
- No dad, mom's still in surgery.
What do you want us to do,
hold her down?
Only until you inject her with
a sedative. Then you can let her go.
We tried.
Seriously?
She's strong and doesn't care.
We'd have broken something
before we could get her
to sit still enough to inject her.
So break her arm. She won't mind.
- You're cranky.
- I'm in pain.
Come on, let's go break her arm.
Nurse Shortie, your biz-nitch.
How long you gonna waste her time?
So glad we're walking somewhere. Another
60 feet and this conversation is over.
When you guys are out of this program,
Cameron will find somebody,
Chase will find eight somebodies,
and you'll be alone.
- 30 feet.
- You'll date and you'll date.
But you're the ultimate Darwinian.
You've got to fight for everything.
Anybody else would just slow you down.
Yeah. I'm still with her, aren't I?
Yeah. I can only imagine it's
because she hasn't given you an excuse
to break up and you don't have
the guts to recognize your own reality.
I wanna see my mother!
Hi again.
Not sure I can say this
without being condescending,
but then you'd get the false impression
that I respect you, so... you're a kid.
You're scared, you're stalling. Grow up.
I'm not scared. I'm never scared.
See? How juvenile was that?
You can't feel pain.
Nothing left but pleasure.
Why don't you tell
me how wonderful that is?
It sucks.
Better than being in pain all the time.
Get in the chair.
Every morning I have
to check my eyes to make sure
I didn't scratch a cornea in my sleep.
Oh, God, stop.
I'm in a pool of tears here.
- I can't cry.
- Neither can I.
Every morning,
I check my eyes for jaundice.
In case the Vicodin's
finally shot my liver.
I can't run anywhere without
examining all my toes for swelling.
I can't run.
Boys can't hold me for
too long because I can overheat.
Girls can't hold me for too
long because I only pay for an hour.
I need an alarm on my watch
to remind me to go to the bathroom.
You know how many humiliating
experiences before I thought of that?
The bathroom's 50 feet from my office.
Every drink of water,
I weigh the pros and cons.
After everything I do, I self-check.
Mouth, tongue, gums, for cuts.
Count teeth, check temperature.
Fingers, toes, and joints for swelling.
- Skin for bruises.
- I got shot.
I sat on the stove when I was three.
Wanna see the coil marks?
- Yeah.
- You think I'm lying?
You think I just wanna check out
your tuchus, as your people would say?
Get in the chair and run the damn tests.
If she moves again, give her nitrous.
You weren't shot because of leg pain,
you were shot because you're a jerk.
- Some think the two are connected.
- He didn't have to do that.
- Yeah, he did.
I'm sick?
No, you EEG was normal.
X-ray showed no breaks.
Blood test showed no infections.
Urine indicated no...
Call a code!
Oh, God.
Need ice packs and cooling blankets.
Got saline in there?
She's not flush, she's not sweating.
You must be--
She has a temperature of 105.
Wow, she's actually sick.
We got her temperature down
below boiling. Could be infection.
No, LP showed normal proteins
and no white blood cells.
High bilirubin.
Could be a liver problem.
Nope, transaminases were normal.
Could be drugs.
She's smoked pot since she was 11.
No again. Tox screen was clean.
We're doing this case backwards.
We do the tests and then she gets sick?
Maybe we did something to her.
Maybe she got sick after the tests.
We should re-run them.
And biopsy a spinal nerve.
You wanna risk paralysis
because she's got a fever?
I want to risk paralysis because
I don't know what's causing the fever.
- If it's neurological--
- It's a fever!
In a CIPA patient.
Obviously, things are a little
different in her upstairs wiring.
And have been since
the day she was born.
It's much more likely that whatever
it is was cleverly waited in hiding
until you guys were done testing.
- Were are you going?
- You're all against this, right?
And you're all gonna stand on
principle and refuse to do it, right?
I'm going to get Cuddy's approval.
How long are we gonna keep
Hannah in the dark about her mother?
As long as possible.
Side airbag should be standard.
I'm sure she'll agree.
She should know her mother's situation.
Breaking that news
is that surgeon's problem.
- Any word from House?
- No.
Maybe Cuddy will say no.
- Cuddy never says no.
- That's not true.
Nobody ever says no.
- We don't say no.
- You don't say no.
He'll come back, he'll browbeat us,
he'll give us seven reasons,
and eventually we'll fold.
We all will, not just me.
The only way we can avoid
biopsying this kid's spine is to find
the answer some other way.
- All the tests were negative.
We need a better history.
How much more paperwork do you need?
We've got pediatric records,
a few dozen E.R. records,
our own admission questionnaire.
- What's the first question?
- Insurance coverage.
- Okay, second question.
- Just make your point.
Where does it hurt?
If we knew where it hurt,
we could diagnose her.
You do know CIPA means
she can't feel pain.
No, CIPA means she's
insensitive to pain.
She still has scattered nerve
fibers that could conduct pain,
but the signals don't
make it to the brain.
What if we give her more pain signals?
A lot more pain signals.
Maybe some of them will make it through.
- You wanna torture her?
- No.
Yes. We do this to anybody else,
it's torture.
Doing it to her is no different
than pricking her finger.
We keep poking sharp sticks into her,
eventually we'll find
the part that's already tender.
So what does a Dean of Medicine do?
Oh, can we please not talk about that?
I will talk about anything else.
I'm just trying to get away from work.
Metaphorically.
Because geographically, the coffee place
around the corner from the hospital
probably isn't the
furthest you could get.
-Well, the snow.
- The roads are clearing.
But it's a good place
to beat a retreat from.
You usually expect
your dates to go wrong?
Experience has taught
me to have an escape route.
Well, low expectations,
that's in my favor.
Whatever happens...
I need you to understand that
there are certain aspects to my life
I'm not happy about.
I need the nerve biopsy.
And you had to come here
personally to tell me that.
- And how did you even know I was here?
- I had to bring the file.
This was the most noncommittal
location in walking distance.
You left your car keys on your desk.
Greg House!
You two must have met online.
Either that or you've got
a friend who secretly hates you.
Don Herrick.
Yeah, we connected through
singleballroomdancelovers.com.
Why would he volunteer that information?
Why would I hide it?
You didn't tell him that anything
he said would be held against you.
- So what line of work are you in?
- Oh, auto maintenance.
Changing oil and filters.
Great, my place overcharges.
Can't trust anything you guys say.
- Where're you located?
- In 14 states.
I own Eastern Lube.
Most CIPA complications are infections
and she's got a fever.
LP? Urine?
Clean, normal.
Same with the white blood cell count.
- Cancer?
- Nothing on the scan.
I think it's her nerves messing
with the temperature control.
Amyloid, sarcoid. There's
a lot of candidates. I want a biopsy.
Fine. If that's what you need,
go get it.
He seems a lot nicer than that one
from Wicca needs a daddy figure dot com.
One of these is warm,
the other is very hot.
Start here, move to the hot one.
Just a few seconds.
Then back.
We're gonna monitor activity
in your brain while you do it.
If you feel any response to the heat,
it could indicate a vascular problem.
How's my mom doing?
She's okay. Do you feel anything?
No.
What does okay mean?
She's still in surgery.
They tell me it's going okay.
You can take your hand out.
And you didn't ask anything else?
Take your hand out of the water.
What's going on with my mother?
You just got second degree burns.
I'll be fine.
What's going on with my mother?
Is she gonna die?
They said she's okay.
Surgery this long is typical
when there are internal injuries.
Naloxone and kinase proteins in.
And that's gonna make me feel pain?
I didn't feel anything when you
guys screwed this thing into my head.
It'll replace missing chemicals
in your nerves. Heighten sensitivity.
We'll be drilling
directly into your skull.
A response should indicate sarcoma.
- What does it feel like?
- It...
hurts.
Sorry.
Bone pain is the worst there is.
So you need to let know
as soon as you feel anything.
She's ready.
So what... I just sit here
while you guys drill a hole in me?
You wanna talk?
Just you and your mom, huh?
You two must be pretty close.
We were. Until I got arrested.
The third time.
- Drugs?
- Fights.
You got an advantage.
Not really. Never know when to stop.
You piss a lot of people off or are
you just trying to piss off your mom?
Those are pretty much
the only two choices you have.
You want us to stop?
Stop the drill. Stop the drill.
It's okay.
What'd you feel?
Where did you feel it?
Hannah, I need to know how it hurt.
I am so tired of this.
Did you know that the new nurse
from cardiology is sleeping with
that weird lawyer from the board?
- The guy with 11 fingers?
He has 11 fingers?
How do you not notice that?
The nurse used to be a man.
- She's not anymore?
- But we can't talk about that.
- I thought we were.
- We were supposed to talk about that.
I came here to talk about that.
But on the way up, I ran into Cameron.
You've got a CIPA patient.
- Tranny nurse is more interesting.
- Oh, it's way more interesting.
But instead,
I've gotta be your damn conscience.
I'm tired of being your conscience.
I don't enjoy it.
- No one enjoys...
- You're studying her.
She's actually sick.
Which you found out
after you took her on.
I was curious. Since I'm not a cat,
that's not dangerous.
I don't think that metaphor
was designed to actually warn cats.
You don't care about her illness,
you care about CIPA.
Which means your focus is gonna
be on getting your answers, not hers.
Thank you. Forewarned is forearmed.
What do you think
you're gonna figure out?
You think her lack of pain
is somehow the answer to your pain.
I think if you'd stop talking
to Cameron, then right now,
we could be ranking nurses
in order of do-ability.
- Need you.
- What did the nerve biopsy show?
- Never did it.
- Then do it.
- Can't.
- Why?
She's gonna jump off the lobby balcony.
You think I can catch her?
- Get away from me!
- I'm not gonna hurt you.
Yes, you are. You're just
jealous that I can do anything.
Hannah, you're having
a paranoid delusion.
- I don't believe you.
- You think she would
This is real. You want me to be in pain.
You even said so.
If we wanted to hurt you,
we'd let you jump.
Just let me see my mother.
Fine, we'll take you to her O.R.
observation room.
I don't believe you!
Your mother is fine.
I just spoke to her surgeon.
I don't believe you!
Hannah, what do you want from us?
What do you want us to do?
I can't feel my legs.
You're trying to pull the
same stunt twice in ten minutes.
I'm not pretending.
They don't hurt, they just aren't there.
Anything?
We're not looking for pain.
Anything at all, pressure?
Nothing.
You have six broken bones, a fever,
a concussion, erratic heart rhythms,
and a complete lack of
sensation below the waist.
I feel fine.
Is my mother out of surgery yet?
Not yet.
This is excellent.
The paranoia seems to have dissipated.
But her vitals keep getting worse.
She could be dead in hours.
But if you're gonna die a miserable,
lingering death,
pain-free is the way to do it.
You sure the fall didn't
cause the paralysis?
The paralysis caused the fall.
Spine's clean. No vertitable
fractures or spinal cord compression.
Even better.
The nuttiness and paralysis mean there's
definitely a neurological component.
Could be a nerve disease.
Which is why we need to look
at the nerve that you didn't biopsy.
- There are other tests...
- HIV? Syphilis?
She was negative for all STD's.
Vascular? No. ANA was negative.
Cerebral clot? No, MRI was...
Thyroid storm.
Makes sense, given her glucose
reaction was slow and potassium's down.
Yeah.
I'll check with an endocrinologist.
- Bennett's on call.
- Perfect.
- No.
- Need a consult.
I already okayed your nerve biopsy.
- Need an endocrinologist.
- Bennett's on call.
Won't pick up.
His cell phone must be broken.
Mine's working.
Had to give you the file.
I assume you're thinking thyroid storm.
Have you done a hormone panel?
Normal. TSH was on the low side.
Is that a cheery fire
I hear crackling nearby?
No.
- What about CPK enzymes?
- Elevated. 275.
People light fires for themselves.
But then they don't deny it.
He's here.
CPK isn't high enough.
Potassium's what you'd expect
because of the bronchodilators.
Oh, my God! You're not wearing a bra.
It's not thyroid storm.
- You just met him.
- I like him.
And I like sex.
Do I need to stitch a letter on my tops?
No. But it might be worth
taking out an ad in the local papers.
Do you like me, House?
I was on the phone with Bennett 15
minutes ago. His cell phone's working.
You're M.O. is to avoid me at all costs.
And suddenly, you need
my input on every move you make.
I can only assume it's
because I'm on a date.
When we met, I noticed--
You noticed he was a Shriner
because the way he parted his hair.
That he was a mama's boy because
of the way he blinked his left eye.
I'm not interested. I'm not impressed.
There are only two reasons anyone
would want to screw with me tonight.
Either they're an altruistic,
decent person
who is worried about my well being.
Or they want me for themselves.
You left out the third option.
Evil bastard who just wants
to mess with other people's happiness.
Good night, House.
We won't be bothered again.
It's late.
- I should go.
- Why?
I part my hair
on the left and I'm a Shriner.
You heard the conversation.
I'm not interested in him.
I don't blame you.
I only said those things
so that he wouldn't come back.
I don't really care about my job.
I do it well, I provide a service.
But my goal
was always to make enough
money to do the things I really like.
- Music, travel...
- I like those things too.
You like them,
but they're not really important to you.
I don't know whether it's House,
your job, or if you just
thrive on conflict, but...
you should hear yourself
when you're talking to him.
Nothing else in the world is going on.
You're focused, confident, compelling.
Don't take this the wrong way, but
I'd like to go out with that woman.
I can get her on the phone.
Where did you go? She's getting worse.
It's not thyroid storm.
Get me spinal nerve.
There are still other tests.
She just said the girl was getting
worse. You're really wanna wait?
We'll be risking infection,
maybe make the paralysis worse.
It is worse. We're making
it worse than worse. Do the biopsy.
We could paralyze her
and get no useful information.
Do the biopsy.
- You're thinking peripheral neuropathy,
we should a take a nerve a
little further away from the spine.
A little further from the truth.
We're talking paralysis.
Good chance the spine is relevant.
And if this thing is progressive,
it'll kill her in hours.
Give me back my papers.
Is he asking for a spinal nerve?
- How did you know?
- Give us a minute.
Did you know they recently found
a protein that speeds up nerve growth?
Fascinating stuff.
If you put that protein
with the insulation from a spinal nerve,
you could grow your own little garden.
- If that spinal nerve...
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
If it happened to come from a person
with CIPA, I could grow pain-free nerves
and graft them into my own leg.
What an evil plan.
You'd have to be on
immunosuppressors for life.
Risking infection, shorter life span...
Shorter. But normal.
Usually jealousy expresses itself
by trying to destroy what someone has.
You're more ambitious.
You actually wanna change
medical fact to get this thing...
- Medical fact changes all the time.
- You're risking your patient's life.
That's how medical fact changes.
A doctor risks--
To serve their patient's health.
Not their own.
- This is medically justified.
- Are you sure?
Are you sure...
that you're the right
one to be making this call?
Biopsy whatever nerve you
figure you can safely get at.
God, Wilson's annoying.
Past 3:00 AM on Valentine's Day night.
I assume you had a date with Wendy.
She'll survive. She knows the deal.
- You're lucky.
- I know.
Someday, when there's time, I would
like to actually have a social life.
Someday?
Come on. If there's one thing a good
looking woman can have when she wants,
it's a social life.
- You mean a sex life.
There's nothing wrong with a little
companionship 'til
the real thing comes along.
I had the real thing.
Forgive me if I don't want to settle.
Right.
What does that mean?
Nothing.
You think I didn't have the real thing?
I have no idea what you had.
And yet you're judging it.
It's late, I'm cranky. Sorry.
You think I didn't have the real thing.
How could you even know?
You married a dying man.
You thought...
six months, a year, it'll be tough.
But then I'll recover and
I'll have the rest of my life.
It's like willingly getting the flu
or joining the Peace Corps. Short term.
Wow, you nailed it.
It's basically like a wasted weekend.
The sacrifices you made were huge.
But they were at the
height of your love for him.
A commitment is only commitment
because it has no expiration date.
You stand next to someone
and watch them floss for 30 years,
like my parents have,
then ask for sacrifices.
That's how you know the real thing.
I wasn't criticizing you.
People who avoid commitment are
people who know what a big thing it is.
This isn't right.
CIPA can't cause this much degeneration.
A few nerve fibers we teased out
of the center have some insulation left.
But the insulation around
the bundles has been stripped bare.
Means the damage must
be coming from the outside in.
Which means it's
secondary demyelination.
Which means the source
is somewhere else.
Which tells us it's not a nerve disease,
it's something systemic
that's affecting the nerves.
Which means that we need to--
Where are you going?
Kid's mom is finally out of surgery.
I'll be right back.
- So what?
- Hannah should see her.
Yes, immediately after we're
done chatting about saving her life.
Most likely causes are metabolic.
They found brain swelling. They're
prepping her mother for another surgery.
Again, so what?
Get a nurse to take the kid.
There are more than 60 different
metabolic conditions that could account
for what she's got.
There's only three of you guys.
- She's scared.
- She should be.
- She'll die if we don't diagnose her.
- So diagnose her.
Mom.
How bad is it?
Are you OK?
I'm okay, Mom.
I'll get better. I always get better.
Are you checking yourself?
Your temperature?
Mom, could you just let it go?
You shouldn't be worrying.
Oh, baby, I'm sorry.
- I should have seen that car coming.
- No.
I did this to myself. I screwed up.
You were right.
You were right and I was wrong.
No.
I... I shouldn't have
gone out on the ice.
I shouldn't have fallen down.
And I shouldn't have made you rush me
to an ER for the tenth time this year.
- Mom?
- You okay?
We gonna have to take
her back to surgery.
Hannah, your BP is way up.
We need to get you some rest.
My hand's wet.
You're crying.
I can't cry.
My head is killing me.
So what does the pain tell us?
No tingling,
no itching, so we can rule out--
It tells us nothing. It wasn't
physical pain, it was emotional.
Exactly.
What were they doing
when she got the headache?
- Saying good-bye.
- You said they were arguing.
They weren't really arguing.
She was just frustrated.
- What were they arguing about?
- Whose fault it was.
Peripheral neuropathy,
fever, and intermittent paranoia.
Lots of metabolic conditions can explain
those things. But what if we add guilt?
Guilt as a symptom?
Alzheimer's can cause euphoria,
pain causes depression,
and B12 deficiency causes guilt.
Along with all that other stuff.
If she felt guilty, she wouldn't
be making her mother's life miserable.
She wouldn't be getting in fights,
getting arrested.
Maybe she's fighting
because she feels guilty.
She's showing her mom she can
take stupid risks and still be safe.
- Means mom can let go.
- Which is rational.
If guilt is a symptom, it's caused by
the illness, not by a thought process.
And it would have to be new.
Two years ago,
she was a model student.
This is pointless.
If the headache was caused by guilt,
she has a B-12 deficiency.
If it's just because she was sad,
it's meaningless.
How the hell do we test for that?
We don't. We give her a shot of B12.
When she gets better, I was right.
We already did.
ER gave her B12 when she was admitted.
Part of a multi-vitamin supplement.
Apparently, she's just sad.
Why are you still here?
Trying to get a couple patients into
a drug trial. Paperwork's due tomorrow.
Why are you here?
Still haven't figured out why...
No, I meant here, in my office.
Just dumped a cool B12 theory.
Moved on to leukemia.
Very pedestrian.
I'm not happy.
Her white blood cell count was low.
But the one she's got...
A whole lot of eosinophils.
The immunoglobin E level's borderline.
If you wanna be 100% sure,
check the bone marrow.
Team's doing a biopsy right now.
So it turns out...
the weird lawyer knew
that she used to be a man.
And he's cool with that?
Turns out that his previous
girlfriend also used to be a man.
Yeah.
Is it possible for
you to just watch me eat?
Or do you get some
primeval thrill out of
beating the other hunters to the food?
See ya later.
You still haven't figured
out that I don't need sedation?
It's so you don't move
during the procedure.
Is that nitrous?
You trying to kill her?
You gave her nitrous during the EEG.
That's what made this
thing rear its ugly head.
- What thing?
- B12 deficiency.
Are you having deja vu? We've had
this conversation. She was given B12.
- She didn't get better.
- Because someone else ate it.
- Get an abdominal MRI.
- What?
What are you doing?
Don't touch me!
See, there she goes.
Another paranoid delusion.
At the rate she's going downhill,
forget the MRI, we need an O.R.
Leave me alone!
- Occupied!
- Her hernia can wait.
Help! They're trying to kill me!
Okay, you can either believe
that we really are trying to kill her...
Or you can assume that she's
suffering from a medical condition.
Seeing as this is a hospital
and we're all dressed like doctors,
and there are easier
ways to kill somebody...
Bev, help them.
I'm gonna need iodine,
scalpels number 10 and 15, forceps,
and a largish salad bowl.
Okay, hold her down.
Come on, weenies, she's in a cast.
Swab.
15.
You're not gonna anesthetize her?
Relax, it's just a magic trick.
She's faking it.
We're not falling for it this time.
Okay, keep that retracted.
Forceps.
Lake fishing can be fun.
It can bring the generations together.
But if you don't cook
that trout or perch well,
you'll be giving room
and board to this fella.
And by free board,
I mean all the B12 you can take in.
I could have a * in me?
Not likely. You'd be in a lot of pain.
- It's gotta be 25 feet long.
- Dammit.
World record's over 60.
Wake up.
Somebody here to see you.
She's got limited
motion on her left side.
You might have to take
care of her for a while.
You don't feel it, but you're
about to rip your stitches out.
Take care of yourself.
Then you can take care of her.
You haven't gone home.
Sorry I screwed up Valentine's Day.
I'm dating a doctor.
I'd be an idiot to expect anything else.
I did get you a gift.
MGH.
Best teaching hospital in Boston.
You wanna be a nurse practitioner,
that's as good as it gets.
I made a few calls.
You're in if you want it.
This is why you've been helping me
get my surgical hours for accreditation?
- I thought you wanted--
- Stupid.
You've got ten feet of
personal space around you.
I step forward, you step back.
I've shared a lot of things with you.
Which is why you're breaking up with me.
You can't stand to be close.
You think I'll stay with
you because you're angry with me?
I'm upset.
Because I care.
Only you'd expect an
argument to be rational.
You and that ass boss of yours.
You could ask her for the spinal nerve.
She's got no reason to give it.
She owes you.
The hospital will send her a bill.
I'm just saying.
If you wanna do it,
do it while her B12 is still low.
Guilt can be your friend.
Breakfast?
Happy Valentine's Day.
A holiday that only applies
to people who are already paired up.
For everyone else, it's Wednesday.
Thank you for that dash of cold water.
Don't get me wrong,
I still think true love's out there,
it's just very far away.
Possibly in another galaxy.
We may need to develop faster than
light travel before we can make contact.
So I'm thinking we should have sex.
That makes sense.
Despite the wisdom of pop songs, there's
no point in putting our lives on hold
'til love comes along.
We're both healthy and busy people.
We work together, so it's convenient.
Like microwave pizza?
And of all the people I work with,
you're the one I'm least
likely to fall in love with.
Like microwave pizza.
The point here is to make
things simpler, not more complicated.
Someday, there'll be time
to get serious about someone.
Meanwhile, we already had sex
once and didn't get weird about it.
I get it. I get it.
So what if I'm offended
by your judgment?
Then you're not the man I'm looking for.
Transcript: FRM - Sync: jh26
www.sub-way.fr