Hajime.
Matte.
She almost took my head off!
Your fault.
You didn't guard your left side.
Hajime!
Matte!
Point.
Hajime!
Matte, matte, matte!
Stop, stop, stop!
Addie...
you're bleeding.
I never even hit her.
Transcript: swsub.com
Sync: jh26
Good morning.
This is funny.
- "People don't... "
- Not done reading. Go away.
Most likely she coughed it up,
which would mean it's from her lungs.
Drugs, toxins, infection?
No fever, no elevated white count,
which rules out infection.
And the blood panels found no drugs,
no toxins.
The bronchoscopy was pristine.
So much for the lungs.
- Good morning.
- Not yet.
So then the blood came from her stomach,
which would mean it's
an ulcer or a GI bleed.
ER also ran an upper and lower GI.
No occult blood in her stool.
Which means no ulcer or GI bleed.
Which means it's not
from the stomach either,
which means it didn't
come from anywhere.
You guys get to the point where
the blood didn't come from anywhere?
Rupture in her sinus cavity?
Drip through the back?
Not that much blood.
Trauma from karate?
No trauma. Kicked the other guy's ass.
Now a good time?
If you can tell me how
blood can mysteriously appear...
Now.
This includes you.
What's going on?
Feel free to speculate
amongst yourselves.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
- Why?
- He's afraid of turning into me.
Well, that's a good enough reason.
Sign here.
That's not promising.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
That's it? You're not gonna
tell him that we're a family,
and families don't abandon each other?
- You want me to?
- No.
- Would it make any difference?
Good luck, Dr. Foreman.
- So, where were we?
- College sophomore coughing up blood.
Not the case, the speculation. The
palace intrigue, the rising self-doubts.
- Did Foreman get a promotion?
- I resigned.
What?
Personally, I can't believe I've had the
same three employees for three years.
The patient could have a heart problem.
Yes, life goes on.
Look at the eager
beaver combing his hair.
Hyperdynamic heart could
force too much blood into her lungs.
She coughed up the overflow.
It wouldn't leave a trace in her lungs
because it's traveling
through normal plumbing.
Foreman, go do a stress
echo test to see if he's right.
Cameron, check out the dorm,
and redo the ER labs.
I'll get going on
Foreman's farewell party.
Everybody good with a
mermaid under the stars theme?
So why are you leaving?
Or is it just some sort of power play?
You can have my parking
space and my locker.
Is it about House?
Let me get all sensitive
and confide in you.
Addie, pedal harder.
We need your heart rate at 170.
Why wouldn't you want to tell me?
I don't like you.
Never have, never will.
You want me to share some more?
Even if you do hate me,
if you found another job, you'd tell me.
If House did something to
drive you out of here, you'd tell me.
The fact that you won't tell me means
that whatever the real reason is...
you're ashamed of it.
Guys...
I'm at 170.
Pulmonary artery looks good.
It's not a heart problem.
- Are you cold?
- No.
- Scared?
- I'm okay. Why?
On your arm.
Addie has goose bumps.
No recovering from those babies.
You don't have goose
bumps for no reason.
They're a reaction to
the body thinking it's cold.
She wasn't cold.
Her temperature was normal.
But her body thought it was,
which means...
What, a brain problem?
A messed-up hypothalamus
could cause goose bumps,
but they're not gonna
cause her to cough up blood.
She has no neurological issues.
She had a shiver.
I think there's an infection.
We've ruled out infection
because no fever, no white count.
I think there's an infection.
Blood goes where it's needed.
An infection likes nice wet places...
her lungs.
Start treatment.
All that cool stuff for bacterial,
fungal, and atypical infections.
Get a lung biopsy.
I want to see the
little bugger up close.
- Why is Foreman quitting?
- He wants to breed llamas.
Interesting.
You're ashamed of the reason too.
No one writes tamoxifen like you.
Well, I use a G.
Foreman resigned.
I'm sorry.
It's okay, no biggie.
Right.
He give a reason?
He said he didn't
want to end up like me.
I had a brilliant retort.
I can't remember what
it was at the moment.
You don't want to end up like you.
Good point. Can I resign?
What's up with that?
With what?
You yawned.
I just told you something interesting,
so you're not bored.
It's 11:00 in the morning, you're
drinking coffee, so you're not tired.
I didn't yawn,
so it's not a mirror-neuron reaction...
which leaves symptom.
Vasovagal issue. Maybe a heart problem.
My heart's fine. I was up late.
You're just deflecting having
a conversation about Foreman.
I'm okay with Foreman leaving.
Either you're lying,
or you don't really think he's leaving.
Or you just jumped right to acceptance.
Sorry, I yawned because I
was trying to communicate boredom.
You could try bargaining with him...
give him a raise.
How much do you think it would
cost to make him want to be like me?
Thanks for the coffee.
She seems fine.
She is fine.
- She coughed up blood.
- Past tense.
She has diarrhea.
From the antibiotics for the infection.
Lung biopsy says she
doesn't have an infection.
Well, then you screwed up the biopsy.
Or you're wrong about infection.
If I'm wrong, then so is her body,
'cause it obviously thinks
she's got an infection,
or it wouldn't have gotten
better from the antibiotics.
What is pandiculation symptomatic of?
Yawning's a symptom of fatigue
or cholinergic excitation.
Does this have anything
to do with Addie?
Let's say yes.
Cerebral tumor, epilepsy.
Could also be a medication
reaction to antidepressants,
or some meds for
end-stage liver failure.
Let's say no.
You don't want to leave this job.
Three years you've been here,
you've never once laughed
at anything he's said.
Because I wasn't kissing his ass.
But now you are? No.
Now you're nervous.
Uncomfortable about your decision.
- It wasn't even that good a joke.
- Oh, crap.
Most of your jokes are excellent.
I just meant in comparison.
Shut up.
I think she may not have an infection.
We better deal with
her before she crashes.
- She can't breathe!
- Get off the bed.
We need a crash cart.
- What's happening?!
- Let's get her down now.
The pressure's collapsing her lungs.
She's not getting any air.
Oh, my God!
She couldn't breathe because
she had a pleural effusion.
Thoracentesis revealed
low protein count.
Effusion was transudative, which
means she has cirrhosis of the liver,
or she's in heart failure.
Heart was fine,
liver enzymes were normal.
There's something called
"blude" in the pleural effusion.
Oh, it's not "blude," it's blood.
Ha... which is great.
Not for her, but for me.
Because it means I
think it's an infection.
The labs indicated
minute traces of blood.
You can't ignore the blood because
it's a minority, can you, Foreman?
If we count the traces
of blood as significant,
the differential isn't just infection.
It could be lung cancer,
breast cancer, lymphoma.
Great, go tell her
she's got one of those.
Or you can tell her that
we haven't given her enough
antibiotics for her infection.
Double the dose, and check her lungs.
We checked her lungs, they're clean.
On the outside.
She needs an arteriogram.
It's about my bowel movements.
What isn't these days?
- You sure you want to be here for this?
- We do everything together.
Of course.
The toilet can be a lonely place.
Drop your pants, I'll suit up.
They float.
My bowel movements.
Honey says they're not supposed to.
I'm a nutritionist.
Yes, I could tell from
the cool toe-loop sandals.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
And the natural-fiber clothing,
I assume,
means some kind of
vegetarian denomination?
We're vegans. At first I was a little
concerned about the lack of protein,
but Honey showed me
you can get it from lots...
Well, whatever floats your poop.
And you've been together how long?
Six months?
How'd you know?
Because after six months,
poop love fades.
And if you'd been together
shorter than that, then...
I'll explain right after this break.
Three ten-milligram pills
of your finest amphetamines.
Arteriogram was normal.
Which means her lungs are fine.
What if the clear
arteriogram is significant?
It is significant.
It means there's no infection.
- I think there's an infection.
- Infections don't come and go.
People don't get better
then worse in the same treatment.
Unless your body can't
finish out the fight.
Maybe goes a couple of rounds,
then gives up.
- Why would it give up?
- Maybe its name is Foreman.
Come on, where's that smile?
That laugh that makes
the whole world sunny
without contributing to global warming.
Maybe she's missing a protein.
Blood panel and enzymes
show her proteins are normal.
You can't have tested for every protein.
I can think of at least
one you can't test for at all.
Complement factor H deficiency.
If she has that, she's dead.
No way to fend off bacteria.
She'll get one infection after
another until her body shuts down.
Maybe we can get ahead of the game.
Manage each symptom as it comes up.
It would give her five miserable
years instead of six miserable months.
There's no diagnostic test
for complement factor H deficiency.
So we isolate the cells
that are yummiest for it.
Stick a needle in her eye.
You're cheating on Honey.
What?! No, I'm not.
Oh, yes, you are.
It's okay.
I get it.
Well, I was gonna say relax, but oddly
enough you seem pretty relaxed already.
You're accomplished, you're funny.
You can have whatever you want...
women are gonna...
He's not cheating with another woman.
He's cheating with another food group.
What?
His floaters float because
they're full of fat.
Probably had a big
cheeseburger for lunch.
You're eating flesh?
It's just a hamburger. Not all the time.
You're disgusting!
The soy cakes taste like cardboard.
Unsalted cardboard.
I'm accomplished.
I'm funny.
Can I...
have whatever I want?
Can we wait a second?
- What's wrong?
- I feel good.
Do you really need to put that needle...
You felt good yesterday,
and then you almost suffocated.
And you know that
that thing is in my eye?
We think it could be.
If we find it,
our hope is that we can treat it.
You hope?
Mom. Don't hang on every word.
He said he hopes.
That means he doesn't know.
I just want to understand
what's going on.
We won't know anything
until we do the test.
Addie, this all looks really scary,
but you'll feel nothing.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- You rang?
- You called me.
I bought you an espresso.
You've been buying me
coffee for a couple of weeks,
I thought I'd pay you back... with one.
How did you walk with
the cane and the two coffees?
Why are you suspicious?
Because it's either that or accept the
fact that you've done something nice.
And then I have to deal with
the horsemen and the rain of fire
and the end of days.
- You think I spat in yours?
Or worse.
I stacked them.
What do you think of me hiring
a nutritionist instead of a neurologist?
They sound almost the same.
I take it you've met a hot nutritionist.
Don't cheapen this.
We had an in-depth conversation
about proteins and fats.
I was about to examine
her boyfriend's rectum.
You asked for a date while
your finger was in her boyfriend?
Got her number.
No, no. No way.
This is an employment application.
She doesn't want to go out with you,
she's looking for a job.
Oh, God, she's 26.
With the wisdom of a much younger woman.
- Have you spoken to Foreman?
- Several times.
- We laugh...
- You're gonna lose him.
And that will be depressing...
and will only make me appreciate
all the good things that I do have.
Macular biopsy was negative,
which means you're wrong.
There's no complement
factor H deficiency.
The most likely cause of altering blood
flow in the brain is a clot or a tumor.
We can rule out a clotting
issue because she has a bleeding issue.
Which means we should
be looking for a tumor.
I think there's an infection.
Just because the cells in her eye aren't
dead yet, doesn't mean they're working.
So why did we do the test?
Because if it had been positive,
it would have proved I was right.
But negative doesn't prove you wrong.
That's the beauty of the test.
- She needs an MRI of her brain.
- Absolutely.
As long as you're scanning,
you mind having a boo for an abscess,
or something caused by an infection?
I didn't expect House to beg me to stay,
but it seems like he's
in a better mood since I quit.
Nothing in the axial view.
You haven't asked me why I'm leaving.
I figured you'd tell
me when you wanted to.
I don't want to be like him.
You're not a jerk.
Thank you.
I mean,
sometimes you are.
But I don't think
we can pin that on House.
And you're a better doctor
than when you came through the door.
I'm better at some things,
worse at others.
Again, not House's fault. It's a job.
You're supposed to take the good,
and leave the bad.
It's easier for you.
Why, because you think
I need to toughen up?
You think I'm weak?
Yeah.
See, I am a jerk.
I've gotta get out of here.
- What's wrong, Addie?
- My head hurts!
Brain's clean. No tumor and no abscess.
We're all wrong.
My head!
- Grody!
- Looks like massive tissue death.
Who cares...
her head blew up. How cool is that.
It's not puss-y.
Meaning you don't
think it's an infection.
And you'd be right,
if you weren't wrong.
Here we go again.
She's got infections that come and go,
which means...
It means it has to be something else.
Good guess, but no.
It means either she's
got a leprechaun in her colon,
which is playing with the doggy door,
letting bacteria in and out.
Or she's got complement
factor H deficiency.
Are you enjoying this?
I'm saving a woman's li...
I'm saving a woman's life!
Actually, I'm diagnosing her.
Technically I'm diagnosing her
with something that's gonna kill her,
but other than that
I am saving her life.
An autoimmune problem makes more sense.
You can't explain a transudative pleural
effusion with Giant Cell Arteritis.
You'd need three white boards
and 100 different-colored markers.
No, it's much more likely
she has an invisible protein
that allowed bacteria to
arbitrarily invade her lungs,
then arbitrarily invade her pleura,
then arbitrarily jump into her head.
If it's autoimmune, she can live.
But we have to give her steroids now,
before her heart ruptures.
If you're wrong and you
give her steroids, she dies now.
You want a rundown on how it feels
to go with your gut and kill a person?
We can get into the whole spiraling out
of control, self-doubt, resigning thing.
Do it.
The worst that can happen is you quit.
Cameron, want to explain to the parents
why you'll be holding
paddles while he's doing it?
Because if her heart goes boom,
it'll boom right away.
She really has to be awake for this?
If there's a problem,
she can tell us what she feels.
- Relax.
- We're scared.
I don't want you to be scared.
Then get better.
Okay, sweetie?
We love you.
I'm sorry.
Ready?
Ready.
My patient's about
to have a heart attack.
It's gonna be massive.
Well, that's too bad 'cause I just got
tickets to a stroke on the third floor.
Have you had a
conversation with Foreman?
- Do me a favor.
- You haven't...
because then you would have
to confront your own emotions.
Is bile an emotion?
Because I could definitely
feel something here.
Get me some licorice.
This is gonna be the
best heart attack of all time.
Oh, wait, wait, wait...
She's gonna shock her.
There's always tomorrow.
You wanted to see me?
Pretty sure the label is straight.
Are you really gonna leave?
Where are you going?
- You lined up interviews yet?
- I'm not sure.
You're pissed at House... I get it.
You're symbolicating killing him.
Symbolicating? What?
Symbolic-a-lating...
Gosh, that's a hard word.
- Are you okay?
- Hey, I'm not the one sym...
I'm not the one pretending
to kill someone.
What'd it take for you to stay?
Is it money?
- He wants you to stay.
- He said that?
If I said he said that,
would that make a difference?
- Are you sure you're okay?
- Hello?
Ugh, I'm leaving now.
I'm late for a breast thing.
You know he wants you. You know he's
good; you know he can make you good.
I don't know what I'm saying.
You don't... I don't...
You know what I'm saying
and you know I'm right. I gotta go.
Sorry it took me so long
to get down here. I'm Dr. Wilson.
I guess Dr. Stein's gone.
Don't worry about it.
I'll talk to him when we're done.
Dr. Stein said they're
probably calcium deposits.
Well, with your medical history
you don't want to take any chances.
I can't seem to put on my gloves today.
It's weird.
Well... that's fine.
One's enough. Well, let's have a look.
You sure talk fast.
This is nothing.
You should see me when we're busy.
I just winked at you. I've never
winked at a patient in my life.
I have no... I am so sorry.
I have no idea what I was thinking.
- It's okay.
- No, it's not.
I was hitting on you.
I wasn't consciously hitting on you,
but what else could you think?
That you were being reassuring?
Yeah, that would make sense.
On the other hand, I...
I feel like my heart's gonna explode.
Are you okay?
I feel a little sweaty.
- Am I sweating?
- Yeah.
- Is something wrong?
- I can't... I can't...
I put on gloves to do a breast exam...
perfect. Sorry.
It's 185.
185.
185?
Excuse me, I have to go kill someone.
You dosed me!
Yes, I did. But only because
you didn't trust me, your best friend.
- You could've killed me!
- Amphetamines aren't gonna kill you.
You don't know my medical history.
I... I could've...
You could've given me a heart attack.
A heart attack is not gonna kill you.
You were in a hospital.
A- ha! You yawned.
A- ha... you tried to kill me.
I put you on uppers,
and you still yawned.
Means it's a symptom of being a big,
fat liar.
Yawning is a side effect
of some anti-depressants...
apparently the ones you're on.
I'm not on anti-depressants;
I'm on speed.
That means it's a symptom of cerebral
tumor. You got six weeks to live.
Mr. Well-adjusted is as
messed up as the rest of us.
Why would you keep that a secret?
Are you ashamed of recognizing
how pathetic your life is?
It's not a secret, House!
It's... it's...
It's personal!
- How long has it been personal?
- It's personal!
Yawning's recent, so either you just
started or you changed prescriptions.
This is why I take them.
They're anti-depressants.
Not anti-annoyance-ants.
You'd think this would naturally
come up in conversation.
Oh, don't act hurt. You don't care.
On one of those occasions
when you're pompously lecturing me on
what to do to fix my life.
- You wouldn't take them.
You'd rather OD on Vicodin
or stick electrodes in your head
because you could say
you did it to get high.
The only reason to take anti-depressants
is because you're depressed.
You have to admit that you're depressed.
Gimme.
Are you gonna admit that...
Nope. I'm gonna prove
that I'm not depressed.
Well, I can't give you my prescription.
You've got to meet with a psychiatrist.
You need a whole work-up.
Give me a Vicodin so I don't stroke.
I... wouldn't drink that.
My leg hurt, and I...
Why didn't you pick up the phone?
- We've been calling.
- I was sleeping.
What did you do?
Nothing.
This is how regular people
look when you wake them up.
Chase was wrong.
Addie's kidneys shut down.
Hemolytic uremic syndrome
shut down Addie's kidneys.
Peripheral smear of
red cells had schistocytes.
HUS is usually caused by an
infection or a protein deficiency.
What a coincidence.
I know a patient with an
infection and a protein deficiency.
You think it's possible
there's a connection?
I want to hear you say it, Chase.
It will please me.
Doesn't mean you're right.
You predicted cardiac arrest...
instant cardiac arrest.
There were only two choices. Since yours
was wrong, mine must've been right.
Either that or we missed the leprechaun.
If you're right,
there's nothing to be done.
The steroid treatment we gave
her means when the next infection hits,
it'll hit hard.
Liver failure, cardiac arrest...
On the bright side,
it confirms my diagnosis.
Don't you see how
incredible this call was?
A protein deficiency.
Can't be tested, can't be seen.
I called it based on coughing blood.
- You're happy about this.
- She's going to die.
That's not my fault.
She's gonna die anyway.
But now, thanks to me,
at least she'll know why.
I'm sure you'll see that gratitude
in her eyes when you tell her.
- I'm not telling her.
No one's telling her.
Not 'til we're sure I'm right.
But we're gonna wait for her to
stroke or have a heart attack to confirm
before we tell her.
Seems like the humane approach.
Her heart went into V-fib.
Brought her back.
Barely.
Congratulations.
You have your confirmation.
What's her name?
- Who? The co-ed?
- Sure.
Dead sophomore girl?
You know her father's name?
Dad.
Her mother's name is Mommy.
Ben and Jodie are about to
lose their only daughter, Addie.
You think they're gonna
give a crap if I know their names?
Five years from now when
the father's looking at photographs
of his daughter graduating from
high school, they're not gonna remember
the nice black doctor who
called them by their first name.
You don't wanna quit.
- You saying you don't want me to quit?
- Didn't sound like I said that.
I'm saying that suddenly you're trying
to turn me into a kinder, gentler ass.
'Cause you know who you are.
And you figure if you
can make me decent and caring,
then maybe there's a hope for you...
You are about to tell a girl she's
dying. And you think it's about you.
God, I hope I'm not you.
I'm sorry.
Addie, you're dying.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Your infections will get worse.
The toxins will spill into your blood.
How long?
Two days...
maybe less.
- You have a condition called...
- It doesn't matter.
It's, um,
a very rare protein deficiency...
I don't want to hear it.
Okay.
It's what's killing you.
This is what's killing you. You're
not interested in what's killing you?
Will that make any difference?
- Will I live any longer?
- Please, could you just leave?
What's the point of living without
curiosity? Without craving the...
So I'm screwing up my last few
hours because I won't listen to you?
Get out of here.
It's... it's... it's like the...
dark matter in the universe.
You're smiling.
No, I'm not.
You can only diagnose a
problem by looking at what's...
missing.
Oh, God.
I have to go.
Nineteen-year-old
didn't want to hear the coolest
explanation of why she's gonna die.
Begged me to shut up.
If you can't shut up,
at least talk quietly.
Amphetamine withdrawal's a bitch.
She thought that I was happy.
- You were happy.
- No, I was hazy.
I don't get hazy on Vicodin
or anything else I throw down.
Which means I was throwing
down something I didn't know I was.
Which got me to wondering... why
didn't you give me those happy pills?
I told you; you gotta be checked out...
No, you just didn't
want me double dosing.
You dosed me!
Those coffees...
They worked.
You've been smiling. Relaxed... happy.
A dying girl thought I was happy.
A moron thought I was happy.
Who the hell doesn't
want to know why she's dying?
- House was happy.
- Hazy.
- Happy.
- Hazy!
Oh, right,
a dying girl mistook hazy for happy.
Because dying people
see happiness everywhere.
- She's miserable.
- She wasn't miserable.
Of course she was miserable.
You just told her she...
She was not different
than she'd ever been.
Oh, God.
I gotta go.
I need a minute with your daughter.
- Dr. House, get out of here before...
- She's gonna live.
Does that help?
Now get out.
Are you jerking us around?
Get out!
You...
have got leprechauns in ya.
Depression manifests
in lots of different ways.
Some people can't
get out of bed all day.
Others have serial relationships
and become oncologists.
- I'm dying; I'm not depressed.
- Wrong and wrong.
You tried to kill yourself
by throwing down kitchen cleanser.
Now, most normal suicidal
morons would've just drank the stuff.
Burn the hell out of
their mouth and throat.
Painful, but not deadly.
But being a college-educated,
suicidal moron,
you wrapped it in gel caps
or gum which left no trace.
It burned a hole in your intestine.
But the body can repair
almost anything...
which is cool.
In your case,
scar tissue closed up the hole.
But it also formed a bridge
between a vein and an artery.
Now, veins are supposed to
help the intestine flush bacteria away.
But the bridge allowed the
bacteria entrance to the artery
where they got a free ride...
everywhere.
Can you fix me?
Surgery can fix the bridge.
Take about two hours.
Psychotherapy's gonna
take you a little longer.
Why'd you do it?
I don't know.
I just...
have never been happy.
Please don't tell my parents.
They'll blame themselves,
and it's not their fault.
Please, you can't tell them.
Technically, all you have to do
is promise me that
you won't do it again.
Then legally, I can't tell them.
I promise.
Yeah. Sure.
- We can't thank you enough...
- Your daughter tried to kill herself.
That's why she's here.
Legally, I'm supposed to
keep that between me and her.
Which makes sense.
She's obviously an adult.
Capable of her own
well-reasoned decisions.
You're sure?
If she doesn't die in
the next couple of hours...
yeah, I'm right.
How could she hide this?
Everyone has secrets.
We'll take care of her. Figure it out.
Make her happy?
Get her into therapy.
Might want to try some meds too.
Can we call you?
If we have any questions.
No.
'Sup?
Nothing.
- You wanted to see me?
- Yeah.
House's patient.
Yeah, the one that would've
died if not for him.
- Subtle.
- Thanks.
You're really scared
you'll turn into him.
Don't tell me I'm better than him. Don't
tell me take the good, leave the bad.
Cameron already tried.
I'm telling you there
are worse things to turn into.
It's not worth it.
I didn't think you were gonna show.
Sorry.
Surgery went a little late.
So you really think I have
all the necessary qualifications?
I can't discuss this with a dry mouth.
What do you got there?
Peppermint tea.
I'm going to have a mug
of peppermint tea, please.
This isn't a job interview, is it?
It's some kind of interview.
You're judging me, I'm judging you.
You have the upper hand.
I don't know anything about you.
I'm on anti-depressants
'cause a doctor friend
of mine thinks I'm miserable.
I don't like them. They make me hazy.
I eat meat. I like drugs.
And I'm not always faithful
to the women I date.
You don't seem depressed.
You do realize you just skipped
over several deep character flaws
that most women would
run screaming from.
- You told the truth.
- Yeah.
I don't always do that either.
Well, how miserable can you be saving
lives, sleeping around, and doing drugs?
Were you on the debating
team in high school?
Also...
I hate...
tea.
Transcript: swsub.com
Sync: jh26