Jasper, hold still.
Stop squirming. Hold still.
What did he do now?
He got in another fight. And
I can't get his nose to stop bleeding.
You have to apply much
more pressure than that.
You had to do this today.
I got office hours.
Supposed to have dinner with the Dean.
You just can't lash
out whenever you get angry.
- He said I smell like a monkey.
- Well, you do.
You can't refuse to take a bath and then
hit kids who tell you that you smell.
- Damn!
- Don't you think we should call 911?
This isn't his first nosebleed.
He'll be fine.
- Daddy!
- Hey, Lucy-goosey.
I'm playing doctor.
So am I. Um, can you go back and play?
- When was this fight?
- Over ten minutes ago.
I feel dizzy.
- Maybe you should make that call.
- Okay.
- Daddy, look. I can help.
- No... that's great, honey.
Can you just please leave Daddy alone?
One of my kids is bleeding
profusely from the nose. Please hurry.
They're sending an ambulance.
Call them back.
He'll be fine.
How you feeling, bud?
- You lightheaded?
- Lucy.
Oh my God.
Lucy, are you okay?
Transcript: swsub.com
Sync: jh26
Oh, for God's sake.
Stop. Don't move.
The way the soft...
evening light catches your eyes.
The gentle caress of dusk on your hair
as you turn around and leave
my office without giving me that file.
- Restrictive Pericarditis.
- Boring.
- She's in Kindergarten.
- Less boring.
Or grandma's been held back a few years.
It's calcified and she's hypertensive.
- Better get her into surgery.
- She already is in surgery.
Tricky procedure. Gonna take all night.
Sleep tight.
No congenital defects,
no health problems.
- But her heart is strangling itself.
- Fascinating.
Since the pathology on
the pericardium won't be back
until after they remove it.
Get started on her blood. You can
test for viral infections, bacteria...
Round up the usual suspects.
Amyloidosis,
Sarcoidosis, Hemochromatosis...
Heck. Go wild. Do all the osises.
All taken care of. Sleep tight.
This thing is already
all around her heart.
If it gets into the muscle, she's dead.
Best bet is Coxsackie virus.
Parvovirus B-19, CMV...
Bacterial infection's more likely
to turn constrictive. It could be TB.
Right. Forgot about the part
where she did time in a Russian gulag.
Her hematocrit's elevated.
A few extra red blood cells means
nothing. She's probably just dehydrated.
Yes, and I could assume three
or four things to fit my theory too.
She's sick.
She obviously hasn't been drinking...
Enough!
I take it you two aren't
sleeping together anymore?
We do what House said.
We test for everything.
Good.
Then I can go home.
Since when does we not include you?
Well, House is gonna
call us idiots anyway.
Might as well be a well-rested idiot.
You guys are idiots.
Why? Because we stayed up all night
doing exactly what you told us to do?
No, because you stayed up all night
doing exactly what I told you to do
and have nothing to show for it.
- We eliminated dozens of wrong answers.
I asked you what two plus two equals.
And a day later, you tell me, not 25.
Pathology report just got filed.
Found granulomas in Lucy's pericardium.
Indicates a fungal infection.
Nice work.
He went home.
Work smart, not hard.
Find out which fungus.
Biopsy a lymph node.
Take "employee of the month" with you.
- I would rather Foreman...
- I know.
- I don't want anymore shots.
Jasper.
Look at me, Goosey.
Squeeze my hand, okay?
This will tell us why you're sick,
so we can make you all better.
Where would she pick up a fungus?
Anywhere moist. Around a pool,
locker room, public shower.
She doesn't have
any gym or swim classes.
She doesn't even like
to play with kids outside.
Haven't taken any trips?
Gone anywhere new?
It's been hard to get away...
since their mom.
My mom's dead.
I'm sorry.
Last year. Brain cancer.
You're gonna stick
that thing in her arm?
Cool!
The cool part is,
your sister won't feel a thing.
Nice necklace.
- Thanks.
- You like videogames?
Love them.
That should do it.
You okay?
I want my bunny.
Are you being silly?
I don't know which one to take.
What do you mean?
What's happening?
So what does the double vision tell us?
Slit lamp revealed the eye's
anterior chamber is swollen. Uveitis.
Means it's not a post-op
effect and it's not neurological.
It's not fungal either.
The lymph node biopsy was clean.
So we're back to square one.
One and a half.
We've eliminated two more conditions.
Yes. Two plus two doesn't
equal 12 or 16 either.
Vision issues plus screwy heart
equals some type of auto-immune.
Lupus and Kawasaki's are
the most common in a six-year-old.
Yeah, tough to find a six-year-old
who doesn't have Lupus or Kawasaki's.
Did you look at her knees?
Those knobby things in the
middle of her legs. Any scars or scabs?
What does that have to do...
Most six-year-olds
hurt themselves a lot.
They crash their bikes,
climb trees, bungee jump.
Dad said she doesn't
like to run around outside.
- Because running around outside hurts.
- She didn't mention anything about...
Most six-year-olds are not familiar with
the phrase, "My joints feel inflamed."
So two plus two equals...
Juvenile Rheumatoid Arthritis.
We're checking her ANA to confirm and
giving her steroids to fix her vision.
Some idiot gave me two
ticket for a play tonight.
Saved his life. Apparently worth $186.
Sorry, I had to take a leak.
Oh, I... I didn't know
you were seeing a patient.
It's an exam room.
What did you think I was doing?
What you usually do...
hiding from Cuddy.
Be stupid to do it in here.
There's a patient in here.
- You been drinking more?
- Uh, no, I...
Guy's peeing all the time.
- The play, interested?
- Sure.
You want me to pick you up?
- I'm not going.
- You said two tickets.
You thought this was a date?
- Any other symptoms?
- My stomach hurts.
I have back pain and muscle aches.
I feel dizzy.
And I have trouble concentrating
sometimes in class.
- I really should...
- You want the tickets or not?
- Why don't you wanna go with me?
- It's a play.
Dudes only go to plays
if they're dragged by women
they're hoping to see naked.
So why are you giving them to me?
Maybe there's someone
you wanna see naked.
All right.
- Any fever?
- No.
- Anything in your pee other than pee?
- I'm gonna need a urine sample.
- No.
Yeah, that last one wasn't a question.
You might have diabetes.
- I can't pee in public.
- We have bathrooms.
I can't pee in public bathrooms.
Where can you pee?
I only live a few miles from here.
I thought arthritis was for old people.
JRA's an autoimmune disease.
Her body's attacking itself,
causing inflammation in the joints,
her eyes, and her heart.
Is it treatable?
It can be crippling. But it
can also go into complete remission.
Well, the good thing
is we caught it early.
Gives her the best chance
to have a positive outcome.
Don't get up, Goosey.
Your stitches.
She's having a stroke.
Stroke was caused by a clot
in her middle cerebral artery.
Started her on TPA.
Should dissolve the clot
and hopefully prevent brain damage.
But we won't know for sure
until she regains consciousness.
Or she has another stroke.
Arthritis... heart disease.
Why can't this kid act her age?
JRA doesn't affect the blood. Means
the clot's a symptom of something else.
It's a symptom of polycythemia.
She's fully hydrated.
Her blood's still thicker
than pancake batter.
Thick blood explains the stroke.
Can also have cause
an auto-immune response.
Which would explain
the JRA kicking into gear.
But what explains the thick blood?
Lack of oxygen forces the
body to overproduce red cells.
- What explains the lack of oxygen?
- Carbon monoxide fume, cigarette smoke.
- I doubt our patient's a smoker.
- Dad could be.
- He's not.
- He says he's not.
Don't make me turn the hose on you two.
Chase is right.
You two go check the house.
See if Dad's a closet Marlboro Man.
You're intentionally punishing us.
By making you do your job?
It does seem kind of cruel, doesn't it?
Take along a carbon monoxide
detector to check for leaks.
And you, start her on hydroxyurea to
control her red blood cell production.
Dig out a Merck manual,
medieval edition,
tell you how to drain a pint
or two so she doesn't clot again.
Dr. Cameron!
I got you flowers.
- For helping my sister.
- That's so sweet.
- Does your dad know you're down here?
- Yes.
Congratulations on your bundle of joy.
Something you forgot to tell me?
You should take these
back to where you found them.
Okay.
Excuse me,
can you make sure these flowers
and this kid get back
to where they belong?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
Let's go. Come on.
Wait.
So you're just draining blood from her?
You're not testing it,
you're not fixing it?
Your daughter's vascular
system is engorged with blood.
Draining some reduces
the chances of another stroke.
We're also starting her on a drug that
suppresses the production of red cells
so we don't have to keep doing this.
Good chance she'll make a full recovery.
- She hasn't spoken yet.
- Give her time.
Uh, this is your boy?
- Where have you been?
- Exploring.
- See ya.
- Thank you.
You know, you just can't
run off without telling me.
Okay. Can I have two dollars?
Oven's a long shot. They'd smell
the gas long before anyone got sick.
Yeah, right. House loves it when we
skip something 'cause it's a long shot.
Why'd you take the flower?
Why'd you kiss him?
- He did something sweet.
- He stole flowers.
He's eight.
You were trying to make me jealous.
Yeah, I want you to
profess your love for me.
Oh, wait, you already did that. And
it caused me to end our relationship.
You're enabling a thief.
And a delinquent.
Letters from school.
Fights, detentions, a parent conference.
Oh, I know, I know.
The bad boy is hard to resist.
It's a crush. It's harmless.
- It's never harmless.
- So I'm learning.
So this is us now?
We snipe at each other?
I'm not sniping, I'm looking for a vent.
Her room's directly above the garage.
There's all sorts
of CO sources down there.
I found a vent.
I think there's something in it.
This isn't right.
You dumped me. You don't get to be mad.
We had a really good thing.
You broke the rules. I'm angry.
I'll get over it.
She's being abused.
A bloody t-shirt doesn't equal abuse.
Kids get hurt all the time.
That amount of blood?
Oh, crap. You two are agreeing again.
Father's overwhelmed. Hectic job,
his wife passed away last year.
He could easily be
taking it out on the kids.
Or she had a nosebleed
and grabbed a t-shirt.
She's so ashamed of a nosebleed
she has to hide the evidence
in a vent under her bed.
She's socially isolated, the brother's
always in trouble. It's classic signs.
But no physical signs.
No marks on her body. No bruises at all.
What if it's sexual?
We should call Social Services.
Well, this sucks.
Either it's abuse or it's not abuse.
Which means either it's a symptom
or it's completely irrelevant.
Either way, we gotta waste
half a day figuring out which.
Full physical exam.
Look for bruises we may have missed.
Check her mouth and do a vaginal exam.
We can't do a vaginal exam on a
six-year-old without the dad's consent.
And if he's abusing her,
he'll never say yes.
Never is just "reven" spelled backwards.
Have you been abusing your daughter?
What? Why would you...
We found this hidden
in a vent under her bed.
I don't know anything about this.
Maybe she had a bloody nose.
- We need to examine her for abuse.
- You can't really think I...
Maybe you, maybe the school bully,
maybe the creepy neighbor.
I'm guessing you're not paying
as much attention as you should be.
You even know where
your son is right now?
Yeah, he was here just...
here a minute ago.
She isn't being abused.
Unfortunately,
that answer doesn't help me.
If you have abused her,
you're obviously gonna lie about it.
I'm not lying!
We need to do a vaginal exam.
No, she may be dying,
she still can't talk, and you're
gonna waste your time with this?
You consent,
and we waste a few hours doing the exam,
or you refuse and
I call Social Services.
And they waste three
days doing an investigation
which ends with them
doing the exam anyway.
I'm gonna look inside your mouth.
Open wide.
I need to look at your
chest and your back next, okay?
I know you can't talk
so stop me if you get scared.
Before you came here,
did anyone hurt you?
Make you bleed?
I need to look in your vagina now.
Do you understand?
I'm a doctor, so it's okay, all right?
Bend your knees,
keep your ankles together.
And just let your knees
fall to the side, okay?
Oh, my God.
She has cuts all over her genital area.
Like slices.
Some are almost healed,
but some are new.
- She could be doing it to herself.
- She's a little young to be cutting.
She's a little young for a stroke.
Depression accounts for the cuts.
Molestation accounts for the depression.
But do the cuts account
for all that blood?
They weren't deep enough.
So she's getting cut,
but that's not the source of the blood?
The other obvious source
is forcible penetration.
Obvious source of the blood,
not the cuts.
And there was no tearing.
There was no evidence at all.
So we have no explanation
for the cuts or the blood.
Where is he?
What if our original
assumption was wrong?
Meaning what?
We found a t-shirt covered
with blood hidden in the heating vent.
- How do we know it's even hers?
- Her dad identified it.
Not the shirt, the blood.
Are... are those the urine test results?
- Yes.
- And...
- I'm going to ask you for some blood.
- Why?
To see if your answer will be,
I can't bleed in public.
This wasn't your urine, was it?
Why would I give you
someone else's urine?
The usual reason is
because you're on steroids.
I'm not an athlete.
Second favorite reason
is because you're on drugs.
- I'm not.
- I am.
Third favorite reason is,
you have insurance,
but your friend Eggs Benedict doesn't.
So eggs describes a list of symptoms
and you repeat them to a doctor.
Which is particularly stupid
because this is a free clinic.
Need you. Now.
My work here is done.
Am I okay? Is it diabetes?
No, you're pregnant.
Six-year-old abuse victim and
you haven't called Social Services?
She might have been abused?
That's horrifying.
Why are you wearing extra
concealer under your eyes?
The law is clear. You suspect abuse,
you call the authorities.
You don't proceed as usual while
the possible abuser sits by her bedside.
Dad consented to the exam,
which means it's not the dad.
How late were you out last night?
It's always the dad.
And I don't have a curfew.
Panty hamster get a spin on its wheel?
I went to a play.
House, you are going
back to your office.
You are picking up your phone,
calling Social Services,
and you are reporting suspected abuse.
Do you understand?
What play?
You're trying to have sex with Cuddy.
Fries?
You took her to a play.
You only take women to plays because...
No, you only take women
to plays for that reason.
That's your theory.
Okay, then why did
you take her to a play?
- She's a friend.
- A friend with a squish mitten.
It is possible to have
a friend of the opposite sex.
Blasphemer!
She's not a friend of the opposite sex,
she's a different species.
She's an administrator. She's
gonna eat your head after she's done.
Yes, I slept with her.
- Seriously?
- No.
Yes, you did.
Yes, I did.
- Seriously?
- No.
You got a problem, House.
We just tested the blood on Lucy's
t-shirt. It's full of endometrial cells.
So it's not her blood.
We tested that too. It is.
Your six-year-old patient?
It's menstrual blood.
She's started puberty.
How can someone start puberty
before they even start the first grade?
She was in diapers two years ago.
For some reason,
her body has too much sex hormone.
Caused her reproductive system to get
confused. Start operating prematurely.
We need to find out the source
of the hormones and cut it off.
She's so young.
I haven't even...
talked to her about sex.
I doubt she even knows what a period is.
Girls talk to their moms about that.
You're going to be okay, Goosey.
I love you.
I...
want...
juice.
She got her period and didn't know what
it was. She was scared and confused.
Her friend told her to
put a t-shirt in her underwear.
When she started growing pubic hair,
she snuck daddy's razor
and tried to shave it off.
Apparently,
forgot to sneak the shaving cream.
Tumors, most likely.
A pituitary adenoma would
send her hormone level sky-high.
In Puerto Rico in the '70s, there
was an epidemic of kids growing breasts
because of estrogen in the poultry.
If it was in the food, it would
be an epidemic. We've got one kid.
She's six. She's tiny.
She lives on chicken fingers and milk.
Dad doesn't look like
the type to read labels.
He's probably buying
stuff packed full of hormones.
Excellent argument. It's a tumor.
There's all sorts of environmental
sources: pesticides, soy products.
Some shampoos are basically
a placenta in a bottle.
If the tumor's not in her brain,
it's her reproductive tract. Get an MRI.
- Can I at least...
- Waste your time?
Wouldn't recognize you if you didn't.
Frontal cortex is clean.
Moving caudally.
For the record,
Cameron's the one who broke it off.
Not interested.
No masses in the hypothalamus.
I wanted more.
- She didn't share my feelings.
- I feel like I'm in a similar position.
Pituitary's clean.
You're an idiot.
Either she's lying,
or she's actually emotionally detached.
Which one sounds more
like Cameron to you?
Neither.
You have to choose one.
There's a bright spot on the left ovary.
Looks like a solid tumor.
They printed my letter.
You were right.
Of course I was.
What are we talking about?
- They printed my letter.
- Great.
You wanna see her naked.
No, no, no. She wants to see me naked.
She sent me flowers.
She's just thanking you for the play.
See, some people feel
an emotion called gratitude...
There's a card.
I suspected. Explains how
you knew who they were from.
"Let's do it again... soon. XX, Lisa."
X's are the kisses, right?
No, I think they're the hugs.
The O's are the kisses.
No, no. The X's are
definitely the kisses.
"Soon" is its own sentence.
I gotta go!
I'll miss you.
You were a good friend.
They printed my letter.
How was the play, Mrs. Lincoln?
- What's up with Wilson?
- He's just a little freaked.
Why?
I sent him flowers.
You're not supposed to be up here.
Is that other doctor your boyfriend?
No.
Your dad's probably looking for you.
He's got enough to
worry about right now.
Do you like him?
He's a friend.
Do you like him like him?
We should get you back to your dad.
Let me put this down
and I'll take you there.
I could be your boyfriend.
I... think that wouldn't
be fair to the girls your own age.
- He seems like a tool.
- He's not.
And that's rude.
I'm taking you back to your father.
Mass is small...
about a centimeter across.
Firing the biopsy needle.
- You nick an artery?
- No.
She's in V-tach; no pulse. Charging 50.
Clear!
Arrhythmia must've been
a reaction to the hydroxyurea.
We have to stop the drug therapy.
Bone marrow will just
go back to overproducing blood cells.
She'll keep having strokes and we'll
have to keep bleeding her... forever.
We resect the tumor, hormone levels
go back to normal, her symptoms go away.
Great plan... except for the
fact that her tumor's not a tumor.
It's a benign cyst.
If it's not a tumor, that
just leaves an environmental source.
Feeling another late night.
I'm gonna leave you two alone.
- You're kidding me, right?
- What?
The answer's right there.
It's just a question of finding it.
You don't need me for that.
Don't get the mochaccino.
They screwed up and put
hot chocolate in the dispenser.
Thank you.
You were right.
The eight-year-old kid grabbed my ass.
I shouldn't have encouraged him.
Well, I was a boy once.
I know how they think.
- You were a pervert at eight?
- Maybe 11.
I didn't realize
you were gonna get hurt.
I'm sorry I misled you.
You didn't.
You have feelings for me.
You come back to me again and again.
For sex. It's a simple, physical...
You have feelings for puppies
and patients that you barely know.
But when it comes to a guy that
you've worked with for three years,
had sex with, spent the night with...
you're telling me you feel nothing?
Absolutely nothing?
Get away from her! Don't touch her!
I'll kill you if you touch her!
Get him off!
Ah! He's biting me! Get him off!
Somebody better be dying.
Lucy's big brother's got a crush
on me so he bit the crap out of Chase.
- And I care because...?
- Just thought you might wanna know
when one of your employees
gets attacked by a sociopath.
Bees or monkeys, yes. Sociopaths, no.
- Hello.
- He's not a sociopath.
- How do you know?
- He's acting logically.
He's got a crush on you.
He's being aggressive about it.
Not just regular aggressive...
he's out-of-his-mind-on-hormones
aggressive.
You think he's...
You better figure out
what's killing the girl...
because her brother's got it too.
Jasper's got 100 times more testosterone
than a healthy, eight-year-old.
But we scanned his brain
and reproductive tract...
no hormone-secreting tumors.
Not surprised. What's more likely?
Brother and sister get the same
type of tumor at exactly the same time
or they both play in
the same toxic sandbox?
Yes, you would think that if, for
some reason, you were completely unaware
of the fact we spent the entire
night testing everything from that home.
It was all negative.
You went home?
Good for you.
- Delegate.
- We're not his subordinates.
Making it all the more impressive.
What if it's genetic?
Anyone else think it's more than
a coincidence these kids have symptoms
that could be caused by a brain tumor,
which is exactly what killed their mom?
You just said there were no tumors.
We scanned both their brains.
They looked clean.
So did their moms, until it didn't.
It can't be genetic.
Mom had none of the same symptoms.
Yes, she did.
If the symptoms were
pubic hair and menstruation.
That's ridiculous. If menstruation
is a symptom of brain cancer,
than I should be on chemo right now.
That's ridiculous. You're
way too skinny to be menstruating.
What if the mom had other problems...
symptoms her doctors ignored on account
of the fact she was already dying?
Pull all her medical records.
Find any similarities to our patients.
Punch the little brat on the nose so he
doesn't have a stroke like his sister.
- I'm not sick.
- Just trying to keep you that way.
I want Dr. Cameron to do mine.
Trust me. You don't want
her cutting you right now.
So... Jasper's behavioral issues...
Could be a function of
the increased testosterone.
Hopefully, he'll be a delight
as soon as we figure this out.
My tummy hurts! It hurts!
No, it doesn't. Don't be such a baby.
- My tummy hurts!
- Where in your tummy?
It hurts!
Stomach pain is from
a cyst in her pancreas.
I found two more in her
kidneys and one in her lung.
They weren't there 48 hours ago.
The hormones are making
her body go haywire.
She gets one in her brain or heart,
she's dead.
No pressure though.
Mom was perfectly healthy
until she got cancer.
She had none of the
symptoms the kids have.
It's not genetic.
It's not environmental.
It's gotta be a pituitary adenoma.
Yes, that would make
complete sense if we had one.
Just because we haven't found anything
on the scan doesn't mean it's not there.
You should remove her pituitary gland.
Two siblings, same condition.
It's gotta be genetic or environmental.
We add in the same time and
we're back to just environmental.
And that would make complete sense if
there was anything in her environment.
That's 'cause we haven't
found anything yet.
She's been out of her environment for
four days and she's still getting worse.
- I'm getting the father's consent.
- No!
- We have no evidence.
- This is your process, House.
You asked us what two plus two is.
We've eliminated every
number except for four.
She needs brain surgery.
The ovaries produce sex hormones
in response to a signal
from the pituitary gland.
Since we know the ovaries are fine,
the most likely cause...
"Most likely" means she wants to root
around inside your little girl's brain
without any guarantee that it'll work.
That's why she's holding
off on doing your son.
Dr. House knows that unfortunately,
we've ruled out every other option.
We need to resect Lucy's
pituitary before...
- Who else visits these kids?
- They don't have any family in town.
You got a girlfriend?
- No one visits.
- School?
They don't go to the same school.
House, I've...
- Nanny?
- They don't have one.
They go to an after-school day care,
but none of the other kids are sick.
Yet.
It took your son twice as long
to develop symptoms as your daughter.
- Maybe the other kids are just slow.
- We wait and your daughter may die.
She does this, your daughter
will need hormone-replacement therapy
for the rest of her life.
- The treatment are extremely effective.
She should lead a
relatively normal life.
And isn't that every parent's dream?
To have a kid grow
up to be relatively normal?
My husband died of thyroid
cancer that metastasized to his brain.
I've been there.
I know how terrifying this can be.
I am telling you that this is your best
chance to save your daughter's life.
You did not just play
the dead husband card.
My wife died
because she signed a consent
form that I didn't want her to sign.
Died.
Thank you.
How did you know?
Know what?
That the other kids weren't sick.
You've been here for four days.
I just...
I would've heard.
Right.
Do you have hair on your special place?
Miss Janie!
Can I help you?
I'm a doctor.
Two of your kids are
sick and I need to know why.
You think they got sick here?
I think you're dating their dad.
He told you?
No...
and I don't really care why he didn't.
I just need to know how often you
go to their house and what you bring.
- I don't.
- Shampoos, fancy soaps?
- Kids get in your bag?
- I've never been to their house.
They just lost their mom.
And we thought it was too soon.
Why are you staring at me?
Lip wax?
I just had it done over lunch.
- Mani-pedi?
- No...
just the wax.
Women get a wax, it's part of
the whole self-indulgent, beauty ritual.
Pedicure, steam, cucumber masks.
No one runs out of lunch
just to get a lip wax,
unless you woke up
looking like Yosemite Sam.
You're an ass.
It's always the dad.
Excess facial hair in women.
It's a clear sign of hormonal imbalance.
Exactly what the little kiddies have.
Is there something wrong
at the day care center?
There's something wrong in your pants.
She's a lot younger than I am. I...
use a...
male-enhancement cream to keep up
with her. What does this have to do...
It never occurred to you to
get a prescription instead of some
penis pumper loaded with testosterone?
I keep it at the gym.
I apply it daily in the shower
just like it says on the bottle.
It's never been in my home.
It's obviously never been near the kids.
- But you have.
- We been through that.
I'm not a pervert or a pedophile!
30% of our waste is
excreted through our skin.
That sounds high.
That's why you stink
after eating garlic.
Jack waters his beanstalk
every day for a week.
He's oozing bean curd
out of his pores for a month.
Every time you gave
the little tykes a hug,
you gave them a dose of testosterone.
Small for you, but more than
their little bodies can handle.
So...
I did this to them?
Just... holding their hands?
If I stop using it?
You'll be floppy, they'll be fine.
Give it back.
He'll still be eight.
You okay?
Yeah, I think so.
- Talk to Cuddy?
- No, not yet.
I don't know what to say.
Just be straight with her.
I'm not sure what that is.
I can't stop thinking about her.
In what way?
Maybe she's right. Maybe.
Maybe this is worth exploring.
- Are you sure that she feels...
- She sent me flowers.
How do I do this? What do I say?
Cameron would tell
you to say how you feel.
Me, I'd get her drunk.
I'm not gonna say anything.
I'm just gonna walk... into her office
and I'm gonna kiss her.
That's a...
bold move.
Cuddy likes bold.
Yeah, you're right.
If you spoke,
you'd say something stupid.
Yeah, I mean, I'll either
get a girlfriend or get fired.
Okay.
Yeah, okay.
You! You... you!
You were gonna let me do that?!
- You made a compelling argument.
- You sent those flowers to me!
Yes, because you took her to a play.
Because actually you do want
to march down there and kiss her.
- No, I don't!
- Yes, you do!
You're right.
Seriously?
No.
You're a jerk.
- Night, Wilson.
- Night, House.
They're beautiful.
I thought about what you said.
And
I really don't want
a relationship with you.
I know.
I also know you like flowers.
I don't get the whole
May-December thing.
Give him a break.
It's May-October at worst.
Well, why can't it be October-October?
'Cause May is when
things start to get hot.
If that guy wasn't trying so hard
to keep up with a woman half his age,
he wouldn't have almost
killed both his kids.
Guy gets a little something-something...
couple of kids have to die...
circle of life.
So many people. So much energy
and drama just trying to find someone
who's almost never
the right person anyway.
It just...
shouldn't be so hard.
I got tickets to a play.
Transcript: swsub.com
Sync: jh26