Merry Christmas.
And a happy go to hell.
What's he doing here? Is he with you?
Detective Tritter and I...
we worked out a deal.
Already got a lawyer.
Get out of my office.
I told him I didn't
write those prescriptions.
I spoke with the DA.
He agreed to two months in a rehab
facility in exchange for a guilty plea.
Get out of my office.
- No jail time.
- Right.
I should get locked up
in some place I don't belong
in order to avoid getting locked
up in some other place I don't belong.
I got you on forgery and fraud.
Enough drugs to--
No sanctions to the medical board.
And you get your car
back and your bank accounts
and your precious tumor-ridden patients.
- I did this to help you.
- Next Christmas, buy me a sweater.
You punched out an employee.
You nearly cut a little girl in
half because you were too strung out--
I was in pain!
You need to believe
that I've got a problem
so that your betrayal
has the illusion of nobility.
- But you just selfishly--
- Knock it off.
Look, I don't care why Dr.
Wilson is doing this.
And right now,
it makes no difference to you either.
You need to deal with the
reality of your current situation.
You want to stand on principle,
you end up in a cell.
And you end up never
practicing medicine again.
So you've got two choices.
Your principles
or your life.
Get out of my office.
The DA put a clock on the deal.
You've got three days to decide.
Transcript: FRM - Synchro: jh26
www.sub-way.fr
House! Just give me a minute.
- You're afraid of the pain.
- You're not?
You can still have pain meds in rehab.
-Tramadol, gabapentin--
- Those don't work.
They will once you're
weaned off the Vicodin.
Look, there's Jesus.
Better go tell the Romans.
Fine, run to Cuddy.
You don't think she's
gonna support me on this?
Well, the stitches are healing nicely.
There's no sign of infection.
Sorry.
Just need her for a tiny moment.
Small favor.
Pills.
- Who's the wit?
- Doctor.
Don't worry. I'll be firing him soon.
Wait in my office.
Incision looks just
big enough for a chest tube.
Collapsed lung?
Someone mistake you for a piñata?
Delightful. Usually we just
get the elf jokes this time of year.
No on trauma.
Negative PPD.
What flavor dwarfs are you guys?
My daughter and I both
have cartilage hair hypoplasia.
Think you can make a pun out of that?
Yes, but I don't want to be insensitive.
She's got a bit of a short fuse,
isn't she?
It's a bleb. Wait in my office.
Bleb's not a diagnosis. It's an evasion.
We'll schedule an MRI to make sure.
But a certain number
of these cases are idiopathic.
Let me translate that into Tolkien for
you guys. Means Dr. Cuddy's got no idea
why your daughter's lung
suddenly popped like a balloon.
You think you do?
Give me her chart. And my pills.
Santa needs us.
Did you get that looked at?
I'm fine.
Great. I just admitted a cartilage
hair hypoplasia dwarf. 15 years old--
What are you gonna do?
I thought I'd get your theories,
mock them, then embrace my own.
The usual.
Wilson told us he ratted.
Your choice of verb, I take it.
It's appropriate. He betrayed you.
And you should take the deal.
Unexplained lung collapse and anemia.
Cuddy thinks it's idiopathic.
"Cuddy" and "idiop" being
the relevant parts of that sentence.
Well, I'd say TB,
but Cuddy's already ruled it out.
Then you'd be just
as big an "idiop" as her.
Don't you people know your dwarves?
There are over 200
varieties of dwarfism,
each with different
medical complications.
You can't expect us to be
intimately familiar with all of them.
- The sick dwarves sure expect you to.
- Cartilage hair hypoplasia.
They have compromises immune systems.
Gold star for Cameron.
For extra credit, explain to
the special needs section of the class
why our patient's negative
TB test is irrelevant.
A PDD involves planting a
fragment of TB under the skin to see
if the immune system recognizes it.
Because of a compromised immune system,
our patient could have
TB but not recognize it.
The little people love you.
Let's go see a dwarf
about a gallium scan.
Gallium is a radioactive isotope.
It travels through your veins
allowing us to see any bright
spots that might indicate infection.
I'm 4'1". That's 1.5 canes in metric.
You don't look a day over four feet.
I saw in the file that
her dad was normal-sized.
It's average-sized.
Compared to you, I'm sure it was huge.
So did he have a fetish,
or did he just fall in
love with your long-legged soul?
He grew up in the circus.
Said I reminded him of home.
Seems like you're
the one with the fetish.
I'm certainly curious
about the logistics.
- Did you stand on a table?
- House.
Pretty much he lay flat and spin me.
Mom!
So, Abigail,
you want to hop up on the table for me?
That's gonna be tough.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Uh, let me give you a boost.
Stop treating her like she's five.
Just bring over a stool
and let her climb up herself.
Mom, it's okay.
I was just trying to be helpful.
She also hates Jews.
I've dealt with worse. Being different,
you get used to people's idiocy.
Still beats the hell out
of actually being an idiot.
What?
Care to go for a spin?
What the hell were you thinking?
You didn't think ratting out
this hospital's best doctor
merited checking with your boss first?
I didn't rat him out. I got him a deal.
- Which he'll never take.
- He will if we--
How long have you known House? Did you
think he'd suddenly become reasonable?
I made the deal. It's done.
You can either keep yelling at me,
or you can help me
avoid a complete disaster.
It already is gonna
be a complete disaster.
He's not gonna take the deal.
He's gonna go to jail.
Because he's a child. He's too stubborn.
When a child misbehaves, what do you do?
You take away something he loves.
We can't take away his Vicodin.
Not only will he be in pain,
he'll start to detox.
And we tell him the only way to
get the pills back is to take the deal.
- He won't be able to function.
- That's the point.
You gonna explain that to his patient?
What choice do we have?
Gallium scan shows no
bright spots of any kind.
Means it's not TB
or any other infection.
There's no bright spots because
the whole thing's too bright.
Except for the liver.
The tech overexposed the image a bit,
but it's nothing.
The liver looks fine.
Could be lung cancer.
Tumor causes structural damage.
Lung caves in on itself.
Also explains the anemia.
Doesn't explain the
liver problem, though.
Her lung collapsed.
There is no liver problem.
You guys look at
the liver on this thing?
- There's no liver problem.
- Seriously, look at the liver.
- There's nothing there.
- Why not?
- Because there's nothing wrong.
Every organ in the scan
is lit up like a 100-watt bulb.
Except for her liver,
which is hovering around 60 watts.
And not one of them good 60-watters,
but an energy saving--
You're saying her liver's shutting
down because the lighting is off?
You just don't want a cancer diagnosis
because then you'd
have to deal with Wilson.
Lung cancer is a lame diagnosis.
Avoiding Wilson is an added bonus.
House, we need to talk.
Not taking the deal. Glad we talked.
Ultrasound her liver.
Sit down.
Stand up.
Your turn.
House, you're off the case.
Your treatment privileges are suspended
until you accept Tritter's deal.
Well, I'm obviously
not gonna take the deal
just so I can have the
fun of treating a dwarf.
So I assume there's more to this threat.
I'm also cutting off your Vicodin.
That could work.
I'm taking over as attending.
Get an MRI of her lungs.
This is not lung cancer.
We'll find out as
soon as we MRI her lungs.
You're gonna come begging
me to save this girl
long before I come
begging your for pills.
I hope not.
For everyone's sake.
- This is wrong.
- Cutting House off?
Might not work, but it's not wrong.
Bone windows looks clean.
Abigail,
we need you to hold still, okay?
Can I come out?
Just hang in there two
more minutes and we'll be done.
Okay.
Because it's effective
doesn't make it right.
Cuddy's bending the rules to
get a patient to do the right thing.
- Who'd work for a doctor like that?
- And the ends justify the means?
If the ends involve
us keeping our jobs, sure.
Lung parenchyma is clean. No masses.
It's not lung cancer.
Abigail, you okay?
House was right. Her liver's failing.
Endoscopy confirmed the vomiting
was cause by variceal bleeding.
Bloodwork also confirms
House's hypothesis--
I get it. House was right.
It's the liver. Let's move on.
What causes liver disease
and a collapsed lung?
- Schistosomiasis, the parasite--
- There's no eosinophilia.
- Cirrhosis could explain--
- Could be a hepatoma.
She's 15. It's not liver cancer.
It's not unheard of.
Cirrhosis fits better.
The question is, what caused it?
- Could be hepatitis, Budd-Chiari.
- Or drugs and alcohol.
If anyone has a reason to dull the pain,
it's a teenage dwarf.
I'll do a liver biopsy to confirm.
I'll search the patient's
home for drugs and alcohol.
Cameron,
you got a moment?
What exactly is your problem with me?
Hepatoma is a weak diagnosis.
- So this is all about the case?
- What else would it be about?
I made this deal to help him.
And helped yourself at the same time.
This is not about my practice.
This is not about my car.
I gave both of them up to help House,
and I would've gone on without them
if hadn't almost maimed that little
girl and if he hadn't punched out Chase.
Was it an easy choice?
Of course not, but it's right.
Then why wasn't it easy?
Because he's my friend. It's
- obviously complicated.
- It's complicated?
When you decided to talk to Tritter,
your life got a million times better.
How do you separate that out?
How do you pretend your windfall
isn't relevant to this decision?
It was the right thing to do.
You pretending your motives
are pure is why I have a problem.
- Where's Cuddy?
- In this drawer.
It's a rescue mission.
But I got it under control.
You can leave.
You were right about the liver failure.
Patient had variceal bleeding
which suggested cirrhosis, but--
Off the clock.
You predicted this.
You obviously saw something.
Obviously.
Liver biopsy was negative for cirrhosis.
But it shows sclerosing cholangitis.
Even weirder, there's no
increase in alkaline phosphatase.
Medical mystery. Sounds like
the kind of thing I'd be good at.
Breaking and entering. Sounds
like the kind of thing you'd be good at.
I take it that's where
Cuddy's been keeping your pills.
One theory, one drawer.
Really?
I thought you'd be all
for this "torture House plan."
It works, therefore it's good.
On the other hand,
I don't want to talk you out
of this deal by pointing out your
hypocrisy, so patient's life at stake...
Forget about the specific nature of
the liver dysfunction. It's irrelevant.
The dwarf's problem is global.
That's why the gallium scan was bright.
And it's gonna spread throughout
her entire body unless you stop it.
If that were true, more than
lungs and liver would be affected.
They will be.
It'll spread though the biliary
tree and hit her pancreas next.
Stop retracing your steps.
Get ahead of it.
Forget the liver and focus
on the pancreas. 'Cause after that--
Actually, after that doesn't
really matter what it hits
because pretty much all
roads lead to a dead dwarf.
I get why you don't want to go to rehab.
But only an idiot goes
to prison for being stubborn.
Only an idiot stands
between Ahab and his whale.
Move.
Sorry.
Santa's got gifts.
Olive oil wasn't in the kitchen.
It was in the medicine cabinet.
Home remedy for ear infections.
Ear infections are fairly
typical among CHH dwarfs.
Or it's a symptom.
Certainly wouldn't indicate
a pancreatic problem.
Or House is wrong and it's a symptom.
Laxatives.
I don't think they were used
to maintain her girlish figure.
Again, intestinal problems are common--
Again, it might be a symptom.
And glucosamine suggests
chronic joint pain--
Who ordered the Alpha-1
antitrypsin deficiency test?
I did.
You think the problem's in her pancreas?
Well, I think it will be. I think we
need to forget about the liver.
We just forgot about the lungs.
Now we need to forget about the liver?
We need to stop retracing our steps and
get ahead of this thing.
House, you've tanned.
You don't think I could've
come up with this?
Did you?
You suspended House because
it'd be dangerous having him in charge,
but getting his opinion--
I'm sure he gave you that opinion
simply because he was
worried about the patient.
Just because House wants his
pills doesn't mean his theory is wrong.
No, the test results mean that.
Your test was negative.
And the biopsy indicated
severe duct inflammation.
Do an ERCP to check the
liver for bile duct cancer.
Just because it wasn't Alpha-1
doesn't mean the pancreas isn't next.
You needed an organ. He needed a fix.
He'd have made up any story for a pill.
You didn't give him anything, did you?
No.
There's no bruise or nothing,
but it really hurts.
Unfortunately, that pain and lack of
bruising is typical
of a zygomatic break.
That sounds bad.
Bones are aligned properly. Which
ER did you go to after the car accident?
Princeton Plainsboro.
Here's my discharge slip.
Okay.
Gonna get you some
acetaminophen with codeine.
I tried that, and it makes me nauseous.
There's a drug called gabapentin which
is good for certain kinds of pains.
Great, 'cause I haven't slept in days.
Gabapentin's not really
gonna help with the sleep.
Is there something else you can give me?
Vicodin's your best
bet with sleep issues.
Thanks so much.
Unfortunately, our policy forbids
prescribing opiates to new patients.
How can a clinic have
a rule against relieving pain?
Just with opiates. We find
that it helps weed out drug seekers.
You think I'm a drug seeker?
- I'm not saying that.
- Then give me the Vicodin.
- I can't.
- Because you think I'm a drug seeker.
- I just said I didn't.
- No,
you said that the policy
was to stop drug seeking.
Then you said I'm not a drug seeker.
Policy doesn't apply.
I'm sorry. That's the policy.
Gabapentin works on nerve damage.
You're prescribing it for a broken face.
Might as well hand out
Band-Aids for a severed carotid.
You're a doctor.
Not by this clinic's definition
since I'm neither a
moron nor a mindless drone.
- Security.
- Forget it.
I'll throw myself out.
That tube is going all
the way down to my liver?
Don't worry. You'll be sedated.
Sometimes doctors have to do
things that make people uncomfortable
- to help them.
- But we always want
to respect the patient's wishes
and not shove things down their throats.
Foreman.
You haven't given her the sedative.
No.
Abigail!
She's unconscious.
Check her airway.
Airway's clear.
- Her breath smells fruity.
- Diabetic ketoacidosis.
Hang an insuline drip at .1 migs
per kig per hour. Pancreas is failing.
You ready to call House yet?
You were right.
The patient's pancreas is failing.
Told you you'd come begging me for help.
Her insulin production
is almost non-existent--
Give me my pills or lose an arm.
- The girl is dying.
- So give me my pills.
Take the deal and I will.
You'd rather kill this
girl than give me my pills.
I would rather lose one patient now
than the dozens we will
lose while you're in prison.
Well, have fun explaining that
to her itsy-bitsy grieving mother.
What if we sacrifice this
girl and House still goes to jail?
I'd feel bad. Can we get on with this?
House correctly predicted the spread.
Means we've got a global systemic
illness affecting lungs,
liver, and pancreas so far. Ideas.
Langerhans cell histiocytosis
attacks multiple organ systems.
Histiocytosis usually
starts in the brain,
then moves to the internal organs.
Abigail's brain is fine.
Cystic fibrosis.
Exocrine function is normal.
Hodgkins lymphoma.
It's a systemic cancer which
her dwarfism predisposes her to.
- Any ideas that aren't cancer?
- Cancer fits.
Autoimmune fits better. We should
treat her with prednisone for lupus.
That'll spike her blood
sugar and put her back in a coma.
It's much safer just to
run a double-stranded DNA test.
Not if she dies before
we get the results.
One of you is probably right.
Why don't we hold the sniping
until we find out which?
Wilson, do an LP for lymphoma. You guys,
run an antibody test for lupus.
Because of your daughter's dwarfism,
we've had to pick a higher entry point
for the lumbar puncture,
which increases the risk.
So why not do the lupus test first?
In the interest of time, we think
it's best to proceed on both fronts.
You have no idea what's
wrong with my daughter.
- We have several theories.
- What does Dr. House think?
He's-- He had to go home sick.
My daughter may be dying,
and he's gone home with the sniffles?
He's not--
He was the only one who seemed to
have any idea what was wrong with her.
He better be really damn sick.
He is.
Unless you got Vicodin, go away.
House, it's me. I, uh--
Oh, God.
- I don't have--
- No pills,
no egg nog.
What happened to your arm?
Cut myself.
Wilson was wrong about lymphoma.
Kid's not losing any weight,
no night sweats.
- Cuddy send you?
- No,
she doesn't trust
me not to give you pills.
Is she right?
House, these cuts are straight in a row.
You did this on purpose.
Cutting releases endorphins.
Endorphins relieve pain.
You gonna get me some pills?
No.
Then you can leave.
No constitutional symptoms means--
Soon as the kid gets cured,
Cuddy's got no pressure to fold.
You really think she's gonna fold?
Autoimmune fits better than cancer.
But lupus loves kidneys,
usually attacks them first.
- Kidneys are fine, right?
- Yeah.
Take the deal.
You can survive without Vicodin.
After you were shot,
you stayed clean for months.
Yeah, I wonder if it had something
to do with the absence of pain.
Leave that. I want to be able to pour
alcohol on it so I can distract myself.
Then you can rip off the bandage.
- Kid been sick lately?
- There's a history of ear infections.
Say Abigail's immune system
is like a shy guy in a bar.
And the ear infections,
they come in and try to coax him to--
To hell with the metaphor.
You get the point, right?
Nerd gets drunk. Trashes the bar.
One of the autoimmunes
triggered by a minor infection.
Factor in her age,
elevated sed-rate, anemia...
It's Still's disease.
You start her on prednisone,
methotrexate, cyclosporin.
Stop this.
Please.
What'd he say?
Still's disease.
It's chronic, but manageable.
A diagnosis that's virtually
unconfirmable. And with a treatment
that's more dangerous than
what we were considering for lupus.
- How bad is he?
- Are you asking because you care,
or because you're wondering
whether to trust his opinion?
- Both.
- He's detoxing.
In agony.
He started cutting himself.
But he's still House.
I'll order the treatment.
Your plan isn't working.
Two days down, one to go.
Figured I'd show you
how much it isn't working.
Yeah, clearly the drugs
have no hold on you.
We both know that my pride far surpasses
my instinct for self-preservation.
You want to redeem yourself?
Give up now.
And you'll go to jail.
I've done nothing wrong.
Which makes this
your last chance to do me a
kindness before ruining my life forever.
The nausea's bad this time.
You can write me a scrip for
metoclopramide so I can stop puking.
They'd give me that in rehab.
Then you should go to rehab.
I have a patient.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
I know it's little solace,
but he went without pain.
Well, look on the bright side.
At least you don't have to go by Mrs.
Zebalusky anymore.
That's gotta be a relief.
- You know this man?
- I'm sorry. He's sick--
Did you hear my diagnosis on the dwarf?
Still's disease.
Did you even consider
those ear infections,
or you just wrote
it off as a dwarf thing?
You sure he's dead?
Dr. Wilson sometimes misses things.
Trying to embarrass me in front of
grieving widow crosses lines that even--
Right! I'm pathetic.
I'm strung out, I haven't slept,
puking every hour,
and I still out-diagnosed you.
But I'm supposed to
let you decide what's best--
Please leave.
Sorry.
I'm done.
You didn't come in here just to embar-
rass me. You could do that any time.
Stealing Oxy from a dead man.
Yeah, you don't have a problem.
How's the girl?
Much better.
House was right.
It happens.
I thought we could handle this.
Still's disease never crossed my mind.
Don't beat yourself up.
I didn't get it either.
I feel like a mob informant.
You wanna go inside?
Got a cafeteria in there, right?
I can't testify.
Drug addicts hurt the people
around them with their habit.
House has hurt plenty of people,
you included.
He saves lives.
People that no one else can save.
And
no matter how much of an ass he is,
statistically
House is a positive
force in the universe.
The pills let him do that.
Vicodin does not make House a genius.
Whatever he does on the pills,
he can do off.
He's just not willing to try.
I won't testify against him.
Then we'll subpoena you.
And your previous statement
will be read into evidence.
And you will be charged with
interfering with an investigation.
And you will go to jail.
Again, statistically,
better me than him.
Statistically...
the two of you will be in jail.
Dr. Cameron, come quick.
There's something wrong with Abby.
Couldn't be too severe.
Her cardiac alarm didn't go off.
It's not her heart. She's bleeding.
Picking up a scrip, under Zebalusky.
This is, uh, Dr. Wilson's patient.
Yeah.
Wilson's busy right now.
What with Mr. Zebalusky dying in agony
on account of his metastic lung cancer
and not having the
pills to relieve that agony
because of some moron pharmacist.
Sign the book.
Bleeding wasn't a ruptured eardrum,
ear infection, or bleeding disorder.
Her heart rate's climbing.
Blood pressure's dropping.
She's on the verge
of a multi-system failure.
Head CT was clean.
Means it's not a neurological problem.
- Basically we have nothing.
- Cancer is still on the table.
Spinal fluid was negative for lymphoma.
What other--
Leukemia.
We need to do a bone marrow biopsy.
None of the blood
tests suggest leukemia.
Cancer doesn't explain
the collapsed lung.
Unless a small clot
lead to a pulmonary infarct.
It's a long shot.
Autoimmune is way more likely.
It respond to steroids,
which we've given her.
And she got better for a while.
We stopped it too soon.
Because she crashed.
All we're doing is bouncing back
and forth between cancer and autoimmune.
We're going in circles.
Give me half an hour.
Can I have a French fry?
Get your own.
You took the last ones.
What's wrong with you?
I got spinal muscular atrophy.
Guess it's not contagious.
Nice bear.
It's a dog.
It's not Still's.
Steroids helped until the patient
started bleeding
from the ears and mouth.
That's a bear.
His name is Bill. He's a dog.
You win. You can have Vicodin.
Words have set meanings for a reason.
If you see an animal like
Bill and you try to play fetch,
Bill's gonna eat you
because Bill's a bear.
Are you on something?
You got your hands on pain meds.
Bill has fur, four legs, and a collar.
He's a dog.
It's between cancer and autoimmune.
See, that's what we
call a faulty syllogism.
Just because you call Bill
a dog doesn't mean that he is...
a dog.
We gotta x-ray our patient's leg.
Her leg looks fine.
Weird, huh?
Why aren't you detoxing?
Will power.
What--what--
Normal's not normal
if you're not normal.
Did you just take a pill?
No.
So how does a dwarf have
completely normal growth plates?
It's impossible.
We must be missing something.
How many pills have you taken?
Not nearly as many as I'm gonna take.
Forgotten how delicious they were.
I didn't give them to him.
Can we forget my vices,
get back to my virtues?
We were missing the fact that
just because we called her
a dwarf doesn't mean she is a dwarf.
Everyone assumed she
was because of her mother.
There's not test for CHH dwarfism. So
she lost an identity,
but we gained a symptom.
If she doesn't have
skeletal dwarfism, then
her short stature must be
caused by growth hormone deficiency.
And something's wrong
with her pituitary gland.
And based on her size,
it's been wrong for a while.
So what connects a
long-term pituitary issue
with problems in the lungs,
liver, and pancreas?
Oh, you guys and your bickering.
Cancer versus autoimmune.
Obviously you think it's something else.
Nope. I think it's both.
Langerhans cell histiocytosis.
Also known as, "you got your
cancer in my autoimmune" disease.
The immune component responded
to the Still's treatment
lead to the short-term improvement.
The cancer portion didn't.
We dismissed this earlier because
there were no neurological symptoms.
Yeah. It's not your fault.
The only neurological
symptom was her height.
Who could've noticed?
This is your pituitary gland.
And this is the granuloma
that's been crushing it.
No pituitary equals no growth
hormone equals about that much.
She's not a dwarf?
Just hormonally challenged.
What about my mom?
Your mom's the real deal.
But you're just a tiny little poser.
Your recent ear infections
caused your body to release
a cascade of the same
cells that made the granuloma.
They attacked your lungs,
moved down to your liver,
then hitched a ride
over to your pancreas.
We can nuke them with
a mild course of chemo and then
remove the granuloma.
And then what?
What will happen to her then?
Let me see if I can make this clear.
This pill represents...
a pill.
And my mouth represents
your daughter's mouth.
We deposit the pill in the month.
You may never be tall
enough to play in the WNBA,
but you'll be able to
post up your mom no problem.
What if I don't take the pills?
What if you remove the thing in my head
and give me the chemo,
but not the pills?
Would I still get better?
Your body needs growth hormone
from lots of things. Like...
to grow.
I like who I am now.
Nobody your age likes who they are now.
I do.
You like needing help when
you want something off a high shelf?
Not being able to press an
elevator button above the eighth floor?
Having to smell ass every
time you stand in line?
You don't need growth hormone. It's
just your ticket out of the freak show.
Can't you deliver a diagnosis
without making her feel
that her life isn't worth living?
I'm trying to help her.
- You're trying to make her taller.
- Not too tall.
Just tall enough to wipe her own butt.
- Are you high?
- Higher than you.
If my daughter doesn't want to choose
the easy path, I won't force her to.
Then you're a lousy mom.
- You want your daughter to be a freak.
- We're not freaks.
- You want her to overcome adversity.
- Yes.
Then why stop at height?
Poke a stick in her eye.
Imagine how interesting she'll be then.
Being little is not the same as--
You and I have found out that
being normal sucks 'cause we're freaks.
The advantage of being a
freak is it makes your stronger.
Now, how strong do you
really want her to have to be?
Tell her what you have to tell her.
Tell her you lied.
Even if you didn't.
This is who you were supposed to be.
You hate normal.
It's not that simple.
If I grow,
I'll fade into the background.
I'll be boring.
We'll get you a funny hat.
You could never be boring.
You want me to be like everybody else?
I want you to have what I can't.
Abigail agreed--
Abigail agreed to take growth hormone.
Who's Abigail?
Your non-dwarf dwarf patient.
Oh, good.
Then the growth hormone makes sense.
- Christmas Eve.
- Yeah, I know.
Deal expires tomorrow.
You have plans for tonight?
You worried I'm gonna
be popping more pills?
Thought you might
prefer people over pills.
Hey, Mom.
I guess you guys are
already up at Aunt Sarah's.
I'm sure Dad's in the egg nog
and you're probably suffering
through another dried out turkey.
Just wanted to say Merry Christmas.
Are you okay?
I called three times.
I'm ready to take the deal.
Well, that's off the table.
- The clock doesn't expire until--
- Got new evidence.
We don't need Wilson anymore.
The thing about addicts is, uh...
no matter how smart they are,
they are dumb when it comes to drugs.
So, uh, I've been keeping
an eye on the pharmacy log.
Seems some patient
of Wilson's named Zebalusky
managed to
pick up his Oxy prescription
after he died.
Jesus walks, huh?
Merry Christmas.
Transcript: FRM - Synchro: jh26
www.sub-way.fr