So you want me to explain
how you just lost?
Or do you wanna stare
at the board your full...
three minutes?
Cling to hope?
Come on. It's called speed chess.
Good bye.
Good game.
I said good game.
What are you doing?
Stop that, son! Stop that!
Back away from him. Back away!
Call 911. Get an ambulance!
Tell them to send two!
My head's gonna explode!
Transcript: swsub.com
Sync: jh26
- Your head still hurt?
- You a moron?
Nate.
I'm clutching my head in pain,
and he asks if it hurts?
What are you, some kind of med student?
You look like you still
have theme birthday parties.
Sorry.
Any problems concentrating
in school lately?
Besides the dreams of running my tongue
along my French teacher's breasts?
No, I'm doing quite great.
The rage and pain could
be caused by a parasite.
- Does he eat a lot of sushi?
- No.
Uh, he was a vegetarian
until just a few months ago.
Any changes in behavior
since the new diet?
No.
He's been this way
since he became a teenager.
It doesn't matter how much I
yell or punish, he's still gonna say...
Yeah, let's all shed a tear
for poor little Nate's mother.
Any more stupid questions?
Nate.
I hate this kid.
I like this kid.
You haven't met him.
I know you hate him.
What more do I need to know?
The kid's not a cliché. Anybody
can get into a fight after losing.
It takes real creativity
to beat up someone you just beat.
The pain's not limited to his head.
The rest is bumps and bruises
accounted for by the 17 fights
he's been in this semester.
- Concussion?
MRI was clean. No frontal lobe tumor.
And the tox screen showed
no trace of coke or amphetamines.
Nate went medieval on the other kid.
Could be...
Hold on.
I'm having a moment.
This...
This could be Foreman's last time
mistakenly suggesting
adrenal gland tumor.
Which could create excess adrenaline.
Causes the head pain and rage.
But not the personality disorder.
There is no personality disorder.
He's a teenager.
Being a teenager excuses
the odd inappropriate comment.
This kid say anything appropriate?
He's having cluster headaches.
Probably been having them for years.
Question is, what's causing them?
If it were just a cluster headache,
he'd have swelling around the eyes.
ER gave him ibuprofen for the pain.
Useless for this pain. But it
could have knocked down the swelling.
Best bet is a vascular problem.
Normal treatment for cluster headaches
is steroids, which the ER also gave him.
He's still in pain. Which means...
Normal treatment is
called normal treatment
because sometimes you
have to use abnormal treatment.
Start him on blood thinners
and give his noggin Transcranial
Magnetic Stimulation.
Don't you dare...
touch that acerbic wit.
50 bucks to whichever of
you steps up and treats this brat.
Not the kid's fault, he's sick.
Fine. You do it.
No way. He's your brat.
I'll do it.
But I've got a job interview after work.
Anything comes up later,
you guys handle it.
- Need a peer recommendation?
- Thanks.
Cameron's should suffice.
This isn't gonna
turn me into some, like,
drooling vegetable
that wets his pants, is it?
It's safe.
The magnetic pulses activate nerve cells
which will hopefully
squelch the head pain.
Is there anything you
can do about the other pain?
From the fights?
Yeah, I mean, my face, my shoulder.
My stomach.
I mean, I can barely bend my fingers.
You're already on pain meds.
Nothing more I can do.
Sure you can, man.
Tell your homies to quit stomping on me.
I'll get the word out
that you're a great guy.
So, do people watch
what they say around you?
- Because I'm black?
- No, because you're gay.
Cluster headaches can persist for years,
cause irritability or
even hostility towards others.
You mean, the illness
is affecting his personality?
- If these treatments work, it could...
- Change him?
Yeah.
Oh, thank God.
Oh, you must think I'm awful. Here
my son's lying in a hospital bed and...
I- I'm pretty sure I get it.
I thought I was a bad mother.
And I hated myself.
Because I hated him.
What have you got
for me this fine morning?
Blood thinners and TMS had no effect.
It's not cluster headaches.
- You accusing the symptoms of lying?
- Could be hemochromatosis.
Wouldn't account for
the personality disorder.
What about hypothyroidism?
He's not getting
aggressive and lethargic,
he's getting aggressive and aggressiver.
What about ruptured dermoid cyst?
Sorry.
Just got dizzy there.
I was expecting to turn right.
It's Foreman's turn to be shot down.
The thing that Cameron said.
Way to think outside the box.
But no fat in the ventricles.
It's cluster headaches.
Normal treatment didn't work.
Abnormal treatment didn't work.
Good point, Foreman.
The treatments don't always work.
Symptoms never lie.
The only approved treatment left
for cluster headaches is brain surgery.
- And that's not even a guarantee.
- Back off, Foreman!
If the approved treatment doesn't work,
we go with an unapproved treatment.
Something on your mind?
Because you totally can't tell.
I had a job interview lined
up at New York Mercy yesterday.
Hospital for Manhattan's glitterati.
Big coup.
Your homies must be kvelling.
Didn't happen,
because apparently I called to cancel.
I don't remember making that call.
You think I have neurological issue?
Yes.
- Why are you jerking me around?
- It wasn't me.
Yeah. It was one of the other petty,
socially repressed asses I work for.
Maybe it was Ashton Kutcher.
If you want me to stay,
tell me you want me to stay.
Would it matter?
No, but it'd be the
adult way to handle it.
If the adult way doesn't work,
why bother with it?
I've been totally professional!
Gave two weeks notice,
continued to work cases.
Scheduled my interviews on my own time.
You have no right
to screw with my future.
You're gonna be all whiny during
the differential diagnoses, aren't you?
It wasn't me.
I only sabotage people
I consider worth it.
You are one evil, cunning woman.
It's a massive turn-on.
You girls can gossip later.
What are you talking about?
You called New York Mercy to
have Foreman's job interview killed.
When I said,
"You girls can gossip later,"
I was throwing you out,
but in a polite way.
Well, I take it you're
off your antidepressants.
Ah, you're deflecting.
Only I'm allowed to do that.
Does Foreman actually think I did that?
No, just me.
But I know something he doesn't.
- I didn't do it.
- Why would I do it?
- Do you want him to leave?
- No.
- Were you planning on doing something?
- I'm waiting for board approval.
But if he takes the job, there's
nothing to be done. You had to stop him.
Wasn't me.
What are you doing?
Looking for a tell.
Rapid eye blink, twitch of the lips.
Send in Nurse Unger when
you pass her on your way out.
Almost forgot.
I need to give a 16-year-old magic
mushrooms to treat a cluster headache.
- Is that cool?
- Yeah, no problem.
I was being sarcastic.
Wouldn't look that way
in the court transcript.
Mushrooms have psilocybins
that work on cluster headaches.
It's either that, or cutting into his
brain and going on a fishing expedition.
I assume you've considered
he could have a psychogenic experience.
Possibly suffer a
fit of severe paranoia.
Well, I have now.
Yeah, it's definitely better
that the dean of medicine prescribes it
instead of an unhinged doctor with a
history of drug use. Takes the stink off
if the patient decides to
put on a cape and fly off the roof.
Low dose. No more than ten milligrams.
Tightly controlled setting.
And make sure the
mother signs off on it.
Party on, Garth.
And don't stand in Foreman's way.
It's just wrong.
New research shows that a chemical
component in the mushrooms can be...
Yeah, lots of technical medical stuff.
So when do I get 'em?
I went to college.
I know about mushrooms.
A friend of a friend
shot himself in the foot.
They're not giving me a gun, Enid!
Sign the consent form.
We'll be monitoring him,
but cardiac arrest is possible.
Big E...
small N...
And if the mushrooms don't work?
The next step would
be a type of brain surgery.
- Oh, God.
- Pain's gettin' worse.
Need 'shrooms now!
- Oh, yeah.
- Nate, how's the pain?
It's Skippy! The bush kangaroo!
Your head, Nate.
We need to know how the pain is.
What I got here
is the opposite of pain.
That means you're suffering from cluster
headaches. Which means, hopefully...
Man, you're hot.
- She's making me horny.
- Deal with it.
You can't get me stoned,
then not close the deal.
- Shut up.
- Take it easy. He's not well.
You'll regret saying no. Check it out.
- Oh, for God's sake.
- Hold it.
What the hell are you doing?
He has undersized testes.
His other secondary sexual
characteristics are normal.
If you wanna curry favor with me, avoid
discussions of other men's testicles.
Thanks.
Focus on phrases like... "You
were right about the cluster headaches."
But wrong about what caused them.
Vascular problem in a major
artery wouldn't cause hypogonadism.
Okay, what causes rage, headaches,
personality disorder, and hypogonadism?
- Where's Foreman?
- He's mad at me.
- Why?
- No reason.
Yeah, that makes sense.
The male genitals are controlled
by the hypothalamus and pituitary gland.
We're not talking about Foreman anymore.
The kid's being pummeled at school.
A couple blows to the head
could cause hypothalamic lesions.
We ever gonna talk about
what happens when Foreman's gone?
If this were an employee-owned
airline in Scandinavia, yes.
It's not lesions. His temperature would
be all over the map. Symptoms don't lie.
He's gone in less than a week
and you haven't even read a résumé.
Doesn't even need to.
The two of us can handle it.
Craniopharyngioma fits the symptoms.
Biopsy the brat's pituitary.
And let the record show I was
right about the cluster headaches.
- Forget it.
- It's a straightforward procedure.
We thread an endoscopic
tube up through the nostril...
And cut something
out of my brain? No way.
If it's a tumor, it could kill you.
Just give me more 'shrooms, okay?
I'll be fine.
You only need my consent, right?
Yeah, but it'll be a lot easier if he...
Do whatever you have to do.
You don't touch me, all right?
You can touch me. Just not my brain.
Nate, you gotta do this.
I can't take it anymore.
My God, Mom! Save me the
melodramatic hand- wringing, okay?
Loosen up! Get yourself coited.
I'm gonna give him a sedative.
You're decent-looking, Dr. Skippy.
Why don't you take her for a ride?
Nate...
Are you in pain?
His heart rate's normal.
Respiration's even.
What's happening?
What's the matter with him?
He's jaundiced.
His liver's shutting down.
We started him on sodium
polystyrene sulfonate.
His liver's operating at
about 20% and deteriorating fast.
Which means he'll be dead long before
Foreman turns in his parking pass.
So, what causes personality disorder,
head pain,
blah blah blah, and liver failure?
Liver failure can cause hypogonadism,
head pain.
Altered mental status leads
to the personality disorder and rage.
All we need to do is figure
out what caused the liver failure.
Yes... also, we need to
figure out how symptoms yesterday
can be caused by liver failure today.
If his liver's failing now,
it wasn't great yesterday.
If it wasn't operating at capacity,
it could have caused...
- Don't sneak up on a person like that.
- I'm listening.
Well, listening doesn't help me.
Okay. Let's go with the
liver and a time machine theory.
- Foreman, what causes liver problems?
- Wilson's disease.
No. Ceruloplasmin's normal.
No enlargement and no palpable mass,
so no cancer.
Could be a narrowing of the bile ducts.
Primary Sclerosing Cholangitis.
Most liver damage begins with
what we put in our bodies. Foreman?
Angry teen... alcohol.
No, blood tests were negative.
No signs of drug use or acetaminophen
poisoning in his tox screen.
Maybe the water was contaminated.
His mother would also be sick.
Sounded like someone with back.
Go.
We'll try and muddle through
without your blank stare to guide us.
So if it's not the bad things he's
putting in, what about the good things?
He was raised a vegetarian.
Was raised. Means he's all grown up.
Or he's not a vegetarian anymore.
He started eating red
meat a few months ago.
Unless he's been buying cuts of mad cow,
his body would have
no problem metabolizing it.
It would if he had an OTC deficiency.
Body can't metabolize nitrogen,
damages the liver.
Run a hamburger test.
It's exactly what it sounds like.
Stuff him full of meat,
wait for his ammonia levels to spike.
I'll double your salary.
Chase and Cameron would
mutiny if they found out.
Chase and Cameron wouldn't be
heading up their own diagnostic group.
You'll work in parallel with House.
It'll be your practice.
Separate staff, separate cases.
Complete autonomy.
I've only been doing
this for three years.
Three years under House.
No better training.
And when that case comes
along that I can't figure out?
You know who I'd have to go to.
Or you can just let that patient die.
That's completely up to you.
No.
Why?
He's evil.
He didn't sabotage your interview.
- How do you know?
- Because I did.
I didn't.
You believed me...
means you're not sure House did it.
Well, somebody did it.
Somebody here did it.
I can't work here.
This isn't a medical procedure.
This is just about Doogie
making me eat garbage.
We need to see how your
liver processes the proteins.
Then get me a steak, some roast beef.
What if I brought
him something from home?
It has to be prepared here
so we know there's no chemicals
or preservatives that
could affect the test results.
I'm not eating anything prepared
by $5-an-hour immigrant hospital cooks
in hairnets.
- Shut up!
Either you start eating,
or I'm gonna strap you to this
bed and shove these down your throat
one by one... got it?
You can't get mad at me. I'm sick.
You're supposed to feel bad for me.
- Nurse, full set of body restraints.
- Yes, Doctor.
Trust me.
It'll be a lot less
messy if you do it yourself.
You killed Foreman's job interview.
Why would I...
Somebody did.
Wasn't me, and it wasn't House,
which means it has to be somebody
who thought he was protecting him.
Which means it has to be somebody who
actually likes House. Which means it's
either you or the weird night
janitor who wears his pants backwards.
I want Foreman to leave.
House has to realize he needs
someone who stands up to him.
Cameron's in love with him, Chase
is afraid of him, and I enable him.
- House needs limits.
- I give him...
You authorize magic mushrooms.
House is a six-year-old who
thinks he's better off without parents.
A few tummy aches
after dinners of ice cream
and ketchup might do him some good.
You're lying.
An enabler doesn't conspire against,
an enabler enables.
- What?
- You're paranoid.
You made that call.
And because of that call, you basically
guaranteed Foreman's out of here.
I thought it would be fun
to work on my boat with him.
And you went shirtless
because skin cancer looks cool.
Well, I realize I got burnt.
I'm not too worried about that.
It's these white marks, you know?
Lie down.
I mean, that boat has all sorts of lead
paint, and there's chemicals everywhere.
When Daddy works on his boat,
does he have a cooler
with lots of brown
bottles with long necks?
And does Daddy like to lie down
on his boat and go nap-nap in the sun?
What... what the hell?
I will give you this for the...
$1.41 in your pocket.
Wait, how could you know...
A psychic once told me that I'm psychic.
One of these quarters is Canadian.
Give me back my syringe.
Hamburger stress test showed
no change in his ammonia levels.
Liver's properly converting
the ammonia into urea.
He doesn't have OTC deficiency.
- Welcome back.
- Sorry.
I shouldn't have been taking
my problems out on the patient.
Or on me. Apology accepted.
Starve him.
What are we looking for?
Diabetic steatosis
would screw up his liver.
Starve him overnight and
see if his blood sugar pops.
We mess with his blood sugar,
we could set off another rage.
Not a problem. You can take him.
- I want something to eat!
- Honey, please don't.
What happened?
I was just trying to get a urine sample,
and he went crazy.
I need to eat!
You're not sticking anything else in me.
- It's just a few more hours.
- You're gonna hurt yourself.
I'm gonna hurt you!
As soon as we get a urine sample,
we can leave you alone.
You want your sample?
Here's your damn sample!
Nate, don't.
Oh, my God.
Nate, you need to get back into bed.
Right now.
Chem panel and urinalysis
confirms the bloody urine was caused
by kidney failure.
He's on dialysis. He's gonna
need it for the rest of his life.
Which is shortening as we speak.
We are looking at a Chinese menu, and we
have got symptoms from too many columns.
They're going to overcharge us.
Multiple organ failure
could mean primary HIV infection.
That would mean someone
agreed to sleep with him.
- Plus his serology is negative.
- His uric acid's slightly elevated.
10% of males in this
country have elevated...
So we're only gonna pay attention
to abnormal abnormalities?
We've been stuffing him with
meat and his kidneys are shot.
Of course his uric acid...
Could be hepatic fibrosis or MCADD.
The brat's got a genetic disorder.
Get the sequencing primers. See
if it's one of the ones we can treat.
I can draw some blood,
but then I gotta run.
Job interview?
You gonna stop me if it is?
You do the nurse stuff,
they'll do the doctor stuff.
This a blood test
for a marriage license?
Plan on kidnapping me
to Massachusetts or Canad...
What did you give him?
- Are you treating him for something?
- Sedative.
- Did he need a sedative?
- I did.
Just shutting him up so I
can draw some of his blood in peace.
You walked in with that.
You didn't even give him a chance.
- People are what they are.
- He's sick.
The rudeness isn't his fault.
If he had tuberculosis,
it wouldn't be his fault either.
But I still wouldn't
let him cough on me.
Where are you going?
The lab. We're testing our
patient's blood for hereditary...
Cuddy thinks I sabotaged Foreman's
interview. She's gonna fire me.
I don't believe it.
She said it was unprofessional and...
No, I mean I literally don't believe it.
Cuddy wouldn't fire
you for something like that.
Which means either she lied to you,
or you're lying to me.
You so would have fallen
for that three years ago.
You were looking for a reaction. You
were looking for me to feel bad for you.
To save your skin.
But how am I gonna save you?
Unless...
you think I'm the one who really did it.
Cuddy's logic was Foreman's
valuable to House. I care about House.
Ergo, I would do anything to save him.
And your logic was... I care
about House as much as you do, ergo...
It wasn't me.
- I don't care about House.
- I don't believe you.
No one does.
House is nothing more than my boss.
Foreman's nothing more than a colleague.
- You're lying.
- Everyone does.
But it wasn't me.
No markers for hepatic fibrosis.
And nothing for MCADD.
Foreman's interview
in New York got screwed up.
I heard.
Foreman thought it was House,
House thought it was Cuddy.
Cuddy thought it was Wilson,
Wilson thought it was me.
And you think it was me?
You think I sabotaged Foreman?
- I don't even want him here.
- I know.
Then why would I do...
I think you sabotaged Foreman
just to sabotage Foreman.
So everyone's a suspect because everyone
wants to help House. Except for me.
I'm a suspect because I'm a petty,
vindictive jerk?
You actually think I
would do something like that?
- It was someone.
- It wasn't me.
Negative for Von Gierke disease.
And it's Tuesday.
I know.
- I like you.
- I know.
See you next Tuesday.
Found something.
He's got a partial
HPRT enzyme deficiency.
Means he could have
Kelley-Seegmiller Syndrome.
But it's a partial deficiency.
So it may not be Kelley-Seegmiller.
Yes. Those are the two options.
It is or it isn't.
Kelley-Seegmiller explains
the aggressive personality.
If he had Kelley-Seegmiller,
he wouldn't just be aggressive,
he'd be self-mutilating.
Chewing his lips, banging his head.
Lovely disease.
Degenerative, fatal, incurable.
I wonder if that's why
Cameron's on the "Not" side.
That and the fact
that symptoms don't lie.
Kelley-Seegmiller carriers
self-mutilate when they're stressed.
He's in the ICU with a
failing liver and no kidneys.
Yeah, his life is sweet.
His vegetarian diet could have
limited the purines in his system,
slowing the disease's progress.
- So let's speed it up.
- Why?
So you two kids will stop fighting.
Also, I don't feel like
waiting for respiratory failure.
Chase, find some way for
the mother to get lost for a while.
I'm going to stress this
kid until he bites off a finger.
They move me to geriatrics?
- Who are you?
- Dr. McCaney.
The man who's gonna kick
your ass all over this chessboard.
Yeah, well, I'm too weak to...
Bite yourself, yeah.
You need some liquid energy.
Now, if you consent, I'm gonna
give you this shot of adrenaline.
I don't wanna play.
Aside from being indicative
of pituitary issues
and certain kinds of genetic disorders,
small testicles also indicate...
that you're a big chicken.
Please don't make
me do the sound effect.
You're not gonna goad me into playing.
Didn't think I'd have to.
Thought you'd just jump at
the chance of humiliating someone.
Age before cripple.
I'm white.
It... is... on!
Bird's opening. Passive approach.
Sign of a coward.
Sicilian defense. Sign of an idiot.
Arrogance has to be earned.
Tell me what you've done to earn yours.
I can walk.
I don't bleed out of my penis.
Check.
You know, it's a real thin line between
tortured genius and awkward kid
who can't get girls because he's creepy.
Why are you doing this?
To stress you out.
Check.
Yeah, but why?
I'd tell you, but I figure it's
more stressful if you don't know why.
Yeah, well...
I'm not feeling too stressed.
You know that no one likes you, right?
- Yeah, well, anybody like you?
- You're dying.
Check.
Your move.
Care to lay down your king?
You can't win.
You can pin my queen.
My knight to E7.
Your king to H8.
Sacrifice rook takes pawn.
Bishop blocks.
Queen to H5. Checkmate.
Save what's left of your dignity.
Lay down your king.
Crap.
He's having a seizure.
- Four milligrams IV lorazepam.
- Right away.
I hate this kid.
I like this kid.
Did you get the job?
They're gonna let me know.
Kelley-Seegmiller didn't
cause this seizure.
So we've got one more symptom,
one less diagnosis.
I assume they're gonna
call for references?
- Did you give 'em my name?
- No.
Amyloidosis can cause seizures,
and the protein buildup
could cause organ failure.
Wouldn't alter his personality.
Whose name did you give?
My last boss.
That can't look good.
I hate this kid.
What if we're not dealing
with one condition?
What if it's multiple conditions?
Uh-uh, it's gotta be one.
It's always one.
Nothing explains this
constellation of symptoms.
We've gotta be missing something.
Maybe the kid lied about some
medication. Maybe he's hiding something.
- Why would he be hiding something?
- I don't know, because he's evil?
What if he is?
What if the symptoms lied?
There.
Now all we're looking at is a simple,
evil jerk with amyloidosis.
- You're not being objective.
- Amyloidosis was your idea.
You were right,
it doesn't fit the symptoms.
Yeah, it does. Look.
You crossed it off because
you wanna hate the kid.
And you can't hate
him if he's a victim...
You want him to be a victim because
you wanna believe that people are good.
And if they're not,
it's gotta be a chemical problem.
Except they're not, and it's not.
Flush him with immunosuppressants,
get a biopsy to confirm,
and find him a marrow donor.
What will happen to him?
Substances called amyloid proteins
build up in the body's organs,
shutting them down.
It's a fairly rare disease.
And I'm afraid it can be fatal.
So do you operate or
something to take them out?
He needs a bone marrow transplant.
Dr. Cameron is searching the donor bank.
We should test you as well.
When you first told me he was sick...
I was...
happy.
Relieved.
Now...
Nate, I'm gonna take a small
piece of nerve from your ankle.
- Let me know if you feel any pain.
- I'm burning up.
Couldn't you just knock
me out like you did last time?
Wish I could.
But your body has to be clear
so it's ready for a marrow transplant.
Hey, Dr. X...
I know you've busted
ass trying to save me.
It's all right.
I wasn't gonna thank you.
I was gonna tell you
you really suck at this.
We're doing our best.
That's sort of my point.
Your best really sucks.
Nerve biopsy was clean.
No evidence of amyloidosis.
It was your idea.
Don't give up on it so fast.
He's running a fever.
If it's two conditions,
one of them's gotta be an infection.
We should start him on antibiotics,
see what clears up, what doesn't.
Is he having trouble breathing?
Yeah, he has mucus in
his chest from an infection.
Could also be an amyloid buildup.
Keep him on immunosuppressants
and biopsy somewhere else, his sinuses.
Look, you got two choices.
Engage me in a futile argument then do
what I asked, or just do what I asked.
You're not ready.
There was a third choice.
Don't do what I asked.
You could have defied me, stuck
the kid on antibiotics. But you didn't.
Because you still trust
my judgment more than your own.
You sabotaged Foreman's job interview,
didn't you?
Foreman's already been over this.
It wasn't me.
Everybody's chasing ghosts over this.
Which means either nobody did it, or
somebody wants everybody chasing ghosts.
Now, who does that sound like?
And why would I do that?
Because as long as Foreman
thought you were guilty,
he was gonna be useless around here.
You know,
sometimes I forget why I hired you.
You cost him a good
opportunity and gained nothing.
I cost him a crappy opportunity.
New York Mercy's where you go to
treat boils and cysts and build a 401K.
If you want him to stay, tell him.
I don't. And there'd be no point.
You do.
And the point would be to
make him feel like he's wanted.
He doesn't need that.
All right, then. It'd make
him feel like maybe you weren't evil.
He needs that.
Talk to Foreman.
We dumped one symptom.
But forgot to add one.
Revenge time, Nate.
Are you...
Yes! I am.
Black or white?
Just limp away.
He doesn't wanna play. Leave him alone.
Pick one, or this comes out.
And for all you know,
this is really important.
- Stop it!
- That hurts, right?
Which is odd,
because I'm really enjoying this.
You hold the pieces that way
because you can't bend your thumb.
Because your bones
have formed abnormally.
Thanks to all the crap that's
been pushing its way in between them.
Actually,
this stuff isn't important at all.
Your doctors said he
needs immunosuppressants.
They're idiots. It's not amyloidosis.
It's iron.
He's got hemochromatosis.
The body absorbs iron from food, but
can't process it. Can't get rid of it.
And idle iron is the devil's playground.
It builds up in the organs and joints,
whacking them in the process.
Caused all of the symptoms.
Including something
that wasn't a symptom.
Those body aches,
they were not from the fighting.
- His personality issues?
- Sorry.
The iron's innocent on that count.
Your kid's a jerk.
And yeah, it's probably your fault.
Although, if you'd stayed
off the meat like your mom said,
you'd have half as much iron,
and be twice less almost dead.
Oh, nurse!
This patient is bleeding
for some reason.
Is he going to be okay?
He'll need dialysis.
He'll have to get his blood drained
every few months for
the rest of his life.
But my condolences. It's going
to be a long and annoying life.
And I wouldn't have taken your bishop.
I'd have moved my queen to D6,
defusing the threat.
Then rook to E8,
attacking the king's pawn.
I'd have lost the exchange,
but won the game.
I know.
I was bluffing.
And that's why...
you lost.
Little jerk.
You just here to watch,
or you got something to say?
Still running the new
biopsy for amyloidosis?
Yeah, but still nothing.
Run the test again.
Recheck your results.
Looks like you're in for an all-nighter.
Transcript: swsub.com
Sync: jh26