Most prisons
manufacture things:
license plates, clothes,
computer chips.
ln Oz, we do one thing
better than anybody:
revenge.
Yeah, we churn out
revenge
with greater precision
than a Ford assembly line.
We're world renowned.
And l'm happy
to say for us,
revenge is
a growth industry.
What the fuck are
you all looking at?
All right, warden
wants to see you.
We believe you arranged
to have Bian Yixue killed.
And your belief is
based on what?
On Bian coming to me
and saying that you threatened him.
McManus, do l look
stupid to you?
You warned me if anything happened to
those illegals l'd be held accountable.
And then the next day l
go out and grease the guy?
Fuck that!
Maybe you grease him assuming l'll think
you're too smart to.
And maybe somebody
set me up.
We have no evidence.
Only the word
of a dead man.
Thanks for arranging
my stay in the cage.
l ain't gonna forget it.
So much for fucking Plan A.
And that's why they
call it Plan A, Chucky,
'cause there's
still a Plan B, C, D,
all the way to fucking Z
if we need it.
We ain't got time to go through
the whole fucking alphabet.
This cocksucker's gonna
make a move on us, and soon.
Hey, yo, Glynn.
My shower don't work, man.
l'm fucking stinking
in here, man. Come on, man!
Warden, l got some
big news for you.
You gotta hear me out.
l got serious 411 here.
Warden!
You gotta let me out.
l gotta talk to you.
Can you hear?
You wanted to see me?
l've got a proposition.
- Have you padded him down?
- Yes, sir.
Close the door,
but stay close by.
All right.
What?
l know me and you we've had
some bad shit between us, right?
And l know you're planning on keeping
me in solitary for the rest of my life.
See, but l can't be in solitary
for the rest of my life
'cause l'll be
a fucking zombie,
- especially after being on the outside.
- Get to the point.
Put me back in Em City,
and in return
l'll be your eyes
and l'll be your ears.
- An informant?
- Yeah.
Whatever you need to know,
l'll find it out.
- And your loyalty to El Norte?
- Fuck 'em.
lt was fucking Hernandez
who tried to get me killed,
put me in this
fucking shithole.
You are in this shithole because you
are the lowest form of animal life.
Do you understand me?
So your answer's no?
My answer's yes.
You're also
the perfect snitch.
You got busted going
into Mexico?
What are you,
stupid or what, Alvarez?
Spic and span, Alvarez.
Bring me back
some pussy, man.
Miguel Alvarez. l was wondering
when you'd come to see me.
You know, a lot's
happened since l escaped.
Hernandez is dead.
And that makes you feel how?
Happy.
l hated that
fucking cocksucker.
Honesty.
l like honesty.
But l hear sometimes
you're too honest.
Look, man,
l don't give a fuck.
You in charge now.
That's all you, man.
l just want back in.
Tell me what l gotta do.
You see that man over there?
Burr Redding?
- Yeah.
- Kill him.
''Vengeance is mine,''
sayeth the Lord.
That's right.
According to the Bible,
revenge is the exclusive
property of God Almighty.
But if God admits
to using revenge,
and if God
can only do good,
does that mean
revenge is good?
Does that mean if
we are made in God's image,
then revenge becomes
not an act of hate, but a holy crusade?
A blessed thing?
All right.
Next item, Gloria.
The Wygert Corporation
has asked us to participate
in testing a new drug
that they're developing.
l'm against using
prisoners as guinea pigs.
Participation
would be voluntary.
Why would one of these
jackasses volunteer?
Benefit humanity?
Come on.
Wygert has also contacted
the governor,
who's agreed to reduce the sentences
of those prisoners
who cooperate in the experiment.
Jeez, what does this drug do?
Cure cancer?
No, it's actually designed to reduce
overcrowding in prisons.
lnstead of serving the time
he's sentenced,
the criminal would take a pill and age
the same number of years.
- Age? What do you mean, like grow old?
- Yes.
- This is real?
- Widespread use is a decade away,
but the tests we do here
will be the preliminary findings
upon which further research
will be based,
until the FDA approves.
Let me get this straight. lf a 20-
year-old is supposed to serve 30 years,
the drug physically transforms his body
into that of a 50-year-old?
Yes.
And he goes free.
There-- there are,
of course, dangers.
Several of the lab animals developed
heart problems, tumors, two died.
We're not completely sure
how the drug interacts with humans,
what rate you would age or if you would
age more years than you're supposed to.
The risk is great.
The sacrifice is great.
That's why the reward
is great, too.
Beecher,
you gonna sign up?
l don't know.
My daughter needs me
full time, but...
what's it gonna be like for her,
me coming out
looking older than my grandfather?
- You?
- No, l can't.
l'm in for life.
Only pill they could
give me is cyanide.
Norma and l are
getting married.
lt'd be nice to have
a normal life together,
but l'm afraid to die.
Yo, you stay in here,
you got no guarantees you live. l'm in.
Me too. l'll take a tumor
over this place any day.
The program is immoral.
lt's unnatural.
l know, but still,
my father had a stroke.
l'd like to be with him
before he dies.
- Oh!
- Hey, stud!
These kitchen whites
you're wearing are so sexy.
- l just love a man in uniform.
- No...
- Look, not here. Not now.
- Why? You got a headache?
l told you, we can't be
doing this anymore. lt's fucking crazy.
And l told you
it's up to me when we stop.
l could go
to the warden.
That'd sure stop me
from fucking you.
Of course, then l'd
have to find someone else,
someone as handsome as you.
God.
Hey, l know.
How about your brother, Cyril?
All right.
Today you're gonna
play the little Dutch boy
who stuck his finger
in the dike.
Mm-hmm.
Listen, Brenda.
The candy came yesterday.
lt was very good.
Let's go,
you fucking 'tard.
l especially liked
the chocolate with the nuts.
Let go of him, Cyril!
Break it up!
l'll fucking kill you!
Settle down!
Cyril's behavior continues
to be erratic.
l think that we should seriously
consider
transferring him
to the Conley lnstitute.
Separating him from his brother
will make him worse.
Yeah, but then he's not
gonna be our problem.
How about that rain check?
- Huh?
- Dinner? What are you doing tonight?
l'm working late.
Dr. Prestopnik has a charity event.
- Tomorrow night?
- Maybe. We'll see.
Time is just so fucked up,
especially here in Oz.
You start thinking about
the time that you've wasted
and the time
that you have left to serve
that you have left to live.
Look...
l heard about what you're doing,
testing this new drug.
You gotta help me and my brother
get out of this place.
Please, Gloria,
make me old.
- O'Reily's not a viable candidate.
- Why not?
Because inmates in this program have
to be eligible for parole.
O'Reily's in for life,
and so is his brother.
l can petition the commissioner
to make an exception.
lf he's gonna listen to anybody about
the O'Reilys, it's gonna be me.
- Why the fuck do you want to help them?
- Humanitarian reasons.
Humanitarian and Ryan O'Reily don't
belong in the same sentence.
- Would you talk to her?
- Gloria--
l'm willing to give the guy a chance.
Why can't you?
- l've given him plenty of chances.
- Sometimes you're so blind.
You put O'Reily
in this program,
l'm gonna do everything
in my power to shut it the fuck down!
l swear to God!
Five of you will
be given the drug.
Five of you will get
a harmless placebo.
Once a week you'll
receive another dosage
and another complete
physical examination
in order to monitor
your health
and the progress
of your aging.
Are there any questions?
Let's go.
Take it, Cyril.
- l don't like the medicine.
- Come on. Take it.
My Uncle Bilbo
once said,
''Revenge is a dish
best served cold.''
Meaning, l guess,
if the person plotting revenge
goes into it
all hot and lathered,
he's likely
to go home hungry.
But the guy who approaches his goal
with a cool, clear eye,
he has himself
a feast.
Bon appetit.
Augustus Hill.
How you doing, brother?
What can l do for you, Vahue?
The answer is no.
Why you gonna be like that, man?
You and me got history.
- Yeah, and it's ancient.
- Ancient?
l remember when l first
got into Oz, l was your hero.
Should be talking about
the '95 Bulls game, boy.
- You scored 58 points.
- Yeah, you always been my hero, man.
That's me.
Fucking role model.
Well, l was still
naive then.
Back then l felt you were as good
a person as you are at basketball.
Oh hold on, man.
Look, during the riots,
l stepped up,
tried to save
Eugene Dobbins' life.
What'd l get for it?
An ass whooping and a transfer.
- Whatever.
- Fuck you, man.
Shit, ever since l been back in Oz, man,
l've been invisible.
Ain't been causing
nobody no trouble.
Now l'm up for parole.
While's you in here rotting,
l'll be back out.
Back on the court.
Why don't you
live with that, little man?
- Damn!
- What's the problem?
l'm trying to find
the name of that woman
who Jackson Vahue
beat up and almost raped.
- The one that got him sent to Oz.
- Why?
'Cause that cocksucker
Vahue is gonna sweet talk
the parole board
into letting him go free.
l want to make sure the girl gets
the chance to tell the board not to.
You still hate him
that much?
Hate? This ain't
about hate.
This is about justice.
He's supposed
to serve 1 2 years.
- He should serve the full 1 2 years.
- lf he gets out now,
he's got a chance of getting
his career back.
- Seven more years, he'll be too old.
- Exactly.
Sounds like hate to me.
Yes, Beverly Reed please?
Oh hi, Beverly.
Uh... huh?
Listen, who l am is not important.
What l have to say is.
Have you been notified that
Jackson Vahue is up for parole?
l didn't think so.
Yeah, l thought you'd have
something to say about that.
Yo, Jackson.
How'd that hearing go, man?
Oh shit,yo.
Yo, Smith. Yo, Smith.
My shower's still busted, man.
- Yo, yo.
- What the fuck?!
Yo, spiffy boy.
Yo, come on.
Hey, my nigger.
Hey, you watch my nigger.
You wouldn't get no bigger.
l just need five minutes
with the warden.
l got something important.
Come on, Smith!
- Hook me up!
- This is moving day.
l just want to be
sure you were aware of what's going on.
Last year during
rec time in the gymnasium,
you stabbed a man
named Louis Bevilaqua.
You killed him.
Do you remember that?
- Do you remember that?
- Bad, bad...
- Bald.
- Yeah.
So the court has found you guilty
of first-degree murder.
The judge...
he has sentenced
you to death.
- Death, dying, dead.
- Yes.
Peter-- Peter Marie?
And they are going
to transfer you to death row
where you are
going to stay...
until...
the day of your--
- No!
- Execution.
Save! Save! Save...
Sorry...
Hey, Lopresti, who's that?
lt's your new playmate,
William Giles.
Peter, Peter Marie.
She's not here
to protect you, pal.
From now on,
l'm your lifeline.
Hey, my name's Moses.
How you doing?
- Tutti-frutti.
- Tutti-frutti?
- What the fuck does that mean?
- Dit dit dit dit.
Dit dit dit.
- Dah dah dah dah dah.
- Great.
My last days on earth and l'm locked up
with a fucking lunatic.
- Puppy dog.
- Right.
You got more than that.
Come on, push it!
Yeah.
That's it.
Yeah, Come on.
Keep it up.
You do not belong here.
- Minister Said, l--
- l told you 100 times,
you cannot become a Muslim.
Please, help me.
Let go of me!
Come on.
Prisoner number 00T255,
Leroy Tidd;
Convicted May 10th, 2000;
armed robbery, reckless endangerment.
Sentence: 20 years,
up for parole in 1 2.
- Whoa!
- Ball!
- Give me the ball.
- Tell your friend Said
- l don't like getting sent to the hole.
- Give me the ball.
Oh, sure.
l got you, nigger.
What happened
to your face?
Let me tell you.
l want to tell you.
Whatever anger
you feel towards
Leroy Tidd...
will disappear.
Okay.
l'm listening.
Thank you for getting me
out of the hole
and for arranging for me
to come back to Emerald City.
l was wrong.
l've been blaming you
for the sins of others.
For that
l am truly sorry.
Salam Alaikum, my brother.
l hate the fact that we all look like
saps while the niggers win.
Don't worry.
Once Said's dead,
- we'll flatten Tidd's black ass.
- Yeah.
Fucker doesn't know
how to pull a punch.
Told you guys
to leave Said alone.
What, do you wanna
start a fucking war?
Vern, Tidd's gonna do
all the dirty work.
No one will know
we're involved.
This is Oz.
People have a way
of finding out the truth.
Look, why don't you
go thump your Bible, okay?
Beat it. Scram.
We're buddies
with Vern Schillinger.
You been fucking
with his head.
Hoyt, we agreed l'd do the talking.
Let me do the fucking talking.
Then get
to the point.
First, you convince him to join that
interaction program with Beecher.
Gentlemen, l assure you,
l didn't convince him to do anything
except look in his heart,
open his heart to the Lord.
- His heart was beating fine.
- Hoyt, go read a book.
Schillinger runs
the Brotherhood.
l understand you look to him
for leadership.
No, we look to him
for balls, not heart.
Balls.
When something needs to get done,
it needs to get done
without no--
What'd you call it?
Moral dilemma.
- There are ways to get things done.
- Not here, Rev.
You back off on Vern,
or Hoyt-- he'll see to it that you
and Jesus have a face-to-face soon...
in heaven.
Let's go.
l got a visit from a couple
of friends of yours,
- Robson, Hoyt.
- They threaten you?
- Yes.
- l'll talk to them.
Ah, don't.
l'm not afraid.
l'm just telling you
l thought you should know.
They would do anything
to get you back.
Look, Reverend,
l-- l've been reading the Scriptures,
talking to you, but l still don't know
where l am in all this.
l don't want to be
some big Holy Roller,
l just-- just want
to have some joy in my life.
Now if those two fuckers can't
appreciate that, then to hell with them.
Yeah, to hell
with them indeed.
Now here's the name and number
of a woman l want you to call
if you need anything
before the baby comes,
or if you just want
to talk things through.
The New Church of Christ.
Man, l heard of them.
Ain't that the group
whose minister got caught stealing
hundreds and thousands of dollars?
The Reverend Cloutier, yes.
He's here in Oz.
And he's a good man, Carrie.
l've told him all about you,
you know, how you got nobody,
- except for me and Hank.
- Hank?
Where the fuck is Hank?
Not even a postcard.
You gotta remember,
the boy left town
before he knew
you were pregnant.
lf Hank was aware of what
was going on, he'd be here.
Yeah, don't be so sure.
Reverend Cloutier says
that this woman, this Sarah,
she was all alone
and pregnant
before she found
his congregation.
When you get lonely, call her, okay?
She understands.
Mr. Schillinger, l didn't take you
for the religious type.
l'm-- l'm not.
l-- l mean,
l've always been Christian.
Just... l'm starting to see other parts
of the picture now.
Okay, Schillinger's on his way
to the interaction.
- Uh-huh.
- You nervous?
You and l have talked through
all my feelings about Schillinger.
l know exactly
what l want to say to him
and l pretty much know
know what he's gonna tell me,
yet my hands are sweaty
and l'm borderline nauseous.
All right, but that doesn't mean
that it's wrong to meet with him.
l just want my daughter
to be safe.
l want my family
And l'd like to wake up one morning
and not be afraid.
Come in, Vern.
Why don't we
all sit down?
Okay, so who wants
to go first?
l do.
With your permission, l'd like to start
with a reading from the Holy Scripture.
Ah, sure.
- Tobias, do you mind?
- Nope, not at all.
''The wolf shall dwell
with the lamb,
and the leopard shall
lie down with the kid
and the calf and the lion
and the fatling together,
and a little child
shall lead them.
The cow and the bear
shall feed.
Their young shall
lie down together,
and the lion shall
eat straw like the ox.
The sucking child shall play
over the hole of the asp
and the weaned child
shall put his hand on the adder's den.
They shall not hurt or destroy
in all my holy mountain.''
Prisoner number 96K423,
Timothy Kirk;
Convicted April 16th, 1996;
Manslaughter, endangering
the welfare of a child.
Sentence: 1 2 years,
up for parole in seven.
Mmm, healthy body,
healthy mind.
ln the Catholic Church, the body
is the temple of the Holy Spirit
that we're supposed to keep pure.
You believe that, Preacher?
The body is
God's gift to us.
We're obligated
to take care of it.
What about sex?
ls that a gift of God too?
Of course.
How'd you like
a blow job?
What makes you think
l want a blow job?
Everybody wants
a blow job.
No, thank you.
Step back, please.
You made a lifetime
out of being adorable,
sexy in a lost-little-
boy kind of way,
but you threw
your baby in the trash.
That's a man's crime.
lt's time for you to be a man.
Bob, did you have
a nice visit with your son?
Yes, though he says my grandson's health
is getting more precarious.
Oh, l'm sorry to hear that.
Norma.
- Bob Rebadow, my fiancee, Norma Clark.
- A pleasure.
Agamemnon's told me
so much about you.
Nothing good, l hope.
l'll leave you
two lovebirds alone.
Did you talk to whoever you needed
to talk to about us getting married?
l have an appointment
to see the warden tomorrow.
- You don't think there'll be a problem?
- Oh no.
Oh good.
We were already engaged
to be married, Maggie and l,
when we learned that
she was pregnant.
Today that's no big deal,
but back in '65,
given her family's
position in society,
''out of wedlock''
meant scandal.
Still, we could've
weathered the storm together.
Maggie was...
Oh, Maggie.
That's enough for tonight.
Two weeks before
the wedding,
l stabbed Norton Pratt
in the neck.
And Maggie,
she died in childbirth.
My beautiful Maggie.
l wish you all the happiness
in the world, Agamemnon.
Thank you, Bob.
l do want to dance
at your wedding!
Busmalis.
l know your dirty
little secret.
l have a dirty
little secret?
A little secret
involving dirt.
You know, like digging.
You dig?
The night before they threw my ass
back up in here again,
l'll be goddamned,
l saw you digging
a motherfucking tunnel.
- Tunnel? No.
- Don't play me.
What the fuck do l
look like to you?
What do you want?
From you... nothing.
But l may use
what l know
to get my ass out
of solitary, all right?
No, please.
- l'm getting married, see--
- What? Married?
What the fuck do l care
if you get married?
- l'll pay you.
- Pay me? Pay me what?
What the hell
good is money
with my ass locked up in here
like this, huh?
Hey, no talking!
l'd allow someone to get married
inside the prison
- only as a reward for good behavior.
- l'm very well-behaved.
You dug a tunnel
and escaped
along with Alvarez, causing me great
embarrassment.
But you recaptured us both.
Busmalis is sorry for what
he did, aren't you?
Yes.
And we could use a little
romance around here, Leo.
Okay.
lf you swear to me that you won't dig
another tunnel,
l'll let you have
the ceremony.
But l find out
that you're lying,
it's solitary confinement
and you'll never see Norma again.
Warden, on my father's grave,
my mother's life
and my honor as a scout,
l swear l won't dig anymore.
Go ahead,
make the arrangements.
l've never actually
filled in a tunnel before.
Feels almost like murder.
Such a lovely tunnel too.
- You'd better get cracking.
- Yeah.
Busmalis,
l think you may--
Uh-oh.
- Shit!
- What's the matter?
l hit something.
Holy Jesus.
Hey, start digging,
Busmalis.
Last year the Hatfields
and the McCoys,
two families who've been feuding
for something like 150 years,
sat down together
and made peace.
lmagine that, giving up all that hate
after all those years.
Some people think the whole brouhaha
started over a stolen pig
though there are those
who swear the feud was over a woman.
Floria, this is
my favorite song.
Bullshit, Lopresti,
you don't even know who's singing.
- Yo, Floria, where you from?
- Jane Street Projects.
Say word.
Yo, me, too.
Well, you know, nearby.
l grew up on MLK in Southern.
l love your eyes.
l just fucking
love your eyes, girl.
- Morning, Floria.
- Hi.
- Long wait to see Leo?
- Yeah, and he isn't even in yet.
Hill, Poet,
what are you doing here?
Yo, everybody signed
this petition to get cable.
That's right, broadcast
television sucks.
Oh, yeah? Well, you should've
brought this to me.
Take them back.
- Bye, Floria.
- Bye.
- Later, Floria.
- Bye, beautiful eyes.
- Beautiful, pretty eyes.
- Would you get out?
Hey, McManus, when the warden comes
you can go ahead of me.
- Yeah. You're so generous, Lopresti.
- Well, you're a busy man.
Hello.
McManus, Lopresti.
Look, give me
a couple minutes, okay?
- Sure.
- Take your time.
Oh, Warden,
before you go in--
What the--
Surprise.
l had the workers
redecorate over the weekend.
Hey, Floria, maybe next
you can do my office.
- Looks okay?
- Okay?
lt's... fantastic.
You're fantastic.
The cafeteria's all set up
for the regional conference.
The other wardens
will be here by 10:00,
- and the governor arrives at 11 :30.
- Good.
And l got a lead
on an apartment for you
about six blocks from here, an
efficiency, all furnished, maid service.
- My wife call?
- No... sir.
Send her some flowers.
Warden, l do have a message.
lt's from her lawyer.
He wants to know who he should contact
regarding the divorce.
l don't know.
How the fuck should l know?
lt's my first divorce.
Well, l could
find you someone.
My brother's an attorney.
He'll know the right guy.
Send the flowers anyway.
Hello, Leo.
Conference is going great.
You really pulled it off.
l should've known
you'd show up, Querns.
Well, l am running Loyler now.
When l heard the commissioner was
considering you to replace Saul Cards,
l called him and told him
what l thought of you.
And you can see how much
influence you have.
Fuck off.
Wait. Don't you want
to know how Clayton Hughes is doing?
Not great. The prisoners all hate him
because he used to be a CO.
And the COs hate him because
they consider him a turncoat.
He's getting
in a lot of fights.
Right now l got him
in protective custody.
But the truth is, l don't think
he'll survive the year.
- Christ.
- Main attraction has arrived.
l want to transfer
Clayton to Oz.
- l can protect him.
- Right.
l can protect him.
Leo, Martin.
Governor, you seem to be getting around
pretty well on those things.
My physical therapist says
l'm recuperating faster
than any patient
she's ever had.
l expect to drop these crutches
in a matter of weeks.
Nice little shindig, Leo.
Lot of people thought
l shouldn't come,
given the fact that this
is the same room...
where l got shot.
But l say,
what the fuck, huh?
Without your boy Clayton's
helping hand,
Alva Case might've won
the election.
Remind me to send
Hughes a thank-you card.
- My God.
- Hello, Leo. Good to be home.
- Which unit am l gonna be in?
- Unit J.
The cop unit?
No way.
Since when do you think
you have a choice? Let's go.
Who were your friends,
dickhead?
Who are your friends,
you little cocksucker?
Son of a bitch.
You little cock!
l'm gonna knock
the shit out of you!
You cocksucker,
shithead, bastard!
Son of a bitch!
You spit on me!
You little prick!
You fucking bastard!
Prisoner number 01Y208,
Alvin Hewitt;
Convicted January 20th, 2001 ;
aggravated assault
of a minor.
Sentence: 1 2 years,
up for parole in seven.
Hey, when's lunch get here?
l'm starving.
Lunch'll get here the same time it gets
here every other fucking day.
Hey you know, Howell,
we had a female deputy sheriff
- back home that was a lot like you.
- Oh yeah?
Yeah, yeah, she was tough,
no bullshit.
Hey, had opinions about
everything.
And l suppose you
and your men
in that little dink farm town
you're from couldn't handle that?
Oh no, we didn't have to.
She got drunk
one night after work,
went to a little bar
in Spencer,
got gang-banged on the pool-table
by a bunch of bikers.
Speaking of which,
why ain't we got a pool-table?
- Officer Howell?
- Yes, sir.
- You know Clayton Hughes.
- Of course. Cell two.
Officer, l want you to make sure
that no harm comes to him.
l'm a CO, Warden,
not a miracle worker.
How you doing, John?
Couldn't be better.
Lunch.
l made this especially
for you, Detective.
Put a little extra
seasoning on it.
- You spit it in?
- l pissed in it.
New guy, is he the CO who tried
to assassinate Governor Devlin?
- Yeah.
- Guess he should've spent
a little more time
on the shooting range.
- What'd you say, motherfucker, huh?
- Hey!
Jesus Christ!
For Christ sake, wait!
Please, man! Please.
You know Goergen wasn't
well-liked, John,
but that doesn't excuse you from pushing
him down an elevator shaft.
But l think most people
in the department believe
that you did what
you had to do.
Not Nancy.
She didn't come to my trial.
She hasn't been here once.
l'm not gonna
lie to you, John.
Nancy's angry.
You were her partner.
She feels that
you betrayed her trust.
The worst part
about being in this place
is you can't talk to the people you need
to set things straight.
Look, l'll tell you
the other reason l'm here.
Your wife called.
She's very upset that
you refuse to see her or Robby.
l can't.
Doesn't Abby understand?
l can't face her...
or him... my son.
- She wants a visit without Robby.
- No.
- John.
Look, she loves you, and your silence
is killing her
in the same way that Nancy's
silence is hurting you.
lt was an honor
serving under you, sir.
Holy fucking shit, Keller.
- Hey, man, Good to see you.
- Oh, man. How are you?
- How you doing?
- Ronnie's cute.
Does he like
to fool around?
Count!
97B41 2, Beecher;
00M87 1, Morales;
96G522, Morales;
95H522, Hill.
- Ronnie boy.
- What's up?
What are you doing,
jerking off there?
Just giving old Magic Johnson
his morning stretch, that's all.
Yeah, as long as old Magic didn't get
any action last night.
Meaning?
Well, they got rules
against us fucking.
Yeah, right. Since when do you follow
the fucking rules, man?
Since you got stuck
with Beecher.
You don't want to be sticking
your prick into that prick.
- No?
- No, the guy's a slut.
Nothing but trouble.
Wow.
Boy, wish you would've told me
that yesterday...
because last night
he gave me a blow job deluxe.
l know what you're doing.
Fucking Barlog
to make me jealous?
You're a miserable little cunt,
you know that?
You killed the last two guys
l slept with.
You gonna kill your old friend,
Ronnie, too?
So let me try to understand
something here.
l mean you-- you were
the king of the scams, man.
You could hustle a cop
out of his badge.
How the hell did you get busted
for robbing a grocery store,
reckless fucking driving?
Yeah, well, after
my last divorce
- l went into kind of a tailspin.
- l remember.
Lots of drugs,
lots of college boys.
You know, a part of me
thinks in retrospect
l robbed that store-- which was
the stupidest thing l could've done...
'cause l wanted
to get caught.
You know, some demented
slice of my brain was saying,
''Hey, take some time
off the street.''
88 years, that's a...
that's a long time
off the street.
What, Keller?
Hello!
Get a room.
Lights out.
Finally.
- Ronnie.
- No, no, no.
- What? What's the matter?
- Keller.
What about him?
- He and l fucked this afternoon.
- What?
Yeah. First time.
And it was great.
l mean, l-- l knew him,
you know.
He and l, we ran together
all those years.
Keller was like
a big brother to me.
Sometimes he'd come up
with some Ponzi,
you know, and--
and l would just go along.
But, uh...
l guess l never
admitted to myself--
He says he loves me.
And he made me promise
that you and l wouldn't do it, so...
He doesn't love you, Ronnie.
lt's just another Ponzi.
Probably.
But, Beecher...
we're in Oz...
so what the fuck
is the difference?
So you were Keller's friend
before he got arrested?
Yeah, l knew him.
Sure, yeah.
On May 2nd, 1998,
Keller was at a gay bar
where he picked up
one Bryce Tibbetts.
He drove Tibbetts
across the state line to a forest
where he sodomized, tortured
and murdered the young man.
What's that
got to do with me?
Did Keller ever mention
killing Bryce Tibbetts?
Nah.
- How about Mark Carachi?
- No.
- Biam Lewis?
- Nope, none of that.
Too bad. See, if he had mentioned
these murders to you
and you'd been willing to testify, you
could've gotten your sentence reduced
from 1 3 years to, say, five.
Five?
The deal is out there
waiting to be reached.
- l gotta call my lawyer.
- You do that, Ronnie.
You make that call.
What is the only position
not mentioned
in the Abbott and Costello
routine ''Who's On First?''
- l hate baseball.
- l hate Abbott and Costello.
Well, it's not
in the infield.
- l need some help here.
- Didi.
Listen, l'm gonna say,
if l were you,
l wouldn't choose
the wrong position.
- Shortstop.
- Don't choose the wrong position?
- Right field.
You're in the right field
with $1,000.
Shit, we gotta
get cable, man.
We're thrilled when
this beauty school dropout
- decides to drop in--
- What do you want?
You're-- you're
a lawyer, right?
- l was.
- Yeah.
Let me-- let me run a little something
by you, if you don't mind.
A deal that the--
that the feds
are offering me.
l don't work pro bono.
l'll, uh--
l'll make the consultation
worth your while.
Maybe we can
work something out.
Keller.
Oh, are we speaking? l thought we were
trying to fuck with each other.
Ronnie Barlog is
about to sell you out.
You're a goddamn liar.
The FBl offered him
reduced prison time
if he testifies against you
in those homosexual murders.
You're saying that
'cause you're jealous.
Believe what
you want to believe.
Write me from death row.
Hey, who was it that
wanted to talk to you?
FBl.
They were grilling me
about that bank job in Buffalo.
There we go with that.
You are amazing, Ronnie.
You fix anything, can't you?
Some people are just
mechanically inclined, that's all.
You got many gifts, Ronnie.
Got a great imagination,
got a way with words.
Me? Nah, come on.
l hear you been telling
a lot of fantastic stories.
- Huh?
- Stories about me
and my encounter
with certain young men.
Chris, l didn't say
nothing about that, l swear.
- You sure?
- Yeah, on my life, man. Come on.
You swear on your life,
that's enough for me.
Suck my dick.
Chris, you know l would
never jabber on you, man.
They did make me an offer, but l turned
those fed fucks down right there.
l told them, you know, ''You can kiss
my ass. lt ain't happening.''
You know,
sometimes l think
l killed all those guys
'cause l wanted to kill
the part of me l despise.
When you take revenge
on somebody,
you are actually paying them the highest
compliment possible.
lt's like saying,
''You affected my life
to such an extent
that l must reciprocate.
l must affect your life as deeply
as you have mine.''
Revenge may be
the ultimate Hallmark card.
Yeah. When you think
of it like that,
the cliche is true:
Revenge is sweet.