Oz... the name
on the street
for the Oswald State
Correctional Facility,
level four.
You may have heard
on the news
that we've been having
a little...
tension around here.
Well, after
14 fun-filled days
of sitting in your cells
smelling your
roomie's farts,
a man is ready
to forgive everybody
for everything,
just to come up
for air.
Attention, the following
will step out of their pods:
93A234, Adebisi;
97 A622, Arif;
97 S444, Said;
99P334, Pinkerton;
95B327, Bismilla;
85T61 2, Tyrell;
95W856, Wolf;
and 88A578, Ahmad.
Get in line
behind officer Howard.
All right, that's it,
move it along.
Let's go.
Move it along.
What the fuck
is going on?
What do you mean?
They're taking
all the niggers.
All right, quiet.
l said quiet!
Shut up now!
For the past two weeks,
we have been
in 24-hour lockdown.
Now l'm not gonna go
into the specifics
as to what caused
this situation.
You know it.
l've brought you together
to say this:
When the lockdown ends
depends on you.
lt is my intention
to put this prison
back on a routine schedule.
But hear me good,
if there is
one single incident
of race-related violence,
l will lock you
away again,
black and white,
24-7,
for the rest
of your fucking lives.
See?
All that shit you talk
ain't gonna do nothing.
Be patient, Kenny,
l have a plan.
ls Glynn
fucking crazy?
This ain't over.
l know, the niggers
are up to something.
And so with
order restored,
Warden Leo Glynn
has ended the lockdown.
ln a related story,
the wife of
inmate Hamid Khan
has won a State
Supreme Court ruling
to have her husband
removed from life support.
Khan, who was serving
a 10-year sentence
for aggravated assault,
went into a coma after
being hit in the head
during a prison
boxing match.
McManus wants
to see you.
The family's in
with Khan now
saying their
final farewells.
And they've asked that you
say a prayer over the body,
- Just before the end.
- Bearing in mind
what happened
between Khan and l...
l'm honored
they asked for me.
With Brother Khan gone,
we'll need
someone to lead us.
l bet l know who
you have in mind.
Yourself.
Yes.
But l need
to know, Said,
will you oppose me?
No, Arif.
l've lost the taste.
- The taste?
- For power.
l hope you use yours
more wisely than l did.
Let's go.
The man l hit,
is he getting better?
Yeah, he'll be fucking
fine in about 10 minutes.
Now go to sleep,
Cyril. now.
Oh, Allah, forgive him
and have mercy upon him.
Give him peace
and pardon him.
- What do you want?
- You killed me, Cyril.
- l didn't mean to.
- Then what about him?
Who is that?
lt's Preston Nathan,
Gloria's husband.
We're never gonna
leave you, Cyril.
We're gonna be right here
inside your head forever.
For all eternity.
Cyril, Cyril, shh,
hey, hey, hey!
Wake up!
Shh... shh.
Shh, it's all right.
Shh.
My brother Cyril,
you know,
He keeps on having
those terrible nightmares.
The valium is not
helping him to sleep?
No. We gotta try
something else.
As l said before,
the nightmares are rooted in his guilt
- for causing those deaths.
- Yeah.
And the cure
for your brother
is to alleviate
his guilt.
And, in the case
of Hamid Khan,
l'm not even sure
that's possible.
However, with
Gloria Nathan's husband--
l'll do anything.
Anything.
You heard about
the interaction program l started?
Victims and/or
victims' families
Sit down with the person
who hurt them and talk.
- Talk about what?
- Their feelings, their anger, whatever.
And, the guilty person
gets a chance
to express remorse.
Yeah, okay.
- Yeah, sign Cyril up for that program.
- Wait a minute,
- Both of you.
- What?
l am not about
to ask Gloria
and Preston's parents
to join us
unless you both
participate.
Hey, l got
no problem with that.
No, absolutely not.
l can't even be in the same room
with the O'Reily brothers.
lt makes
my skin crawl.
This is a chance
to put the past to rest.
l could give a shit about Cyril O'Reily
sleeping better.
Hell, l'll quadruple
his dosage of valium,
maybe he'll sleep
permanently.
Gloria, this is not about Cyril
and you know it.
This could give
Preston's mom and dad
a chance
to have closure.
You could have closure.
Closure?
People always
think l'm a nurse.
No matter how many times
they hear me referred to as Dr. Nathan,
they call out to me,
''Hey, nurse.''
Now l don't know
if that's because l'm a woman or Latina.
Maybe l'm just too goddamn
nice to be a doctor.
Does this mean
you'll do it?
lt means l'm not taking shit
from anyone anymore.
Damn!
Hey, Sister Pete, hey.
What did Gloria say?
She says no, Ryan.
l'm sorry.
Maybe in time,
she'll change her mind.
Yeah, but
what about Cyril?
l mean, come on.
l guess we
increase his dosage.
What?
Ahh!
Ryan!
- What happened?
- O'Reily cut himself.
There you go.
- Now how's that feel?
- Tight.
- You rest here for a while.
- Yeah.
You know, l asked Said
to tell me about last night,
about Hamid Khan's death.
Said told me that
you wrapped Khan's body
in a clean
white cloth
and then added perfume
and prayed.
O'Reily, you don't
care about Hamid Khan.
No, l do,
l don't know.
l just wanted to make
sure the fucking thing got done right.
Hey, my brother won
that fight fair and square.
Congratulations,
America.
This year
the prison population
has reached
an all-time high--
two million.
Two million people are,
what do you call it?
lncarcerated.
Two fucking million.
That's the population
of Vienna.
of Houston, Texas.
of the world's
population,
yet it has 25°/%
of the world's prisoners.
Whoopee!
Bevilaqua.
Alvarez.
Giles.
McCullum.
Fuck me!
Command,
this is C-11.
We have a 7 4, cell 23.
- What happened?
- ls he dead?
Yeah, but Christ almighty,
look at his arms and his legs.
- They're all chewed up.
- He ate himself.
That's disgusting.
Yeah, l'm gonna be
filling out paperwork for a month.
You goddamn
piece of shit!
The M.E. has ruled
McCullum's death as suicide.
He bit into his skin,
chewing off chunks of muscle
over the course of a week or so causing
himself to bleed out.
- Sweet Jesus!
- Like a cannibal.
A cannibal eats
somebody else's flesh.
So what do you call a guy
who eats his own flesh?
- lnventive.
- How he did it
is not as important
as what he did.
This is the third suicide
we've had in solitary in two years.
Well, not to mention Alvarez's
almost successful attempt.
What's your point?
We've got to do something
about the conditions in there.
Conditions? lt's solitary,
for Christ's sake!
What do you want us to do,
serve high fucking tea?
There's no reason to talk like that.
No reason for the attitude.
l'm sorry, l wish
life in solitary
was all peaceful and rosy
like it is in Emerald City.
But we get the dead-enders
you other units can't handle.
l agree with Claire.
The only way to deal with
these types of criminals
is to sit on them.
You got no arguments
out of me, warden,
but l think there
is a compromise.
- Let's hear it.
- A lot of other maxs,
they give the dinks
in solitary
one hour of rec time
every day or so.
- Very controlled.
- That's right.
So if they get a chance
to walk around,
- they have more incentive to behave.
- lt's worth a try.
As long as it's
my ass on the line,
any of you wanna volunteer
to serve as escort?
Okay, Claire, enough.
Like Gloria says,
it's worth a try.
Bevilaqua!
Prisoner number 99b521,
Louis Bevilaqua;
Convicted,
April 2nd, 1999;
Murder in
the second degree,
illegal possession
of a firearm.
Sentence: 25 years,
up for parole in 1 2.
Hey, Alvarez,
why you in solitary?
This time, it's for
killing Carlo Ricardo.
Carlo's dead,
you killed him?
Yeah, well, l had to.
El Cid sent me here
to a-hole me, brother.
Carlo was my cousin.
You're supposed to be
exercising your legs,
not your mouths.
Shut the fuck up.
Bevilaqua says he just found out
Alvarez killed Carlo.
Bevilaqua wants
to know, man,
if you want him to finish
the job on Alvarez.
Tell him yes.
Tell him l want him dead already.
Alvarez.
Bevilaqua.
Hey, Aqua, man.
l got a funny story
to tell you, bro'.
You know, Glynn started
giving me a hassle
about who raped
his daughter,
so he put me
in solitary.
- l told him Carlo did it.
- Carlo wasn't there.
Yeah, l know.
What do you think
will happen
when Glynn finds out
you raped his kid?
Command, this is C-11.
We need backup
in the gymnasium, now!
- l repeat, backup in the gymnasium!
- Bevilaqua's dead.
- What about Alvarez?
- lntensive care.
- ls he gonna live?
- Unfortunately.
l hope this puts
an end to rec time.
Yeah, but l'm also transferring you
to another unit.
- 'Cause l was right?
- Open the goddamn door.
Peter...
Peter Marie.
Yeah, that's right.
William, why?
l, little shaver,
cookie jar,
Mama mad,
George Washington,
cherry tree,
chop-chop.
So you told your mother the truth
about stealing the cookies?
Chocolate chip,
yum-yum.
But what has
that got to do
- with attacking Bevilaqua and Alvarez?
- Liars, liars.
l kill, but never lie.
Never, ever lie.
Fucking Alvarez, man,
he's got more lives
- than a cat!
- Yo, man, he still alive?
He's barely,
in the hospital ward.
Well, you make sure
that fucking scumbag
don't make it out
of there, okay?
This one's for me.
Shit!
What's up?
- Your sons?
- Yeah.
A cousin of
mine sent it.
She heard
about Andrew.
Hard to get over
losing a kid.
Makes me miss my other son
Hank that much more.
You haven't heard
from him, right?
Not since
l came to Oz.
When they're this young,
all you see is
the possibilities.
Let's go.
Oh, time to renew
my subscription to TV Guide.
Hey, Beecher,
this one's for you.
lt's empty.
Yeah, we had to
confiscate the contents.
A letter from
my grandmother?
What could have
possibly been in here
that you had to
confiscate it?
Well, if l told you,
then you'd know.
- Hello, Tobias.
- Father M.
ls Pete around?
Ah, no, she went into town
to see her psychiatrist.
She's seeing
a psychiatrist?
Yeah, ever since
she started thinking about
not being a nun.
l thought you knew.
No.
Well, it's really
none of my business.
How are you
doing, Tobias?
Uh, you know.
Yeah.
Any more trouble
with Vern Schillinger?
Well, there's always
gonna be trouble,
at least until one of us
ends up in the morgue.
Oh, now
l don't believe that.
l know that
the two of you
caused each other massive amounts
of pain over the years,
but there's gotta
be a way to call a truce.
You've got to
forgive Schillinger.
l tried that and l ended up
bleeding internally.
lf it wasn't for Chris Keller,
l'd be dead.
How did you let him know
that you forgave him?
What do you mean, how?
l told him to his face.
Well, maybe this time
you don't tell him.
Maybe this time
he just knows.
So any ideas?
You must do something absolutely
extraordinary for Schillinger,
but you must never
tell him that you did it.
Well, then how's
he gonna know?
All these things have a way
of revealing themselves.
But when Schillinger
does find out,
He'll see your gesture
for exactly what it is--
an act of kindness,
reconciliation.
- This is bullshit.
- Chris.
No, you're not
doing anything.
You got that?
What, are you
giving me an order?
Fuck yes.
- Hello, Dad.
- Toby...
oh, God, son,
you look terrific.
Well, better than
the last time you were here.
- l've put more money in your account.
- Thank you.
There's not much else
l can do, is there?
Well, actually, Dad,
there is.
One of the other prisoners,
Vern Schillinger,
had two sons.
his oldest, Andrew, was--
died recently.
The other, Hank--
well, Vern's
lost track of him.
They're estranged.
l was hoping
one of the P.l.s
from the law firm
could do some digging.
You want to
locate the boy?
This is all the information l've been
able to pull together so far.
Mm-hmm.
Well, l'll put
Swannee on this.
He's the best
private investigator we have.
Thank you, Dad.
Toby, l'm very proud
of you.
- Proud?
- Well, here you are
Living in hell
with your own problems,
and you're trying to
help a fellow inmate
to reunite with his
last surviving son.
You are a remarkable
human being.
Yeah.
l'm remarkable
all right.
Hey.
How's Daddy?
Good, great.
You smell sexy.
lt's my father's
aftershave.
Mm-hmm.
- Hey, don't.
- What?
l need to talk to you.
So what's so
fucking important?
Look, l know
how you'll react.
Jesus, what?
l asked my father to locate
Schillinger's other son.
We discussed this.
Yeah, we agreed.
- No, we didn't agree.
- So now all of a sudden,
you wanna help that fuck,
Schillinger, huh?
No, l wanna help us,
you and me.
l wanna stop living
every fucking day in fear.
Hey, that's what being
alive is all about, pal.
lt doesn't
have to be.
Chris, sometimes,
most times,
l wish l could
wipe away the past.
l wish l could wipe away
everything l've done,
everything l've said
to hurt the people l love.
l wish l could
look at people
and not see all
the hurt they caused me.
And maybe, maybe
this is the way
to start making
that wish come true.
Are you listening
to yourself, man?
What are you,
Tinkerbell?
You wishing
upon a star?
l'm partially responsible
for Andrew Schillinger's death.
l need to
atone for that,
so should you.
You know what?
Oz didn't make
you a bitch.
You were born one.
Yeah, okay.
Shit.
- Let's go!
- Come on, you bitch.
- Hey, who started it?
- l fucking started it!
- Take him to the hole!
- l'm nobody's bitch!
You're not
my fucking bitch, you cunt!
Party's over, guys.
Break it up!
l'm nobody's bitch.
Now most citizens would say,
''two million inmates?
l got no problem with
that 'cause crime is down.''
But California, which increased
its prison population
at a much higher rate
than say, New York,
had a smaller drop
in crime.
Cause and effect?
l don't think so.
Shirley Bellinger,
who sat on death row for a year
awaiting execution for the murder
of her young daughter,
will be returning to Oswald State
Correctional Facility today.
Bellinger's death sentence
had been commuted
when she became pregnant
while serving time.
But after she miscarried
under suspicious circumstances,
Governor Devlin
revoked his decision.
Here you go, Shirley.
Well, can't l have
my old cell back?
As you can see,
it's occupied.
Well, maybe
he'd switch with me.
Would you
switch with me?
Sorry, sister,
l'm all spread out.
l'll make it
worth your while.
- There's nothing you got that l want.
- You'd be surprised.
Get inside.
How do you do?
My name's Shirley,
what's yours?
Suck my dick,
you fucking cunt.
Well, that's not polite.
How about you?
You got a kind word
for a stranger?
Yeah.
Moses Deyell.
Moses? Well,
maybe you can lead us
out of Egypt
to the promise land.
l wouldn't
count on it.
How'd you end up here?
Prisoner number
00D7 18,
Moses Deyell;
Convicted
February 3rd, 2000,
on two counts of murder
in the first degree.
Death.
She was cheatin' on ya?
Yeah...
with her husband.
They were married?
The bitch told me
they was through.
l don't fuck with
another man's wife.
- l got principles.
- Oh, l love a man with principles.
You know, when l was
first elected governor,
crime was
out of control,
but we went to work, fighting
for three strikes and you're out.
That bastard's running
for another term
after all the crap
he's pulled?
l'm voting for him.
What, why?
Well, things
are better now
than they were
four years ago.
Better for who?
Not for us.
Well, in general,
life has improved across the state
since Devlin took office.
The economy's up,
crime is down.
- You'd actually vote for that asshole?
- Yes.
You can't vote.
You were convicted of a felony.
- You are no longer eligible to vote.
- Really?
Really.
Oh. well, that's okay.
l never used
to vote anyway.
The courage to lead--
James Devlin, Governor.
- Welcome.
- Thanks for seeing me.
l get a call that the governor's
campaign manager
wants to chat,
l'm intrigued.
Please,
have a seat.
You'll find that l'm not
the type to dance around.
Frank Feeley won't be running for
re-election as lieutenant governor.
We haven't announced
this yet to the press,
but he has cancer,
throat cancer.
- Pity.
- l know.
He was a great draw
for the upstate vote.
Governor Devlin has asked me
to make a short list of people
to replace Frank
on the ticket.
l'd like to add
your name to the list.
Me?
Run with Devlin?
l know that you and the governor
have had your differences in the past,
but l also know you're as conservative
as he is on most issues.
This wouldn't have
anything to do
with Alvah Case announcing
he's running against Devlin?
Well, l'll be honest, sure.
This administration's
reputation
with the African-American
community is a bit tarnished.
But deeper than that, l think you'd make
a great lieutenant governor.
You offering me this?
No. You're on the list.
The convention
is two months away.
Between now and then, you'd need
to increase your public profile.
- How?
- Well, that's what l'm here for,
to walk you
through the steps.
l'm glad you're
interested, Leo.
- l haven't said that l am.
- Oh, yes, you have.
- Hey, Andrea.
- McManus.
What brings you downtown
from Emerald City?
- Well, have you seen Diane?
- No.
Wasn't she due back
from vacation today?
Yeah, but she didn't show up for her
shift, so they asked me to stay,
which is a pain in my ass
'cause l think l got the flu.
Oh, look, look.
Don't breathe on me.
- l can't afford to get sick.
- And l can?
Please, l got three kids.
My husband's been puking
for the past two days.
Oh, shit. Well, listen,
if you hear from Diane,
will you please
tell her to call me?
- Sure.
- And feel better.
l've been thinking
or feeling.
l know l've been all over the place
and back with this thing,
but maybe we could
try it again together.
You busy?
Oh, no, no, no,
come on in.
What's the problem?
No problem.
Hey, l just got off
the phone with Diane.
Where is she?
Well, she's
still in London.
l just called her hotel.
They said she checked out.
- Yeah...
- You know, her two weeks are up.
She was supposed to
come back to work today.
What's she still
doing in London?
Well, you know,
she and Didi
were standing in front
of Buckingham Palace
and she got into
a conversation with
a guard.
- l thought they didn't talk.
- He was on break.
Anyway, one thing
led to another,
and...
they're going
to get married.
Right.
l'm serious.
- She's getting married?
- Yeah.
To a Bobby?
No, no, not a Bobby, Tim,
he's a guard.
He guards the Queen.
Yeah, well, then l can see how they've
got a lot in fucking common!
Oh, fuck!
Jesus fucking Christ!
Did she leave
a number?
She doesn't want
to talk to you.
Well, l got a hell
of a lot l wanna say to her!
Which is why she doesn't
wanna talk to you.
- She really feels very badly.
- Oh, really?
Now listen, Tim,
Diane Wittlesey has
not had an easy life.
Poverty, spousal abuse,
single motherhood,
her mom dying after
a very long illness.
And just now
on the phone, her voice--
she sounded so happy.
Happy?
Sure.
lf you need
to talk--
What l need
is a drink.
- Tim--
- Don't worry, Sister.
This is what guys
who've been dumped do
in order to move on.
Cheerio.
Adebisi, you still
got the gun?
Lower your voice.
- You still got it?
- Yes.
And when you
gonna use it?
- l'm not.
- Then what is the point of having a gun
if you don't
use the shit?
lf l use the gun,
l end up in the hole,
solitary or death row.
No, our goal was to get rid
of McManus, remember?
To have a black man
running Emerald City.
Yeah, like you can
make that happen?
l can, depending on
who l get to shoot the gun,
- And who gets shots.
- l don't understand, man.
Of course
you don't, Kenny.
Of course you don't.
All right, time to go
back to your cages.
Line up!
Andrew said you was
gonna get me, Poet, and Pierce
sent back to Em City.
what's up with that?
- l will.
- When?
Patience, Kenny.
Patience.
Fuck patience, man,
that's all you ever
say is patience!
Patience!
l've got too much time
in this motherfucker to be patient!
- No, l won't do it.
- Why?
Look, Wangler accused me
of sexually harassing him.
- l don't want him anywhere near me.
- Look, Wangler admitted
- he exaggerated his claim.
- Exaggerated?
Look, Tim,
Adebisi came to me
requesting that Wangler,
Poet and Pierce get
transferred back to your unit.
Now l'm trying to put
a lid on the racial tension.
And if giving Adebisi
this one small thing helps do that,
l don't see what
your problem is.
lf you say no,
l'll transfer him anyway.
Fine.
- What's up?
- Baby.
Same old shit.
What's up, baby?
Welcome home.
Yo, let me
see the gun.
Let me see the gun.
Damn.
Let me hold it.
Let me
hold that piece.
Come and get it.
You three have been
chosen to do your time
in an experimental unit
we call Emerald City.
ln Emerald City, you're given a lot more
leeway than the rest of Oz,
But the leeway has a price.
we've got rules.
There's no yelling,
no fighting, no fucking.
You're expected
to keep yourselves
and the common
areas pristine.
You obey the rules,
we get along fine.
You don't, we drop-kick
your ass to Gen Pop.
Now these guys, these guys are gonna
be your sponsors,
help you acclimate
to your new life.
Augustus Hill,
that's Desmond Mobay.
Chucky Pancamo,
that's Ralph Galino.
And Guillaume Tarrant,
that's Jaz Hoyt.
You've gotta be
kidding me, man.
Where you from, man,
Jamaica?
Yes.
- How long you been in the States?
- Six months.
What got you
sucked into Oz?
Are you writing
my life story?
- l don't know you.
- Like he said, my name is Ralph Galino.
l don't know you or where
the fuck you came from.
Well, l'm a contractor.
l built a housing complex that collapsed
it killed two people,
but it wasn't my fault.
- So you're not connected?
- Connected? You mean...
- Anybody got their arm around you?
- Oh, God, no.
Until this little brouhaha,
l never even gotten a parking ticket.
- Oh, yeah?
- No offense, Mr. Pancamo,
but not every ltalian-American
is mobbed up.
ls that so?
Yeah, most of us live normal,
law-abiding lives.
The Guido gangster is an
ugly and unfair stereotype.
So who is he?
Just another
fucking asshole.
Yo!
You got money?
Gimme it.
Fuckin' pussy.
Everybody in Oz has
a job, which can range
from maintenance
to food service to machinery.
You have
secretarial skills,
so the warden has requested
that you work in his office.
- Okay.
- You also have a history of drug abuse.
History.
l'm done with drugs.
Uh-huh, just in case,
l'm gonna have you take
part in our rehab sessions,
at least for
a few weeks.
You keep
your nose clean,
both figuratively
and literally,
and we'll get along.
Go see the warden.
Next!
Yeah.
Warden, this
is Desmond Mobay.
- Okay, you can leave him, Armstrong.
- Yes, sir.
- Detective Basil.
- Hello, warden.
Have a seat.
Nice little prison
you run here.
Little?
Oz is the largest correctional
facility in the state.
And, yet the place feels
so intimate, so friendly.
Now l have to tell you
the drug problem here is substantial,
but l'm not sure
how effective
an undercover
operation will be.
Several years ago we had another
narcotics detective come in.
- Paul Markstrom.
- Yeah.
l knew Paul.
He was a good man.
Then you also know
he was executed,
- hung by the neck.
- Those are the risks.
Well, l intend to keep
a close eye on you.
That's why l wanted you
working here in the office.
l want to be
updated constantly.
No problem.
All right, let me
show you your desk.
The place might
be a mess.
My last secretary left
in kind of a hurry.
Very nice.
l can use this
to e-mail my partner.
By the way, l type
85 words a minute.
Shit, l might hire you
as my secretary for real.
lf l don't make this bust,
l'll need the job.
My lieutenant,
he wants results.
What's your first step?
Making good friends
with the bad guys.
Yo, man,
how's it going?
Some cultural reading, eh?
What, all of a sudden
you wanna be my Yaga-Yaga?
l asked around.
people say you cool.
- Do they?
- They also say
you know where a man
can get some relief.
- Some relief or some reefer?
- Same thing.
Though l could use
something stronger.
Well, whoever
you jawing with,
they're misinformed.
l don't do drugs.
- No?
- No, not no more, no.
Oh.
So who do
l talk to?
Just stand still,
they'll come to you.
Hi, honey, it's me.
How am l doing?
How the fuck do you
think l'm doing?
Listen,
call Dan Bosey,
Tell him to get
his ass in gear.
l want that appeal
signed and sealed.
l've gotta
get out of here.
l love you
too, babe.
All right, bye.
What do you want?
Permit me
to introduce myself--
Nikolai Petrovic
Stanislofsky.
- Okay, what do you want?
- That cell phone.
How did you
get it into Oz?
My brother brought
it to me, why?
They're not allowed.
Really, no one
mentioned that.
The prison, they want us
to use the pay phones.
First, because they
monitor calls randomly,
and second, because the state gets a cut
from the phone company
of all the long-distance
calls we make.
Shit, l guess
l better turn it in.
l don't need any more trouble
than l already got.
You know, if you like,
l will take care of it for you.
l can say l found
the cell phone
and no one will
be the wiser.
lt's up to you.
Thank you.
What's your name?
- Nikolai.
- Ralph.
- l owe you one.
- No, no problem.
Better take
the charger too.
Prisoner number 00T416,
Guillaume Tarrant;
Convicted
January 2nd, 2000;
Destruction
of private property,
concealment
of a deadly weapon.
Sentence: 10 years,
up for parole in three.
Yo, what's up, yo?
Welcome to Em City.
Nice shoes.
Your mother
give you those
before they shipped you
off to summer camp and shit?
Leave me alone.
What kind of accent
is that? Where you from?
Leave me alone.
Yo, man, l'm just trying
to start a conversation, dog.
l'm just being
friendly and shit.
Where you going?
Huh, where you going?
Yo, just sit your ugly
white ass back down.
Check this. Your shoes,
offer 'em to me.
- What?
- Offer 'em to me.
Do it.
Would you
take my shoes?
Louder.
Would you
take my shoes?
Louder, motherfucker,
louder, louder.
Take my shoes, please!
Oh, damn, cool,
a gift for me? Word.
Hook me up.
Let me take those shoes.
Let me see these.
Oh, these the real deal.
My size and everything.
Hook me up.
Yo, for real.
Thank you.
All right, damn,
good looking, cuz.
My love, appreciate it,
all right?
See ya,
And then they took them.
Here you go,
blow your nose.
Guillaume,
here's the problem.
lf l go to Wangler and tell
him what you just told me,
he's gonna deny it.
his word against yours.
Well, he's got Poet
and Pierce to back him up.
What you need is
evidence or a witness.
He's wearing the shoes.
That's evidence.
But then you have
to find somebody
that says that they saw you
wearing the shoes earlier.
- Can you do that?
- No.
See, any witness
l find is gonna say
that they heard you offer
the shoes to Wangler.
- So what do l do now?
- Call your family.
Have them send you
another pair of shoes.
Wangler will just
steal those too.
Probably.
Look, ummm...
l don't like those three
being around here
any more than you do.
So if you ever see
or hear anything
l can use to hang
their balls out to dry, let me know.
And in the meantime,
go to the infirmary,
tell them l sent you,
get a pair of slippers that
will tide you over until...
Yo, Frenchy!
How about a game
of one-on-one? Me and you.
- No thanks.
- l'm not asking.
That's why we say it
like that, baby.
- lt must be the shoes, baby.
- lt must be the shoes.
Good game.
- Hey, McManus.
- l got no time for you today, O'Reily.
Hey, you ought to transfer
Frenchy out of Em City, man.
Hey, since when
do you tell me
who lives here
and who doesn't?
You don't do something,
there's gonna be trouble.
Yeah, thank you
for the advice.
Hey.
Oh, man. l heard what
those niggers did to you.
- Go away.
- Hey...
this is for you.
- Marijuana?
- Yeah, plus a little something extra
We call a ''duster.''
Oh, no, why don't you
wait a few minutes?
lf the hacks see you, they're gonna
eat your ass for lunch,
so all right?
Look, life in Oz,
it sucks.
The only way
for you to survive
is to teach Wangler
and his crew
that they can't
bully you around like this.
How?
How do l do that?
Well, l don't know.
But if an opportunity
presents itself, grab it,
'cause you're not
gonna get a second chance.
The scariest part is,
all those criminals
that were locked into all
those prisons in the '80s--
you know, the good,
old Reagan years--
all those criminals,
their sentences are up.
Those bad men who
are more dangerous now
than when they went in,
they're getting out...
and coming to dark
street corners near you.
Lights out!
Beecher.
- Who are you?
- Tarrant, Guillaume Tarrant.
You the guy that
destroyed that statue?
- Oui.
- Fucking sicko bastard.
Damn, your mom work quick.
- She send your shit air mail?
- Get the fuck away from me.
Tough talk. you know
you shouldn't swear,
- your mama'd be P.O.'d.
- l'm warning you to back off.
What the fuck, son?
You trying to get tough now?
Huh? What the fuck
you gonna do, huh?
Huh, huh?
Stay down, stay down...
Ow! God damn it!
Chris!
Come on,
put the gun down.
There's no way out.