Back in the 1950s,
there was a game show on TV
called, ''You Bet Your Life,''
hosted by Groucho Marx.
Every week, Groucho
would ask inane questions
and insult the
contestants.
A fake duck would
drop down on a string,
and Groucho would go,
''Say the secret word
and win $100.''
But not once did anyone
ever actually bet their life,
unlike in Oz.
No one ever put
their life on the line.
The attempted assassination
of Governor James Devlin
by a former employee
of the Oswald Correctional Facility
has sent a shock wave
through this election campaign
and the entire state.
Devlin, who is listed
in stable condition,
announced that he intends
to stay in the race for re-election.
The suspect,
Clayton Hughes,
is being held without bail
at the Crown and Shield Holding Center.
Clayton! Clayton!...
Kill Hughes! Kill Hughes!...
- Sean.
- Lockdown?
Lockdown! Let's go!
Move your asses now!
Come on, get inside!
Come on, let's go!
Get in your cell.
Now!
Clayton Hughes
is a close friend of our family's,
and though l find his actions
utterly reprehensible,
l feel compelled,
out of loyalty to his mother
and late father,
to stand by Clayton's side
at his hour of need.
l am therefore
withdrawing my name
as a candidate for the nomination
of Lieutenant Governor.
That is all.
The niggers playing again.
You two fucks ain't
selling enough tits.
The fuck you mean
we ain't sellin' enough tits?
- You buggin'.
- Who sells more than us?
Desmond Mobay.
Man, fuck
that Jamaican fuck.
Fuck you, nigger.
Now my fuckers get pumping.
Let's do this.
Hey, Mobay.
You gotta stop making us
look so bad, man.
You dig
what l'm saying?
l do what l'm told.
Well, we's telling you
something different.
l am not afraid of you.
Or you.
Hey, hey!
Back! Back!
You have gotta learn
to control your emotions.
- Follow Officer Keating here.
- You sending me to the hole?
Not this time. Detective McGorry
wants to interview you.
l don't know no McGorry.
Who the fuck is that?
Homicide cop investigating
the Bruno Gergan murder.
l don't know nothing
about Bruno Gergan,
- all right?
- Tell it to her.
Punk ass.
According to the files,
you and Leroy Tidd
had a little altercation
with Bruno Gergan
in the gym.
- An alter-what?
- A fight.
Oh. We was just
fucking around.
You beat him
to a pulp.
Yeah, well,
sometimes we get
carried away.
He lived, though.
Not for long.
Look, l didn't push Gergan
down no elevator shaft.
lf you didn't,
who did?
The only one l know
grieving Gergan was Mobay.
- Desmond Mobay?
- Oh, yeah.
The two of them had
some weirdness going on between them.
l'm here.
Sit down.
Found out some
very disturbing news today.
Yeah?
What's that?
There's an undercover narc
in Oz.
Shit.
His name is Brand,
Cecil Brand.
He's over
in Unit B.
And he's one
of your customers.
- What do we do?
- Whack... his... ass.
- Who?
- You.
l want you to kill
that fucking cop.
No problem.
Go.
You know,
for a minute,
l thought
you was undercover.
l mean-- but you can't be,
you know,
given the amount
of shit you were snorting,
given the amount of
shit you been selling.
lt's crazy, l know.
But that night you were
so cranked up on tits
that your accent
suddenly disappeared...
l was, like,
what the fuck is that?
And then your girlfriend--
what's her name?
Kina?
l was positive that l
recognized her from somewhere.
Tore my brain out
trying to remember--
trying to remember where.
Then l had a flash.
No! No!
When they threw me
off the roof,
l was laying
on the cold pavement,
and this woman police
came over to see
if l was still alive.
That woman police...
she's a dead
ringer for your Kina.
Lights out!
Well, good night, Mobay.
Or Officer Whoever-the-fuck-
you-are.
Hey!
You talk that shit
to anyone,
you're next down
the elevator shaft.
All right,
break it up in there.
l'm telling
nobody nothing.
l'm telling nobody
that you're a cop,
a cop who breaks the law
all in the name of the law.
l just want you to know
that l know you're a fraud.
And l don't mean
that you're undercover.
l mean as a person.
You're a fraud.
He's still alive.
Get a doctor up here!
- l murdered Bruno Gergan.
- What?
l committed a crime.
l should be punished.
Why are you confessing?
Because l took
an oath.
Because l'm not a fraud.
Because l don't want
to be one of them.
The arrest
of Detective Basil
for the murder
of Bruno Gergan
has obviously put an end
to the undercover narcotics operation,
at least for the time being.
With all due respect, Warden, l think
you're gonna have to accept the fact
that the war on drugs
is unwinnable.
You know,
that's not true.
We have to be diligent.
We have to keep fighting.
We can't just give up on education.
We have to rehabilitate.
l'm not saying you're not gonna get
lucky with a slug or two,
but if you think
you're gonna eradicate heroin from Oz,
well, that's just
plain stupid.
Who you calling stupid?
- Hey, if the shoe fits...
- Fuck you!
- All right, enough!
- Pussy!
- Come on!
- Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
What the fuck
is happening here?
Pete!
l am sick to death
of sitting in on these meetings
and listening to you
people with your petty little egos.
The walls are crumbling
down around us,
and all you
care about is yourselves.
Well--
Go after her.
Pete?
No.
Shh, l wanna talk.
No, no.
l'll be fine, Ray.
No, really,
l'll be fine.
- l don't get cravings anymore.
- That's horseshit.
- What are you doing here?
- l'm an addict.
l'm getting yearnings.
l may start again. l need your help.
l don't want
you in this room.
Sister,
you can't refuse me.
Oh, yes.
Yes, l can.
Take him back, please.
So, Augustus,
you were about to make
some point?
Oh, yeah.
- Hi!
- Hi.
l was gonna come up
to the office and see you,
but l thought... no.
Listen, l'm surprised
you got this far.
How you doing?
Small increments
are better, you know?
- Yeah.
- You?
Ahh, l'm in a mood.
Today l got
the documents to sign.
- Documents?
- To stop being a nun.
So this lunch
we're having
is a celebration?
l don't know.
l still haven't
made up my mind.
When you join
a religious order, you know,
you become
a bride of Christ.
lt's hard to accept
that when l put my signature
on those documents
Christ and l
are divorced.
Oh, fuck me,
you piece of shit.
Oh, fuck!
Okay, what's
the matter now, Cyril?
You and that woman.
- What woman?
- Officer Howell.
What about her?
You and she are bad.
Huh?
- Come on, tell.
- Tell? What?
There's nothing to tell.
Wink, wink.
l'm gonna tell.
- Shut up, Cyril.
- Fuck you.
- You shut up or l'll--
- What? You're going to what?
l can take you.
l can beat you up.
Jesus fucking Christ, man.
This fucking place!
Here it is.
l sign that document,
l stop being a nun.
You gonna sign it?
Yes.
Wanna watch?
No, thanks.
Sister, hey.
- l really need to talk to you.
- l was just leaving.
No, Father.
Please stay.
l'd appreciate
your input.
- What's up?
- lt's my brother.
He seems to be okay
after the OD,
but he's having these
terrible nightmares again.
So he only gets
but a few hours of sleep,
and l'm beginning
to think that the--
the-- what'd you
call it?
- Deprivation?
- Yeah, that.
That shit's just starting
to affect his brain.
Why? What's he doing?
He's becoming aggressive.
He's making things up
and claiming to see things
that just aren't there.
- Really?
- Yeah.
l was wondering if maybe
you could put him back
on some kind of medication,
you know, something
to knock him out.
Just for a little while
until he gets some sleep?
All right,
l'll meet with Cyril,
- then l'll decide what's best for him.
- Okay.
You gotta remember this:
this stuff he's saying,
man, it's crazy.
And the nightmares
are always the same?
Pretty much.
ls there anything
in your dreams
that you see
when you're awake?
No.
Cyril, do you remember
anything before your accident?
Before l got hit
in the head?
Yeah.
My mother's hands.
They were rough,
all red from working,
but soft
when she touched me.
Anything else?
The cross...
like that...
around her neck.
She'd pray to Jesus.
Do you believe
in Jesus?
That's a silly question.
Why?
'Cause it's not
up to me,
believing
or not believing.
We don't choose God.
God chooses us.
Cyril, do you mind
if l talk to your brother for a minute?
Sure.
So?
l don't see any
of the symptoms you described.
ln fact,
quite the opposite.
He's always on his best behavior
with you, Sister,
- but l swear to God, the kid's--
- Ryan, don't swear.
What is true
is that he's exhausted,
so we need to try
to find a medication
other than the Haldol
to help him sleep.
Good, thank you.
l'll have Dr. Prestopnik
write up a prescription.
- Hello, Chris.
- Sister.
Stay where you are.
As you know,
for the past month or so,
l've been preparing
to leave the convent.
Mm-hmm.
Part of that stems
from the conversations
we had together.
You made me doubt myself
as a psychologist,
as a nun,
as a woman.
l'm sorry if l
caused you grief.
Oh, you caused me grief,
and l wanna
thank you for it.
What?
You know, Chris,
most of us
tumble into our lives.
We become who we are
almost by accident.
We try very hard
not to look backwards,
afraid to find out
that maybe we should've
done something else.
But you forced me
to look backwards,
to question
every element
of my identity.
By questioning,
do you know--
do you know
what l discovered?
l am a psychologist.
l am a woman.
l am a nun.
And all of these parts
of me are not an accident.
They were put together
by someone else.
Someone far greater.
We do not choose God.
God chooses us.
What happens to those of us
who he don't choose?
Like in grade school,
you're waiting
for one side or the other
to pick you
to play kickball,
but you're too small,
you're too stupid,
or maybe you're just
too weird.
All bullshit aside,
Sister,
l want God
to pick me.
Pick me!
Maybe he will.
There's still time.
You know something,
Sister?
l don't think so.
Oh, fuck!
We gotta stop.
What?
This.
- Why?
- People are talking.
- Fuck 'em.
- You'll as get fired.
What is this, O'Reily?
l'm sucking your dick so much
you're losing your balls?
- No, but l just thought that maybe--
- This ain't over
till l say it's over.
You start thinking different,
l'll crush these balls of yours.
You got that, punk?
Good.
Same time tomorrow,
cunnilingus.
Let's go.
There's nothing like
the thrill of gambling.
Nothing compares to that incredible
feeling of anticipation.
You wait breathlessly
for the roll of the dice,
for the spin of the wheel,
for the flip of the card.
You wait to see what fortune
fate will hand you.
Bob! Bob,
you're alive!
Apparently so.
Busmalis, get to work.
What did the doctor say?
Did the surgery go well?
Was the tumor benign?
- Yes, l'll survive, only...
- What?
l have this terrible scar
on my head.
They tell me
in time it'll go away,
but even so, l'm embarrassed
to be seen like this.
Bob, you're
so vain.
Don't get insulting.
No, vain is good.
When you got out of the hole,
you were kinda dragging.
But vain means
you still feel alive.
Stop talking nonsense.
Scar's hardly noticeable.
Bullshit!
This is your
lucky hat.
l'm lucky.
l'm glad you're
still breathing.
Miss Sally is really
coming to Oz?
When she heard after my escape,
that l went to her house,
that l'm her
number-one fan,
my goddess decided
she wanted to meet me.
Miss Sally in Oz.
Next we'll have
Seinfeld in here.
- How do l look?
- Truth?
- No, lie.
- You're very handsome.
Thank you.
- So where'd you get the flowers?
- That's a secret.
- Wish me luck.
- You're gonna need more than luck.
- Miss Sally?
- Yes.
How do you do?
These are for you.
Thank you.
They're lovely.
lt is a great thrill
to meet you, Miss Sally.
When l got word that you were dropping
by, it knocked me for a loop.
l am the envy
of every cell block.
That's very sweet.
l brought you something.
Oh my God.
There are guys in here
that would kill for this,
literally.
Miss Sally, l gotta
tell you,
you don't laugh
like you do on TV.
And while we're
on the subject,
you don't look the same
as on TV.
You seem smaller.
The camera adds
10 lbs.
To your breasts?
Fuck.
Miss Sally, you swore.
What about yesterday's lesson,
watch your tongue?
l'm not Miss Sally.
l work as a secretary
at the station.
l'm in charge of answering
all the letters
that Miss Sally receives.
When l heard about you escaping,
l remembered getting your letters.
l thought they were so sweet.
l went to Miss Sally
and asked her to visit here.
- And she said no?
- She got angry.
- She threw Neuter at me.
- Oh.
So l thought, hell,
l look enough like the bitch,
maybe l'll pull it off.
But l failed.
No, no,
this means a lot,
that you read my letters,
that you wanted to come.
- What's your name?
- Norma Clark.
Thank you, Norma.
You're welcome,
Agamemnon.
And if you don't mind,
l'd like to keep writing.
Of course.
But this time,
l'll write to you.
That'd be swell.
Everybody gambles,
from a card-shark
in Atlantic City
to an old lady scratching
at a lottery ticket.
Taking a chance,
risking it all,
that's as basic
a human need as
food, clothing, shelter.
lt's as fundamental to our genetic
makeup as killing thy neighbor.
Deyell, what the fuck
are you doing over there?
l'm digging an escape hatch.
Dumb-ass negro.
Fucking come sack.
- Miles.
- No. No, no!
No, no!
- Miles.
- No, no, no.
Your execution is set
for two weeks from Thursday.
Now there are certain matters
we have to discuss.
- No, no, no!
- The most important being
- how you're gonna die.
- No, no, no!
lf you don't make up your mind soon,
l'll be forced to decide for you.
No! No! No!
Take him down to psych.
Get up, Rembrandt.
Give me a--
Slam his ass!
Wait a minute.
l can't talk to him
all chained up like this.
Believe me, Sister,
you don't want him running loose.
All right.
Wait outside.
No way.
Come in.
Mark,
the warden thought it would be a good
idea for us to get together.
He says you're--
you're having problems
accepting the fact
that the date of your
execution
is approaching.
Problems?
l'm scared
shitless.
l seen Shirley Bellinger go
and that fag Ginsburg
die right there in the cell.
lt gets you thinking.
Look,
l am not a fan
of capital punishment,
and there are a lot
of others like me
who are doing
everything they can to stop it,
But that's
not going to happen
before two weeks
from Thursday.
Oh, Christ.
Mark,
you made a choice
to murder your family,
and as a result,
you don't have a choice
about staying alive.
So what you need,
and what l want
to help you do,
is to...
prepare for the end.
l know what you're
going through, man.
Sometimes the reality of what's gonna
happen fucks me up, too.
l don't need your
fucking sympathy, Sambo.
You don't quit,
do you?
l'm trying to work here,
so shut your fucking jive-ass mouth.
?? Amazing grace ??
Shut up.
?? How sweet the sound ??
l said shut up,
you fucking black bastard!
Holy shit!
Yo, Lopresti.
Can l get that mirror?
lt was Shirley's.
Oh, gee.
Seven years' bad luck.
Lights out!
- Fuck!
- Step aside, Vern.
Let a real man
at the table.
- Schillinjer.
- Schillinger.
Whatever.
You got a visitor.
Well, l'm not
expecting anyone.
She says she's
your daughter-in-law.
My what?
Mr. Schillinger?
Yeah?
l'm Carrie.
Hank's wife.
Look, honey, l don't know what kind
of scam you're trying to pull--
He didn't tell you
he was married?
No.
Oh, God.
Are you okay?
She's fine.
Mind your own fucking business.
l'm sorry.
l'm just so afraid.
Hank and me met,
and we had sex right off
and started hanging out
all the time together.
And then a few weeks ago,
he came into some money
all of a sudden
and says,
''Let's get hitched.''
So l say, ''Okay.''
But now he's gone.
He's disappeared
off the planet
and l don't know
what l'm gonna do.
You got any kind of proof
you two are married?
Our wedding certificate.
We done it at City Hall.
Why the fuck
didn't he tell me?
Oh, that's Hank.
Mr. Secretive.
l know where he is.
He went to Miami.
l gave him money for the trip.
Miami?
When is he due back?
- l don't know.
- Sooner than later?
'Cause it's
gotta be sooner.
See...
l got a...
situation.
l need his help.
What kind of situation?
Maybe l can help.
l'm pregnant.
- What the fuck is this, man?
- l ain't tryin' to hear you.
- What the fuck is you saying?
- l'm saying get up off my face.
Trust me,
l don't want to be peeping
your ugly fucking mug
any more
than l have to, okay?
Hey, what's the problem?
- This fucking child won't be talked to.
- Nigger, fuck you.
Mondo, here--
l ain't one
of your dogs, man.
of your prags either.
What l am is sick and tired
of all your bullshit.
Kids today...
We gotta do something
to shut his ass down.
Yeah, relax, relax.
Listen,
got some ideas l want to
talk to you about.
Ah, trouble
in paradise.
Yeah, but not enough
to be of any use to us.
You know what we got here,
O'Reily?
A fandango,
and we gotta
do something about it.
Hey, l don't like being in the minority,
but what can we do?
Even these fucking Muslims
are kowtowing to Adebisi.
Well, we could detonate
a few well placed
depth charges.
Whatever you need, K-Boy.
My God. Oh my God!
Help! Help!
Help, murder!
Murder! Murder!
Murder!
Like my day wasn't
already in the toilet.
Do you know what we've got
down there?
A dead fucking body.
Do you know what that means?
My record of no violence
is kaput.
You know what that means?
You are up to your
African ass in shit.
This is not my fault.
Oh yes it is.
We had a deal.
l would let you do
whatever the fuck you wanted
as long as you kept
the horseshit to zero.
A corpse is not zero.
So what do you
want me to do?
l want you to find me the bastard
that did this and bring me his ass,
- alive.
- You want me to play cop?
Life sucks all around.
Anything?
The dead guy, Shemin,
he was a complete fucking loser.
He ain't had no friends,
and as far as we know,
- he ain't had no enemies.
- Found out one thing,
- him and Tobias Beecher fucked.
- Yup.
- Beecher?
- Mm-hmm.
Bring him to me.
l didn't kill Shemin.
l heard about you
fucked him, though.
Once. He was lousy.
So were you, Mondo.
- What the fuck are you doing?
- l'm looking for the murder weapon.
Adebisi says that if l don't
find out who killed Shemin,
they're gonna beat
the shit out of me.
Get the fuck
off my stuff, man.
l saw you go
into the laundry room
with Shemin.
l saw you come out alone.
That don't mean dick.
Why did you do it?
Why did you kill him?
See this tat?
l got it the night
of my second marriage in Vegas.
l'd just run
this great Ponzi on some elderly couple,
so you know,
l'm celebrating--
some single malt,
a little X
and a whole lot
of Bonnie.
And as we fucked,
l kept yelling, ''l'm a God.
l'm a fucking God.''
l'm fucking tripping
out of my mind.
l go to this all-night
tattoo parlor
because l wanted every slob
on the strip to know
l was Almighty.
But l'm not.
See, l know that now,
Beecher, but this tattoo,
it ain't going away,
not without a lot more blood.
And l am supposed to glean
what from that story?
Well...
l see you fucking all
these other guys.
You said you didn't care
who l fucked.
l do.
l do, okay?
And you killed Shemin
'cause he and l fucked?
No, l--
- l'm gonna tell Adebisi what l know.
- Oh, l don't think you will.
- Why not?
- Well, for two reasons.
One, l know
you hired Pancamo
- to put a hit out on Hank Schillinger.
- No, no.
Oh, yeah. And Hank's dead.
Vern doesn't know it,
but that's only because
Pancamo makes sure
no one's gonna find
the body.
Let's say they do,
you know, find the body.
Schillinger's gonna
come back after you
and he's gonna destroy the rest
of your family. He will murder Holly.
- Fuck you.
- The second reason is,
you tell him l killed
Shemin, they will kill me.
But l think you love me
too much to see that happen.
Hey, Mondo.
How's it hanging, baby?
How was Browne
in bed?
Chris, don't.
You should take care
of where you stick your dick.
That baby is lethal.
You know, l liked it better
when we weren't speaking.
Winning and losing,
the two sides
of the same silver dollar.
But winning isn't always a good thing.
Think on it.
You suddenly come into
a lot of cash.
You start worrying
about how to spend it,
how to save it,
invest it.
You buy all this stuff
you don't really need
and you get weighed
the fuck down.
Losing,
on the other hand,
has a kind of purifying
effect.
When you got nothing,
and you're stripped
of all the doodads in life,
you are free.
Supreme Allah,
what is up
with Mondo Browne?
l mean, that boy
is nothing but trouble,
just a deluxe
pain in the ass.
You take care
of the other thing?
Yeah, l made your phone call.
Delivery truck's gonna get a flat tire.
Sweet.
Browne, get in line.
l'm waiting on a shipment.
The motherfucking truck caught a flat.
lf we miss that shipment tomorrow,
we don't have no breakfast.
l'll be back
for you later.
Everybody else,
let's go.
Looking for these?
Keller, what the fuck
are you doing here?
You and me, we got
personal business to do.
l ain't got
no business with you.
How'd you like
a blow job?
You sure?
Browne is dead.
Bullshit.
Murdered
in the cafeteria.
Hey, that's not
Em City.
He's still
one of ours, Adebisi.
Glynn is
pissed off royal.
Everything we've built
is on the verge of collapsing.
We found this
at the scene.
Do you know who the necklace
belongs to?
Yes.
- Come on.
- What's up, man?
- What's up?
You killed Shemin.
What the fuck am l gonna
kill Shemin for? He was nothing.
- You killed Browne.
- See?
That shit must've fell off when
l was working in the kitchen.
Yeah?
You cocksucker!
- Fuck you, bitch!
- Yeah, fuck me? Fuck you!
Fuck you! Fuck you!
Fuck you, bitch!
Fuck you!
Fucking kill you!
Fucking up my shit!
- Fuck you!
- l'll kill you!
Look what was
under Supreme's pillow.
That fucking shit
ain't mine!
Fuck!
Motherfucker!
This is some fucking bullshit!
Get the fuck off!
Some fucking bullshit!
Get the fuck off me!
Get the fuck off!
l ain't fucking
do that shit!
Motherfucker,
let go of me!
Let 'em out.
Deaths of Shemin
and Browne.
This is the hand
of God.
Maybe.
But do their deaths fit in with
your plan to bring Adebisi down?
Oh, yes.
l'm getting close
to Adebisi to find that one flaw
that'll finally
cripple him.
l hope
it happens soon.
Adebisi?
l said wind slowly.
l said slow!
Wind slow!
You don't know slow?
You're not even a woman.
Wait here.
Man, l got to admit,
l was struck stupid when you joined
forces with Adebisi, man.
What he's up to--
hold on.
Man, given what
you believe in,
man, it's tough to take
this conversion seriously.
l swore to Allah.
l think that swearing
of yours
got something to do
with you trying to stop him.
You always did have
a very vivid imagination.
l'll tell you
what else l got.
l got the knack
for picking winners and losers,
and you,
you're gonna win.
Sure hope to shit
you do.
What's the matter, Poet?
You done with gangster life?
Man, l ain't done
with shit except Adebisi
and fucking videotapes.
Videotapes?
Yeah, he likes to record
his antics for posterity.
You talking about the sex
and drugs, right?
And life
in Party Central.
These videotapes,
can you get a hold of them?
He keeps them in his pod.
l mean, l could try.
Do it now.
Simon, can l have
a word, please?
Yeah, go ahead.
ln private.
Gotta get
all the young brothers
to go to class,
get an education.
- Like that, huh?
- Yeah, excellent.
You say a word
about me being in here,
you're dead.
You hear me?
Simon, l'm not done
talking with you yet.
We'll talk later.
But we have to let
Querns know.
Yeah, later.
They're in
the ceiling tiles,
but l didn't get
a chance to get one.
Lots of Native Americans,
a.k.a. lndians,
used to live on reservations
in utter poverty.
Alcoholism was rampant,
morale was low.
Then some chief got the
brainstorm idea
to use the land,
not to hunt buffalo,
but to raise money
by building a casino.
Then faster than you
can say ''Custer,''
the lives of the members
of the tribe changed for the better.
So you see, sometimes
you can eliminate your own vices
by exploiting
the vices of others.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
Unfortunately we don't have
another option.
You're gonna ask Adebisi if
you can move in with him,
- live in his pod?
- l need access to those videotapes.
What makes you think
he'll say yes?
Believe me,
he'll say yes.
Man, l don't
even smoke these.
What's up, Poet?
Yo, Leroy.
What's happening, man?
- Nothing.
- Hey, Mondo, man,
he was a wild boy, man.
He got greased. You okay?
No, not really.
- Hey, give me some of that shit.
- Here, man.
Hey, it's
you and me, Poet.
We gotta cover
each other's backs now.
- Yeah.
- Adebisi is a crazy a motherfucker.
l'll tell you that,
though,
you ain't have to worry
about Adebisi that much longer.
- No?
- No, man.
Me and Said, we're
working on an angle.
For real?
What you up to?
l can't tell you that.
lt's top secret.
- No doubt.
l hear that.
Later, blood.
All right.
- lt's what we thought.
- Okay.
You want me
to whack Poet?
No, not yet.
Don't want them to know
that we know.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
So...
which bunk
do you want?
When was the last time you were in
Emerald City?
l don't remember.
- Since Querns took over?
- Probably.
Well, don't you think
it's time for another fucking visit?
Watch the way
you talk to me!
Leo, this is not
just my ego.
The behavior in there
is illegal, immoral,
and Querns
turns a blind eye.
Now you gave the man a free hand
because he kept the violence down,
but two inmates
are dead.
You gotta step in.
You know, l remember
when you first came to Oz.
Jefferson Keane had come
to challenge you.
You got one of your fellow
Muslims to hit you harder, harder,
until you bled.
l didn't know what
to make of you then.
Still don't now.
Simon, the both of us
have been on
an extraordinary journey.
And l've tried to learn
from mine,
tried to find
the common thing that binds us all.
Crime.
Crime is
the common theme.
See, we are
all of us bad men, even you.
l know you have come
to destroy me.
Simon,
l don't wanna
destroy you.
l want to help you
change.
That is what
would destroy me.
See, l am who l am,
just as you are.
And l do what l do,
just as you must.
Does that mean you're
gonna kill me?
Kill you?
l wanna kiss you.
But because l admire you
more than l desire you.
This is what
you came for.
Why are you
giving this to me?
Because l have
everything--
everything l need,
every love satisfied,
but it's not enough.
lt'll never be enough.
But like you said,
between the pair of us,
we can do great things for our people.
But for what?
We're still in Oz.
Yeah!
Kiss my foot,
kiss it.
Turn it off.
l've seen enough.
Leo,
What are you gonna say, Querns?
You gonna hand me a lot of excuses?
You didn't know?
You did know?
lt doesn't matter.
You're fired.
Officer, escort Mr. Querns
off the property.
Let me at least
clean out my office.
We'll send you
your belongings.
Get out.
You have yourself
a lovely evening.
This is all
my fucking fault.
Been so caught up in the campaign,
l haven't been doing my job.
You want Em City back?
Let me think it over--
yes.
All right,
listen up, everybody.
l'm back.
The following are
being transferred out of Em City.
When you hear your name,
pack up your belongings,
line up
behind Officer Johnson.
93A234, Adebisi;
- 00T255, Tidd;
- What the fuck?
097 C332, Cody;
00W216, Washington.
So the end
is here, huh?
No, more likely things are gonna go
back to the way they were before.
Oh, not for me,
or for you.
You said you weren't
gonna kill me!
You swore to Allah
that you were my brother.
- And l meant that.
- Liar!
Liar.
l gave you that tape
as a final test
of your loyalty,
your friendship,
- your love!
- Oh, God!
- This is how l'm gonna die.
- No!
No!
Oh, yes, yes!
This is 25,
we got a 16.
Drop it.
Drop it! Drop the shank!
Easy, easy.
Let me go!