There's all kinds
of slang words for prison--
''The Joint,'' ''The Slammer,''
''The Big House.''
But my personal favorite
is ''The Clink.''
That's because the word comes
from the sound the chains made
back in the 1400s.
They had these big-ass,
motherfucking iron chains.
The prisoners
weren't allowed to talk,
so when they moved
around the dungeon,
all you heard was ''clink.''
Listen up.
The following are being
transferred
out of Emerald City:
96G333,
Guccione;
91H481,
Hardin;
94S727,
Shirner.
Get your
stuff
and follow
Officer Keating.
Yo, so long, suckers.
Psst!
Blow me.
You got to fix
this damn thing by noon.
Querns...
how can you condone
what Adebisi is doing?
The drugs,
the sex?
He even has a curtain across
his cell to hide his sins.
l don't have to explain
why l condone
what l condone
to you.
No, you don't.
But l can go
to the warden.
l can send you
to the hole.
You know others
have tried to silence me.
Others ain't me,
Said.
lf you want
to move to another unit,
l can arrange that.
lf not, do what you do best.
Pray to Allah.
Rest of the time,
keep your mouth shut.
Arif...
look out there.
Look!
Can you see
what's going on?
Yes.
Then how can you
just sit there?
You said you
wanted to lead.
Well, in the name
of all that's holy,
lead.
All right.
Okay, bye-bye.
Bye.
You're on.
l've been trying to get five minutes
with you for days.
Well, you got
them now.
Don't waste them
by complaining.
First off, when you set up
this new system,
why wasn't l named
one of the trustees?
The Muslim population
constitutes 18°/% of Oz.
As their leader, l expect some sort
of representation.
l know the Muslim
population is large,
but as a force,
you all seem...
rudderless.
You wait, Querns.
You'll feel the full force
of our power.
Are you
threatening me?
Hmm?
Hmm?!
Huh?
Huh?!
Are you
threatening me?
Get your ass
out of here.
But me and Supreme,
we were just talking.
l don't want you
anywhere near him.
But l was just listening
to what he had to say.
That's an order.
Yes, sir.
Now go.
l must pray.
And just then,
l heard a voice,
a thunderous voice
with like--
with like an Eazy-E-type
of nasalness saying,
''Truth casts no shadows
because it soaks sun
like fava sponges,
do bungee-cord jumpings
into the abyss.
Hold truth
tightly in your fist.''
What did l tell you,
Ketchum?
My name's
Supreme Allah.
Your name
is Kevin Ketchum.
You're nothing
but a low-life corner boy.
What are you,
Arif?
Other than a Kareem Said
wannabe?
l'm not warning
you again.
Adebisi.
That's me.
We need to talk
about this guy Ketchum.
Oh, yeah?
What about him?
He's a danger
to us both.
Yeah?
How so?
He's making all these converts
of my people, yours.
l'm not worried.
You should be.
Pretty soon they'll be
following his orders.
Well, me and Supreme,
we have an understanding.
You can't
trust him.
What are
you suggesting?
You should do what you usually do
when you face an enemy.
You mean kill him?
l thought you Muslims
are against murder.
Ah, yeah, but it's okay
if l kill him for you, eh?
- Adebisi.
- No.
l says no.
You want him dead,
grab a knife, eh?
Morning.
Hey, Sean, what are you
doing here?
The new guy running
Em City, Querns,
- he and l came to a parting of ways.
- Oh, yeah?
The warden reassigned
me to reception,
but l'll tell you, l'm not cut out
for deskwork.
My guess?
l'll be gone
in a week or two.
Hey, listen,
you know what l said
about being mad at you
because you didn't quit
when l was fired? That's bullshit.
Given my
behavior at the time,
how could l possibly pass
judgment on what anyone else did?
Tim, you-- you sound
so enlightened.
You find God?
Better.
An affordable
shrink.
Let's have dinner
tonight.
Okay, but you're
buying.
Okay.
Hey, Andrea.
lt's morning
already?
Quiet night?
lf you count two
fistfights
and some anal
penetration as quiet, yeah.
Who got
in the fights?
That biker, Hoyt,
and one of those lrish boys, Keenan.
- Cocksucker!
- Fuck you!
Fucking rape--
Break it up, break it up.
Come on.
Martin, what's up?
As you know,
Sean Murphy has been asked
to transfer out
of Em City
and l've made Travis Smith
my new CO supervisor.
Problem is, some of the officers
are loyal to Murphy.
So l'm asking you
to move these COs out
and bring these in.
Okay, done.
Mobay!
l need these transfers
taken care of right away.
Yes, sir.
- So how's the campaign going?
- Great.
l say we talk
to the warden.
Nah, he's got his head
up Devlin's ass.
He's not paying attention
to our problems here.
We ought to go
to the Union.
Huh? Go to the Union
about what?
My pal Querns is replacing
all the COs in Em City
with people
of his own choosing.
That's his right.
Yeah, only he's choosing
all black guys.
Oh, well,
good news is you can come
work for me in Unit B.
Really?
Yeah, l could use
the muscle, believe me.
l'll go to Glynn.
l'll make the transfers.
- Thanks, Tim.
- Sounds good.
- Hey, we were a great team, right?
- Yeah.
Okay.
- l'll put the paperwork through.
- Good.
- Hey, Leo.
- What?
Doesn't it bother you
that Querns is putting together
an exclusively
black staff?
Look, l told the man
he could run his unit any way he wanted
as long as the violence
was kept down.
Okay? You know,
since Querns took over,
there's been no significant
nonsense in Em City.
Yeah.
How long is that
going to last?
There's that Romanian place around
the corner.
lt's a dump,
but the food's delicious,
especially that
''chumala de mia.''
Well, well,
Frick and Frack.
l hear you two choirboys
are working
together
again in Unit B.
That's right.
l just got a
transfer myself.
Seems the warden was in
a tizzy 'cause Querns
got all black
COs in Em City.
You're going to work
in Emerald City?
Yeah.
Life's full of ironies,
isn't it?
For Christ's sake, Ginzburg,
l can't take it anymore.
All day, all night
with the vomiting.
Why don't you
hurry up and die?
Jesus.
l just came from seeing
Nat Ginzburg.
What's he want?
You know he
has AlDS.
Yeah, but he refuses
to move to the AlDS ward.
Gloria tells me
he hasn't got long to live,
but he's tired
of fighting the disease,
so he asked me
to ask you
if it would
be possible
to move up
the execution.
Move up
the execution?
Yeah.
No one's ever asked
to be executed early.
l mean, the court set
a specific date.
There's no legal precedent
to change it.
So let's start
a precedent.
You're encouraging
me to do this,
given your own position
against capital punishment?
The man is
dying, Leo.
l believe, in this particular case,
ending his life would be a--
a blessing.
That's euthanasia.
l thought your church
was against euthanasia.
My church is against
a lot of things l'm not.
Okay, l'll call
the lawyers.
Good.
State troopers closed
Bear Mountain this morning
after a reported sighting of escaped
convict Miguel Alvarez.
An extensive search
was launched, but Alvarez,
who has been missing
for three weeks,
once again
evaded capture.
ln a related story, Superior Court Judge
Mason Kossler today
granted the unusual request
of convicted murderer
Nathaniel Ginzburg,
who asked to be executed
two months earlier
than the court
had ordered.
The execution will
take place next Thursday
at the Oswald
State Correctional Facility.
Sister Pete's
here to see you.
How do l look?
You look like
Susan Hayward.
Bingo. That's what
l was going for.
Sister,
l'm so grateful to you
for everything
you've done,
but l've got to ask you
one more favor.
Anything.
My nails.
l'm so excited
l can't hold
the damn brush still.
- Will you do me?
- Sure.
Sit down.
Okay.
Try to keep your
hands still.
Okay, that's it.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, yeah.
You know what? No, no.
You'd better lie down.
We'll finish
your nails later, okay?
5:00 AM...
l got me a date
with an angel.
You rest.
Ginzburg's dead tomorrow
because he killed Antonio Nappa.
Yeah?
- You wanted him to do it.
- Yeah.
Doesn't that bother you
a little?
He's dying
'cause of you.
No. This is
the life we chose.
Sure,
but Chucky...
are you afraid of
dying?
No.
What the fuck are you
doing with a cigarette, Pancamo?
Smoking it?
Put it out.
Now!
Or l'm coming
in there.
Now her,
l'm afraid of.
l heard Ginzburg
picked the gas chamber as a way to die.
That'd be
all right.
One minute you're sitting
there breathing in and out,
stuff fills
your lungs.
Next thing
you know,
you don't
know nothing.
- A blow job.
- What?
lnstead
of a last meal,
they should give you
one last blow job.
Yeah.
Ginzburg, it's time.
Ginzburg?
Nat?
Oh, my God.
He's cold.
He's dead.
Get a doctor.
Go figure.
He dies in his sleep
of natural causes.
He looks so beautiful.
What are
you doing?
l'm going to
finish his nails.
Count!
Mobay.
Mobay, get your ass
in the air.
Yeah, yeah.
Coming.
Mobay, pay attention.
Tomorrow
we get healthy.
''Healthy?''
What does that mean, ''healthy?''
lt means we're getting
a new shipment in.
- Where?
- None of your business.
So, Mobay,
T-Brown,
l want each of you
to bring me five new babies.
Babies?
- Some new customers,brother.
- Babies. Okay.
Poet,
you supervise.
l don't need
supervising.
What you need
is to learn
to take an order.
Yes... sir.
Mobay.
You know Detective McGorry
from Homicide?
- Sure. Hi, Guinevere.
- John.
You're here about
the death of Bruno Gergan.
Gergan may have been a bad cop,
but he turned state's evidence
in the gun
smuggling case.
The DA is pissed
that his prime witness
didn't last a week
in Oz.
Any idea
who killed him?
l thought him falling
down the elevator shaft was an accident.
No, my gut says
otherwise.
You think somebody
whacked Gergan
'cause they found
out he was a cop?
No, this is--
this is something else.
l just can't figure out
what yet.
Wait, Mobay.
Please, man, please!
Well, if l can help
your investigation in any way...
Yeah.
Keep your ears open.
You hear boasting,
you call me.
Warden, l'm gonna
set up some interviews,
- starting with Gergan's cell-mate.
- Okay.
Later.
So, you in good
with Adebisi
and the boys?
Yes.
They've got a fresh supply
showing up tomorrow,
only l can't find out
which door.
They also wanted me to recruit
some new buyers.
As a police officer,
you can't sell drugs.
l know.
l'll use the cash l have
and pretend l found my ''babies.''
- Hey, there's your boy.
- Okay.
l got him.
- Where you been?
- Recruiting.
l got two babies.
- Who?
- l don't know their names.
Well, point 'em out
to me, man.
- They already left.
- Shit.
Well, give me
that money, man.
Come on, come on,
come on.
- l'm out of tits.
- All right.
Here you go.
Keep on selling,
baby.
Keep on selling.
Hey, Mobay.
Give it a rest, man.
You been shoving that shit
up your nose since lights out.
l want to get
some sleep.
So sleep.
What'd you say?
Nothing, sorry.
Sister Peter Marie.
l'm glad the warden
told you who l really am.
l need to talk and l need
this to be confidential.
Of course.
Oz is my first big
undercover assignment.
A lot of the guys
l work with in Narcotics
didn't think l could handle
the job, but l knew l could.
Thought l could.
Left my wife
and son,
told them l'd be gone l don't
know how many months.
Abby--
that's my wife--
she's worried,
naturally,
that l'll
be found out,
that l'll be killed.
Today's Robby's birthday.
l thought l was close
to busting the drug ring,
but l'm not.
Only l've got to.
l blow this,
my career is over,
l'm back to riding
the subways arresting bums.
So l gotta stay.
l gotta see this through.
But--
but, Sister,
l'm an addict.
People in love
sometimes say that they're
''head over heels,''
but if they knew what
the phrase really meant,
l'm not sure that
they'd make the claim.
Back in the bad
old days,
as a warning
to criminals,
judges would order
malcontents to be
hung by their ankles,
heels over head.
The phrase came to mean
a state of helplessness,
confusion.
Now that l think
of it,
that is being
in love.
What should l do
if l ever find out who killed Gary?
You should
whack 'em.
Yeah?
lt'll be my pleasure.
What the fuck?
You murdered my son!
My son is dead.
Nothing can change that.
And Keller
had Gary killed.
Nothing's gonna change
that either.
Beecher, killing Keller
is no way to mourn your child.
What, now you're defending
that cocksucker?
No. He must
be punished.
But not by you.
Tobias, the F.B.l. found
your daughter.
Holly's alive.
We investigated
the lead you gave us.
Bob ''Big Butt'' Towland
had nothing to do with the kidnapping.
He'd been arrested
two days before
and was sitting
in the Crown and Shield Holding Center
awaiting arraignment.
But if he didn't do it,
that means...
Chris Keller
is innocent.
Oh, Christ.
Oh, Jesus fucking Christ!
We arrested
the real kidnapper this morning.
Tobias...
it's Hank Schillinger.
Sit down, Vern.
We got a couple
of items to discuss.
Oh, do we now?
l got a file
just full
of fights between
you two.
Plus...
l'm told you like to fuck
each other up the ass.
Now l'm not wild
about either practice,
so, Keller, l'm moving
you to another pod.
But if either of you
touches the other in love or war,
l will transfer both of you to Gen Pop.
Understood?
- Yes.
Keller, go pack.
Beecher, l have
other business with you.
The warden tells me
that an inmate from Unit B,
Vern Schillinger,
may be responsible
for your son's death.
So we've decided
for the time being
to restrict your movements
through the rest of Oz.
No library or gym
privileges,
and you'll eat your
meals here at Em City.
He killed my son
and l get punished for it?
Well, given the fact
that l have transferred
all the Aryans out
of Em City,
this is the safest
place for you.
Safe?
Relatively speaking.
- Chris?
- Don't. Don't even.
My son died horribly.
l was out of my mind
with grief.
You actually thought in your heart
that l could do such a thing?
Order the murder
of a child?
Your child?
Yeah, you've got plenty
of reasons
to assume
the worst about me.
but l worked very hard...
to regain your trust,
your love.
l thought l had,
but this proves that l haven't.
- Chris...
- l don't, l can't--
- Please.
- l never will.
- No. We're over.
We're finished.
We're done.
Chris, you gotta
forgive me.
No.
l forgave you.
Well, l guess that
makes you the better man.
Howdy.
l's your
new neighbor.
This is my bunk.
lt ain't no more.
Mondo...
play nice.
Lunch detail!
Follow me.
- Feds arrested Hank?
- Yeah.
After letting
the girl go,
feds surrounded him.
Push comes to shove
and the federal boys leaning on him,
think your son'll
give you up?
Honest to Christ,
l don't know.
Hey, Vern.
Four marriages,
l never had any kids,
so l don't know dick about parenting,
but you, fuck,
you deserve some sort of prize.
One son, you give him
drugs knowing he'll OD.
The other you set up
for lethal injection.
You're father of the fucking year,
but you know what the best news is?
When both your sons are dead,
that'll be the end of it,
'cause you ain't making
any more children. Not in here.
So that when you die,
your name dies with you.
Everything you are
dies when you do.
And the world'll be
a better place.
Well, well, well, what have
we got up in here?
Oh, l see.
My man Keller.
What's up, dog?
Hey, Keller, man,
l gotta ask you a question, man.
You mind if l fuck
your girlfriend Beecher?
You mind if she
sucks my cock?
l don't give a fuck what you do
or what he does.
You heard that,
Leroy?
l did, Mondo.
l did.
All right, 'cause we
don't want no problems in Em City,
so it goes on record
that l got Keller's permission
- to fuck Beecher up the yazoo.
- Yes, you do.
Peace.
What happened
to your hand?
l was remembering
what hell felt like.
Bless me, Father,
for l have sinned.
ln the past year or so, l've committed
numerous homosexual acts.
Do you want me
to elaborate?
No.
Before coming
to Oz,
l had sex
with several men...
and then
l whacked them.
What?
After sex,
l murdered them.
Why?
l didn't want them to tell anyone,
to speak my name.
You have to go to the authorities
and confess.
What?
You can't
absolve me?
l can absolve you, but the only way
to show God
that you're truly sorry is to go
to the police.
Look...
l'm truly sorry, okay?
So just fucking absolve me.
No.
Give me my
fucking penance.
No.
God damn you.
God damn you
to fucking hell,
you goddamn
hack in black.
Oh, no.
Come on, Beecher,
suck my dick.
Jesus, you're such
a romantic.
That the way you talk
to your women?
Well, when l'm horny,
the less talk the better.
Okay, lover boy.
Pucker up.
For centuries,
part of any punishment
was humiliation.
ln England, they'd hang
a criminal inside a cage
a few feet off the ground
in the middle
of the town square.
The filthy fuck sat
in his cage looking like a canary,
like a parakeet.
So people started calling
them ''jailbirds.''
Only the kind of chirping
we do in Oz...
ain't all
that pretty.
- Mr. Morales.
- Mr. Rebadow.
My request.
You said you needed time
to think it over.
Ah, yes.
Well?
When you asked me
to kill Raul Hernandez,
you said l could have
anything l wanted in return.
And now you want me
to let you kill someone else.
Yes.
Oddly enough,
there's no one l need exterminated
at the present time.
Besides...
as a newly-appointed trustee,
l have promised Querns
that there will be
no violence in Emerald City.
You're going
against your word.
Ask for
something else--
cigarettes,
money, drugs.
l want to kill
somebody.
lf you have
your heart set on it,
why do you need
my permission?
Not permission,
protection.
That you can have.
No matter who l kill?
You aren't gonna
do anything crazy, are you?
Like waste Pancamo?
Certainly not.
Then who are you
gonna kill?
Who indeed?
May l join you?
May l join you,
Busmalis?
You're talking
to me?
You're actually saying words
intended for my ears?
Yes.
l've been treating you badly,
and l'm sorry.
You mean all's
forgiven?
That's right.
All's forgiven.
Would you like
my pie?
Yes.
Yes!
l'm tired
but happy.
You're speaking
to me again.
The chicken
at dinner was edible.
All in all,
life is good.
l'm the happiest
of men.
Lights out!
l've been reading
''The Art of War'' by Sun Tzu.
Fascinating stuff.
The instinct to kill
is as common as the need
to procreate.
Those of us in Oz are actually
the normal ones,
following nature's lead.
Funny, huh, Busmalis?
Busmalis?
Jesus!
Help!
What are you doing?
- Get him off me!
- Fucking Christ.
He's trying to kill me.
Jesus Christ!
He cut me!
Give me this!
You're doing fucking time.
- You're okay.
- What the fuck did he do that for?
Shit! God damn,
l'm all cut up here.
Eddie.
Hey. Yeah.
No, it's me.
That's why
l'm calling.
Yeah.
Right.
You'll get it done
by next week?
Good. No later
than next week, right?
Okay. All right.
See you.
- You called for me?
- Did you put Hoyt into solitary?
No.
- He tried to kill me.
- l know.
But so far,
neither of you will tell me why.
lt's personal.
Fine.
You ask for
protective custody,
l set you up here.
But sooner or later,
l'm bringing you back,
and Hoyt or one of his
biker buddies
will finish the job on you.
So go ahead,
keep it personal.
Wait!
l will tell you.
Everything.
Galino had a cell phone.
After he died,
l got hold of it.
Now O'Reily's got it.
He's hidden it somewhere
in Em City.
Where is it?
The cell phone.
What-- what cell phone,
Mr. Querns?
You know
which cell phone.
They're against
the rules, sir.
Mm-hmm.
- You didn't find it?
- No.
And without that cell phone,
l have no way
- of proving your story is true.
- So what happens now?
Well, l leave you here
a couple more days,
then l'm sending
you back.
To die.
All right,
Mr. Querns,
l have two requests.
l would like to see
my girlfriend
and a rabbi.
l'll set it up.
l am soon very likely
going to die.
- Nikolai.
- There is one thing you must do for me.
Anything.
Tonight at 5:00 PM,
l want you to dial
this phone number.
lt must
be 5:00 PM sharp.
ln my proudest moment
as your Governor,
l signed the law that
reinstated the death penalty.
Together, we've made
great strides
in the war on crime,
but there's much more to do.
Let's finish the job.
The courage to lead:
James Devlin for Governor.
A long time ago...
if a man stole
another man's cow
or lamb or pig
and butchered it
and was found
with the animal's blood
on his fingers,
he was said to be caught
''red-handed.''
Of course, if the robber
was too cocky to wash his hands,
maybe he deserved
to get busted.
Count!
Shit.
Fuck.
l never touched
the cell phone.
He never let me
touch it.
l didn't kill
Galino.
Stanislofsky did.
lt's his word
against mine.
l got five guys
that'll back me up.
l want Stanislofsky dead.
Protective custody?
No can do.
l thought you had some
clout in this fucking place.
Sorry, O'Reily.
Your brother,
he sleep all day?
No, no, they just got
him on this new medication
to calm him down
and stuff.
lf you ask me,
he's too calm.
Cyril, psst.
Cyril?
Cyril, wake up.
Cyril!
Cyril, wake up!
Cyril, wake the fuck up!
Cyril!
Fuck!
Officer Smith, there's something
the matter with my brother.
- What do you mean?
- l don't know. Hurry up.
Call a fucking doctor.
Let's go.
Central, this is 16.
We got a possible four here.
Let's start two large lVs
with normal saline running wide open.
- We'll need to tube him.
- What happened?
He OD'd
on the Haldol.
- O'Reily?
- What?
- Any news on your brother?
- No.
The-- the fucking hacks,
they tell me to wait here
and l'm fucking waiting
here and there's nothing.
What's going on
in there?
l'm sure he'll
be fine.
You know, she did this.
This-- this fucking
Dr. Nathan.
She gives him too much of the
drugs on purpose.
lt's her way of trying
to get back at me.
l don't think she's capable
of something like that.
Hey, Gloria
fucking hates me.
Wake up. l mean, she thinks
l hired Keenan to rape her.
Now she's got my brother back
there in her clutches
and there's not a fucking thing
l can do about it.
l fucking hate
this place!
Fuck!
Cyril!
Gloria.
How's Cyril?
They pumped his stomach.
He's breathing normally.
Problem is, we don't know
how long he was unconscious
before they brought him in
so the next few hours will be dicey,
but l think
he'll be fine.
How does that
make you feel?
- Are we suddenly in session?
- No.
No, l just wanted to be sure
that he gets the best care that he can.
Oh, and you don't think
that l'm capable of separating
my professional obligations
from my anger?
l think that right now
you're so turned around
you can't see
which way to go.
- l have other patients, if you don't--
- Gloria.
Ryan O'Reily did not hire
that man to rape you.
He admitted that
he did.
He told you what
you wanted to hear.
Keenan raped me
because of O'Reily.
The attack on
you was random.
lf Keenan hadn't
raped you,
he would've raped
someone else.
- Hi, Keenan.
- Hey.
Hey, luck
of the lrish, right?
- Yeah.
- All right.
Hey, l want you to do
something for me.
Anything.
l want you
to tell me.
About what?
When you raped
Dr. Nathan,
l want to know what it
was like to fuck her.
Okay.
She was heading
into her apartment,
looking so hot.
Yeah.
How you feeling?
My head hurts.
That'll go away.
Where's Ryan?
l don't know.
Probably Em City.
And then l just
slammed my cock into her.
l slammed her.
You don't like us,
do you?
l like you.
Until she couldn't
scream no more.
Couldn't breathe
no more.
My brother...
he does bad things,
but deep down he's
not bad.
l came inside her
and she was moaning.
He loves you.
With all his heart.
Jesus.
You sure did
a job on her, huh?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
So you say you want
to work for me?
Definitely.
l do things different
here in Oz
than the way we
worked on the street.
For instance, when l want
someone dead,
l never grease
them myself.
l always--
l always talk someone else
into doing
the deed for me.
l make them believe
the person l want dead is their enemy.
That way the kill
can't be traced back to me.
That's so cool.
You got, what,
seven years till parole?
Uh-huh.
You think you'll
go the distance?
- Sure, l'll get out.
- Yeah. That's good.
You keep believing
that, Patrick.
You know how l said
that l always
- get someone to kill for me?
- Yeah.
Well...
in your case, l'm gonna make
an exception.
Take him down
to the morgue.
My only real memory from that night
was this shamrock.
l remember the light from
the streetlamp kept bouncing off it.
When they brought Keenan
into the ER, l thought,
''Good.
He's dead.
Good.''
You were right.
l came back
too soon.
l need to take
some time,
you know, just put
my anger back
in its proper place.
Maybe then l can learn
to forgive,
myself more than anyone.
The job will be here
whenever you decide
to come back.
lf l come back, Leo.
''To seal one's fate.''
Years ago, the death sentence
could not be carried out
unless the death warrant
had the judge's official seal
affixed to the bottom.
lmagine...
the only thing standing
between you and death
is a little lump
of melted wax.
But that's the thing
about life.
The big changes all
come because of
little lumps of wax.