The Bill of Rights,
those first 10 Amendments
to the Constitution.
We invented them, us,
the US of A.
Before our Founding Fathers
dipped their quills
into the inkwell and wrote
the Bill of Rights,
no other country
had ever defined
a government's
responsibility to its people,
the prime
responsibility being
to preserve liberty.
Liberty!
Of course,
there are those
who take all kinds
of liberties with liberty.
Sometime yesterday
before 5:00,
two inmates escaped
through a tunnel
under the southeast
wall of the prison.
Miguel Alvarez,
30s, Latino;
and Agamemnon Busmalis,
50s, Caucasian;
are not believed
to be armed.
Alvarez is, however,
considered dangerous.
Alvarez!
l want to assure the public
that there is a coordinated effort
by Warden Glynn's staff,
the local police department
and state troopers to locate
and apprehend these criminals.
Warden Glynn?
Warden Glynn, how long
did it take for them to dig this tunnel?
- l wouldn't know.
- Can we assume the digging
- took more than a day?
- Yes.
- More than a week?
How can your staff not have
known what was going on?
Busmalis is a low-risk prisoner who
demonstrates no aggressive tendencies,
and so was given slightly more freedom
than, in retrospect, he should have.
- You say Alvarez is dangerous?
- He has a history of violence,
but he's been under medication
to control that kind of behavior.
Hey, Hernandez, look like you missed
your chance to kill Alvarez, huh?
Adebisi, you'd better
shut the fuck up, man.
Those goddamn
reporters.
You handled yourself well, Leo,
all things considered.
l appreciate your
standing by me.
People love a prison break.
lt's sexy, exciting.
ln the end, they want
the escapees captured.
We know where their families are,
who their friends are;
we're watching every plane, train
and highway in the state.
- We'll get them.
- l hope so,
because if we don't,
your chances of becoming
lieutenant governor are zero.
You had no idea
Busmalis was working on a tunnel?
No.
The truth is, l'm a little hurt that he
didn't ask me to go with him.
Alvarez never
talked to you about escaping?
When? He's in solitary,
then he's in the hospital.
Come on, Hernandez,
you hate Alvarez as much as l do.
- Help me bring him back.
- l don't know dick.
l want word out
on the street.
When Alvarez shows his face,
l want his fucking heart ripped out
and shoved up his
fucking ass.
- That's it?
- Go.
''Alvarez,
l'll kill you.
- l'll kill you.''
- No, no!
''l'll kill you.
l'll kill you.''
Adebisi,
feeling cocky today?
Always!
You won't be feeling so fucking cocky
after l talk to the hacks.
About what?
About you giving
the French guy the gun.
Warden wants to know
how Frenchy killed four guys.
lf l tell him it was you
that was responsible,
they're going to ship your cocola ass
to death row, bro'.
Tell them it was me,
l'll tell them it was you, papi.
Hey, that's fine.
We'll see who he believes.
So Adebisi gave the gun
to Tarrant?
Yeah. He wanted a white man
to shoot a black man.
- Why?
- Why? To stir things up.
One last question...
who did Adebisi
get the gun from?
Step out.
Who?
- Hughes.
- Hughes?
Clayton Hughes?
The day you fired him
as a C.O.
Oh, fuck.
Leo, what's up?
You called,
said come right over?
Look at you...
like a Zulu.
What's this about?
Right there.
Right fucking there.
Yeah, l know,
that's where my dad died.
Stabbed
by an inmate.
A white inmate.
Clayton,
l'm going to ask
you something
and l want you
to tell me
on your father's soul
the absolute truth.
Yes, l gave
Adebisi the gun.
- Feel better?
- No.
l knew the minute
l heard your voice on the phone
you knew what l had done.
Because of me, four people are dead.
- Four black people.
- Clayton, shut up.
- No, Leo, listen...
- Don't say any more.
Don't say
another goddamn word!
Officer Mineo.
Look, we're going
to get you a lawyer,
and until then l don't want
you saying anything to anybody.
- you understand?
- l am guilty.
Clayton, l'm trying
to protect you.
Hey, Clayton,
how you doing?
- arrest him.
- what?
l said arrest him.
Yes, Hughes gave me the gun.
And you gave
it to Tarrant?
No. The cocksucker stole
the weapon from my cell.
Take him to the hole.
Prisoner number 00M87 1,
Enrique Morales;
convicted April 6th, 2000,
murder in the second degree;
sentence: 25 years,
up for parole in 15.
Hernandez, Adebisi and me
- have been partners selling tits.
- This l know.
Hernandez is having some kind
of nervous breakdown.
- This l also know.
- We don't want a partner who is loco.
You come with cred,
so we're offering you
Hernandez's third.
- lf l waste him?
- Yes.
Do it quietly...
and soon.
- May l come in?
- Well...
l won't hurt you, sir.
Sit.
l'm not like Hernandez
or Guerra.
They're spics,
old-school thugs.
Me, l'm a businessman.
l like Armani suits,
l surf the net.
Really?
l have a proposition
for you.
Really?
Raul Hernandez must be killed,
but he's so paranoid
he won't let anybody near him.
l need the person he would
suspect the least
to finish him off,
and that, Mr. Rebadow,
is you.
Me?
l can't kill anyone.
You did once before,
and that's why you're here.
No, l won't do it.
Well, you see, sir,
this really isn't a multiple choice.
You kill him, or l kill you.
lt's that simple.
l can go into
protective custody.
For the rest of your life?
lt's pretty lonely up there.
l would hate to think of you
spending your twilight years
mumbling to yourself.
But if l kill Hernandez,
l go to solitary, or death row.
No, no, no, no.
Here's the beauty part.
We get you moved into
Hernandez's cell.
l'll handle
the arrangements.
And in the middle
of the night,
you stick him
in the neck,
just like you did
that guy 35 years ago.
You yell for help,
and say that Hernandez
was attacking you.
And l killed him
in self-defense.
Exactly.
Such a sweet, old fella,
Who's going to doubt
your word?
So do we have a deal?
What do l get in return?
- Anything you want.
- Okay...
l'll kill him.
l've known Raul Hernandez
for many years,
and he's changed,
and not for the better.
Sure is quieter lately.
He's edgy, dangerous.
And you suggest?
He needs
a calming influence,
someone like, say...
Rebadow.
lt's not my fault,
l didn't ask to move in here.
l know.
We have no say.
So how many years
have you been here in Oz?
35, give or take a day.
That's about as long
as l've been in prison.
All my life, in and out,
35 years and what
do we get?
Get?
Yeah, l mean, ain't we
supposed to get something
- out of being locked up?
- No, l don't think so.
l want to see
Alvarez dead.
l don't know why.
You know, it's like
one of those
reflexes you get
when they tap you in the knee
and your leg jumps up.
What's your first name,
viejo? Don?
- Bob.
- Oh, Bob.
Go to sleep, Bob.
Yeah?
- We got him, Warden.
- Bring the bastard in.
Yes, sir.
Bring him in.
- Hi, Warden.
- Busmalis, good to see you.
Likewise.
These cuffs are very tight.
Well, you're gonna
have to endure the pain a little longer.
- You and me are going on TV.
- Really? How do l look?
Busmalis was found stalking
the home of Miss Whitney Allen,
who plays Miss Sally
on the popular children's show,
''Miss Sally's School Yard.''
Any sign of the other
escapee, Alvarez?
No, but we're
closing in on him.
No person shall be held
to answer for any capital,
or otherwise infamous crime
unless under presentment
or indictment of grand jury.
Now that's part of Article V
of the Bill of Rights.
The first two Articles
get all the press, you know--
freedom of speech,
freedom of religion,
the gun thing,
but Article V, baby,
that's the one you've got to cling
to when they slap on them cuffs.
No person shall be compelled
in any criminal case
to be witness
against himself,
nor deprived of life,
liberty or property
without due process
of law.
Deprived of life.
Out of the hole already?
- Yeah.
- You missed all the fun.
You know, Hernandez's
murder only helps us.
Now we can go to Glynn, and tell him
that Murphy can't control Amorsi
any better than McManus,
and that Glynn has to hire
a black man for the job.
We tried that
and got nowhere.
The more we push Glynn in one direction,
the more resistant he gets.
Then we have to apply
pressure from the outside.
We get community
leaders to pressure him.
We don't know
any community leaders.
- Said does.
- No, not Said.
He won't get involved.
Have faith
and we'll see, man.
Have faith.
You're looking good.
l need your help.
Yama.
Let me ask you,
Do you agree that life would be
better if a black man ran Emerald City?
That depends
upon the black man.
Let's say you get
to help pick.
Now why would Glynn
let me do that?
Because you have
influence.
l know the man
that l would choose
would not be
your choice.
- Are you sure?
- Yes...
because you are looking
to manipulate someone.
And you are not?
Don't play me, Adebisi.
l know you're
up to something.
You and me,
we have different ways,
different reasons
for what we do, okay,
but our goal
is the same--
the survival
of our people.
Yama.
We appreciate you taking
the time to see us, Warden.
Well, l'm always open
to input from the community.
Actually, we're concerned about the most
recent incident of racial tension
that has culminated in the deaths
of several African-Americans.
We believe that your decision
to fire Tim McManus
as unit director of Emerald City
will only help ease the situation.
This murder last night,
a white man killed a Latino?
That wasn't
racially motivated.
Even so, the man that you have
running Emerald City temporarily
isn't any more qualified
than McManus.
What we're interested
in is this,
who you plan to replace McManus
with on a permanent basis.
Well, l'm going over a number
of applicants.
Obviously, we know you'll
select the best man.
We simply ask you that,
if possible,
- you choose a person of color.
- Ah.
We believe that many mistakes
were made because McManus
didn't have enough experience dealing
with men from the inner cities.
l see.
We hear that you may running
as Devlin's lieutenant governor.
We would certainly consider
throwing our support behind you
if we knew that you were
sympathetic to our concerns.
The truth is, l am thinking
about hiring a black man for the job,
maybe a black woman.
That's excellent news.
l'm not making
any promises.
Of course not.
Whoever's most qualified.
Absolutely.
Mobay?
Mobay!
- Yo, man.
- Yeah, man?
You move my chair?
How many times l gotta fucking
tell you, don't move my chair?
l had to pee last night.
l don't give a shit
about you peeing.
Look, man, all day
l got people fucking with me,
jumping on the back
of my chair and shit.
- l don't need you fucking with me, too.
- Okay, okay.
l'm sorry
l moved the chair.
lt's all right.
l finished typing your speech for the
downtown businessman's association.
Oh, yeah?
What did you think?
Cut it by half.
Oh.
l've been summoned.
Summoned?
To meet with Adebisi,
Pancamo and Morales.
They'd asked for the name
of a Jamaican drug dealer
they could check with
about me. l gave them Nester Parks.
We busted Parks
four years ago,
now he's
up for parole,
knows we'll lean on the board
if he says the right things.
Well, l guess he did.
Yeah.
Well, l doubt
it's my last hurdle.
Our merry little trio will probably want
to share some heroin with me.
As a law enforcement officer,
you're not allowed
to use drugs.
Don't worry,
we have ways of faking it.
Usually the perps are so fucked up
themselves they don't even notice.
Even so, from here on
it's going to get a lot more dangerous.
- You worried about me, Warden?
- No.
l just don't want to have to break in
another new assistant.
- By half, huh?
- At least.
Where is he?
He's coming.
l don't like Jamaicans.
You don't like anybody.
So far, you check out.
But there are a few more steps
you've got to take
before you can gain
our friendship.
You could be
an undercover cocksucker,
but undercover cocksuckers
aren't allowed to use drugs.
And we know you've been buying
a lot of product...
but no one's ever
seen you use the stuff.
Enjoy.
We want to see it
go up your nose.
More.
What's up, man?
You okay?
Mobay!
Yo, Mobay?
Mobay?
Mobay? Oh!
You've got a serious problem, bro'.
Yo man, look at me,
l know where you at, right,
under a whole shed of shit.
We've got to get you
some help, man, all right?
Shake down!
Stand up.
Everybody in front
of your cells.
You, out!
The right of the people
to be secure
in their person, houses,
papers and effects
against unreasonable
searches and seizures
shall not be violated.
And no warrants shall issue
but upon probable cause
supported by oath
or affirmation
and particularly describing
the place to be searched
and the person or things
to be seized.
What's this, Hill?
l don't know,
looks like drugs.
- Those are mine.
- No kidding?
To the hole.
Leave us.
Hey, you okay?
Momentary setback.
l'll be fine.
- Al Salaam Alaikum.
- ls the rumor true?
Are you going to defend
that... man?
Yes, l am.
l forbid it.
- You forbid it?
- You swore you wouldn't challenge me.
Over leadership, Arif.
l did not say that l would
subjugate my actions to your will.
Harley vs. The State.
A black man's life sentence
was overturned
when it was discovered
that the judge presiding over the trial
was an active member
of the Ku Klux Klan.
So you think 'cause a juror at my trial
made anti-gay remarks,
l might get set free?
Let's just say at best
you can hope for a retrial.
Excuse me, Said?
l just heard the news
on the TV.
Our lawsuit-- we won.
What?
The jury decided the State
was responsible for the deaths
and injuries caused
after the riot.
How much money are we
gonna be getting?
The amount
won't be announced until next week,
but the newscaster said
it could be the full 45 million.
Oh, fuck, yes.
Nice.
- Great news, huh?
- That's very good.
Now if you'll excuse me,
Jason and l are working.
Yeah, okay.
Now where was l?
Yes...
Harley vs. The State.
- l thought you'd be happy.
- l am happy.
Kareem, Arnie Zellman says
that we could get
upwards of $250,000 each
from the settlement.
l've decided l'm going to take
the money and start again.
Well, that's terrific.
l hate my job.
l hate my apartment.
l hate everything about living in town.
l'm moving to California.
California?
The only thing
l'll miss here is you.
And even this,
my visits here
seem wrong...
'cause we can never
be intimate
the way l know
in my heart we should.
l love you, Kareem.
And l know
you love me.
And l know why
you can't say it,
but please...
just this once,
please say it.
Tell me
you love me.
No.
This will make
your leaving
easier...
for both of us.
- Hello, Minister.
- Mr. Fortunato.
- My client, Jason Kramer.
- Hey.
How you doing?
Congrats on winning that lawsuit
against the State.
- Thank you.
- All rise for Judge Mason Kossler.
Be seated.
All right, gentlemen,
l have read the motion by the plaintiff.
l am ready
to hear arguments.
Your honor,
Jason Kramer
is a homosexual,
but he was not
on trial for that.
He was on trial for murder
in the first degree,
kidnapping, assault
with a dangerous instrument.
Now a juror,
a Mr. Christopher Jacobs,
during the jury's
deliberations
made continuous defamatory
statements to the others
regarding Mr. Kramer's
sexual orientation.
l did not go on and on.
l made a couple of simple statements.
Every one of those people
on the jury agreed with me.
And was one of those
simple statements,
''this should not
take long,''
that he was a fag,
that all fags should be dead?
l don't know if l said
those words exactly.
Before you heard
any other evidence,
any other witnesses,
how were you going to vote?
Guilty.
- Mr. Kramer.
- Yes, Your Honor?
Your lawyers should never have
allowed Christopher Jacobs
a seat in the jury box.
That was their mistake.
Normally, l would chalk it up to bad
luck on your part and wish you well,
but there was a judge presiding
at your trial
and he should never
have allowed Jacobs to serve.
And for that reason,
and for that reason only,
l am going to grant
your motion for a new trial.
- Yeah!
- Your Honor, Your Honor?
You can whine to me, Counselor,
on the way back to town.
Thanks.
ln all criminal prosecutions,
the accused shall enjoy
the right to a speedy
and public trial
by an impartial jury,
to be confronted
with the witnesses against him...
and to have the assistance
of counsel for his defense.
l suffocated
Antonio Nappa.
- The mob boss?
- One and the same.
- That took balls.
- Not really.
l killed him at the behest
of Mr. Chucky Pancamo.
Pancamo wanted to take over?
l don't know the politics, honey,
l just got the job done.
Lights out.
- Hi.
Let's get rid of this.
Zeke Bellinger, the ex-husband
of condemned prisoner,
Shirley Bellinger,
has requested that after the execution,
the state hand her body
over to him
for burial beside
their slain daughter.
Rumor has it that
Shirley Bellinger
wanted to be buried
in an unmarked grave.
So why's he going
against her wishes?
l hear hubby went
Born Again after the drowning.
Hello, Shirley.
Zeke, you're looking
very thin.
That new wife
not feeding you?
Patsy's a singer,
she don't have time to cook.
- Singer, huh?
- A chanteuse.
My, my.
Lucky you.
ls she pregnant?
We decided
not to have kids.
She afraid what it might do
to her figure?
Might ruin that
chanteusing career?
No, l just wouldn't
be able to survive losing another child.
l want to be buried
in an unmarked grave.
- No, it's wrong.
- All the years we were married,
you never did one thing l asked.
Do this.
- No.
- l want to be lost in oblivion.
lt's too late for that, Shirley,
you're infamous.
l don't understand.
l'd think you wouldn't want me
buried anywhere near Katie.
Well, you see,
you're wrong,
'cause l forgive you.
You forgive me?
lt took me all this time
to get my heart in place,
but Reverend Nahi's been very
helpful to me, praying with me.
Praise the lord!
- You forgive me?
- Yes.
What makes you think l want
your fucking forgiveness?
- Now, Shirley, don't cuss.
- You come in here all high and mighty
deciding to free me
of my guilt?
Well, Zeke,
l don't feel guilty.
l did what l had to do,
and unlike you,
at least my balls
were big enough.
You came to console me?
Well, l've got a little
consolation prize for you.
You and the chanteuse ought to go ahead
and have yourselves another child,
because when Katie died,
you didn't lose a child.
She wasn't yours.
- What?
- Your father raped me.
That child was his seed.
God damn you.
l'm going to put this under
my pillow tonight
and wait for the Tooth Fairy
to come.
Yeah, l need that by Friday.
l'm dead serious.
All right.
Thanks.
And the money.
You know, Nikolai,
l figure since we made
our peace pact
and now that we're
comrades and all,
that you wouldn't be
charging me to use the cell phone.
Just because we're not trying
to kill each other,
- doesn't mean you get a free ride.
- Yeah, Nikolai,
you and l are the only two
who know about this phone.
l can tell a few people
and they could take it away.
lf the hacks
confiscate my phone,
you won't be able
to use it.
Who said l was going
to tell the hacks?
l'm busy here, O'Reily,
so whatever you want,
make it fast
and make it good.
- Ralph Galino.
- What about him?
l don't know.
Strike you odd that he's dead?
Odd?
Why odd?
'cause on the outside,
he had no history of using.
A lot of guys who were clean
outside get hooked in Oz.
Yeah, but not Galino.
He and l became friendly.
He was here, like what, a week?
And he goes from zero tolerance to OD?
l'm not big on morse code.
Just tell me what you want to tell me.
l got nothing to tell.
l don't know why anybody
would want to grease Galino,
but l do know he was having
some run-ins with Stanislofsky.
- Run-ins about what?
- You'd have to ask Stanislofsky.
Get the fuck out
of my office. Come on.
You're here because you're
concerned about Ryan O'Reily.
Well, the other day,
l saw him unwrap his bandage
and hit his hand repeatedly
against the sink
deliberately causing it
to bleed.
Really?
l'm worried about him.
He's self-destructive,
perhaps even suicidal.
You should examine him,
put him in isolation, by himself.
Mm-hmm.
l have to tell you, Nikolai,
l'm a tad suspicious of your motives.
ln my experience,
every time a prisoner
shows genuine concern for another
prisoner, he usually has an agenda.
You want to run that
past me again?
That Stanislofsky guy's
been talking shit about you.
- Stan who?
- The Russian guy.
What do l care about him?
He's just a nothing, nobody.
Huh-uh. Those Russian mobsters,
they're crafty, Adebisi.
They're crafty
and they're cold-blooded.
He came to me asking
if l'd help him make a move against you.
Yeah?
Let him try.
All right.
l'm just warning you, that's all.
Go away, O'Reily.
No problem.
l love it when he talks like that.
What's shaking, man?
Ryan O'Reily.
He knows we killed Galino.
- He swears to get revenge.
- O'Reily and Galino don't add up.
They weren't in business together,
and they weren't fucking each other.
So why the fuck would O'Reily
give a shit about Galino?
l'm telling you
what l heard.
We should take care of O'Reily
before he comes at us.
We whack O'Reily now,
the whole joint goes back on lockdown.
- No way. We wait.
- Hoyt, listen to me.
What, all of a sudden,
you don't understand English?
- We wait.
- Yeah, yeah. No, tomorrow's great.
Okay, thanks.
Bye.
Here you go, pal.
- Anytime, my friend.
- Yeah.
- Cyril, stop playing around.
- l'm not playing around.
Well, then wash behind
your ears.
Nobody can see
behind my ears.
Listen, Cyril,
today's the day that we're meeting
with Dr. Nathan
and her husband's parents, okay?
- l know that.
- Come on,
You've got to take
this stuff seriously, man.
- l am.
- Then wash behind your ears.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
Gloria, you seem anxious.
No, l'm fine.
Well, l'm anxious.
l know, we've been
preparing for weeks,
and Sister Peter Marie
feels we're all ready,
but l'm not sure what
my first reaction will be.
l'm afraid l might
just want to clobber them.
Lars, they're
half your age.
They'll clobber you.
Oh, well, even so...
we can still cancel,
you know?
No. We've come this far,
let's see the saga through.
l still can't understand
how you can keep working here.
- How's your hand?
- Oh, it's fine.
Didn't you have to go
to a hospital?
lt was nothing. A little bleeding.
The wound reopened.
l heard you reopened it.
Really?
Where'd you hear that?
Some people are
self-destructive, but not you.
l can guess why you did
what you did.
l can even guess why you're going into
this interaction with the Nathans now.
Well, l'm here to cure Cyril
of his nightmares, that's all.
Listen, Ryan,
l've told you this before,
l am not going
to take you in there
if you intend to cause
Gloria and Preston's parents more pain,
because by professing your love
for Gloria, you will cause more pain.
l know.
l promised you, didn't l?
Okay.
Lars and Patricia Nathan,
Ryan and Cyril O'Reily.
- l'm sorry.
- No, no, l'm sorry. l'm sorry.
A child dies of a disease,
in war,
hell, gets hit by a
crosstown bus,
somehow you can convince
yourself his death makes sense.
But this...
it was all premeditated,
so cold-blooded.
l was behind him,
so l couldn't
see his eyes.
lf l had seen his eyes...
l don't know if l could have
kept going.
l keep thinking about
the future.
Gloria and Preston
were almost
ready to have children...
my grandchildren.
l hate you for taking them
away from me!
You can blame me and Cyril all you want
for not having grandchildren,
but the truth is
you're just fooling yourselves.
- Shut up.
- No, let him finish.
The marriage between
Gloria and your son,
it was over.
- ls this true?
- No.
- Liar.
- Ryan.
- We were having some problems.
- She had an affair with Tim McManus.
That's enough. You speak one more time
without my asking you,
l'm shutting down
this session.
- You had an affair?
- Preston and l were separated briefly.
- He never told us.
- We wanted to work it out ourselves
- without any interference.
- lnterference? He was our son!
And because of you,
he's lying in the ground!
- Patricia.
- But it's true, isn't it?
Because of what went on
between her and him,
Preston's dead!
This is what you wanted,
isn't it?
To get us fighting
with each other.
- No.
- Yes.
You always have some plan,
O'Reily, some secret agenda.
Not this time!
Unlike you,
l never made it a secret!
- l love you!
- Stop it!
l always will,
and that will never change!
- Officers!
- No, let him say it!
Let him try
and convince himself.
Everything you have
ever done
for your entire life,
O'Reily,
you've only done
for yourself.
You don't know
how to love.
l'm leaving.
l'll call you later.
Once something's bad,
it can never get good.
Yeah. Yeah.
l need it done
by tonight.
Yeah, l'm serious.
Okay.
All right.
- Who were you talking to?
- Nobody. Let's go watch ''Miss Sally.''
- You're shitting me.
- No, l heard it from Kirk this morning.
Hey, who's this spic, Morales?
Yo, O'Reily,
you hear the news?
- No, what?
- Dr. Nathan.
Last night on her way home
from work, she got raped.
- Raped?
- Yeah.
Huh.
Article Vlll, excessive bail
shall not be required,
nor excessive fines imposed,
nor cruel and unusual
punishment.
Cruel and unusual.
ln Oz, cruel
is the usual punishment.
Sister, what happened
to Gloria,
fucking sucks.
- Yeah, it's terrible.
- Before we begin,
have you heard any more
about how Chris is doing?
No.
Rumor has it he'll be back
in Oz today,
though he'll be spending
some time in the hospital ward.
Where'd you hear that?
My sister.
She's a doctor
over at Benchley Memorial.
Your sister's
a doctor?
Yeah.
What's she practice,
voodoo?
Hey, can we get started,
please?
Poet, since you're in such
a talkative mood,
why don't you do the kickoff?
Okay. l wrote a poem.
Fear not love loosen
its hooks from its sheath
and capture you in its
painfully seductive grasp.
Fear not the blood
that oozes from your wounds
and holds your patience
to task.
Fear not the tearing
sounds of passion
as they rip apart
the feelings at the start.
Fear not the fainting pulse
of heartbeat,
for that, that is
the very best part.
- Hi, Padre.
- You asked to see me?
You know l got shot.
You know l died?
During surgery.
They brought me back
from the dead twice.
Now you come nose to nose
with death like that,
you begin to see things
different.
Are you telling me
that you've changed?
Sister Peter Marie okay?
Yes.
l don't mean physically,
l mean here.
You know l fucked
with that woman.
l enjoy sex, don't you?
l'll bet you're
a wild broad.
l wanted her to help me
with Beecher.
Now l hear she's thinking
of quitting the convent
and l want to do something
to make it up to her.
Well, Chris, even you would admit
that your credibility's pretty low.
Look...
there's no--
there's no reason for you
or her to believe me,
but l've got to try.
l've got to try to make
her see that l know
that what l did
was wrong.
l don't want
to burn in hell.
What do you want
me to do?
Have Sister Pete
come visit me.
- Pete?
- Hi.
l just came from
visiting Chris Keller.
How is he?
He's back in full force.
He says that he wants to talk to you.
Well, l don't want
to talk to him.
Tobias, maybe you
should go.
No. We have work to do.
Stay where you are, Tobias.
He seems full of remorse.
How genuine that is is tough to gauge,
- but if it's true...
- lt's not true.
Chris Keller
is a manipulative, sociopathic liar.
- l won't go see him.
- But what if he really needs you?
psychologically...
- spiritually?
- That's too bad.
- Let me go.
- Tobias, no.
Look, l know better
than you...
the hurt he can cause,
but still...
l-- l love him.
Take this to
Dr. Prestopnik.
Don't.
Hey!
Hey.
Beecher, what are you
doing in here?
l came to drop off a file
to Dr. Prestopnik.
- Where's the file?
- lt's on his desk.
lf you delivered it,
take a walk.
- Yeah, l just...
- l don't give a shit.
Take a walk.
l'll see you later.
Now that was
such a touching moment,
l'm going to write about it
in my diary.
Where do you think
you're going?
l have information.
Mr. Schillinger,
l'm the altar boy
for Father Mukada at mass.
l'm in the office
changing out of vestments,
sometimes l overhear things.
This is primo stuff.
- About what?
- About you.
What do you want
in return?
This guy in my unit,
Stan Buttwin, stole my watch.
Done.
What have you got?
Your son, Hank,
l know who paid
to have him found
- and arranged to have him see you.
- Who?
Beecher?
You won't forget my watch,
will you?
lt doesn't make
any sense.
Why would Beecher pay
to find your son?
This is some plan of his,
some double-dealing plan
to fuck with me.
He was going to use Hank
against me,
the same way he did
with Andrew.
What are you
going to do?
Take the offensive.
Look, l know l was tough
on you and your brother growing up,
but you've
got to understand,
when your mom died,
l had to raise you
all by myself.
l'd drop you off at school--
same one l went to,
only it turned into
a shithole...
niggers and gangs...
drugs.
lf l was hard, it was
only to protect you.
Yeah, l know that, Dad.
- Do you?
- Yeah.
l'm not like Andrew,
blaming you for all
the fucked-up shit in his life.
l know you did the best
you could.
- Thank you, son.
- You got so huggy, man.
Listen, l want you
to do something for me.
- Want me to do something?
- Yeah, a mission.
All right.
Yes.
- How much?
- How much what?
- How much cash?
- Cash?
You want the crime,
you've got to pay the dime.
$1,000.
l'm all yours,
Daddy.
Here's what l need
you to do.
- Beecher?
- Yeah?
- Come with me.
- Where?
Warden Glynn's office.
What's the warden want
to see me for?
All he said was for me
to get you, so move your ass.
Oh, fuck.
Holy shit,
what's wrong?
Sit down.
Tobias, there's
no easy way to say this.
Well, then just say it.
Your son and daughter
have been kidnapped.
No, no.
The declaration of independence
says that we are, all of us,
due certain rights,
the most important being life,
liberty and the pursuit
of happiness.
l mean, and isn't
that what it's all about?
Life, liberty...
happiness.