The criminal mind--
For the past 200 years,
scientists, sociologists
and other folks
who fret about
such things,
have debated whether
a person commits a violent act
because of their environment
or their biological makeup.
What turns on
the red crime light in a man's brain?
lf we find the cause,
can we eliminate the effect?
Can we end violence
now and forever?
Prisoner number 00G115,
Detective Bruno Goergen;
Convicted March 15th, 2000;
lllegal possession
and sale of firearms,
murder in
the first degree.
Sentence: 36 years...
Up for parole in 18.
You know that guy?
No.
He's just
so fucking ugly.
''He's just
so fucking ugly.''
This guy.
When l first saw you,
l thought,
''What the fuck is Johnny Basil
doing in Oz?''
And then l remembered
last year you went to narcotics, right?
One of the greaseballs told me your name
was Desmond Mobay? Huh?
- You gonna blow my cover?
- Depends.
- On what l do for you?
- None of the inmates know l'm a cop.
lt was part of my deal when
l turned state's evidence.
l got a new identity too.
Now scumbags out there
find out the truth,
l'm prime beef for any asshole looking
to up his cred.
And so?
And so one hand
washes the other, my brother in blue.
You know what l remember
the most about you
when we were working
the streets together?
What a bully
you were.
Strong-arming people
when there was no need.
You were always
a bad cop, Goergen.
l wasn't surprised
when l heard you went down.
Oh, so you do want me to tell the guys
you're undercover?
l would be happy to help you
in any way l can.
Glad we understand
each other.
Excuse me there, Butch.
Butch? Yo.
Normally when a police officer's
brought into Oz
l give them
special counseling.
Why?
lt's going to be
tough for you
going from a position
of authority
to being strip searched.
- You might feel humiliated.
- Not me.
- Vulnerable.
- Uh-Uh.
Okay, that's fine, but if you should
experience feelings like that,
- l just want you to know l'm here.
- Thanks. Later.
- You know, my wife's an ex-nun.
- Really?
Yeah. She fucks
like a $500 whore.
Must be all those years
of pent up chastity.
- Know what l hate more than anything?
- What's that, Mondo?
This white trash
trying to be thugs.
l feel you.
l hate that too.
How about you, pussy?
How you feel about that, huh?
What l hate is
jive-ass niggers.
How the fuck is this you
watching my back?
l got a C.O. there
as soon as l could.
- Should've pulled those apes off me.
- Apes. Yeah.
Niggers, yeah.
l jump in and save you,
a fucking white,
redneck asshole,
l might as well
pack up and leave Oz.
Well, then maybe
you better start packing,
'cause anything like this
fucking happens again,
everyone's gonna know
who you are,
and you're a
dead man, Johnny.
Hey, Mobay.
Did you forget?
What?
lf you want to join us,
you gotta kill somebody.
l haven't forgotten.
The new man doesn't want
any violence in Emerald City,
so if you're
gonna do the deed,
make it look
like an accident.
Do it far away
from here.
l gotcha, man.
Hill. Hill.
l'm asleep.
Hear that?
That's me snoring.
- l need your help.
- l don't give people help.
Adebisi and the others
say they will let me in
if l kill somebody.
And what?
You want me to volunteer
to be your victim?
No.
l have decided who to kill,
but l need your cooperation to do it.
That shit you're snorting
is rotting your brain.
l ain't helping you
kill nobody.
- But--
- No. No way, no how.
- Hey, look, shut up, Mobay.
l'm tired of hearing
your lips flap.
Let me get
some fucking sleep.
- We got problems.
- What?
- My cellmate Hill knows you're a cop.
- Shit. How?
Who knows how?
He says he'll keep quiet for a price.
- He wants a meeting.
- Where?
Dress factory's
freight elevator.
Now, l say we tip his chair and let him
go tumbling down the shaft.
Right.
Fuck.
Are you sure this
guy's coming?
Yes.
Jeez, you don't know
how good you got it till it's gone.
All those times l moaned
about walking the beat,
l'd give
my fucking right nut
to be in the snow
working the fucking Spick Day parade.
Okay, Mobay.
l'm here, man. What you want?
You think you got
me over a barrel, don't you?
- What?
- So long, butch.
What the fuck are you
doing, man?
- Fuck are you doing?
- Wait, wait. Let me, let me.
Mobay, for Christ's sake.
Mobay! For Christ's sake,
wait. No, man, wait.
Please!
Fuck me!
You should've let me
tell you the plan.
What the fuck is
wrong with you?
Are you out
of your fucking mind?
Lockdown! Lockdown!
What the fuck happened?
Someone died.
An accident.
Far from Emerald City.
l'm seriously considering
moving to another cell.
- Relax, brother. The worst is over.
- Yeah, right.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
l thought we agreed you
shouldn't come visit.
Hill thought
he recognized you.
l am here because l'm worried
about you, partner.
You're supposed to
be e-mailing me regularly.
Not only don't l hear from you,
but when l do,
- the reports make no sense.
- l was in the hole for a few days.
- Are you using?
- No.
You are. l can see it
in your eyes.
- Okay, but l had to.
- That's it.
l'm telling the Lieutenant
to pull you out of here.
No! Shuman wants
the job done,
and l'm so fucking close
to busting these guys.
l know l fucked up,
but l can turn it around.
l know l can, Kina.
Trust me.
Okay, but l want to hear
from you every day.
Every goddamn day.
Warden, we need
to touch you up a bit.
- Touch me up.
- This is Cassandra and Betty.
- They're makeup and hair.
- What's the hubbub?
The Warden is shooting
a public service announcement.
Oh, that's right.
l forgot.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it is my honor to...
Are you all right?
l may be
getting the flu.
Quick as you can, guys.
Warden, your wife
is here.
- Mary.
- We need to talk.
Uh, excuse me.
Warden, we're moments away here.
Sir, please.
Excuse me.
What's the matter?
l just got a call from a reporter asking
about your brother.
Well, l knew
this was coming.
He said that tomorrow the Tribune
is breaking the story
that Mark is serving a life sentence for
murder and did you have any comment.
l got a lot of comments,
none of them printable.
Warden, l'm sorry.
We're trying to make
our little movie here.
We're on a very,
very tight schedule.
Excuse me.
l'm sorry.
Thank you so much.
Sorry about that.
Okay, you guys,
just sign off on him, all right?
- So we can get this over with.
- Okay.
- This isn't such a terrible thing.
- Oh, no?
We anticipated that some
dedicated journalist
would eventually
dig up the dirt.
There's a way to use this
to our advantage.
- How?
- Your brother committed murder, yes,
but you got him
to turn himself in.
Three months
after the fact.
Press doesn't have
to know when you knew.
l'm starting to feel
like Ronald fucking Reagan.
We also leak the news
that your daughter was raped.
Public will love
the fact
that you know
all sides of crime.
l'm not gonna exploit
Arnet's rape just to get elected.
Leo, people don't vote for candidates
because of what they believe
or their position statements
or any of that shit.
They elect a father,
a husband,
a good old guy
they can chug a beer with,
someone who
understands pain,
because he's suffered too.
And you've suffered, Leo.
All l'm saying is
let them weep for you.
l said no.
That's no.
My advice is get your hat
out of the ring.
l need a Lieutenant
Governor who's got balls.
Open the goddamn gate!
l'm a family man,
and there's nothing harder
for a family man
than to see those he loves
suffer or cause suffering.
My brother's crime
devastated us.
My daughter's rape
did too.
There's a new study out
which claims that some people
are wired to
commit violent crimes,
that they have defects
in their brain,
that they have
less gray matter
in their prefrontal lobe
just behind the eyes.
They're missing the piece
that keeps rage inside.
lf true, those people
are predestined
to rape and murder.
They cannot
be held accountable.
Anatomy is destiny.
l don't give a fuck
about this toilet paper.
You know, take your fucking
toilet paper, all right?
Hey.
Lockdown!
McManus, where's your
fucking sense of fun?
- Hello.
- Tim?
- Yeah.
- Diane.
- Yeah?
- How are you?
l'm good.
l wrote you,
but l didn't hear back.
Did you get my letter?
Yeah. l got it.
l been busy.
l heard
you're running unit B now.
My boys behaving
themselves?
Diane, what do you want?
To see if you're okay.
l'm good.
l gotta go.
- Oh, man.
- Tim.
- Hey.
- How's things?
The truth?
l miss Diane.
l miss Em City.
l'm constantly constipated.
l've managed to completely
and literally fuck up my entire life.
That's how l am.
Constipation--
That you can fix.
Right.
Want to grab a beer?
No thanks.
l got a date.
Every time
l ask you to do something,
you're otherwise engaged.
l'm getting paranoid. You pissed at me?
When Glynn fired me,
what did you do?
l called you immediately.
Oh, yeah. You were very sympathetic,
and then you took my job.
Only temporarily. l told Glynn
l did not want to replace you.
l brought you in to Oz.
- When l was fired, you should've quit.
- Tim.
- l gotta go.
- Tim, you know, give me a break here.
Kareem Said.
According to this file,
you are one incredible pain in the ass.
Well, that is only one
interpretation.
Another could be that l strive
for justice where there is none.
What l strive for
is peace and quiet.
My mandate from Warden Glynn
is simple: no violence.
l applaud you on your mandate.
l abhor violence.
that is incredibly
sweet of you.
l'm thinking of making changes and l'm
hoping you're not gonna stir up trouble.
Depends.
What kind of changes?
Patience. Patience.
We must be as patient with others
as we expect Allah to be with us.
Now you don't mind
if l quote you, do you?
Found this in the bottom
of the drawer.
McManus must've
left it behind. l gave it a quick read.
- And?
- Didn't really hold my interest.
Too self-righteous.
You can go.
$100. Ride it out.
That's all for you
if you want it.
That's funny.
Prisoner number 00K251,
Kevin Ketchum,
aka Supreme Allah;
Convicted March 22nd, 2000;
murder
in the second degree.
Sentence: 25 years,
up for parole in 10.
This is your sponsor.
He's gonna help
acclimate you to life in Emerald City.
Kevin Ketchum,
Kareem Said.
My government name
is Ketchum.
My real name
is Supreme Allah.
All right.
Let's go, Allah.
- Who's that?
- Supreme Allah.
Knew him back on the corner.
What kind of a name
is the Supreme Allah?
He's a five percenter.
A five center what?
He believes that 5°/% of all black men
are enlightened with the true
understanding of life.
Yeah, they also believe
that the black man is God
and that we whiteys
are the devil.
They're like Muslims
except they smoke weed,
they deal drugs,
they do what they gotta do.
Oh, fuck.
He's gonna be my cellmate.
Shit.
Bye-Bye.
Peace, black man.
Look, look, l ain't buying what
you selling, dog.
Met a lot of you five percenters along
the years, with your prophet moves,
sayin' how much
the Earth weighs shit.
You know, we stuck in here.
We stuck in here together.
And l don't need you preaching me,
you understand?
- Yeah. All right.
- All right then.
They call you ''Poet,'' huh?
Damn skippy
they call me ''Poet.''
Can l read some
of your stuff?
Why do you want
to read any of my stuff?
Like poetry.
You know,
l suck at writing, myself.
- Start on page 16.
- Thanks.
Some of my shit got put
in that anthology.
Damn.
Yo, this is good, man.
Fuck me, man.
No more pens.
Yo, yo.
You must fall
in line behind us.
l ain't got no problem
working with you.
You're not hearing
what l'm saying.
Oh, l hear clearly, Arif.
Thing is, you don't own me
any more than the Devil does.
You will obey me.
You don't want
to be touching me, son.
This is getting us nowhere.
Why don't you all just back off?
Supreme Allah,
you call yourself Muslim.
Well, we believe
that your way,
that is a corruption
of the truth.
We don't want you
poisoning the minds
of the young brothers
here in Oz.
l'm gonna speak my mind
while l'm here.
And whoever listens,
listens.
Whoever don't, be damned.
Thank you, officer.
You want me
in or out?
Out.
- Hey there.
- Yes.
What are you up to,
Adebisi?
Me? Nothing.
Nothing? So how am l to be included
in your ''nothing''?
The Earth is about to quake.
l came to warn you,
take shelter.
- How big a quake?
- Big.
But you, you can
be safe with me.
Once again, you honor me with your
offer of protection.
- And once again you refuse?
- Regretfully.
You can ask a girl out on a date
so many times and get refused.
You could just tell me
what's going on.
Count!
You'll find out
soon enough, eh?
l have decided
to junk the council
that used
to meet regularly
and replaced that system
with trustees
who will be responsible
for citing grievances
and maintaining order.
These trustees will be
Simon Adebisi,
Chucky Pancamo
and Enrique Morales.
Now having met with each
of you individually,
l've decided to transfer
several of you back to Gen Pop.
The following men will
follow Officer Johnson out:
97H81 3, Henke;
99S81 2, Sands;
98B643, Blakely;
97 S532, Simpson;
95J932, Jarvis;
98H432, Hoyt.
This sucks!
No one asked
your opinion, Hoyt.
That's enough out of you.
Grab your stuff!
Now this is nuts.
Making Adebisi, Pancamo
and Morales trustees?
l mean, they're the three
worst motherfuckers in this place.
And transferring
all the Aryans and bikers?
- l mean, what kind of logic is that?
- l'm not Tim McManus.
l'm not looking
to create some Oz version
of the rainbow coalition.
l reviewed their records.
All of them have repeated
incidents of violence.
- And Adebisi doesn't?
- Gonna have to learn to trust me.
l wish you'd learn
to discuss policy changes with me
- before you announce them.
- Not my style.
- Clearly.
- You don't like it,
you can follow Hoyt
and the rest of them out the door.
- You know what? l will.
- l'll start the paperwork.
- The sooner the better.
- The sooner.
Yeah.
Ah, yeah...
Did you know about this?
That you'd be made a trustee?
Yeah, yeah,
but l was sworn to secrecy.
- How come l wasn't made a trustee?
- Ask Querns.
And how come all these new arrivals,
none of them is Muslim?
- Ask Querns.
- We had a deal, Adebisi.
That's true.
We did.
Now if you'll excuse me,
l've got business to do.
No, no, no, no.
- We have to talk, Querns.
- Later.
- Now.
- Johnson.
We'll talk later.
Back off. Back off.
Hey! Hey!
- Officer!
- Get him off now!
Move it!
Damn it, we got to get him
to the hospital.
This is unit B.
Get a fucking gurney over here!
- What happened?
- He's been raped.
Gloria,
you don't have to--
- l'm fine.
- No.
No, Tim, l'm fine.
Let's drape and prep for an anoscopy.
You know, when l was
first elected Governor,
crime was out of control,
but we went to work
- fighting for three strikes
- Hey, can you turn that down?
l'm waiting for my soap
to come back on.
Mac just left
Felicia... again.
Turn it the fuck down.
Why are you
always so grumpy?
Hey, what you doing?
Painting.
Well, they just painted our cells
a couple weeks ago.
Painting a mural,
asshole, a portrait.
- Of who?
- Of myself.
l want to leave something behind
after they execute me.
Miles, what makes you think
the next guy in that cell
will want to spend
his last days staring at your ugly ass?
- You calling me ugly, black boy?
- Motherfucker.
Are my little darlings raising
their voices? Do we need a timeout?
Lopresti, how come
you still here?
Shirley Bellinger told the warden
you were fucking her every night.
Yeah, that bitch almost got me fired,
but l was able to persuade Glynn
that she's a lying
sack of shit.
Well, she wasn't lying. You were eating
that pussy like chicken chow mein.
- God damn!
- l don't want to hear any more
talk about that cunt.
Got me?
Things sure are different
around here without old Shirley.
Yeah.
That's been
happening a lot.
Yeah, fag.
You keep me up at night.
Jeez. God forbid you shouldn't get
your beauty sleep.
Maybe you should be
in the hospital, man.
No. Don't want to die
in a hospital.
- You'd rather die in here?
- l'd rather expire
sunning myself on the Riviera
in the arms of a 17-Year-Old Adonis,
but c'est la vie.
Still, maybe you should
have yourself checked out.
Thank you, Moses,
for your concern.
- You going fag, Deyell?
- When you gonna shut the fuck up, man?
When l die, nigger.
Ow!
Fuck! My hand!
My fucking hand!
Oh, fuck!
You gotta remember, Deyell, you hit
a wall, generally the wall wins.
Yeah, Moses here is not known
for his mental muscle.
l got more brains in my little finger
than you, Lopresti.
Well, right now your little finger
is in little pieces.
All right, listen.
Try to keep this cast clean.
You're gonna have it on
for six weeks.
All done.
Dr. Nathan, you ain't been up
to see Ginzburg lately.
No, l took a short
leave of absence.
l assumed Dr. Prestopnik
was examining him.
Prestopnik ain't
been up there one time.
Quit yapping, Deyell.
Again.
You've been having chills, night-sweats,
shortness of breath?
Yes, a trifecta.
l should probably transfer
you to the AlDS ward.
When l got the death penalty
for suffocating Antonio Nappa,
l thought,
''Oh, this'll be fun.''
Fun?
To see what kills me first--
the State or the disease.
Guess the disease
is winning.
Prisoner number 00K414,
Patrick Keenan;
convicted March 25, 2000;
assault
in the first degree, rape.
1 2 years,
up for parole in seven.
- Hey, O'Reily.
- Hey.
Have you met
Patrick Keenan?
No.
Patrick,
this is Ryan O'Reily.
l heard of you.
You and your brother used to run
the Bridget Street gang.
Yeah.
Boy, that's a--
that's a nice shamrock.
Yeah, thanks.
My lucky charm.
- So what did they catch you doing?
- Rape, assault.
- That so?
- Patrick's the one who did Dr. Nathan.
You raped Dr. Nathan?
- Yeah.
- Why?
l don't know.
l was in the mood.
He was ''in the mood.''
That right?
Hey, it's good to meet you
there, Keenan.
You and me, maybe we can get together
and do some business sometime.
l'd like that--
working for the O'Reily brothers.
Okay. See you.
Yeah...
Where're you going?
Hey, Goldilocks,
want to suck some chocolate?
No!
l'm switching him
to one milligram of Haldol.
- Are you sure?
- Well, what do you suggest? Counseling?
What the fuck is going
on, Adebisi?
Letting these assholes
fuck with my brother.
- We had a goddamn deal!
- Relax, O'Reily,
before you blow
a blood vessel.
l've already spoken
to Tidd and Browne.
- Haven't l?
- Yes.
- Brown?
- Yeah, man.
This type of bullshit
won't happen again.
Okay?
He all right?
They got him
so tanked up on Haldol
it's like he's
in a fucking coma.
ls that such
a bad thing?
O'Reily...
l got a question for you.
Stanislofky...
come here, sit.
l been playing catch-up
on a lot of what's been happening here.
Been reading the file
on the death of one Ralph Galino.
Tragic. Drugs very
serious problem.
Yeah. Except he had
no history of drugs,
- so how does he die of an O.D.?
- A mystery.
l understand you and Galino
didn't get along.
Who says that?
Did you ask me
a question?
Because you don't get
to ask me questions.
You are my main suspect
in Galino's death.
You are my
only suspect.
l'm gonna be
watching you,
perched like
a Czarist eagle.
You said
we should wait.
So we wait,
and look what happens.
O'Reily goes to the hacks
and tells them you and l killed Galino.
O'Reily said that?
You and me?
Yes.
So take care of him.
We whack O'Reily now,
they'll have all the proof they need.
No thanks.
l got a birthday coming up.
l don't want
to spend it in Solitary.
Look, l know that Russian cocksucker's
been talking smack about me, Jaz,
but you can't trust
that motherfucker.
l don't trust him.
l don't trust you neither.
Okay, fine. Only he's supposed
to be your pal, right?
l'll bet he hasn't told you
about the cell phone.
Cell phone?
What cell phone?
Ralph Galino's
cell phone.
- That's why he killed that wop.
- Shit.
Now who do
you trust?
What's going on?
Druke,
what is problem?
Cut the shit.
Give me
the cell phone.
Give it to me.
So what is going
to happen to me now?
l'm thinking...
maybe you die.
They're murdering me!
Guards!
Guards, guards!
Break it up,
break it up.
Get up against the wall.
Get up back there!
Everybody's always
looking for an excuse.
''l killed
that man 'cause:
A) l was abused
as a child;
B) l had
shitty parents;
C) l was raised
in poverty;
D) All of the above.''
lf the only thing you know
from the cradle on up is violence...
what other choice
have you got?
- Fuck!
- Nyet!
What other reason
do you need?
Morning, Bob.
Bob, please.
When are you gonna stop
this silent treatment?
l said
l'm sorry
that l didn't tell you
l was building a new tunnel,
that l didn't ask you to escape with me.
What more can l do?
Count!
- How is he?
- Not good.
88K214, 77P326,
98K514, 97B41 2.
Hey, Beecher.
Get your ass out here.
Leave him alone.
- Beecher, now.
- You can see he's there.
Why does he have
to stand in line?
Rules is rules.
Fuck you.
- What?
- Fuck you. Fuck your rules.
Rebadow, l'd expect
Keller to be mouthy, but not you.
The man's children
have been kidnapped,
his son's hand
cut off.
Beecher's obviously in pain.
Why torture him more?
Right! Yeah!
Keep going.
- 96Q415, 18T304...
- All right, quiet down!
- Quiet down now!
- Who knew you had balls?
Shut the fuck up!
A few years ago,
l was attacked by some of the black boys
- and landed in the hospital.
- l remember.
The bruises healed,
but l was flooded
with fear.
Well, that's
natural.
l hadn't felt such fear since
l was about to be executed
and then wasn't.
Killing Raul
Hernandez, as--
as terrible
as it was, as--
l don't know.
l feel alive.
l'm not afraid
to die.
- Teach me.
- Teach you what?
How to box.
You got to be
kidding me, right?
l want to learn
to defend myself.
Rebadow, l ain't got
the time or the interest. Take off.
- l can teach you.
- Cyril.
No, l can
if l want.
Okay.
First,
you gotta learn
how to stand.
Fucking Cyril.
Hey, Rebadow.
- Give me your pie, pops.
- No.
Oh, you're gonna
give me your pie,
or l'm gonna break
your old ass in two.
Okay.
You get pie!
How does
it taste, man?
You missed a great lunch,
but l got you something. Here.
Psst, psst--
Toby, take it.
Toby, you got
to eat something. Take it.
Take the fucking
orange and eat it. Come on.
Nothing like fresh-squeezed
orange juice.
Cell-mates--
it's like being married.
Rebadow still
ignoring you?
Worse. He's like
a different person.
lt's like when l was gone
some alien took over his body.
He certainly
has changed.
lt's
unsettling.
After a certain age,
people shouldn't change.
Shh. Here
he comes.
- Mr. Morales...
- Whoa. Slow down there, Rebadow.
l want to talk
to you.
Let him be,
Chico.
What do you
need?
When l agreed
to kill Hernandez,
you said in return
l could have anything l wanted.
True. And now you want me
to repay the debt?
Yes.
Okay. What can l
do for you?
l want you to let me
kill someone else.
Daddy!
Daddy?
He has these dreams
a lot?
Ever since his
kids got nabbed.
- Well, l'll speak to him.
- Sister Peter Marie, too.
Given her relationship
with Beecher,
she's being
rather...
casual
about all this.
That's not true.
l can't help thinking her distance
has something to do with me.
Well, shocking
as this seems, Keller,
not everything
on the planet has to do with you.
Keller's right.
lt is about him.
The doubts he put in my
mind about being a nun,
my effectiveness
as a psychologist--
But Pete,
Beecher needs you.
Ray, l know.
Do you remember
what l said to you a few weeks ago
about putting on a facade
so l could get through each day?
- Sure.
- l am unable to comfort Tobias.
l mean, l--
l don't even look him in the eye,
because l know that
if l do, my facade will crumble.
So that-- that's worse than--
than no help to him.
Beecher hasn't been
out of his cell for two solid days.
He just lies
in his bunk
sobbing like
a wuss.
Good.
That's what's truly elegant
about this plan of mine.
We don't physically
touch Beecher,
and yet the damage
done is far more hideous.
Time to put parts
three and four into motion.
Hank?
Yeah. l want you
to drop off the other package.
Right. The one
we talked about.
Bye.
You should stop
smoking, Father.
l know, l know.
lt's bad for my health.
There's a law about
smoking in public places
- in state-owned buildings.
- ls this bothering you?
Yes!
Hello,
Tobias.
Thank you, Officer.
Wait outside, please.
Take a seat,
Toby.
l know what this
is about, Dad.
The FBl
found Gary?
Yes.
Gary's body.
He's dead.
Yes.
l knew.
l knew when l heard
about the hand.
And Holly?
Any news?
No, no.
Not yet.
l'd like to go
to Gary's funeral.
We've already made
arrangements.
l want him buried
right next to his mother.
l want to see the graves
l've dug lined up one next to the other.
Oh, Son.
Son.
lt's funny,
l can't cry.
l don't have
any more tears left.
Chris,
l want to
ask you
something.
l probably haven't asked you 'cause
l didn't want to know the answer.
l know you were married
all those times,
and l'm wondering
if l was the first--
you know,
the first man.
Well, l guess that
answers my question.
No.
No, it doesn't.
l just--
l think it's an odd conversation
for us to be having
right before you go
to your son's funeral.
The FBl says you're responsible
for a series of homosexual murders.
The FBl...
l'm not asking you to tell me if you
committed the murders.
l'm asking you if you've
ever felt this way with another man.
No.
l have not felt
this way.
l swear,
Toby.
You're lying.
- Toby, l'm not--
- You're lying.
Sweet dreams, baby.
Yes.
Ah, come in. Sit.
Thanks, Officer.
Smoke?
They're bad
for you.
Shirley Bellinger,
before she was executed,
gave me a little hint as to who
impregnated her when she was in Oz.
She said,
''Neither rain nor snow,''
which l believe is part
of the old motto
of the U.S.
Postal Service.
Since you deliver
the mail to death row,
l'm figuring she was telling me
that you were the father.
Well, you're wrong.
l never had sex
with Shirley.
Not that l didn't
want to.
Even if you had been right,
what's it matter? She's dead.
l don't know you,
Schillinger.
l don't know what you're capable of.
l know your reputation...
of course.
But even so, l find it
hard to believe
that you would cut the hand
off a small child,
that you would
kill a boy
who never
hurt a soul.
l never did anything
to Beecher's kid.
l'm gonna tell you
something now.
Beecher is the one
who found your son Hank.
l know.
You know.
Yeah, he did it
to fuck with me,
- the same way he did with Andrew.
- No.
He did it to make up
for what happened to Andrew.
He did it in the hopes
of putting the anger
that exists between you
behind you.
This l swear to you
on my vow as a priest.
lf l'm lying to you,
may l be damned for all time.
Schillinger,
don't let anything
happen to Beecher's daughter.
lf you have any decency
left inside you,
lf you--
if you have
a soul,
you'll let that girl
go free.
All right. So you asked me
to do a little digging, right?
So l dug here, nothing.
l dug there, zip.
But then,
a gusher.
- Tell me.
- ''Tell me''?
l got valuable
information
and we haven't even
negotiated a price.
- How much?
- Hey, l got kids too, all right?
My youngest,
Tabitha,
she needs massive amounts
of dental work.
That poor girl's teeth are fucked up,
man. They're all rotted out.
Zabitz...
Please, not now.
All right. But you
pay the dental bills,
every last one
of them.
Okay.
Just tell me what you know
about the kidnapping.
According to a very reliable
source on the outside,
this was
a job for hire.
The actual perp's name
is Bob ''Big Butt'' Towland.
Who hired him?
- l hesitate.
- Why?
Because it's someone
l understand
is very near
and dear to you.
Who, for
Christ's sake?
Chris Keller.
Can you be
sure of this?
l'm as sure as anybody can be
about anything.
l need you
to find out the truth.
That's my job.
He's done a lot
of fucked-up things to me, but this...
makes no sense.
Guys like Keller
are hunters.
They kill
for sport.
You think you're a
pretty cool customer, huh?
Well...
let's just say l spent my share of time
in interrogations.
You ever hear of a fellow
by the name of
Mark Karachi?
- No.
- Byam Lewis?
- Nope.
- How about Bryce Tibbetts?
No, no and no.
All three of these men
were homosexuals.
All three hung out
in the same gay bar.
All three
turned up dead.
That is, after they were
sodomized and tortured.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
But here's
what's curious.
You moved to the city
in December of '97.
These men were killed
in January, March
and May of '98.
You got sent
to Oz in June of that year.
Suddenly
the killings stopped.
What a bizarre
coincidence.
We know
you're guilty.
You got proof?
Evidence?
Witnesses?
You frequented
the same gay bar.
Oh. Well, you know,
that doesn't make me a murderer
any more than it
makes me a fag.
And yet you are,
aren't you? A fag?
- You suck Tobias Beecher's cock.
- He sucks mine.
From what l hear, you and he have had
a pretty bumpy courtship, huh?
Lots of pain
inflicted on both sides.
You in on this
latest round?
l don't
follow you.
The death
of his son.
Me kill his son?
You're joking, right?
Now when have you ever
known the FBl to joke?
Lights out!
How you doing?
You've been
very quiet today.
Let me ask you
something.
What should l do
if l ever find out who killed Gary?
You should whack him.
l'd help you.
Yeah?
- Well, that'd be my pleasure.
- What the fuck?!
You murdered
my son!
Get the fuck
off him!
You think
l'd do that?!
You're capable
of fucking anything!
You bitch!
- l'm here for my money.
- Pay him.
- You got a kid with rotten teeth?
- Yeah.
You should see her mouth, man.
Nothing but decay.
Genetics...
or environment?
Like in everything else,
society searches...
for the ''magic bullet''--
the easy answer,
'cause the more complex
the answer is,
the more terrified
we become.
ls the root of violence
much deeper,
much darker?
How about...
''pure evil''?
Maybe we human creatures
are inherently evil.
Maybe evil
is ingrained,
embedded
in our souls.
Flip Wilson
used to joke,
''The Devil
made me do it.''
Maybe he
was right.
Or maybe not.
Hello, Hank?
Yeah.
l want you to drop off
the other package
at the grandparents'
house.
No... alive.