l've been
wondering something.
From the time we
learn to speak until the day we die,
how many words
does the average person say?
l mean, we talk
and talk and talk, filling up the ozone,
secretly hoping that in
all those syllables,
we've said something
worth remembering.
Deep down,
we know the truth.
Most of what we say
is trash.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Where do you think
you're landing, chief?
Where do you think
you're landing?
- l need to talk to Burr.
- He busy.
- l'll wait.
- He's never not gonna be busy
when it comes to you,
snitch.
Stupid bitch.
You're not having
much luck
getting the brothers
to turn against Redding.
You also said Hill
was going to kill the old bastard.
Don't worry.
Redding's gonna die...
and soon.
Shakedown!
No, no, no.
- That ain't mine.
- Bullshit it's not.
Hey, Murph, that's not--
that ain't mine, man.
lt's definitely not mine.
Take him to McManus.
- Take him away.
- lt's not-- come on, man. That's not--
Sister, look,
you know me.
l've been clean
for over three years.
He's not using, Tim.
l would stake my reputation on that.
lf you're not using,
then you're selling.
No, somebody planted
that shit in my pod.
- Why?
- l-- l don't know.
- Do the tits belong to White?
- No!
- Then who are you protecting?
- Nobody!
All right.
l'm going to put you back in Em City,
only with no punishment.
This way all your little friends will
- think that you ratted on them again.
- McManus, put me in the hole.
- Officer.
- McManus, put me in the fucking hole!
You see what l'm saying?
Redding's the one that put
them drugs in your cell.
Maybe you arranged that.
Fuck, l don't know who to trust.
lt don't matter.
Redding don't trust you,
never will.
You only got one choice:
grease him.
l kill Redding,
then you take charge.
And l won't forget
what you done.
Well, l haven't forgotten
what you've done,
jabbering to the cops
on me.
l told you l'm trying
to make that shit up to you.
And l told you to leave me
the fuck alone.
You know, l'm done trying
to please you, Augustus.
l'm gonna take care
of business myself.
No, don't.
Supreme. Supreme.
l'll kill him.
Look, if he's gonna die,
l'd rather he die at my hands.
- l'll make sure it won't hurt.
- Whatever.
Just do the deed.
- Hardin.
- You wanted to see me?
- You still working bedpan?
- Uh-huh.
l need some
medical records.
Poet?
Yo, Poet?
Don't be talking
to me, snitch.
As far as we're concerned,
you're a dead man, a ghost.
- A ghost on wheels.
- Hey, listen, man.
l'm trying to save
Burr's life.
What you
talking about, man?
Supreme Allah--
l remember
back on the corner
he used to be
crazy allergic to something.
According to his records,
it's eggs.
Yeah, when we be
prepping his meals,
we got to fix
his shit real special.
Not today.
Eat hardy.
That bitch Burr
is still alive, Augustus.
What's up
with that?
l got to get close
to him, don't l?
l got to get back
in his good graces.
That's going
to take some time.
Well, you ain't
got time.
Something wrong?
- Oh, shit.
- You did this, didn't you?
You fucking-- oh!
Poet told me
what you done.
l came to thank you
and welcome you back
into the fold.
l accept your thanks.
But l don't want
to be back in.
l don't want
to sell drugs.
Your choice.
l respect that.
Respect?
l killed a man today.
l caused his death
to happen.
And even though Allah
was going to hurt you,
even though the motherfucker
screwed me to this chair,
l don't feel good
about what l done.
Well, then, Augustus,
l raised you right.
My daughter's coming today. Says she
has something important to tell me.
Well, when you
finish your visit,
l need you
to perform a task.
Like l said,
l'm here for you.
''Airhole'' Morales.
What about Pancamo?
His time will come,
but Morales goes first.
- Hey.
- Patricia.
So what did you
want to tell me?
Jeez, Dad, no ''How are you?
How's your mom?''
ls it bad news?
You're not leaving the Corps, are you?
Stop looking
so grim.
l'm getting married.
Married?
To Max?
Of course to Max.
That's wonderful news, sweetheart.
l'm so happy for you.
Thanks.
Dad, the thing is...
since you won't be there
to walk me down the aisle,
l was going to ask Myron.
l know how you feel
about him,
but he and Mom
have been married 20 years.
l-- l grew up
in his house.
l've got work detail.
Dad, l need your answer.
Do whatever the fuck
you want.
The goddamn thing
stopped dead.
We were able to get the warden out
but he wants it fixed pronto.
You both work mechanical,
so we figured you could take a look.
Oh, when l was a kid, l used to work
for Otis fixing elevators.
l know these suckers
backwards and forwards.
Whoa there, Otis.
Were you in the cafeteria
when that colored guy bought the farm?
Supreme Allah?
Yeah.
Talk about bugging out.
Hand me a wrench.
Life's pretty precarious
around here.
Yeah? Even more so
than in Nam?
The land-mines in Oz
are even less visible.
Friends turn on friends,
enemies buddy up.
l'm not used to that
kind of behavior.
l like to know who
my adversaries are.
Get up!
Be all you can be, babe.
When someone dies,
we look at the last thing he or she said
in hopes of finding
a summation of life,
a deep truth that those of us above
ground can cling to.
Like the novelist,
Daniel Defoe,
''l do not know
which is more difficult,
to live well
or to die well.''
ln Oz,
we do neither.
Jeremiah, the purpose
for my visit is--
and l wanted to do this
face to face.
The board of elders
met yesterday and decided
to ask you for your
resignation
as head of the new
Church of Christ.
The elders voted unanimously
on the day of my conviction
that they would
stand behind me,
- to support me no matter what.
- l know.
But the scandal has severely damaged
our fundraising efforts.
l want to talk
to the elders.
How, via satellite?
They can come here
to Oz.
Oh, Jeremiah,
be serious.
Those old men are not
coming here.
Letter of resignation.
Sign.
All l'm saying is Cloutier thinks
he's better than all of us.
- How do you mean?
- Warden's got us doing physical labor.
Cloutier's got a cushy job
in the requisitions office.
We're loading cement,
he's pushing a pen.
He should be
slaving alongside us.
Sowing more seeds
of discontent?
Just telling
my friends what's what.
Get up.
Did l ever mention why he threw me out
of the congregation?
Not because
l threatened someone
in the name of the Lord,
but because l disagreed
with him.
He tries to silence anyone
whose opinions differ.
Jim, escort this man out.
He has the right
to finish his thought.
All right,
let him speak.
Excuse me one second.
Hoyt,
you still looking to do
the Reverend Cloutier some harm?
Why?
You want him dead?
Not... dead, exactly.
Looking for this?
Give me the towel.
And so this proves what,
that you're stronger than me?
ln brute strength, maybe,
but l got the power
of Jesus on my side.
Well, good.
Then have the Lord Jesus
get you another towel.
When l was 10, my father
was a tent revival preacher.
He called me up on stage.
l was 10 years old.
l touched the eyes of a blind man
and he was healed.
From that moment on,
l-- l was special, famous.
Everywhere l went, on TV, crowds
of people wanting to touch me.
Wow.
That must be something.
Fame became
all that l knew.
Penthouses, limousines.
When l took the money
from my congregation,
l didn't even think
that l was stealing.
lt seemed like l was taking
what was rightfully mine.
Listen to me.
Pride.
Pride is the worst sin
for it is pride
that separates us from God.
Deliverance
comes from Jesus.
Yes, and He has
humbled me.
ln order to win
your congregation back,
you must show them that you're not
their superior, but their equal.
How do l do that?
By joining them
in their work.
''The labor of the righteous
tendeth to life.''
The last three words spoken by Jesus
were, ''lt is finished.''
Now, being the Son of God,
he probably knew
the end was coming
and had a chance
to consider what to say.
The rest of us don't
get that luxury.
When death comes,
it's a surprise,
and we got to improvise.
l have to tell you, Cloutier,
you really impressed me.
You really heeded the call.
Your followers
are tickled to death
you're helping me
build this wall.
Please, son, l beg you, think about
what it is that you're doing.
Oh, l've thought
about this completely.
When the hacks ask where you are,
l'll say, ''l don't know.
Maybe the good reverend
ascended into heaven.''
Help!
Help me!
They can't help you.
Nobody's here, remember?
And l paid the hacks
an extra 200 bucks to take a hike.
You're both going to burn in hell
for all eternity.
You should have just taken the blow job
when l offered it.
Help!
Help me!
Help! Help me!
Help!
The Lord is my shepherd,
l shall not want.
He leadeth me in the path
of righteousness for His name's sake.
Yea, though l walk
through the valley
of the shadow of death,
l will fear no evil!
Oh fuck.
Hughes?
Hey, l don't feel too good.
Fuck!
Hey, you stupid fucks,
listen up!
l hereby declare this unit
the Republic of Huhru.
Huhru! Huhru! Huhru!
- Are you fucking crazy?
- Until such time
as we can organize free
and fair elections,
l have assumed command.
You shall henceforth and to wit refer
to me as ''Your Excellency.''
Hughes, you're
a fucking nut job!
For that insubordination, Alvarez,
you shall remain inside your cell.
ln fact, until all of you
have proven your loyalties
to our new republic,
and to the principles
stated in my manifesto,
you shall stay
right where you are.
Hey, open the fucking door!
Get a fucking CO in here.
Central, this is Gamba Kufu,
acting President
of the Republic of Huhru.
l want to speak
to Warden Leo Glynn.
Hello?
Yes.
Oh, l'll tell him.
You better stop this nonsense,
and give yourself up right now.
And you better stop
your yapping, Smith,
or you're going to find my dick
burrowing towards your prostate.
Clayton, this is Leo.
You shall refer to me as Gamba Kufu
or Your Excellency.
- Clayton--
- Gamba!
How's Officer Smith?
Well, that depends on you.
- Listen to me, Clayton--
- Gamba.
- Clayton!
- Until you begin addressing me
with the respect befitting
my high office,
l am terminating
this conversation.
- Do you have the key?
- On its way.
l want you to unlock the door.
l'm going to go in first.
l wouldn't recommend
that, sir.
This isn't heroics,
Commander.
lt's good
old-fashioned guilt.
Hey, Your Excellency.
You seem to have everything
under control.
Only l want to make sure
you don't get the rest of us killed
and l want to know
what your plan is.
- My plan?
- Yeah.
'Cause l remember during
the riot a few years ago,
Said, Adebisi
and the rest of them,
they created a strategy.
Pender, your experience
makes you invaluable to the revolution.
l hereby name you
my acting Vice President.
- l'm honored.
- Ready to take the oath of office?
l don't think we time
for that, 'cause any moment
the SORT boys are going to burst in here
and mow us down.
Like Napoleon
back from Elba,
l shall speak to the men
and convince them to join our side.
Okay, but if that
doesn't work,
you might want to consider using
your hostage as a shield.
- Excellent idea.
- Yeah.
Fuck, here they come!
Hello, Leo.
Welcome to Huhru.
l've never lied
to you, have l?
Then l want you to listen
carefully to what l say.
The thoughts in your mind
aren't real.
You spent too much
time alone.
You've created a world
in your head.
There is no Huhru.
Your name is Clayton Hughes.
l am Gamba Kufu.
Your name
is Clayton Hughes,
and you're lost.
l want to help you.
l remember the day my
dad died,
l felt this way.
l remember you and me
in the hospital.
You hugging me.
l miss those hugs, Leo.
Will you hug me now?
l'll give up if you
hug me right now.
All right.
lt's all right, Clayton.
lt's going to be all right.
Hey!
- Commander!
- Go, go! Move!
Oh, fuck!
l saved your
fucking life, Glynn!
You owe me!
Clayton. Oh God.
Clayton--
my God.
My plan worked perfectly.
Hug me, Leo.
Hug me.
- Hug me.
- Oh, my God.
Not everybody leaves this mortal coil
miserable and confused.
Ethel Waters said,
''l'm not afraid to die, honey.
ln fact, l'm kind of looking
forward to it.
l know that the Lord
has His arms wrapped around
this big,
fat sparrow.''
l'm heading out
for the night,
unless you need me
to do something.
Today, l had to call
my best friend's widow
and inform her
that her only child was dead.
That he died in my arms
the same as his father.
l don't ever want to have
to make another call like that again.
There is one last thing
you can do.
Take a letter.
To Martin Douglas...
Commissioner,
Bureau of Prisons.
Dear Martin,
l resign as Warden
of Oswald State
Correctional Facility,
effective as soon
as a replacement can be found.
Why'd you stop writing?
Because you don't mean it.
Oh, l do, Floria.
lt's time for me to move on,
move up, move out.
No-- but you do a lot
of good here.
l do shit!
That letter goes out
first thing tomorrow.
Okay, well, why don't
we have dinner?
No, that's okay.
Well, l'm not going
to leave you like this.
l'm headed over
to see Clayton's mom.
My wife's already there.
We'll sit together, cry,
remember the good times
and try to make sense
out of...
what is senseless.
Good night.
Any news on how
Dave Brass is doing?
He's out of the hospital,
but his leg's
all fucked up.
He's never going to play
basketball again.
Heard the last game
was called off.
Glynn told me
that was your decision.
So?
What's the difference?
- l want to take Dave Brass' place.
- What?
l want you and l to play
the last game together.
Fuck you!
Because l turned
you down before?
- That's right!
- Okay, well, fuck me for that!
But listen, Tim, you made
a believer out of me, man.
- Huh?
- l was watching.
You played balls out with a lot
of fucking heart in both those games.
But Brass, he was
a phenomenal player.
l don't think anybody really noticed
how good you were playing.
And isn't that
the whole point of all this?
To show the dinks in here that if a guy
puts his mind to something--
- We can't win.
- l know.
But if we could
hold our own,
two average white guys
with bad bodies,
hanging with Vahue.
l mean, that would
mean something, man.
?? Get on top ??
?? Help me ??
?? Come get me ??
?? l'll bite, but...
she bit me ??
?? Gorilla, cuntilla ??
?? Sammy D
and salmonella ??
?? Come with me,
'cause l'm an ass killer ??
?? You're ill
but l'm iller ??
?? l'll malinger
on your block ??
?? And give the finger
to a cop ??
?? And pick a lock
before l knock ??
?? And set you up
to get on top ??
?? Get on top ??
?? Complications
of a mastermind ??
?? Last temptation
of my kind ??
?? lnterplanetary sign,
when do we align? Get on top ??
?? All in time ??
?? Right on ??
?? Get up,
come sit up ??
?? l light but...
she lit up ??
?? Grasshopper,
show stopper ??
?? The life
of a wife swapper ??
?? Come with me
'cause l'm a big bopper ??
?? You do
but l wopper ??
?? Exterminate my cause ??
?? You want to draw
some straws ??
?? Be the one
to see my flaws ??
?? Make me bleed
with painted claws ??
- ?? Get on top. ??
- l don't know why l think l can help,
but l'm not giving up
on you, Omar.
You understand?
l'm not giving up.
Thank you.
Hey, yo, Omar.
What's up, man?
Man, you know l don't fuck
around with that shit no more.
- Call me Mr. Clean around here, man.
- Oh yeah. Oh shit.
- Morning.
- Hey, my man, MacDaddy McManus.
How you doing, man?
How was your weekend?
lt was good.
l got a lot of work done.
Work?
What, no play?
You ain't have no, like,
romantic interludes?
Well, sure. Saturday night l took out
this Portuguese dancer.
What, a stripper?
- No, no, ballet. Ballet.
- Ballet?
Them ballet bitches,
they too skinny and shit.
They looking like
teenage boys and shit.
You got to get you
a stripper.
- See you. Okay, Omar?
- Can l go up with you?
Well, you know--
No.
Let me get settled
for a while, okay?
O--okay.
ls there a problem?
ls there something that can't wait?
Well, no.
lt's just, you know,
l'm feeling a little shaky,
you know what l mean.
Yeah, okay.
Come on up.
Come on. Come on.
Yeah, like l was saying, man.
You got to get you a stripper.
l used to have this stripper,
a bitch named Angelina.
Whoo-hoo! And that bitch could suck
a dick, too.
Omar's been off the drugs
for weeks now.
He goes to rehab regular,
he goes to class,
he does his work
assignments.
He's become
the model prisoner.
- And he's driving you crazy.
- Yes!
Whenever l'm in Em City,
he follows me around,
everywhere,
like a two-year-old.
And he goes on and on
about nothing.
So? Tell the jerk
to beat it.
And risk him sliding back?
No way.
Well, then,
as the French say,
you are up shit's creek
sans paddle.
For the second
straight week,
we have a new contestant
and a new celebrity.
ln fact, a man who's been let out
of jail especially for the show.
- Tim McManus, welcome.
- What?
Holy shit, look at that. Motherfucking
McManus starring up on TV.
And l want to introduce
our young star today.
He's the other Tony Soprano,
Robert ller.
- Robert, thank you...
- We got to get cable.
We are missing out
on all the good shit.
Hey, yo, l hear the women on ''Sex
and the City'' are hot, son. Hot
l'd fuck that Sarah
whatever-her-name-is, man.
Would you guys just shut
the fuck up, please? Shit.
We start off
with $10,
and the category today,
Tim, is vocabulary.
And the questions is:
What is a ''tittle''?
l think l know this.
l'm going to humor you,
l'm going to ask for a hint.
Did you cover this in
sixth-grade English, Robert?
Well, first off,
l'm in high school.
And yeah, they did cover this
in the third grade.
Would you like to give
him a hint, Robert?
lt comes
with crosses on t's.
l saw a show where there were
discussing ''tittles,''
and it wasn't punctuation.
Yeah, it's not punctuation.
lt's a diacritical mark.
- Kid's right.
- You're a good guy, Robert,
but l've been around
a little longer.
A ''tittle''
is a breast implant.
Leave it to McManus
to go for breasts.
No. ln fact,
it is the dot above an ''l.''
l always knew McManus was an idiot.
Now everybody else does, too.
Yo, don't be fucking
dogging McManus out, all right?
Oh, l'm sorry, White.
l forgot you've been
sucking his cock these days.
l'm not sucking
his cock, faggot.
Then you must be
taking it up the ass.
- Oh.
- You mother!
- Oh, shit!
- Motherfucker!
- Central, this is 11. We've got a 66.
Get out of here!
- Pedro Calderon died.
- The fuckin' spick came at me.
- Yeah, after you charged Guerra!
- He was making fun of you!
Well, the warden wants
you in solitary.
You said you'd never
give up on me.
You said you'd never let them
take me back.
l tried.
l argued as best l could. l lost.
l won't fucking survive in solitary,
you understand?
lt's too much dead air,
too much dead time!
- l can't do it!
- There's nothing l can do.
You fuck.
You fuck!
You fucking liar!
You fucking lied to me!
- Settle down there, White.
- You fucking settle down!
You motherfucking liar.
You fucking lied to me!
You fucking, motherfucking,
cocksucking liar!
You lied to me!
Everybody's always
fucking lying to me!
You said you wouldn't never
give up on me.
l don't want to go back!
Let me go!
You lied!
Okay, you're all done, Tim.
You should go home.
l'll drive you.
You know, White was right.
l didn't fight you hard enough.
l wanted to lose the argument.
l wanted him in solitary.
- l could tell.
- How?
You didn't stomp out of my office when
l wouldn't let you have your way.
l do want him
in Em City.
He already stabbed you, and now he
literally kicked the shit out of you.
l don't care.
Let him keep kicking.
l lost that basketball game,
because l gave up hope.
l won't abandon
Omar White. l won't.
You stay home a few days, and we'll talk
after you've had a chance to think.
Okay, but l'm not going
to change my mind, Leo,
because if l give up
on even one of these guys,
l might has well just open up a diner
somewhere, flip burgers till l die.
You know what?
l may join you.
ln 1955, James Dean said
to a friend,
''My fun days are over.''
An hour later, his car crashed,
and he was dead.
A self-fulfilling prophecy,
or just bad luck?
Hey, how'd that go?
l gave the blood. They're taking
a sample out of the baby.
lf the two match,
she's my granddaughter.
While you were gone,
l heard something about Beecher.
- What about Beecher?
- You know he's up for parole?
No.
His hearing is scheduled
for sometime this week.
Jesus.
Rumor is, cocksucker's
got a good chance of getting out.
Give me that stick.
What are we solids?
Vern, Beecher fucked up
your parole.
Don't you think
l fucking remember that?
lf you'd been paroled, maybe your sons
would be alive and your granddaughter--
Shut the fuck up!
- Why didn't you tell me?
- Vern...
Why didn't you fucking mention
that you're up for parole?
This is not the way to start an
interaction.
Stay out of this! We're supposed
to be totally honest here.
- Officer!
- On equal goddamn footing.
Session's over.
All this time, you knew
you might be getting out.
- All right, Schillinjer.
- ''Schillinger!''
God damn it.
''Schillinger!''
l've been here
nine fucking years,
you'd think you'd learn
how to say my goddamn name!
Oh Christ.
He's going to do something
to mess up my parole.
No, no, no.
l will talk to him.
- lt won't do any good.
- Tobias, l'll talk to him.
l'm fucked.
Hey, buddy.
Hey, mind if we
chow down with you?
- You gonna eat that orange?
- How about this milk, huh?
l'm sorry l didn't tell you
about the parole.
The truth is l don't really believe
it's going to happen.
Oh, it'll happen.
Those cocksuckers on the board
see a rich boy like you,
sobbing his story,
their little hearts will melt.
- Look--
- You're not going free, bitch.
You're not walking out of here
and leaving me behind.
Clean up this fucking mess.
l spoke to Schillinger.
He said all the right things.
He apologized
for his outburst.
He explained how important the
interaction sessions have been for him.
- Well, he's lying.
- l know.
Can you put me
in protective custody?
Well, normally, l would,
but the unit's full.
Well, then put Schillinger
in solitary.
Well, he hasn't done anything yet.
And besides, the unit's full.
- Well, fuck, lock down the prison!
- Just for you, Beecher?
Let's get serious. No, You'll stay in
your pod. You'll get your meals there.
l'll place an officer
outside your door. You'll be fine.
Why am l not
overwhelmed with relief?
Arif! Those bikers
are plotting something.
They want to provoke Beecher into
committing an act of violence,
- end his chance of parole.
- Yeah.
And l'm going to see
that he doesn't.
- And you're doing this all for Beecher?
- Oh yeah,
and for Salah Yudin,
and all those other lives
the Aryans have
already destroyed.
Hoyt said he can't
get anywhere near Beecher.
Oh, fuck!
- When's the hearing?
- Tomorrow, 11 :00.
Oh shit.
Well, well,
well, well...
lf it isn't
my old friend
James Robson.
Said, l promised the warden there
wouldn't be any trouble between us.
Officer...
You better stay nearby.
There might be a hoedown.
Can l see Beecher?
How you holding up?
Just got to make it through
one more night.
l've just been very
clear with Schillinger.
Any harm comes
to you,
and he will feel
the full wrath of Allah.
l appreciate that,
Kareem.
Assalaam alayka,
my brother.
Peace be unto you, too.
Though from what
l can see,
you're not in a very
peaceful place, huh?
l struggle, same as you.
You know...
when l was all screwy
about my hand
in Andrew Schillinger's
death, you told me
to embrace my guilt
or it would eat away at me forever.
Mm-hmm.
lt's funny that you haven't taken your
own advice regarding Adebisi.
How many times
l got to tell you, Tobias?
l feel no guilt
for killing Adebisi.
What haunts you
is not Adebisi's death, but his life.
- His life force.
- Haunts me?
What are you talking about?
l saw your face the moment
after you killed him,
and a bit of Adebisi
had bled into you.
- No.
- His anger...
- his violence...
- No, you're wrong!
Your entire life you've kept tight
control over your feelings.
You denied the Adebisi
in you, but you can't do it any longer.
You got to make him
part of you, Kareem.
Make him a part of you.
They're not going to
take my sweaty palms
as a sign
of criminal intent, are they?
Come on, will you relax?
l've been doing these kinds
of cases for six years now.
l have never been more sure
of an outcome in my life.
Yeah, well, you've never
had Tobias Beecher as a client before.
l got you a present.
l didn't have
a chance to wrap it.
- An appointment book.
- Yeah.
Mr. Beecher?
- We're ready for you.
- Okay.
Well, wish me luck.
l'll do more than that.
l'll do something
completely unprofessional.
Mr. Beecher.
Yeah, l'm coming.
Go.
And then they asked me about
defecating on Schillinger's face
and biting off the tip
of Robson's penis.
l'm not sure my answers
really satisfied them.
They voted yes.
Oh my God.
Oh my--
- Tobias?
- l'm going home.
l'm going home.
- Un-fucking-believable!
- Oh my God!
Fuck me!
Cocksucker!
- All right, Beecher.
- Shut the fuck up.
- Beecher's going free.
- No.
No.
l want him dead.
You understand?
Beecher does not leave Oz alive.
Mail!
Let's go, line it up!
- Here's a letter for Beecher.
- l'll give it to him.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
You motherfucker!
Motherfucker!
Louisa, please make sure
you hold his hands down.
l'm going to miss you.
Don't. Try not to even think
of this place.
Well, that'll be hard.
l still have a swastika
tattooed to my butt.
Be strong.
Love your daughter.
Love yourself.
So...
think you can do what
Sister Peter Marie said,
- not think of Oz?
- Yeah.
Prisoner 97B41 2 is dead.
l'm leaving
all his shit behind.
And then they asked me about
defecating on Schillinger's face
and biting off the tip
of Robson's penis.
l'm not sure my answers
really satisfied them.
- Well?
- l'm sorry Tobias, they voted no.
They were impressed by the progress
you made over the past few months,
but didn't feel it balanced all the bad
behavior from before.
Fucking Christ.
l am so sorry that l painted
such a rosy outcome.
l am completely
and utterly in shock.
l'm sure you did
the very best you could.
They did say that they be open
to another hearing in a year.
A year?
Another year.
Fucking Oz.
Tobias.
- Take me to my cell?
- Stay here and talk for a minute.
Later.
l want to be alone.
Beecher.
l am so glad that you and l get
to interact some more.
Get the fuck
away from me.
Now, now,
don't be bitter.
Let's kiss
and make up, huh?
l warned you
to keep away from him.
No!
He's mine.
Adebisi lives.
Okay, Vern, l need you
to move your foot.
Can you move your feet?
Start him on an lV.
- Motherfucker!
- l need some more right now.
- Okay, it's okay. Move your hand.
- Fuck!
''l want to go back
to my old home before l die.
l asked the great white Father
to allow me to go back.
But He said 'No.'''
Geronimo.
Didn't l tell you all
motherfuckers?
Cable is the best!
O'Reily.
O'Reily!
- What?!
- A package.
- That's the wristwatch?
- Yeah.
Last piece we need
for the bomb.
- We're gonna detonate during rec hour?
- The best time.
The gymnasium won't take the blast
being so far from Em City.
Are you sure about this?
The US government
made me a prisoner of war.
l'm being sent back to England
for purely political reasons,
and that's wrong.
So, we have to act.
Will our single deed
create change?
Maybe.
Probably not.
So then, you're saying
it's not the battle, but the war?
l'm saying whether we ever win the war
is for God to decide.
For man,
there's only fighting.
Fight for fighting's sake.
That's so fucked up, man.
No, fighting because injustice
must always be met head on.
Live like that.
We may not win,
but we ensure we never, ever lose.
- Ryan!
- Hi, kid.
- How you doing?
- You feel all right?
Yeah.
Hey, l can't thank you enough for
getting Cyril sent back to me.
l didn't transfer
him for you, Ryan.
l did it 'cause
it's the right thing to do.
No, l-- l know that,
you know,
'cause you always do
the right thing, the moral thing.
That's why l love you.
Kiss me.
Officer!
Take O'Reily
back to Em City.
Hey, l didn't mean
to upset you, you know?
All l meant to say was l got every
reason to live now, every reason.
Hey--
We got to talk. Look, we got to call
this operation off.
For fuck's sake, keep your voice down.
We'll discuss this later.
No, later's going
to be too late.
We're going to end up
killing a lot of people
- that shouldn't have to die.
- We've been through this.
Em City will be nearly empty.
l'll get word to the COs.
They'll have five minutes
for further evacuation.
No. What if the hacks
don't act fast enough?
l can't control that.
What if the blast
spreads to other areas,
other cell blocks, maybe even
the hospital, the visiting rooms?
There's nothing else
can be done.
No. Look, l-- l've killed anybody
for just about anything.
So l-- l'm not going to try to get all
high and mighty on you.
l know that this mission
makes sense to you.
But for me, l see
what we're about to do,
and for the first time
in my miserable, fucking life,
l feel like
l finally understand.
Understand?
Understand what?
Our actions, they
make us who we are.
And up to now, my actions don't amount
to a pile of shit.
Hey, Jesus Christ, Padraig,
l've got a brother
and even a woman inside
these walls who believe in me.
They believed in me
when l gave them nothing to believe in.
One hour from now, we're going
to complete our mission.
- Fuck you!
- What are you doing?
l've always been the guy who walked
tall, held his head high,
but that's always
just been a move, for show.
For once, l'm going to earn
the right to walk that way.
Hey, excuse me.
l need to go back to Em City.
l got an emergency.
O'Reily, what the
fuck is wrong with you?
You left the fucking
gas on again.
- Well, turn it off!
- No, you turn it off.
Where you going? Hey, l ain't gonna do
your fucking job for you.
Uh-huh. No. l'm taking this fucking
bomb to the hacks.
Relax, Ryan.
lt took me a minute,
but what you said
in the cafeteria
is starting to penetrate
this thick skull of mine.
Yeah? Jesus. Look,
that's good, Padraig,
because we could
still fight the good fight.
We just got to figure out
a different way to do it. All right?
Careful.
Did you shut off the time delay?
- No, l haven't done anything.
- Give me it.
Hey, what are you doing?
What must be done.
You've two minutes.
No, Padraig-- fuck!
Cyril, beat it!
McManus!
- McManus, Murphy, he's got a bomb!
- Huh?
Down there.
Connolly's got a bomb!
He's got a bomb!
Fucking Connolly's
got a bomb!
You've got exactly
one minute,
30 seconds to evacuate
Em City!
Padraig, put the bomb down.
Put it down. Let's talk.
- One minute, 15.
- Fuck!
You. You.
Check the computer room.
You three make sure
every fucking pod is empty.
Open the gate.
Hey, Padraig, Padraig!
Cut those wires.
There's no turning back.
Less than a minute. You should go.
No, just put it down
and we'll both go.
A foreign army still
occupies lrish streets.
That's all the more reason for you to
stay alive, remember?
To fight, remember?
l've no illusions about
what l face back in England.
l'll not die
on their soil.
l end here.
- O'Reily! Come on, let's go!
- 20 seconds!
- Ryan!
- God damn you, Padraig!
10 seconds!
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women, and
blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners,
now and at the hour
of our death. Amen.
Oh, Christ almighty.
How soon
till detonation?
lt should have
gone off by now.
Fucking piece
of shite!
lt's a dud.
- lt's a fucking dud.
- Go get him.
Maybe what we say when we go is less
important than what's said about us.
When you die, what's the nicest thing
someone will utter about you?
What's the worst?
Somewhere in-between
is who you are.
Or maybe mere words aren't
enough to define a life.
Maybe only
one's actions can.