Some big high roller
once said,
the business of america
is business.
And l'm happy to report
the criminal justice business
is booming.
Heavy industry headed south,
small towns are battling
for state contracts
to build correctional
facilities.
Who'd have thunk it?
Nice, upstanding citizens
begging to have rapists,
drug dealers and murderers
right in their own backyard.
How is your brother?
The doctor says he's fully
recovered from the overdose.
They're going to keep him in the
hospital overnight for observation,
but Cyril's
going to be fine.
Praise the lord.
Hey, O'Reily,
sorry to hear
about your girlfriend.
Who's his girlfriend,
Adebisi?
Dr. Nathan.
Yeah, she took a leave of absence.
Apparently, she almost choked to death
when Ryan here came in her mouth.
Fuck you!
- Bring it on!
- Fuck you!
What the fuck are you cuffing me for?
l didn't start shit!
Shut your fucking face,
O'Reily!
Eat me,
you goddamned clit!
l'll take this one.
Fuck you!
- Are you crazy?
- God damn it! Fuck!
Just stay down.
Stay the fuck down!
Blow me.
- Again?
- Yeah.
Oh, fuck!
Rabbi.
So, feeling better?
A dead man needs
to cover all his options.
You sure you're
a dead man?
Mr. Querns,
sometime after you send me
back to Em City,
a day, a week maybe,
O'Reily will have
found a way to kill me.
l like you, Stanislofsky.
l don't know why,
but l do.
l can let you stay up here
for a few more days.
What good is going
to come of that?
- Death is inevitable.
- Not necessarily.
l plan to have a little talk
with your old pal Ryan O'Reily.
You know...
l'm trying to eliminate
violence from Em City.
And doing an amazing job, sir.
Cut the crap!
When Stanislofsky returns,
if anything happens to him--
l mean, anything--
he cuts himself shaving,
l'm holding you responsible.
Hoyt's got the hots
for Stanislofsky, not me.
l don't care.
You're responsible.
- Understand?
- Uh-huh.
lf Nikolai gets hurt
when he gets back to Em City,
- my ass is grass.
- Right. Now get lost.
- Claire? Baby?
- Yeah? Yeah?
- How much do you love me?
- Oh, plenty.
Yeah? Enough to do
anything l ask?
- Yeah.
- Thattagirl. Come on.
Cyril! Hey!
How you doing, huh?
You okay?
You feeling better?
- Yes.
- Good.
- O'Reily?
- Mm-hmm.
That certain someone
you asked me to inquire about?
- Yeah.
- He's coming back to Em City tomorrow.
Stay right there.
Shit.
Ready for this?
He asked Querns for a favor.
- What?
- He wants to take a bath.
- There's no bathtubs in Oz.
- Hospital therapy room.
That's perfect.
You know
what to do, right?
l'm here to pick up
Stanislofsky.
Thanks.
You almost done?
Five minutes, please.
l'm enjoying myself.
l'll bet l can help you enjoy
yourself even more.
Ah, that's good.
How's that?
lt was never like this
in gulag.
You men are alike.
So quick, so easily satisfied.
Most of you don't know dick
about making a woman happy.
- Ryan O'Reily does.
- Oh, really?
Here's a small token
of his affection.
What is this?
A rubber ducky.
Rubber ducky?
Call the medic.
l think the russian guy is dead.
Hey, Mr. Querns,
l heard about Stanislofsky.
That's weird. Guy dies before
he gets back to Em City.
Yeah.
Picasso, bend over.
Hey, Miles,
special delivery.
Paints, thank fucking Christ.
l'm almost out.
- lt's coming along real nice.
- Nice?
This is a masterpiece
of 21st century art.
This wall should be
in The Louvre.
Hey, Schillinger, next time
try handing them to me.
- Fuck you.
- Lunch.
- Hey, what you got, Leroy?
- Chicken nuggets.
Again? Don't you niggers know how
to shake 'n bake anything else?
Yo, we've got state dietary
guidelines to follow, dog.
Careful.
You spilled my nuggets.
Fuck you.
- Time to go, Deyell.
- Go?
- Where's he going?
- Meeting with his lawyer.
You still trying to appeal
your death sentence, black boy?
Fuck you, bitch!
Man, they ain't
never gonna let you off.
No one's asking
your opinion, asshole.
Yeah, Miles,
give your mouth a rest. Okay?
Judge Fee has denied
our appeal.
Shit. Shit.
Shit, Shit, Shit!
- ls there a problem?
- He's fine, officer. We're fine.
So what's next?
We go to the state
supreme court
and appeal the appellate
court's decision.
How long is that
going to take?
Given the court's
current caseload,
- l'd say at least a year.
- A year?
Dawn, l can't sit up on death row
another day, much less a fucking year!
l didn't create
the system, Moses,
l just wallow in it.
Well, can't you drop
some speed on the process?
l don't even know if they're
going to hear our case.
Chief Justice Ginther,
who was appointed by James Devlin,
tends to turn a deaf ear
to anything he considers
''soft on crime.''
So what you're saying
is l'm fucked?
What l'm saying is
time may be on our side.
Rumor is Ginther's
got prostate cancer.
He dies, retires, a new chief might look
at the death penalty differently.
- And meanwhile?
- You're alive for another year.
Make the best
of a bad situation.
Hey, Deyell, you know how l'm
always calling you ''black boy''?
Well, while you were downstairs
with your legal beagle,
l thought, Shit,
there's a whole bunch
of other names l can use.
Nigger, of course.
Or coon,
jigaboo,
spear chucker, schwatza,
mulonian.
But l settled on negro.
Negro!
lt's got a kind of simplicity.
Negro is the Spanish word
for blacks. A negro.
Negro.
Negro. Negro!
Negro! Negro!
Negro, negro, negro!
ldiot! Move out
of the way. ldiot!
lt goes like this, faster!
See this?
Now move.
Cry-baby.
Prisoner number 96Z858,
Eli Zabitz.
Convicted April 1st, 1996,
aggravated assault.
Sentence: nine years,
up for parole in six.
- Zabitz.
- Oh, Keller.
- No, no. Where you going?
- l gotta be somewhere.
No, you got to be
right here with me.
Yeah, yeah, okay.
How are your
daughter's teeth?
Oh, l'm proud to say
every one is now a pearl.
l'm glad.
That makes me happy
that you're able to provide
dental care before you die.
Die? l'm not--
Jesus, Keller!
Why don't you just sit down
and shut the fuck up?
Now, you told Tobias Beecher
that l killed his kid.
- Yeah, but Schillinger made me do it.
- Shh, Shh, Shh.
Regardless...
soon you're going
to be joining your ancestors.
lf you're going to do it...
why tell me?
So you can get
your affairs in order...
and to watch you sweat.
Are listening to me?
Keller says he's going
to whack me.
Will you get off my back?
You're ruining
my concentration.
Listen, you got to protect me,
because if you don't protect me,
l'm going to the hacks
and l'm going to tell them
you paid me to lie to Beecher.
Lower your voice.
You see what you made me do?
You're fucking up my game here.
Your game, huh?
This is my life we're talking about!
Look, l said l'd protect you
from Keller.
l'll protect you. Okay?
- Okay.
- Now buzz off.
Jesus, l thought the jews
were supposed to be tough.
That's just the lsraelis.
Hmm. Kill him.
l'm going to take
that shot again.
Hello, Eli.
You know, this room
really isn't that safe.
l got stabbed here
once myself.
Fuck, Keller, no!
Oh, thank god.
Get him.
- Schillinger wants you dead.
- What? Fuck!
- Robson, this is my kill.
- Take a fucking walk, Keller.
Please!
Please don't kill me!
Fuck!
- Later.
- He dead?
- Heart attack.
Jesus.
l told him you got to watch
that red meat.
Beecher!
l'll see you.
You know, you used to be
addicted to alcohol,
then heroin.
But this obsession,
that's the worst
and the most dangerous.
Toby,
l'm talking to you.
Oh, l like it
when you're rough.
You're a slut, Beecher.
You'll sleep with anyone.
So?
How does that sex make you feel?
You feel better about yourself?
No, worse.
Then why do it?
Because at least
l'm feeling something.
l prefer to be happy,
but self-hate
will do in a pinch.
Don't hate yourself.
Why not?
My son is dead
'cause of me.
My daughter's a mess
And Keller--
Keller doesn't love me.
But l tried
this new detergent.
lt really seems
to get the whites clean.
Hello, Chris.
l'm here about Beecher.
l get a half-hour in the gym.
You're eating into my time.
Will you just hear me out?
Please?
The man is dying inside.
Well, that's not on me.
l'm not blaming you. l'm asking you
for your help to turn him around.
The two of you
had a relationship.
You had an intimate
relationship.
Oh, come on, Father,
you can say it.
We fucked each other
up the ass,
- in the mouth.
- No, no. Not the fucking,
The love.
The two of you loved each other.
l know that is all over now.
But still,
if you had any real
feelings for him,
l can't believe that you would sit
by and watch what's happening.
He tried to kill me.
You murdered my son!
And my relationship
with Beecher--
it started in brutality
and that's where it's ended.
Love was the smallest part.
l don't really believe
that you believe that.
You don't?
Where do you live, Father?
Where do you live?
ln a rectory
at St. Margaret's.
A rectory. Only men
live there, right?
Yeah.
You share common experiences,
a common belief.
You accept each other's
eccentricities, flaws.
Some flaws are unacceptable,
like, say,
one priest wants
to fuck another.
- Oh, Keller...
- You said, hear me out.
l mean,
l'm just asking
for the same courtesy.
Okay.
Unless, of course,
l'm hitting too close to home.
- You never have, have you?
- What?
- Fucked a fellow priest.
- No.
- Ever wanted to?
Oh, come on.
You share a bathroom together.
You walk in and some seminarian's tight,
little ass is hanging out.
Keller, l see
what you're up to.
You want me to do
the honorable thing,
the selfless thing.
Say, l'll help Beecher out.
Hey, Mukada,
we're in Oz.
And like l said,
other rules apply.
Now according to the code
we got here,
l'm not expected
to save Beecher.
l mean, fuck, l'd be breaking
that code if l did.
lt only takes one man
to change the way things are.
Yeah?
Well, l'm not that man.
Seven out of 10 inmates
are from cities,
but 90°/% of the prisons
themselves
are in rural areas.
You know, farmland,
hillsides, forests.
Now you'd think such
bucolic surroundings
would have a calming effect
on those inside.
But no,
out in the wild,
things only get wilder.
Tobias, we have bad news.
Bad news?
Gee, that's a change.
Hank Schillinger got off
on the murdering
and the kidnapping charges.
What?
- You mean he's free?
- Yes.
Evidently, when the arrest
was made,
the police didn't do something
they were supposed to do
and the judge
just let Hank go free.
- On a technicality?
- Yeah.
What happens next?
Nothing.
There's nothing that can be done.
Okay.
Tobias, aren't you going to stay
and talk about this?
lf there's nothing
to be done,
what is there
to talk about?
Your anger.
Sister, you do not want
to see my anger.
My anger is massive,
all-encompassing.
l'm not afraid.
Fine.
Where the fuck have you been
during all this shit?
- Tobias.
- What?
Let him talk.
l thought you actually cared,
but only if it doesn't get in the way
of your own fucking bullshit.
You are nothing
but a selfish cunt.
Now can l go?
Yes, but think
about something.
There's only one person who
really matters in all of this
and it's your daughter Holly.
Holly needs your strength!
She needs her father!
What is your name?
Hank.
Yo, Dad.
Yo?
What kind of talk is that?
l was shittin'
in my pants.
l thought the feds
had me by the balls.
They can't touch you, son.
Do you have
any more cash?
l was thinking
of going to Miami.
Leaving town?
For awhile.
l was hoping we'd get
to spend some time together.
Well, yeah.
When l come back we'll do
the father-son thing.
So what do you say?
Can you give me
some more money?
Sure, anything you need.
Cool. Cool.
l've arranged with the warden
for you to have regular visits
with your daughter.
We spoke to your parents,
and they've agreed
to bring Holly here
three times a week--
twice after school
and Saturdays.
You and she
need the time together.
You need time to heal.
Mail.
Stop them!
l'm going to kill you,
motherfucker!
Well, l guess you heard
the good news about Hank.
Cocksucker!
You fucking cocksucker!
- Take him to Em City!
- You wait!
You fucking wait!
Wowee.
Got quite a temper,
hasn't he?
What do you want?
l'd like to have a chat
with Mr. Pancamo.
A chat?
Let me see if he's in
a chatting mood.
Nice shirt.
You can go in.
Mr. Pancamo,
thank you for seeing me.
l have to admit
l'm intrigued.
You and me ain't
exactly paisans.
l need you
to arrange something.
- Drugs?
- No.
Two of my children
were kidnapped.
My son Gary was killed.
Yeah, l heard.
Schillinger's son Hank did it,
but the bastard got off
on a legal technicality.
That sucks.
He's out free
and my son lies
rotting in the ground.
l want Hank Schillinger dead.
Wait a minute.
Are you asking me
to set up the hit?
Yes.
Well, how do l know this isn't
some kind of sting operation?
You working with the hacks
to fuck me over?
The only proof
l have is this.
While you're taking care
of Hank,
l'm going to kill his father.
Okay.
You got a deal.
A thousand for me,
a thousand for the job.
- Cash.
- Okay.
Hey.
You gonna see
your daughter?
Yup.
The first time
since the kidnapping.
That'll be good for her
and for you.
Listen, l saw you
talking with Pancamo.
- You saw me with Pancamo?
- Yeah.
lt doesn't take a rose cutter
to figure out what's in play.
You're gonna have Hank
Schillinger killed aren't you?
What's the matter,
aren't you going to deny it?
You know, you killed Andrew,
Schillinger's son.
He killed Gary, your son.
Now you want to kill Hank?
Beecher, when is all this
madness going to end?
After l kill Schillinger.
And then you're going
to end up on death row.
And what good are you going
to be to your daughter then?
What good am l to her now?
Holly?
Oh, baby.
How are you doing?
lt's so good to see you.
My beautiful girl.
l love my daughter.
- l know you do.
- l only want the best for her.
Of course.
She shouldn't have to carry
the weight of my mistakes.
- Excuse me, Mr. Pancamo.
- Hey, Beecher.
Thanks for
the prompt payment.
l wish others lived
by your example.
Look, l have thought it over
and l've changed my mind.
l want to call off the hit
on Hank Schillinger.
That's fine,
except for one little thing.
You're too late.
He's dead?
Bullet right through
the brain.
Oh, shit.
But don't worry.
They're never going
to find the body,
never in a million years.
Hank Schillinger
has simply disappeared.
Time to go home, Rebadow.
Since l took over this unit,
violence has decreased by 92°/%.
92°/%!
That statistic would be higher
but for you, Rebadow,
trying to shank Busmalis
in the middle of the night.
l'm very sorry, sir.
And l assure you nothing
like that will happen again.
Good.
Because if it does,
l'm sending you to Gen Pop,
where they'll eat your ass
for lunch.
Take off.
- You feel better now?
- Hey, killer.
- Dog in the house.
You talk to God lately?
Watch out
for Busmalis.
lf you come at me,
l'm ready to go down fighting.
No, no, no.
l apologize, Agamemnon.
l don't know what
came over me.
lt was like l was
possessed or something.
l ask for your forgiveness.
Well...
Please!
Stop!
Just stop!
Stop talking!
Please!
Mr. Querns, sir, did the doctors figure
out what's wrong with Rebadow?
Brain tumor.
Oh, my god.
They're shipping him off to Dennsley
Memorial for emergency surgery.
Before he goes,
may l see him?
No.
He wanted me to shake
his hand.
l didn't shake his hand.
Please, can l see him?
No.
We're here to pick up
Robert Rebadow.
Over there.
Hey, stop that.
Leave me alone.
- Leave me alone!
- Relax, pop.
l want somebody l know
to go with me.
On three.
One, two, three.
l don't know you.
Dr. Nathan.
Dr. Nathan!
Busmalis!
Mama.
Mama!
Mama!!
The census bureau
counts prisoners
just like they count
everybody else.
But the census bureau considers
prisoners as residents
of the township
where the prison is located,
not where they lived before
they got convicted.
''So what?'' you say.
The state uses these numbers
to determine where financial aid
like poverty funds are spent.
Some rinky-dink town upstate
gets a big, fat check,
while the inner city
where the money would keep
people from committing crimes
gets zippity-doo-dah.
The census,
is senseless.
You all wanted to see me?
Yeah, Adebisi's got
a bug up his ass
- about your friend Mobay.
- l don't like him.
Mobay's filled his quota.
He brought us five new customers.
- Leave him the fuck alone.
- Which customers?
Look, Tidd and Browne, they gave us
the name of their new babies.
Mobay only knows
them by face.
You actually seen him sell
tits to anybody?
No, no.
We got the cash.
Who cares?
He could be undercover.
With the amount of shit
he shoves up his nose,
no fucking chance.
Look, next time he sells,
l want you by his side.
By his side!
All right.
Yeah.
This hands sucks, man.
They insist on watching me sell
the drugs to somebody.
Only l can't legally do that.
So either way, l'm fucked.
Unless...
call your lieutenant.
Have him bring in another
undercover detective.
You sell the drugs
to another cop,
nobody gets hurt.
Warden, that's genius.
lf l'm such a genius how come
l can't pick out a poster?
l mean, none of them
look like me.
See, l told you
Mobay's okay.
Bruno Goergen fell down
an elevator shaft.
Yeah, freak accident.
No, he was pushed.
Wait, Mobay.
Please, man.
Really?
l'm here to find out
who murdered him.
- Any suggestions?
- Nope.
You never saw Goergen have any
confrontations with anybody?
No.
And you never had any
confrontations with him yourself?
No.
Now you see,
that's not what l heard.
Look, lady,
you can keep excavating,
but there are no secrets
buried in my brain.
l'll be back.
- Anything?
- This one knows something.
l'm gonna let him sit there
alone for awhile,
see what percolates.
Where you been?
With a homicide detective
avoiding her questions.
Relax.
She don't know nothing.
You ain't got no guilt
about what you did, do you?
Guilt?
We are both of us,
the same, Mobay.
Cop killers.
Except every single day,
l wish l could take back
what l'd done.
Goergen was a monster.
Yeah, it takes a monster
to kill a monster, right?
l guess so.
Peace, black man.
You wishing me peace?
- Move out of my way.
- You ain't going nowhere.
l see you went to Adebisi,
asked him to grease me.
ls that any way
for a brother
to act towards
another brother?
Move.
l could kill you right now.
But you won't 'cause Adebisi
promised Querns
no violence in Em City.
- Move.
- Okay, Arif.
But watch where you walking.
You wouldn't want
to get hit from something
falling down from the sky now,
would you?
All right, everybody.
Let's go!
Do you need something?
Yes.
lmam,
l have committed
a great sin.
l am no longer the lmam.
l have failed,
l have disgraced myself
and our faith.
And because of my blindness,
we are all in danger.
l know.
Lead us, Kareem.
No.
Stop hiding
from who you are.
Stop hiding from who God
wants you to be.
ln the name of Allah,
l ask you.
Lead us.
- Oh, Miss Sally.
- Miss Sally, l love you.
Attention!
The following prisoners are
being transferred to Unit B:
94D696, Downing;
98M922, Masters;
96Z506, Zonioni.
Get your stuff,
follow Officer Howell out.
Let's go, ladies!
More white guys
leaving Em City?
They're white,
but they ain't guys.
Still, it's looking
pretty dark around here.
True.
Prisoner number 00B563,
Raymond Browne,
aka, ''Mondo'' Browne,
convicted April 10th, 2000,
murder in the first degree.
Sentence: 27 years,
up for parole in 11.
- Fuck you, man.
- Fuck you, nigger.
What the fuck
do you want to do?
- l'm a patient man, l'll wait.
- Take Zanghi to the hole.
What do you mean? He didn't do a fucking
thing. You know it!
l heard him say nigger.
He provoked Browne.
- That's bullshit!
- Back away, Pancamo.
Fuck all you guys.
All right, break this up!
Break it up!
Browne, get out of here!
Come on, break it up.
Yeah!
Do it, baby.
Slowly, slowly.
Kiss my foot.
Kiss it.
Hello, boys.
- We gotta talk.
- So talk.
What the fuck
are you doing?
We're your partners.
You think you're
going to fuck us over
and we're just going
to take it up the ass?
Morales, nobody
wants your ass.
Johnson hits me
with his fuckin' stick,
throws Zanghi in the hole.
That ain't the fucking deal,
Adebisi.
Besides it's been 10 days since
we've seen any green.
You pocketing the profits?
No, there's plenty of profits.
But there's been a change
in the organization.
How so?
Well, you know,
we three were partners
and now we're not.
- What?
- l don't need you boys anymore.
You looking
to start a war?
Now if there was a war,
you'd lose.
Look around.
See all these faces?
They match mine.
No, boys,
there won't be any war.
And why the fuck not?
Because you
and your pal
are about to take
a little holiday over to Unit B.
What?
When?
Oh, look.
l would say now.
Come on.
Hey, l'm going to miss you.
Say hi to Schillinger
for me, huh?
As you can see, we have some
more prisoner transfers
including trustees
Pancamo and Morales.
So l'm naming Supreme Allah
and Poet to replace them
as trustees.
Said...
l told you.
l told you to join me.
But you never listen.
You never listen.
You know what?
That is what is going
to kill you in the end.
And what's going
to kill you, Adebisi,
AlDS or an O.D.?
Don't worry about me.
l don't.
l worry about
the people around you
breathing the air
you poison.
Look, l've created a utopia.
Your Shangri-la Sama.
This is not Sama.
This is an inferno.
We have all the control
and all the power,
finally.
A bad system
run by blacks
is the same as bad
system run by whites.
Bad? We have everything
we want.
We have everything
in our grasp.
You think you've recreated
the world, don't you?
Simon,
lt's just an illusion.
Real power can only
come from the grace of God
The Almighty.
lf l wanted to,
l could crush you
like a cockroach.
Yes, but you won't
because l am the only one
who speaks the truth
to you.
Your truth, not mine.
Adebisi's turned Em City into
a fucking Zulu nation.
What the fuck are we
supposed to do?
Create our own country.
McManus, we got to talk.
Make an appointment
with my secretary.
This is serious.
Yeah, l can tell.
You got that Schillinger
scowl going.
Your precious little dream,
your Emerald City,
is now a ghetto.
You been there lately?
Crap all over the floors,
drugs everywhere,
the lack of primary colors.
Well, that unit is no longer
my responsibility.
Hey, l got no problem
with that.
What we don't want
is that new attitude over there
to come wafting this way.
They hear about
what's going on,
empowerment,
they're going to want
the same thing here.
And you're suggesting what,
that we make Unit B
all white?
Yes.
Get the fuck away
from me.
Let the niggers
have Em City.
Fuck, let them have
the whole goddamn prison,
as long as we're safe
over here.
Goodbye, Vern.
Don't be a bigger fool
than you've already been.
Lockdown!
- Lock the unit down!
- You'll see.
You'll wish you listened
to me, McManus.
Now!
The new electric perimeter fencing
will go into operation next wednesday.
As of then, we'll be able
to eliminate
the 24-hour watchtower
surveillance
which should save us
countless manhours.
Hey, sorry l'm late.
Emerald City
is a shithouse!
McManus--
There's garbage
all over the place.
Oh? And in Unit B
you can eat off the floor.
Enough!
The motherfucker's
jealous of me.
- Jealous?
- That's right, jealous.
- Martin, please.
- No, he knows it.
Since l took over Em City,
there's been next to no violence.
My system works.
At what price?
Huh?
At what fucking price?
McManus?
For God's sake, McManus,
stop, please.
Conditions in Emerald City
are deteriorating rapidly.
Something has to be done
to stop Adebisi.
Hey, why are you
coming to me?
- Talk to Querns.
- l have.
Querns is willing to turn
a blind eye to what
Adebisi is doing as long
as order is maintained.
Then talk to Glynn.
l've tried that, too.
He seems indifferent,
distracted because of his
election campaign.
No.
lt's up to you and me.
You and me?
Adebisi needs to be
shut down and fast.
lf that means
eliminating Querns,
so be it.
- You have a plan?
- Yeah...
l have a plan.
l was wrong, Adebisi.
l see that now.
You truly have transformed
his cell block
into a paradise.
A utopia.
l'm going to say it
for everybody to hear.
l want to join you,
and serve you in
whatever way you choose.
- Are you serious?
- Yes.
Then swear to me
in the name of Allah.
l do so swear.
l've waited for this moment.
Now l can raise you
as my equal.
Together there's nothing
we can't do.
Nothing.
Nothing!
Nothing, nothing.
Nothing.
Nothing!
Nothing. Nothing.
Nothing! Nothing!
Let me see
your hands up!
Adebisi and Said,
hand in hand.
lt's the end
of the fucking universe.
Those census numbers
l was talking about,
they're also used to determine
election districts.
A senator from a white
rural area with a prison
can count the inmates
as his constitutes,
and therefore, increase
his political influence.
Those inmates
who are largely of color
aren't allowed to vote.
The senator has no allegiance
to them at all.
ln fact, he benefits
by voting for laws
to keep them
incarcerated longer.
The town benefits
by the increased
prison population.
Yeah.
Everybody benefits.
Somebody must
stop him and soon.
Nora?
Leo, l'm sorry for
stopping by so suddenly.
l know you're busy running
things and the campaign and all,
- but l didn't know who else to call.
- Well, what's the matter?
lt's Clayton.
Sweet Jesus, l don't know
my own son anymore.
l mean, with him giving
the inmate the gun
and then the African dress
and now...
What?
l found this in his room.
lt's like he's collected all
of his anger toward the world
and is pointing it toward
the Governor.
Where's Clayton now?
l don't know.
He hasn't been home in days.
Well, when he comes back,
you call me. Okay?
ln the meantime,
try not to worry. All right?
With these new
stab-proof vests,
the correctional officers
here and across the state
will have the very best
protection.
Their safety
is paramount to me.
These are the men and women
who keep the forces
of darkness at bay.
There are those who
say no more prisons;
Well, l say
no more crime.
Fuck you!
Somebody get a doctor,
get a medic in here.
The governor's been shot!
Get some help!
Get a doctor!