Oz...
the name on the street
for the Oswald State
Correctional Facility, level four.
Now in Oz,
our entire day is structured.
We know when we'll eat,
sleep, work,
when we'll have
free time.
Now giving a man
who's locked up free time is a joke,
'cause there are still
all kinds of restrictions
as to what you can
and cannot do.
Some people try
to better themselves
by reading or exercise.
some pray...
some plot.
Some just watch TV.
Live from Burbank Studios
in Burbank, CA,
it's time to play
''Up Your Ante.''
And here's your host,
Gordon Elliot.
Hello and welcome
to ''Up Your Ante.''
And let's meet our first
contestant tonight,
Mr. John Carpenter.
Now let's meet our star.
Joining us this evening, the divine,
the purrfect, Miss Eartha Kitt.
Eartha, thank you
so much for being here.
Categories start on fashion.
Take a look
at this photograph.
Can you tell me
what kind of beard this man is wearing?
l think l need a hint.
Eartha?
Well, l can
give you a hint.
- lt can also be called a Rob Petrie.
- Oh.
Rob Petrie?
lt's a goatee,
you stupid fuck!
Come on, just say it,
just say goatee.
He could say goatee,
but he'd be wrong.
That's not a goatee?
- lt's a Vandyke.
- Vandyke?
''Rob Petrie''?
Get it?
No, who's Rob Petrie?
Yo, would y'all just fucking clam it up
so l can hear the answer?
- Count!
- lt's a Dick or a Vandyke.
Up My Ante!
Yes, television keeps us busy,
keeps us happy.
l'm what we call
a segment producer.
Each of our shows is divided
into four 10-minute stories,
anchored
by a different newsman.
- l work for Jack Eldridge.
- l like Eldridge. He's a ball buster.
That piece you did on heating oil,
you really tagged that corporate clown.
Have a seat.
We want to do a three-part series
on Oswald.
You know, inside one of
America's toughest prisons.
- No.
- No?
Like l said, l saw what he did to that
guy, and l don't want to be that guy.
What have you got to hide?
Nothing. But in the four years
since we had the riot,
life around here's
been rough.
Attitudes are just starting
to settle down.
You bring in the TV cameras,
you're gonna stir the situation up.
Well, l've spoken
to the commissioner, and he's agreed.
- Then l'll call the Governor.
- He also agreed.
Well, if you already had permission,
if you already knew it was a done deal,
- why'd you even ask me?
- To get your honest reaction.
First we're gonna do
an overview of life in Oswald,
then we're gonna follow
one new prisoner coming in
and we will close
with Jack Eldridge
spending the night
locked in a cell.
- Spending the night?
- Yeah, just him and one real inmate.
By the way, when does
the great man get here?
Not till the day
we actually shoot.
For the next few days
l'm gonna have a crew here
while l do
preliminary interviews
with you staff members
and as many prisoners as possible.
Please understand, our goal
is to show the audience
how incredibly difficult
your jobs are
and to kick
''60 Minutes'' in the ass.
That's all.
Tomorrow and for several days,
a television crew
will be walking the halls
taping a piece on Oz
for their news magazine.
Quiet down! Quiet!
Now l know when the cameras
are rolling
you guys will run through
your bag of tricks-- plead innocent,
run scams, cry foul,
or whatever else you think
is gonna get you some attention,
get your faces on TV.
But let me warn you,
when those cameras are gone,
l'll still be here.
When the story airs,
l will be watching
and l won't forget
what you say or what you do.
That is all.
Lights out!
l gotta think
of some good shit to tell this jamook.
He's only gonna use
the best stuff.
- You gonna make shit up?
- l can't tell him the truth, can l?
But l want to be on camera.
Can't let these
matinee idol looks go to waste.
Callate!
Ay-yi-yi.
Callate.
You gonna sit down
with those news people?
Yes, l am.
l've got a lot to say about
the conditions up in here.
- What if they ask about Adebisi?
- Adebisi.
The court found me innocent
of his death by way of self-defense.
Even McManus testified
on my behalf.
But still, the reporters--
they're bound
to dig up old bones
and make us Muslims
look bad.
Arif, l am not afraid.
- We gonna be on TV?
- l am.
But if you see a camera, you duck
out of sight, all right?
- Why?
- You don't remember Jack Eldridge?
- No.
- Well, l do.
He fucked us over, Cyril.
He fucked us real bad.
This might be
our chance to get even.
Go to sleep.
Hey, girl!
Prisoner number 01W7 11,
Omar White;
Convicted
January 4th, 2001 ;
Murder in the first degree.
Sentence: 75 years,
up for parole in 20.
Yo, that's what
l'm talking about.
Check out--
look at the poontang nooky.
This is Receiving
and Discharge,
where prisoners come in, where prisoners
go out, unless they're in a body bag.
- Okay, so which one is Omar White?
- White, Omar!
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, come here.
l'm Officer Murphy.
This camera crew has been authorized
to follow you on your first day.
- You got a problem with that?
- Oh, like, l'm gonna be on TV?
- Yup.
- l ain't got no problem with that.
- What, you and me, baby?
- Easy, Omar.
Mr. White, you will be serving
75 years for murder.
- ls that correct?
- Look, l ain't even know the bitch.
l mean, why the fuck--
why would l shoot her?
Well, she was the prime witness
at your cousin's murder trial.
See, your mistake
was not killing that little girl, too.
You think?
Shit.
- l mean-- shit.
- Get back in line, you mutt.
Who the fuck
are you calling mutt, huh?
Jake Willard,
escort Mr. White back in line!
Get out of my face!
Hey, hey!
See what l'm saying?
l'm gettin' hosed up in here!
Get your hands off me, motherfucker!
Y'all don't know
who you're fucking with.
So, 500 prisoners
arrive each week?
- Uh-huh.
- And how many are released?
Not enough.
This is Emerald City,
also ''Em City,''
the experimental cell block
started by Tim McManus five years ago.
ln Em City, the prisoners are given
a lot more leeway than the rest of Oz.
Hey, baby,
how about a little head?
Hey, Hoyt, move along!
Jesus.
Okay, the first one
l want to talk with is Tobias Beecher.
Um, all right,
this way.
Okay, Mr. Beecher.
The way this works is that you and l
are just gonna talk
very informally, no pressure,
and based on our conversation,
we'll decide
if you get interviewed
by Jack Eldridge.
- So the camera's not on now?
- No, yeah, it's on.
- But we can turn it off if you want.
- l don't care.
Okay, you came to Oswald in 1997
as a result of a DUl
- vehicular manslaughter conviction.
- Uh-huh.
Prior to that you were
a successful lawyer
from a prominent family
with a wife and two children.
How has being in prison
changed you?
Well, describe some of your experiences
since coming to Oswald.
Describe?
Hmm...
ever read
''The Book of Job''?
According to the file, at one point
your had your arms and legs broken
- and in another you were stabbed.
- Yeah.
You wanna see the scar?
You once tied a fellow inmate
down and defecated on his face.
- Yeah.
- ls that what it takes to survive?
l'm not the man l was.
Or maybe now l'm the man
l always was and never knew.
All these incidents
involved two other prisoners,
Christopher Keller
and Vernon Schillinger.
Tell me about your
relationship with them.
We sing
in the choir together.
What's going on?
Well, either he stole drugs
or he owes for drugs.
So there a lot
of drugs in Oswald?
Define ''a lot.''
Well, how many people in this unit
use heroin on a regular basis?
l don't know.
One in two, one in three,
one in 20?
l don't know.
Okay, how about sex?
- ls that an invitation?
- Sh-- right.
So, a lot
of homosexual activity?
Well, by homosexual,
do you mean deep-rooted love
of one man for another
or guys fucking guys
in the ass?
- Ass-fucking.
- Shit happens.
- And the authorities?
- Frown on it,
But they do
their darnedest to stop it.
- As they do on the drug taking.
- Yes.
- And have you?
- What?
Fucked a guy up the ass?
Gotten fucked?
Well, if l had,
why would l say so to you?
- Tobias Beecher.
- What about him?
l don't know, you tell me.
We sing
in the choir together.
That camera's making me so nervous,
l can't even shuffle.
Give me the cards.
Do l look okay?
You look like you.
Oh, shit.
When l was on TV
after l escaped,
l couldn't believe how bad l looked.
My skin was gray.
Gentlemen, l'm looking for some
background information
on a Tobias Beecher's relationship
with Vernon Schillinger--
Get the fuck away from me!
Okay, relax, Busmalis.
Come on, let's talk to somebody else.
- Come on, come on, come on.
- We'll go over there.
That's nice.
Now all of America's
gonna see you acting like an asshole.
What do you want?
That news bitch was asking
an awful lot of questions.
What did you tell her about me?
Get the fuck
out of here.
You tell her
anything about us,
you tell her anything
about anything--
And what, huh?
What are you
gonna do?
Shakedown!
Later.
- What up?
- Shut up, you asshole.
Get the fuck
outta here.
What do we have here?
Come on, Briggs,
l'm taking your ass to the hole.
l think
l take drugs because
l know
they're destructive.
l feel
unworthy of love.
- Oh, Christ, what a load of shit.
- Tobias.
No, well, look at him being all sincere
and cuddly because of them.
- Keller's nothing but a poseur.
- Shut the fuck up, Beecher.
Shut up, Beecher.
You're spoiling this for everybody.
Oh, yeah, O'Reily? Oh, right, you
and Keller are butt-buddies now.
Let me see, when did
that happen? When who died?
- What you fuckin' sayin', huh?!
- That's enough now, stop it!
Turn that camera off.
Turn it off right now.
Now! Turn that light off.
Off!
Tobias Beecher
and Christopher Keller.
- What about them?
- There's a lot of bad blood.
There's a lot
of spilled blood.
Why?
The men in Oz
are very distressed--
mentally, physically
and morally.
Christopher Keller, for example,
is a sexual predator.
So does that factor into
his problems with Beecher?
You know, l'm really
not comfortable
specifically talking
about these cases.
Okay.
Have you ever
been harassed?
Have you ever been sexually threatened
by one of the inmates?
No.
Hey, what are we gonna
do about Beecher?
- Do?
- You heard the guy in rehab.
The fucker almost goes public about us
killing Shemin and Browne?
He's playing around.
He would never spill all the beans.
Are you're sure of this?
Just his way of saying
that he still loves me.
You know, the two of you
are just so fucked up, man.
Whoa. Don't you hurt
Beecher, O'Reily.
lf you hurt Beecher,
l'm gonna have to hurt you.
Don't make any threats, K-Boy.
Might put me in a bad fucking mood.
Vern, check her out.
- She's not my type.
- Your type?
She's got a pussy,
ain't she?
Yeah, and like you're gonna
get anywhere near her pussy.
Unit B is your typical
cell block.
- How many units are built like this?
- Uh, 10.
- Hey, Vern, you're up.
- Him? What about me?
l give good story.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Maybe later.
- All right, this way, come on.
So, you're
a white supremacist?
You people
in the media,
you love to label us.
l know no matter what
l say here,
you're gonna trim it
and make me look like a monster.
But, l'm no monster.
l'm a widower
whose first son
died tragically.
l'm gonna
be a grandpa.
l believe in family...
ln America...
ln God.
- Does that sound evil to you?
- Now your other son,
Hank,
has been accused of kidnapping
Tobias Beecher's children
and of murdering
his son Gary.
The FBl believes
you orchestrated the crime.
That sounds
pretty evil to me.
Lady, you don't want
to be having opinions
about things that you could not
possibly understand.
Oh, if l didn't know you were such
a fine, upstanding citizen,
l might consider
that a threat.
Yo, l got something to say.
Schillinger's a pussy.
Hey, sit down.
Shut your face, nigger.
Hey, stop filming!
Keep shooting!
- Keep shooting!
- Move it, move it!
Move it, that's it.
So this Beecher story,
you think it has legs?
Oh, yeah. Usually the less
people are willing to say,
the better the story.
l just gotta figure a way in.
Each prisoner is assigned
a number and photograph
and then they're sent
to their respective units.
- And White's going to Em City, right?
- Yeah, God help us.
Here you go,
home sweet home.
Come on, let's go.
Yo.
What, you crippled
or something?
No, l'm physically challenged.
- Well, you got any tits?
- No.
l don't do drugs no more.
- Well, you ain't no faggot or nothing?
- No!
Thank God for that.
Can't stand
no motherfucking faggots.
Drive me crazy.
- So, what now?
- lt's nighty-night.
Lights out!
- Hey.
- The Fourth Estate is gone?
- Yeah, for today.
- Any problems?
Well, we had a minor skirmish
in Em City and a major battle in Unit B.
- They get everything on tape?
- Oh, yeah.
- Did our guys respond?
- Both incidences over in a flash.
You know, l don't care if the prisoners
look bad, l just don't want us to.
Well, she seems to be
mostly focusing on Beecher.
- His is a cautionary tale.
- Let's hope Logan doesn't dig too deep.
l wouldn't want her
uncovering any skeletons.
You mean Adebisi?
Among others.
Television is a medium
rarely well done.
My Uncle Bilbo
said that.
Okay, somebody
said it first,
but my Uncle Bilbo
was the first one to say it to me.
Now, don't get me wrong,
l love watching the news on TV--
Dan and Tom and Peter
and maybe a little Jim Lehrer
if l'm feeling brainy.
l flip back and forth
between news shows
in hopes of catching
the same story,
'cause each news show tells a story
in a different way.
ABC leaves out a fact
that CBS makes a big deal of.
CBS interviews its expert
who totally disagrees
with NBC's expert.
NBC goes in depth,
while ABC gives the same story
five seconds air-time.
You see, l figure if l catch
all three versions,
maybe combined, l get a little
taste of the truth.
Count!
88P728;
96J522;
98A498;
92M220.
Yo, yo, dog.
Dog, l need your help.
C'mon, man.
You know me, man.
Why you wanna do me
like that, dawg?
Omar, my man.
Jesus Christ, you're looking
a little crispy there, brother.
- l gotta get some tits.
- Wow.
You know, times are lean
right now. The hacks,
they're doing too good a job
keeping that shit out of Oz.
Trick is you gotta
know the right person.
You have
a good day.
Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo.
Look, l been
to every nigger up in here.
Look, they think
l'm a nark, man.
- Motherfucker, they don't know me.
- Hey, shh.
Abracadabra.
Now what you want
in exchange for this?
l ain't gonna suck your dick
or nothing like that.
Hey, l'm no
fucking fag.
l just might need you to take care
of a little business for me.
- That's all.
- l got no problem with that.
Knock yourself out.
Hypocrisy.
Hyp-ocrisy.
That's what this is.
They strip me
of my clothes, of my rights,
they strip me
of my self-respect.
All 'cause they say l broke the rules--
trafficking in illegals.
But they-- they more guilty
than l could ever be.
Fucking uppity-ups.
See, they don't want
us in there.
Adebisi singing, snorting, suck.
And when his blood ran out,
when his blood got spilled,
the truth ran out,
and the wall of lies
got built.
After Said greased him, fucking hacks
act like he ain't never breathed in.
And the lies got buried
with his number.
- You saying there was a cover-up?
- Yeah.
Sheets and blankets-- enough to cover
up all them high and mighties.
- The warden, too?
- The warden more than most!
- All right, come on, that's enough.
- You see?
They're still trying
to shush me.
- You got any evidence to back this up?
- Yeah.
Yeah, there's a videotape.
Adebisi, he documented it,
just like you're doing right here.
You know what l'm saying?
Right up until the fade.
You ask O'Reily,
you ask said, you ask--
- All right, shut up. Come on, let's go.
- He's got something to say.
He's always got something to say.
Come on, let's go.
- Hypocrisy!
- Yeah, okay.
- Conspiracy!
- Right.
Take a nap.
Jack...
l found our story.
l'm not sure about
all the details yet,
But something happened
surrounding the death of an inmate.
Yeah, and evidently
it's on videotape.
Well, the sooner
you get here, the better.
Officer Murphy--
You ready?
You're gonna love death row.
Yeah, rather than do that,
l wanna go back and interview
a couple of prisoners again.
Okay.
- And l'd like to do so in private.
- Private?
- Without you present.
- That's not gonna happen.
Don't worry,
l'll get permission.
She asked to see Said and O'Reily again?
What's she want with them?
Murphy thinks it might have
to do with Adebisi's death.
- But O'Reily wasn't involved with that.
- l know.
- l miss Mama.
- So do l.
Why'd she have
to die, Ryan?
l told you a thousand times,
Cyril, the cancer ate her up.
Hey, Miss Sally's on TV.
Why don't you
go watch, okay?
Please?
- All right.
- Okay.
How's it going, cuz?
- l need some more tits.
- Whoa.
l ain't got
a never-ending supply, you know?
Just a little bit, just till l feel
a little better, you know?
You know, it's too bad
you got here when you did.
Six months ago, we had tits coming out
of our fucking asses.
When this guy Adebisi
ran the operation,
- the well never ran dry.
- What happened to him?
He got shanked.
But that's not the point.
When he died,
the spicks and the wops,
they took over everything.
And between you,
me, and this sink,
they're doing
a half-assed job.
- How come brothers don't organize?
- They should.
They need a leader. l mean, right now
all they got is this fool, Poet.
- He's a complete come-stain.
- l know, l used to run my block.
Well, there you go.
Maybe you should step up,
- Huh?
- Yeah.
Come here.
- Have some.
- Shit yeah.
You see, to get anybody's
attention around this place,
- you gotta do something large.
- Large?
Yeah, like Adebisi.
He was large and in charge,
bigger than life,
feared by one and all.
Yeah, well, that's what l want.
l want 'em to fear me.
Then you gotta
kill somebody,
but not just anybody.
You gotta go huge...
monumental.
Somebody...
- famous?
- Like who?
All right, who's next?
Come on through, lady.
Step over here,
open your purse. Next!
Put all metal objects
in there. And you're visiting?
Peter Thorpe.
Go through again.
And your name is?
- Helen Keating.
- And the watch.
Christ, what do you think l'm trying
to smuggle in, a fucking bazooka?
Oh, officer,
can you, please...
Ah, Tom.
Listen, he's okay. Let him in.
Oh, why didn't you say?
l'm a big fan.
Yeah. Oy, oy!
Wake up.
- Jack?
- Yeah?
- This is Ryan O'Reily.
- Uh-huh.
- Jack Eldridge.
- Oh, how do you do?
Hi. You don't
remember me,
- do you?
- No, l'm afraid not. Have we met?
- About 20 years ago.
- Oh, well, you'd understand then.
Yeah, you must meet so many people
in this job, right?
- What were the circumstances?
- lt's not important.
- Oh.
- Okay, Ryan. Comfortable?
Ah, yes.
And we are... rolling.
Where were you
when Adebisi died?
The common room.
Any inkling as to what
was gonna happen to him?
No, no. As far
as l could see, Said and Adebisi,
they were
getting along just fine.
Okay, so walk me
through this.
- You were in the common room...
- Doing nothing.
And?
l heard this noise
from Adebisi's pod...
and he had these white curtains
hanging up in the room, and, poof...
it just went red with blood everywhere,
splattered. And then Adebisi,
He falls out of the pod,
down on the ground, dead.
And Said follows out
with the shank
still in his hand.
- Have any idea what led to the fight?
- No.
All right.
You told me there were curtains on
the windows of Adebisi's pod.
- ls that unusual?
- Yes.
- Was Adebisi privileged?
- Privileged?
Was he allowed to get away with things
the rest of you weren't?
Hold on for a second.
Excuse me.
Wanna kill
these things?
Sure. Dell, guys, cut.
What's the problem?
You want this knowledge,
you're gonna have to pay.
We don't pay informants.
- Then l'm not saying another word.
- Ryan, in the prescreen you said
- you would tell everything you know.
- Look, it's gonna cost me.
The warden's gonna be up my ass
like one of them proctoscopes.
All l'm looking for here
is a little compensation.
No! Get the fuck out.
Suit yourself, Mr. Eldridge.
Pleasure to see you again.
You bastard.
Find out where the fuck l know him from.
- How am l gonna do that?
- Well, use your head!
l certainly didn't meet O'Reily at
a cocktail party on the Upper East Side.
20 years ago, l bet l did
a story on him. Track it down!
Commendable work, love.
Nice fucking interview.
A pleasure
meeting you finally.
- l've admired you for years.
- Thank you.
The feeling
is mutual.
l've read
both your books.
Well, actually
there are three.
l've always felt
that your conviction
was politically motivated.
Gentlemen?
We're ready if you are.
Well, just relax,
speak your mind.
Minister Said,
you murdered Simon Adebisi.
No, l, um--
defended myself.
He attacked me
with a knife.
Why?
Why did he attack you?
l was under the impression
that we were gonna talk about
the conditions in Oz.
Well, isn't this one of the conditions?
Brutality, senseless violence?
Was his attack
on you unmotivated?
No.
So you said something to him,
you did something to him.
l'm a Muslim. l did not agree
with some of the ways
that Adebisi
was conducting himself.
Then why did you ask
to move into Adebisi's pod?
You see,
l have here a form
signed by you,
requesting the change.
lf you hated
Adebisi so much--
- l didn't say l hated him.
- Then why live with such an animal?
l was trying
to save him.
And yet instead
you killed him.
What about the videotape
documenting Adebisi's conduct?
You know, right now
l would like
to move past this
particular conversation
and speak about
the larger issues.
Do you deny that
there's a videotape?
Every day we suffer
fundamental
civil rights abuses.
The tape, sir,
yes or no?
l am done
talking with you.
Minister, we are only
trying to get the facts.
That part of
the story is over.
Don't you understand?
Adebisi is dead.
Adebisi is irrelevant.
Nothing that brings about
the death of a man is irrelevant.
You want us to hear
what you have to say, fine.
You have to tell us
what we need to know first.
And then which part
will be aired?
They're definitely working
the angle on Adebisi.
His death?
Nope, what went on
before that.
Poet told them about the videotapes
that Adebisi made.
Christ.
Yeah, and they're trying
to verify that the tapes exist.
- Maybe we should pull the plug.
- l can't do that.
l spoke to both
the commissioner and the governor
And they feel if we back out now,
it'll only look worse.
And since l never told either of them
about the videotapes--
Well, l sure as hell
can't tell them now.
Well, you may
have to, Leo.
The truth may
have to come out.
- Hey.
So, you got
information for me?
l can't go on camera
and say the things that need to be said.
Why not?
Because it'll be the end
of Leo's career
and the Governor will
have enough ammunition
to close down
Emerald City permanently.
Okay.
So, then what would you
be willing to say?
On camera, nothing.
But as deep background...
the guy you want to go
after is Martin Querns.
He ran Emerald City
after you.
And what about
that videotape?
Have you seen it?
Has Glynn?
Come on. Talk to me.
What you're asking me
to do is betray a friend.
Friend?
He fired you.
With good reason.
And he gave me
back Em City.
Like l said,
go after Querns.
Leo, what the fuck
is going on?
l get a call asking me
if l'm willing
To be interviewed by
Jack fucking Eldridge?
They found out what went on in Em City
when you were in charge.
-They heard about the videotapes.
- Fuck.
When you asked me to resign, you said no
one would ever know the reason,
that we were gonna keep it internal so
that neither one of us would get hurt.
Refuse to do
the interview. l did.
Fine.
Where are
the videotapes?
ln a safe place.
What are you keeping them around for?
Destroy the tapes, Leo.
Destroy the goddamn
motherfucking tapes now!
Warden.
Mr. Eldridge.
So, l understand you've canceled
our interview.
- That's right.
- May l ask why?
You can ask.
l won't answer.
Come on,
off the record,
between two guys
holding their dicks.
When l was thinking of running
for Lieutenant Governor,
l spent too much time
in front of the camera.
Between you and me,
off the record,
that's bullshit.
- You've spent how many years at Oswald?
- Too many.
Yet it would bother you
to leave, right?
To quit?
To be forced out
because of some indiscretion?
Because some mishandling
of the job was exposed on TV?
l've spent my entire life
punishing people,
and over the years,
l've had to make choices.
Some were good
and some led to violence.
Lives have been lost
and l...
l wonder, could l have
stopped the carnage?
Simon Adebisi,
could you have
prevented his death?
Yes.
Balls-on truth,
l should be fired.
But l'm afraid
whoever they bring in
to replace me would
only be worse.
lt's a terrible thing
to reach this point
and realize your whole life
has been a sham.
So for a man whose job
is meant to punish others,
you ultimately punish yourself
more than anyone.
Off the record?
Yes.
No comment.
Lisa.
What?
- The Adebisi story, it's a dead end.
- What? Jack, no.
My instincts tell me that no one is
gonna come forward with the facts.
We've faced tougher resistance than this
before. l can get McManus to crack.
Some people do things for malicious
reasons. This prison is full of them.
l don't think Leo Glynn is one. He's
imperfect, but he's not incompetent.
That is no reason not
to expose what happened here.
- A man died.
- Yeah, from all appearances, a bad man.
You're making judgments now?
What, he isn't as important as the Pope?
Don't get high and mighty with me.
l've brought presidents,
serial killers,
corporate giants to their knees.
- And now's not the time to go soft.
- l'm going home.
Big day tomorrow.
You're making a mistake, Jack.
Letting this story go is a mistake!
Yeah, probably, but you know,
every once in a while,
even a newsman
has to have a heart.
Hey, can l have your
autograph, Mr. Brokaw?
What a dick.
Journalists are supposed
to be impartial.
They're supposed to keep their
personal opinions to themselves.
However, on TV, we know
what the reporter is feeling.
We see Sam Donaldson
or Andrea Mitchell
giving us the facts,
but with the camera
that close up,
we can also tell
by a raised eyebrow,
a tiny inflection,
what they really think
about the person
who they're
reporting on.
Now, Walter Cronkite,
he had the poker face.
Nobody ever knew what
old Walt was thinking.
So while he was
telling the truth,
he was also lying
to the camera.
That's genius!
Yo, yo, yo, O'Reily,
O'Reily, my man.
Yo. l forgot
to thank you, man,
for getting me put down
in this cafeteria. This shit is dope.
Oh, hey, no problem, cuz.
Hey, come here.
l got a little
something for you.
Hey, little morning
pick-me-up.
We call it
''the duster.'' Yeah.
So, Omar, l hear
you're the lucky fuck
who's gonna spend the night
in the cell with Jack Eldridge.
l'm gonna be a TV star,
shit, like... Martin Lawrence
or Bart Simpson and shit.
This shit is good, man.
Have some more.
You know, l just hope
he doesn't disrespect you,
that's all.
Dis me?
How he gonna dis me?
Well, l overheard him
telling somebody yesterday
- that you were a faggot.
- Yeah?
Yeah, that's what
he said.
- Faggot?
- Yeah.
- l ain't no motherfucking faggot!
- Omar, Omar, Omar, hey!
l know that,
but you know
them news media cocks,
they love
to twist shit around.
You know, they don't
give a fuck about the truth.
They make a guy look the way
they want him to look
for the sake of their story,
to boost the ratings.
Ratings?
Fuck the motherfucking ratings.
This motherfucker ain't calling me
no faggot!
But the funny thing is, is the tabloids
say that Eldridge is actually a faggot.
l heard that somewhere,
l know.
He's like one of them
closet cases, you know?
But to cover up
his shame,
he's gonna skunk you
on national television.
No.
- Hey, O'Reily.
- Huh?
- Those eggs ain't gonna fry themselves.
- l'm coming.
- Okay, let's go, man.
- l know, l'm coming.
Hey, if l were you,
tonight when l was alone
with that cocksucker,
l'd teach him a thing or two
about being a real man. Enjoy that.
- Hello, hello.
- Mr. Eldridge.
Hello, Lisa.
Jack.
What did you find out
about Ryan O'Reily?
When he was 16, you did
a piece on urban gangs,
about how the black kids were taking
over the turf of the whites,
- especially the lrish.
- l interviewed O'Reily?
Yeah, and his brother Cyril.
Here are
the transcripts.
Lisa.
l don't have time
to read that.
Did Jack make
O'Reily look bad?
l reviewed the tape
last night and yeah,
the O'Reilys came off
as being brutal, heartless.
l want to
see that tape.
Let's go,
come on in.
Watch the paint.
At 5:00, all the prisoners are locked
down in their cells. 9:00, lights out.
- Until?
- 6:00 am.
Oh, Mamacita.
Keep it in your pants, Guerra.
Let's go, keep a-moving.
Jesus.
There he is.
There's the fuck.
- Omar, just chill out till tonight.
- No, the bitch is mine.
Hey, Omar!
- Wait, wait, wait, wait.
- Get the fuck off me.
Hey, hey, hey!
Hey, you!
You fuck.
- You fuck.
- What's your problem, White?
- l got your punk for you, all right?
- White, what's your problem?
What's my problem?
He's my problem!
l got another problem,
too, all right?
This! This is
my fucking problem!
- Hey, hey, hey, relax, man.
- Calm down, White. Let's go.
Fuck!
He's got a knife.
Central, this is 11,
we got a 66. Lockdown!
Mineo, you Guinea fuck,
you want some more?
Put down the shank!
Come on, you fucking bitch!
Come on, l'll fuck you up!
Motherfuckers!
Motherfuckers!!
God damn it.
This is exactly why l didn't want you
here in the first place.
l think at the very least
you ought to postpone.
No, by postpone, you mean
never reschedule.
Our concern is for
your safety, Mr. Eldridge.
l've been at this game
a long time. l can take care of myself.
So we're gonna go ahead with it tonight?
You're gonna sleep in a cell?
Yes, but now we have to find someone
else to match up with Jack.
Well, we could put you
in a cell alone.
Ted Koppel did that on ''Nightline.''
lt was horseshit.
Then who?
l've been reading the files
on the O'Reily brothers.
The younger one, Cyril,
he's now brain damaged
and under medication
to control his actions.
l choose him.
l don't want my brother
involved with this, okay? l refuse.
O'Reily, we don't
have a choice.
Let's just try to make it through
the night and pray for the best.
You know what? You pray.
Say a whole fucking rosary.
You tested the camera?
- Twice. We're good to go.
- All right.
- Lock me up.
- Wish you'd let the SORT team be here.
No, l want this to be like
any other typical night.
Here we go.
Hello, Cyril.
l'm Jack Eldridge.
Hello.
Jack, you ready?
You're on.
lt's 5:00 pm
and already--
lt's only 5:00 pm,
but the prisoners
of Emerald City are already
in lockdown for the night,
two to a cell with nothing,
but a pair of beds,
a sink,
and a toilet.
The room is about the size
of the average American bathroom
and it smells
like one as well.
lmagine, if you can,
spending the rest of your life
locked up with a complete
stranger in your bathroom.
Who you talking to?
Well, that camera,
which l want you to ignore.
So, this evening, here we
at Oswald Penitentiary.
Jack, you gotta move to your left.
You're blocking him. That's good.
- What do you do before lights out?
- Wait.
- For what?
- The lights to go out.
Um... here.
And then?
Um...
l say my prayers
and sleep.
And what
do you pray for?
Oh, l pray to Jesus
that Ryan will be safe
and Aunt Brenda,
and my daddy
will smile
and they'll take care
of my mama in heaven.
Your mother died?
Years ago in
the hospital.
l hate hospitals.
l hate the smell
of hospitals.
- And the medicine tastes bad.
- Yeah.
Ryan tells me to
take my medicine,
but l don't sometimes,
like today.
What about, uh,
before the accident?
Do you remember
anything about that?
There are flashes
once in a while...
like now...
l see you...
and l think
maybe l know you.
We met many years ago.
You were 15.
You, your brother and l, we talked
about your lives in the gang.
You made Mama sad.
You made Mama cry.
You gave
my Mama cancer.
Holy shit!
Central, this is 11.
We got a 66.
Ryan said at the grave
that you gave my mother cancer.
No!
Cyril!
You gave my mama cancer!
You gave
my mama cancer!
Cyril!
Cyril!!
Mama!
Ryan!
Cyril!
Jack! Jack! Jack!
- Oh, Jack!
- Did you-- Lisa, did you--
- What? Did l what?
- Did you get it all on tape?
Television has the power
to enlighten, to inform,
to lay the bare truth
before the eyes of the public.
Television is an
extraordinary gift,
as much a miracle
from God as Lazarus
rising from the dead.
But do we use
the gift wisely?
Have we ever?
News anchor Jack Eldridge
became a part of his own story yesterday
as what many industry insiders called
a ratings stunt backfired.
Convicted murderer
Cyril O'Reily
brutally beat Eldridge,
causing the veteran reporter
to suffer a severe concussion,
four broken ribs and a punctured lung.
He remains at Benchley Memorial
in critical condition.
Despite the objections
of Eldridge's producer, Lisa Logan,
the network has decided
not to air what was intended
to be a three-part series
on life inside
Oswald's Maximum
Security Prison.
The Emmy and Peabody
Award-winning Logan
resigned in protest.
We all wish Jack
a speedy recovery.