Back in the old Greek times
there lived a man
named Orpheus.
Loved his wife.
Took it easy on the ouzo.
Played a mean guitar.
Upstanding guy.
So what did
the almighty gods do?
They fucked with him,
made his life Hades.
Why? Because that's what
those in power do
to those of us with none.
The time for action
has arrived.
Tug, you waste Pancamo.
We don't like Burr Redding
any more than you.
You want him dead,
we want him dead.
l want Morales.
l was in the hospital
10 days.
l'd like to think that's when this
little brouhaha began,
but l have an inkling
it's been brewing a lot longer.
At any rate, we narrowly missed
a major war with significant carnage.
The question then becomes:
what happens now?
Now l'm gonna give
you gentlemen a couple of options.
l could stick you both
in that cage
where you can maul
each other
until one of you's dead
and the other on death row.
l could transfer you both
to different units,
where you could still kill each other,
but not on my watch.
Or we can come
to some kind of truce.
What do you say?
Peace.
lt's a beautiful thing.
Yeah. Shake hands
where everybody can see you.
Burr. Burr. Burr.
- You keep away from me.
- Wait a minute, man.
l know it was you
who tipped off them hacks.
You betrayed me.
Me, who raised you
like you was my own.
lf you was anybody else
you would be dead now.
But l'm gonna let you live.
Live with the shame
of what you done.
Only you and me is through.
Whoa.
Step back, Chinaman.
Don't push your luck
with me, Guerra.
And just 'cause you
and Redding made nice-nice
doesn't mean l'm not gonna whack
your taco-eating ass.
l said step back.
Jesus, man!
You're not out of the pod
10 minutes,
you're already causing trouble.
ln the fucking cage.
Supreme Allah.
l heard you were dead.
Now that's funny.
l heard the same thing
about you.
Guess you can't believe
rumors.
Like the one that says you fools
signed a treaty with Burr Redding.
- What would you have done?
- Tell you what l will do.
That nigger's going down.
We've been trying to airhole
that motherfucker since he got here.
No success.
Besides, if he dies now,
the hacks will be after us.
Not if he gets greased
by one of his own.
Who have you got
in mind?
Him.
Augustus,
how come you ain't chowing
with your old pal Redding?
Take a fucking walk,
Ketchup.
You know Omar White?
He tried to kill me.
Tug Daniels,
he tried too.
But l'm still
on my hind legs.
Now that you're on the outs
with old Burr,
you need a friend.
Yeah, well that ain't you,
nigger.
Look, l want to make right
what l done to you,
putting you in this chair,
putting you in Oz.
So remember,
from now on
l got your back covered.
Redding, meet your new cell-mate,
the colonel.
l don't want a cell-mate.
Your reservation for the single suite
must have got screwed up.
What the hell is McManus
thinking anyway,
putting me and you
in here together?
l don't know.
Why did he call you
the colonel?
Because that's what l am.
You're a marine.
Affirmative.
l was in the army myself,
4th armored cav,
1st infantry division,
Vietnam.
l was in Vietnam,
3rd battalion,
4th marines.
McManus might not be
as stupid as l thought he was.
Make yourself at home.
Colonel,
l just might have
a little mission for you.
A search and destroy.
Physically Omar White's
fully recovered.
l was planning to send
him back to solitary today.
- Pete, you had a session with him?
- Yeah.
He's a volatile young man,
but much of that is fueled by drugs.
So if we can keep
Omar White clean, then he's salvageable?
- Tim, what are you--
- l'm bringing him back to Em City.
Tim, he stabbed you.
That's all the more reason
for me to be the one to make the effort.
Hello, Omar.
Look, man, l-l'm sorry
for shanking you.
- l just don't know what comes over me.
- l forgive you.
You do?
How'd you like to come back
to Em City?
lnstead of solitary?
You don't have
to ask me twice, you know.
Well, l can make
that happen,
but we gotta go over
some ground rules.
Yo, man, so how you
get out of solitary?
McManus.
He forgave me.
- That motherfucker's on crack.
- Who you telling?
So Orpheus' wife's
strolling along,
gets bitten by a snake
and dies.
Orpheus freaks out
and heads down into the underworld
to demand that his lady
be returned.
Then some goddess says,
''Okay, on one condition.
lf you look at her before you get back
to Earth, she'll disappear.''
With, like, 10 feet to go,
motherfucker turns around,
and wifey's sent right back
to hell.
Orpheus should have
known better.
You don't fuck
with the gods.
That's what l told him,
Shirl, but you know how men are.
Yeah, about...
What, you want
something there, kid?
What kind of name
is Yood?
What do you mean, what kind of name?
lt's a last name.
- Jesus.
- Let's deal.
l meant, what kind
of nationality is Yood, you dumb ass!
- lt's American.
- There are no American names, dumb ass.
- Quit calling me that.
- Because there are no Americans.
Oh, here we go again.
We're all from someplace else
originally.
My name is American.
Your name is dumb ass!
Officer Howell.
- What?
- Do your job.
l'll call you back.
Clayton, are you starting shit again?
l'm just making
conversation.
Well, shut your trap!
Basil, you taking
Yood's side against mine?
Yeah, why shouldn't l?
'Cause of what he is
and what we are.
What you are
is a fuck wad.
Oh, Johnny.
God, l missed you so much.
l didn't know how much
till now.
Shh. Don't cry.
Let's sit down.
l want you
to come home.
- Sweetheart, come home.
- You know l can't.
As much as l want to,
not for at least three years.
- l won't make it three years.
- Yes, you will.
You'll have to.
For Robby's sake.
And for mine.
You being there waiting is the only
thing that keeps me whole, Abby.
And someday you, me and Robby,
we're gonna be together again.
And we're gonna laugh.
And we're gonna forget,
okay?
Next week l want you
to bring Robby.
l'm finally ready
to face my boy.
- Basil.
- Yeah?
Your son, you think he's gonna be okay
growing up without a father?
What?
Now who's the fuck wad?
You crazy son of a bitch!
What the hell is going on?
Open this fucking door now!
Open the door now,
you sons of bitches!
Open the fucking door!
l'm heading home.
l'll walk out with you.
- Ooh, l'll get that.
- Leave it.
- The stain might mess up--
- Leave it alone!
l want the broken glass
there in the morning
to remind me
of how drunk l am.
You can't drive
in this condition.
What's the worst
that could happen?
Wrap myself
around a tree?
l'll call you
a cab.
- No.
- Then l'll drive you myself.
John Basil and l had
a lot in common.
Good intentions
that turned to shit.
He warned me about Clayton.
l did nothing,
'cause there was nothing
l could do.
Come on.
Let me take you home.
Well, l just love snow
before Christmas,
and l could tolerate it
in January,
but come February,
snow is redundant.
Well, good morning
to you, too.
l'm sorry.
Good morning, Sister.
What's the matter?
l miss Keller.
We can't call each other,
and if he's written me back,
one of the Nazis in the mailroom
probably destroyed his letters.
Or maybe he hasn't written.
Maybe he's already found somebody else.
Maybe he's dead.
l'll contact the head of psychiatry
at Cedar Junction
and find out how
Keller's doing.
l'll even try to arrange a phone
conversation between you two.
Well, that would
be great, Sister.
Because since he's
been gone l just--
l feel like, um--
l don't know, not dead,
not empty.
You know, Tobias,
you have a lot to be happy about.
Your daughter's finally beginning
to respond normally,
Katherine McClain is setting up
your parole hearing.
That's part of all this weirdness
inside me.
lf l get out,
who will l be?
So l've walked Steve Dawkins
through your case.
l have to say,
l'm guardedly optimistic.
You actually think there's a chance
the parole board might let me out?
Yes.
Yes, l do.
Oh my God.
Katherine, that--
l can't thank you enough.
Don't thank me until
you're on the other side of the wall.
Okay, but if l do go free
l'm gonna take you out to dinner.
Nicest restaurant
in the city, Dom, everything.
Hmm.
l'd like that.
Are you married?
- l'm--
- You know what?
You don't have
to answer that.
What am l thinking,
asking you personal questions?
- You're my lawyer, for Christ's sake.
- Stop.
lt's okay. l know every detail
of your personal life,
why shouldn't you
know something about mine?
l'm divorced.
Any kids?
One. A son.
He's eight.
That's the same age
as Holly.
- l know.
- Oh, yeah.
Right.
Party's over.
Let's go.
That's the problem
here in Oz.
You never get to finish
a conversation.
We're far from finished,
Tobias.
Okay, here he is.
- Hello?
- Chris? This is Sister Pete.
- l'm with Tobias
- Hey.
- Warden Glynn and the fellow
who runs Cedar Junction have agreed
to this phone call on the condition
that l stay in the room here
and that someone stay
with you there.
So l-l'm afraid that this
won't be as, um,
intimate as you might like.
Thanks, Sister.
Toby, how are you?
Better now. You?
Hey, me,
you know,
making new friends,
surveying the lay of the land.
Chris, l might be
getting paroled.
- No shit.
- Yeah.
Maybe as soon
as a couple weeks.
l thought if l do, l'm gonna make
the trip up to Massachusetts.
Hey, Toby, don't.
lf you are lucky
enough to get out,
l want you to turn your back
on this shit and run.
You understand?
You gotta fucking run for your life.
- You giving me an order?
- No.
Man, l'm on my knees and l'm begging
you, stay away from me.
- l'm hanging up now.
- Chris.
Thank you.
Here we are.
Let me hold her.
l never got the chance
to hold her when she was born.
- You got it?
- Yeah, l got her.
Okay, say hello
to grandpa, Jewel.
You named her Jewel?
Well, she is one,
isn't she?
And Hank loved
''You Were Meant for Me.''
Jewel Schillinger.
Jewel.
Yeah, Vern,
she's real cute.
Her name's Jewel.
Jewel?
Sure as hell hope the other kids
don't nickname her Jew.
Yo, you Salinger?
Schillinger.
All right.
l knew your son Hank.
- You knew my son?
- l heard you're a fucking pimp.
And proud of it.
My girls are the finest
on the strip.
- And my son?
- Short on some cash,
wanted to rent out
his girlfriend.
- All right, look--
- Casey, Carrie, something like that.
- Cute little blonde.
- You fucking liar!
Wait a minute, chief.
l don't want no trouble.
But, fuck, l thought you knew Hank
pimped that bitch.
Even a couple
of the brothers hit it.
l'm surprised
that baby ain't come out golden brown.
There is the possibility
that Curtis Bennett is lying.
Well, how do l find out
the truth?
Have you discussed
this with Carrie?
No, l can't see her again until
l get visiting privileges next week.
She has been talking
to Sarah over at my church.
l'll ask Sarah if the girl
said anything about her past.
ln the meantime,
be patient.
Patient!
Reverend, this thing is gonna
gnaw on me non-stop.
l need to know if this baby
is really my grandchild,
really my blood.
Why are you still
talking to Cloutier?
l gotta find out if Bennett's telling
the truth about Carrie.
- And if the nigger's lying?
- Oh, he's dead.
l'll stick him myself,
right between his banjo eyes.
James Robson hired Leroy Tidd
to assassinate me,
but when Leroy
converted to lslam,
he became Salah Yudin.
Robson had to hire
Carl Jenkins to finish the job.
He died saving me.
And Jenkins is on trial
for the murder.
But not Robson.
There's only one person
that can corroborate your theory,
that's Jenkins.
He ain't gonna squeal on a fellow Nazi.
l know how to turn
Jenkins around.
You let me speak
to the boy.
No. You face to face
with Jenkins
will only set off another race war.
l pass.
Glynn, you just do
what you always do--
nothing.
May we speak alone?
What's on your mind?
l've been watching you.
l believe you
to be a man of God,
true to your faith.
That you believe
in justice.
l do.
Then l have a favor
to ask.
You here to kill me?
No.
To help.
To save your soul.
Jenkins gave you up.
He pinned Leroy Tidd's
murder on you.
What did you do,
beat a confession out of him?
You're going down,
Robson.
- lt's his word against mine.
- You're gonna fry.
lt's his motherfucking,
cocksucking word against mine!
Thanks, Vern.
Carl.
This is for you.
From your friends
in the Brotherhood.
ls there a problem?
You been a comfort to me,
Reverend.
So l'm gonna
let you live.
But don't you ever
meddle in the affairs
of the Brotherhood again.
- Vern--
- ''And l will pour out
mine indignation upon thee.
l will blow against thee
in the fire of my wrath
and deliver thee into the hand
of brutish men and skillful to
destroy.''
Hey, what's up,
half-dick ?
- Fucking mick!
- Hey, hey!
Get in there.
There you go,
Alvarez.
You stupid fuck.
Hey, Smith.
- Yeah?
- Jenkins don't look so hot, man.
What do you mean?
Oh.
Guess he won't be eating
his chicken nuggets.
Oh, shit!
Oh shit!
Phelan!
You get on your phone
in there and call pest control!
l'm sick of sharing my cell with Mickey
and the other rats.
Mickey is a mouse.
l'm serious,
God damn it!
Your shot's off.
- Nothing wrong with my shot.
- No, it's off.
- There's no follow-through.
- Give me the ball.
Watch. See?
That's follow-through.
Come to think of it, your jumpshot
was erratic before you got to Oz.
Erratic my ass.
See that last game l played?
Shit, l busted
the Bulls for 55.
Yeah, if l remember right,
your team lost that night.
Well, l had
no supporting cast.
lt seemed to me
you were being too selfish.
You and every other
come-to-the-game-
live-your-dreams-
through-me motherfuckers.
Hey, l played.
l didn't have your gifts,
but my teams won.
White boy city league?
Not exactly the NBA.
Hey, winning's winning.
You either know how to win
or you don't.
lt's just in a guy.
So you're saying
if you and l played, you'd beat me?
Under the right circumstances,
ball bounces the right way,
who knows?
No circumstances
are you beating me.
Shit, l'd spot you
nine in a game of 10,
l'd beat you 10-9
every time.
l could take
the sorriest motherfucker in this prison
and you take the best,
and l'd still clown your broke-down,
pushing-50 junkyard ass.
Well, let's do it.
- Do what?
- You take the worst inmate,
l'll find the best CO
play a little two-on-two.
You're serious.
- As l stand here.
- You're gonna be pissed if l say no.
- l say no.
- Yeah? Fuck you.
lf you think about it,
it's really fuck you.
Hey! Hey!
You say yes,
l'll bring you back to Em City.
Basketball tournament?
More of an exhibition match.
Best of three games.
- Here we go again.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- What if something goes wrong?
- Nothing's gonna go wrong.
That's what you said about the boxing
and Hamid Khan died.
Basketball isn't boxing.
l'm more concerned
with crowd control.
The gym won't accommodate the amount
of prisoners we had attend the fights.
We limit the numbers.
Make good behavior
the price of admission.
All right.
That's all.
l need a teammate.
You're looking
at the wrong guy.
Oh, come on, Leo.
You love basketball.
l love basketball, but l'm not about
to go against Jackson Vahue.
- Leo, together l think we could--
- No, Tim.
Find another sap.
This one is staying on the sidelines.
- Hey.
l need you to play
with me in the game against Vahue.
Thanks, but you know,
l don't think so.
Hey, you're my guy.
l need you.
Tim, look, l--
l really think you should
call this game off.
- What?
- This is bad for us, man.
l mean, it ain't just you
out there.
All of us hacks
are gonna take
a tremendous amount of shit
when you lose.
Who knows?
We might win.
You're not gonna win.
You're gonna get your ass kicked!
lf l can get the space
to get my shot off,
l can score.
And you used to be
All-State in high school.
That was 20 years ago,
and you just got out of the hospital!
- l'm not playing.
- Oh, fine!
- Go fuck yourself!
- Jesus, Tim.
You know, you can be such
an asshole sometimes.
What's the matter? Timmy can't find
anybody to throw the ball to?
Dave!
Hey, looks like
you're a player.
You're good.
Oh, yeah.
All right.
You're better than good.
- Did you play in college?
- JUCO.
Had two good years
at a school upstate.
You didn't go on
to a four-year program?
No, l did.
University of lowa.
But l had to drop out.
Ah, grades?
Yeah?
Got caught scalping my player comps
to football games.
Any minnie moo bullshit
l could think of.
Upside was l was never charged
for any of it.
Yeah, but the school was still forced
to run you off, huh?
Yeah. l guess
in my heart of hearts
l knew l wouldn't have
lasted there anyway.
Listen, uh,
l challenged Jackson Vahue
to some two-on-two.
- l heard.
- So you want to be my running mate?
- Go head to head with Vahue?
- Yeah.
That'd be a dream.
You wanted to see me?
- Busmalis, come in.
- Sit?
- Stand. You play basketball?
- No.
- How about when you were younger?
- Any sports at all?
- Nah.
l was the guy
with the towel.
Go introduce yourself
to Jackson Vahue.
You're his new teammate.
As you all know, this is the best
of a three-game series,
and due to the fact
that our court is
smaller than regulation size,
the games will run full court.
We'll set the clock,
20 minutes.
Each team will be given
one time-out,
and the three-point line
is in effect.
All right,
let's hoop it up.
Air ball! Air ball!
Vahue! Vahue! Vahue!
?? Na na na na
na na na na ??
?? Hey, hey, hey,
good bye... ??
The court has set
next Thursday
as the date
of your execution.
Have you decided
how you want to die?
l'm not like
my buddy Giles over there.
l'm not going for anything flashy
like being stoned to death.
Lethal injection will suit me
just fine, sir
- Good.
- l've contacted
the organ donor association
regarding your willingness
to donate your organs to people in need.
They were thrilled
by your generosity.
Plenty of folks are gonna
be thrilled to see me breathe my last.
The association
was resistant to having you meet
with those who would be
receiving your organs,
but after a little
gentle persuasion, they have agreed.
But only as long
as the patient does.
- Well, that's fair.
- One already has.
Tomorrow morning you meet
with one Jiffy Karas.
- Who's that?
- A blind man.
And your corneas will help
restore his sight.
Oh, don't get up.
l'm Jiffy Karas.
Don't ask why
my dad named me Jiffy.
- Moses Deyell.
- Ah, my hero.
Nobody's ever called me
a hero before.
Well, that's what
you are.
My children's children will
sing your praises.
You been blind
all your life?
No.
Lost my sight
two years ago.
But thanks to you,
l'll be able to see the faces
of my children again.
Well, l'm glad my death
could bring about some good.
Mr. Deyell, would you mind
if l touched you?
- Touch me?
- Your face.
l want to remember
exactly what you look like.
Yeah, sure.
All right, Deyell. We're shipping you
over to Benchley Memorial
so that the transplant
doctors there can do whatever tests
they need to do
before Thursday.
You'll also be
meeting a Deborah Beck,
a 20-year-old
social science major.
She'll be receiving
your heart.
You know what's
so crazy about this?
On the brink of my demise
l feel more alive than ever,
like l got more reason
to live.
- Take him out.
- So long, Said.
Funny,
he said so long
like he was never coming back.
You're gonna risk it all
and go for the $1 million?
Absolutely.
l feel lucky.
What is the capital city
of Burkina Faso?
Any idea?
Burkina Faso City?
Now, l need either a hint
or an answer.
What's the answer,
Beecher?
l do not have
a fucking clue.
l dated a girl
named Burkina Faso.
And the capital
of Upper Volta is Ouagagoudou.
- You're sure?
- l'm positive. Ouagagoudou.
l'm sorry, John.
The answer is Ouagadougou.
- Ouagagoudou is wrong.
- You've got to be kidding.
We interrupt this program
to bring you a special news bulletin.
WYAT has just received word
that convicted murderer
Moses Deyell has died
in an attempted escape while
being temporarily transferred
from the Oswald Correctional
Facility to Benchley Memorial Hospital.
Deyell, who had decided to donate his
organs immediately after his execution,
was being transported
in a van
when he apparently leapt
out of the moving vehicle.
We'll have more details
on this story as it develops.
So Orpheus returns
to Earth
alone, sad,
and what happens?
Do the townspeople console him?
Fuck no.
They blame him
for his failure
and tear him to bits,
literally.
Then they throw his organs
in the river.
All this 'cause
he let his family down,
'cause he took one last look
at someone he loved.
The gods don't have
a sentimental bone in their bodies.
Prisoner #01C972,
Padraig Connolly;
Arrested
February 28th, 2001 ;
lllegal entry
into the United States.
Being held
pending deportation.
Padraig Connolly
is here?
Came in this morning.
You knew about Connolly?
Yeah, from the papers.
Member of the lRA,
British government wants
to extradite him
for his involvement in the death
of a British soldier.
A few days ago the court ruled
in Connolly's favor,
they granted him asylum.
The lNS Appealed
the decision.
Connolly's been sent here
to wait out the legal battle.
- Why isn't he in a federal prison?
- He was.
He kept getting
death threats.
Almost got murdered
by a Protestant sympathizer,
so our friends at
the State Department
asked if we could hide
him in Oz.
- Put Connolly in Em City.
- Why?
Why not?
You just want him there
so you can study his every move.
Genuine terrorist.
l admit, l'm intrigued.
Okay, he's yours.
God help you both.
Padraig,
l'm Tim McManus.
l'm Unit Manager
of Em City.
Have a seat.
l've been following
your situation,
and so l know how
fucked up it is.
So l took the liberty
of calling your lawyer
and l got
some pretty good news.
lt doesn't seem like you're
gonna be here long.
Since you're litigating
to stay in the US
it's presumable you don't pose
any flight risk.
So your lawyer feels
that with the judge already sympathetic
to your cause, along with the support
of human rights groups,
bail's gonna get set.
That is good news.
May l go now?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, sure.
Who's he?
Padraig Connolly.
That's all we need
in this place.
Another dumb fucking
spud-eating mick.
- Hey, Ryan O'Reily.
- Stand back!
- Huh?
- ln the doorway.
- No, l just came--
- Step back.
All right,
l like that, Padraig.
You're a soldier,
you're cautious.
This is good.
How do you know
me name?
Oh, on the TV,
past couple of days,
nothing but you
and the lRA executing
that British limey commander
officer fuck thing.
That was on the telly,
that we executed Captain Harley?
That's not what happened.
lt doesn't matter
what happened.
That's what the guys in here
think happened.
And believe me,
that's a good'n for the both of us.
Mr. O'Reily,
l've no need for what you're selling.
You know, Padraig,
you're starting to piss me off,
so l'm just gonna say
this once.
You best start treating Oz
like a North lreland,
because in here you walk,
talk, sleep, work, eat,
shit and drink
with your own kind.
You fucking understand me?
Because your name's O'Reily
you're one of my kind?
We got the same color
green running through our veins, bro'.
lf that were true,
it would matter to you?
- What would matter?
- There was no execution.
You should be looking
at me.
- We're being watched.
- Watched?
l walk out of here
and on body language alone
everyone's gonna know
what's what between the two of us.
l won't be here long enough
to need your friendship,
so have a good walk.
Connolly?
l'm Timmy Kirk.
This is Jim Burns.
Why should l care
what your names are?
We're inviting you
to a Bible study
that the Reverend Cloutier
is holding this afternoon.
Cloutier?
Who's Cloutier?
Today's your conversion day,
Padraig.
Well, either that,
or we beat the Catholic
right off you.
Your choice.
Shit.
Burns, Burns, off.
What's wrong, boys?
Let's not stop now.
All right.
Who started it?
We're only boxing.
- Yeah, without gloves?
- He speaks the truth.
Only boxing, sir.
l was demonstrating the techniques
of the great
John L. Sullivan.
All right, you two get
the fuck out of here.
Listen, Padraig,
if you want me to put
you in protective custody, l will.
Sounds very confining.
No thank you.
Mr. Zelman,
what's wrong?
Ah, sit down, son.
The bail hearing
not happen?
No, it happened,
and it was all set.
But here, take a look. That's a letter
from the Justice Department
specifically urging
the court to deny you bail.
Fucking Christ.
So now what?
Well, l'm afraid
this appeal may play out
all the way
to the Supreme Court.
The fact is you may
be stuck in Oz
for a very long time.
Did he-- did he beat you?
- What?
- Dad, did he beat you.
- ls-- is that why you left?
- No.
He cheated on you.
l was barely 17
and the world was new
and there were people to see
and places to explore.
So it was you
who cheated on him?
l guess.
ln a way.
l hate him.
You know?
And l would never blame
you for leaving that son of a bitch,
but what l don't get is--
is, Jesus,
didn't you even just--
Miss you?
Ryan, from the night
we made you till the day l left,
you are the only
real happiness l have ever had.
l just didn't know
that then.
l was a child
with a three-month-old.
lt didn't even occur
to me that l'd never see you again.
lt's just how things
had to work out.
No, you-- you're thinking
of Cyril.
- What?
- You said three months.
Cyril would've been
the baby.
No, Ryan,
you were the baby.
But l'm a year
and a half older than Cyril.
Your father and l
didn't have Cyril.
What are you
talking about?
Cyril's your half-brother.
Hey, Cyril,
you remember that--
that one time when Dad made us go
spend the summer
in lndiana
at Uncle Bill's farm?
lt was you, me
and those three neighbor kids
in the fields
walking beans.
And Uncle Bill had made
me the foreman
and those three kids
decided to quit
because they thought
l was yelling too much.
l think they wanted to go
swimming or something like that.
And they wanted to take you
with them,
but instead
you decided
to stay with me
in the fields
until we were finished.
l've always wondered
did you stay with me
'cause we're brothers
or did you stay
'cause you thought that if you tried
to leave l'd beat you up?
One, two, three, four.
Up. One, two, three.
All that time in the cage,
l never got to exercise.
Not enough room to move.
Hey, Jia, we're trying
to work out here.
- Want to shut the fuck up?
- l want to try that.
- No, stop.
- l could teach you a lot of things
better than
that bullshit boxing.
- l want to learn.
- Okay.
There's this.
Hey, motherfucker!
No, stay back!
Back!
He hit you!
Back! Back!
Oh, fuck.
- Well?
- Jia is in a coma.
We sent him over
to Benchley Memorial,
but l have no idea
when or if he'll wake up.
Another knockout
for Cyril O'Reily.
- Jia provoked Cyril.
- So says his brother.
But Ryan O'Reily
isn't exactly trustworthy or unbiased.
- What are you saying?
- We've put off this decision enough.
l think we should ship Cyril
to the Conley lnstitute.
- No, that would be a tragic mistake.
- For who?
Cyril's brother is his only lifeline
to reality.
We separate them,
the guy's gonna spiral into lunacy.
We keep him here,
he gets into more fights,
maybe puts somebody else
in a coma.
l think we should transfer
him out today.
- You're being cruel.
- Rather cruel than blind.
l have an alternative.
Let's place Cyril
in protective custody for a while,
allow Ryan regular visits
and see how Cyril adjusts.
- That makes sense to me.
- Tim?
Fine.
As long as he's
out of my hair.
But l don't want to go.
Cyril, trust me.
You have to.
Because if you don't, they're gonna send
you far, far away from me,
and you and l ain't
gonna see each other no more.
Hey. Come on, man.
lt's okay.
Come on, take your bag.
Come on, let's go.
Let's go.
Hey, Cyril.
Toughen up, all right?
- Hey, O'Reily.
- Yeah?
Eliminating Jia,
l owe you.
You got a problem,
friend?
l have a confession
to make.
Several months ago
l was heading into the gym.
No one was there
but Ryan O'Reily
and Patrick Keenan.
Because l was so wrapped up
in my own failings,
l just pushed
the incident aside,
but every day, every time
l'm near O'Reily
- l say to myself, ''Do something.''
- Do what, exactly?
Tell the authorities.
The attack on Jia Kenmin
only proves
that O'Reily will continue
hurting people.
Okay.
We'll go
to Warden Glynn together.
Because if O'Reily finds
out that you told...
he'll kill you next.
l don't know what
you're talking about.
Patrick Keenan
was my friend.
Whoever told you this bullshit
must have it out for me.
The informant has
no motive to lie.
Look, Warden,
when those news people were here,
they asked me all about
Adebisi's videotapes
and l didn't say
word one.
What? You're expecting
a return of the favor?
- Yeah.
- Fuck you!
l'm gonna
thoroughly investigate these charges.
lf l find any corroborating evidence,
you're going to death row.
You got that?
- What happened?
- CO said he collapsed.
- Ryan, are you okay?
- Yeah.
l just needed
to talk to you,
so l faked falling down.
- You scared the shit out of me.
- l'm sorry.
What's wrong?
We need privacy.
You realize this
is the first time
you and l have ever
been alone?
l need to get back
out there, Ryan,
so tell me
what's so important.
Everything's turning
to shit, Gloria.
There's a good chance
Cyril's gonna end up in a loony farm,
and now there's a chance l'm gonna
be convicted for whacking Keenan.
What? How?
Someone jabbered on me
to the warden.
Oh, hey, it wasn't you,
was it?
- No.
- No, those eyes don't lie.
Go on.
l also hear
there's a sizable chance
that you're gonna lose
your doctor's license, which means
l'll never see you
again.
l know.
So l have a proposition
to make.
Don't answer me
right away.
l want you to take the time
to really think
about what l'm asking.
Which is?
l want you to help
Cyril and me escape.
Myths are supposed
to teach us something.
But what's the life lesson
in this sad tale of Orpheus?
No good deed
goes unpunished?
Fuck that.
Ain't no such thing
as a good deed.
Love conquers all?
Never has, never will.
Maybe the moral
of the story is that those in power
are just as fucked up
as those who ain't,
and the worst thing a body can do
is give up his or her own power
to some butt-heads
on Mount Olympus,
'cause if they're
so fucking powerful,
how'd they let us get away
with all this shit in the first place?
Answer me that.