A blizzard is coming, y'all.
Heaps and heaps of snow
will fall from the sky
and bury everything--
sidewalks, cars, houses.
The ground will grow frozen
and slippery, dangerous.
But here in Oz, we're oblivious
to the weather outside.
Here in Oz, we're all
toasty, cozy and warm.
Fuck.
Cyril?
Hey, you okay?
My hair
is changing back.
Oh, shit.
Look at that.
And my skin.
l'm not wrinkled.
Let's go, let's go.
Well, none of the other
nine prisoners
show any long-term or adverse effects
when taking the drug.
Since we've stopped testing, their
bodies have been reverting to normal.
Oh, thank God.
- Morning.
- Coffee ready?
- Yeah.
Great.
Hope we're not running low.
Weather Channel says
a big storm's a-brewing.
With our luck, we'll get
snowed in with no java.
Any word
on how McManus is doing?
Yeah. l stopped by the hospital
on the way here.
He's in
great spirits.
Doctor says he's doing well,
and he should be back next week.
Good.
Wow, great news
all around.
Dr. Nathan?
Jeffrey Sykes.
What can l do for you,
Mr. Sykes?
l'm an attorney at
Downing, McNally & Dima.
The Wygert Corporation
has retained my firm
to handle all the litigation
regarding the so-called aging pill.
Litigation?
The family of the prisoner
who died, Fred Wick,
is suing
for $25 million.
You're named
as a co-defendant.
- Wait, l am?
- Relax.
l'm confident that the Wicks
will settle out of court.
The more serious problem
is the State Medical Board of Ethics,
a decidedly
less predictable group.
They want to hold
a hearing to determine
if there was any malpractice
on your part during the drug testing.
You mean...
Yes, you could lose
your medical license.
Dr. Nathan, is it true
you're being forced to resign?
- Dr. Nathan--
- ls it true you didn't follow protocol?
15 inches of snow
over the next three days.
With temperatures below zero
and winds at 30 miles per hour,
the morning commute...
O'Reily,
you got a visitor.
- Who?
- l don't know. Some broad.
Who are you?
- My name is Suzanne Fitzgerald.
- Do we know each other?
Yes, but we haven't seen each other
since you were a very small child.
Look, lady,
l'm not real big on nostalgia,
so what
do you want?
Ryan, l came because l have
something to tell you,
and it's something l think you're
gonna find impossible to understand.
Try me.
l'm your mother.
- My mother's dead.
- No, l'm your real mother.
The woman that you
thought was your--
My mother's dead!
Well, finally!
Jesus.
Damn it.
l feel like you've been in there
since Halloween.
Hey, l got a lot
on my mind.
Like l give a shit.
You know, Howell,
you are such a cunt.
Look at us arguing
like an old married couple.
You know, O'Reily,
that's the problem--
the thrill is gone.
Meaning what?
What, we're through?
Yep. Time for me to move on
to greener pastures.
Oh, l'm just
heartbroken.
About time.
l'm starving.
Alvin, all you do
all day is eat.
So what?
l'm supposed to preserve
my girlish figure?
Hughes, food's here.
Fuck you!
Hello there,
Blondie.
You afraid of me?
You don't need
to be afraid of me.
l'm good friends
with your brother.
l'd like to be good friends
with you, too.
You can't
do that to me!
Get off me!
No!
Officer Howell says that your brother,
without provocation, hit her.
- She's a lying cunt.
- ln any event, l've sedated him.
He'll sleep
in the ward tonight.
We seem to be coming back
to the same problem.
- l'm not sure what else we can do.
- l don't understand.
We're thinking Cyril should
be transferred to the Conley lnstitute.
The insane asylum?
Uh-uh. No fucking way.
We won't decide anything
until McManus gets back.
John, take him
out of here!
Gloria, don't let them do this.
You know he won't survive in there.
Gloria, l'm serious!
- Hey, Dad.
- lt's snowing like a motherfucker.
They say we'll get maybe
15 inches by Thursday.
l appreciate you
making the effort.
What's wrong?
The hacks are talking about sending
Cyril away to the state loony farm.
- So?
So if he goes to that shithole
by himself then he's gone forever.
What's the difference?
This shithole, that shithole.
Yeah, but at least
here in Oz, he's got me.
And you've been such a force
for good in his life, huh?
Fuck you.
That's my boy.
You didn't call me about Cyril.
You got some other
nonsense going.
Now out with it, because l want
to get back before the roads get worse.
Suzanne Fitzgerald.
She came to see me.
She says she's my real mother.
She's a lying cunt, a miserable
lying cunt! You hear me?
- Fuck! lt's true.
- l got to go.
lt's true, isn't it, Dad?
lt's true!
A son's obligation
is to protect his mother,
no matter from whom,
even his own father.
The woman who l thought
was my mother,
l knew she never loved me.
Now l see why.
And Suzanne Fitzgerald?
l think she's my mom.
Only l chased her out,
and l have no idea
how to reach her.
Well, maybe
l can find her.
Would you?
Would you do that for me?
And this bullshit about
sending Cyril away,
you'll take care
of that, too?
Ryan, l can't make any promises.
This isn't my decision.
But you'll plead
my case, right?
- Ryan...
- Please.
Don't let them
separate us.
Ryan?
- Hey, how you doing, champ?
- Better.
You all right?
l know you'll do what's right.
- So how are you getting along, Clayton?
- l'm fine.
- The men in your block, who are they?
- They're cops.
One was
an undercover narc,
- the other some yokel from mid-state.
- So at least you're safe.
You've got to stop
worrying about me.
l'm not a little boy
anymore.
l know that.
My entire life, you and Leo treated me
like l was some fragile piece of china,
afraid l'd break
at the slightest touch,
because Dad was stupid enough to get
shanked when l was seven years old.
Clayton, don't speak
that way of your father.
All l'm saying is you were
too protective of me.
You'd rather what?
That l let you run with the gangs?
Yes. At least then
it wouldn't have taken me
this long to find my balls.
Oh, and you found them
by shooting at the governor?
For the first time,
l know who l am,
my true self,
the thing
l was born to do.
l can change
the world.
But tucked away in Unit J
l can't do anything...
at least not yet.
What do you mean,
''not yet''?
Clayton, what
are you planning?
Nothing.
Don't worry.
Mail!
Hmm, another letter
from your wife, Basil.
She sounds
worse and worse.
l think you ought
to let her come visit.
Always grateful
for your input, Robson.
My pleasure.
A couple of magazines
for you--
''Newsweek,''
''Field and Stream,''
''Swank.''
l like my reading
to be well-rounded.
Check out the pussy
on page 15.
Oh, hey, nothing
for you today, tough guy.
Bite me.
- Where?
- Fucking cocksucking piece of shit!
Christ, not again.
Take off, Robson, now!
Yes, sir.
Bye-bye, baby.
Fuck you, you
fucking dickless Nazi fag!
Clayton, if you keep this up,
l'm going to have to spank you.
Careful, he might
enjoy it.
- Fucking cocksucker!
- Put Hughes in his cell!
Fucker!
Fuck it!
Uncuff me!
First, you got to learn
not to run with scissors!
We've got to do something
about Hughes, Alvin.
We've tried being friendly.
Now we've got to do something else.
Like what,
boil him in oil?
We should talk
to the warden,
have Hughes transferred
to Solitary.
That guy's like
a son to Glynn.
Would you put
your son in Solitary?
My son.
You got to--
here, let me
show you.
Thanks.
John, come on in.
Office looks great.
Oh, l hope you're not here to ask
for a new microwave.
Clayton Hughes.
Look, l've been meaning
to come down to J
to talk to Clayton.
l just been so goddamn busy.
How's your wife?
She's okay.
How's yours?
l haven't seen Abby
since my trial.
Why not?
l'm too...
mortified.
John,
look, l'm the last one
to be counseling
on marriage.
But trust me, you don't want
to push her away.
You push
once too often,
and she won't be there
when you need her.
Abby?
please come...
and soon.
?? Oh, the weather outside
is frightful ??
?? But the fire
is so delightful ??
?? And since
we've no place to go ??
?? Let it snow, let it snow,
let it snow. ??
?? Let it snow... ??
lt's cold in here.
You guys cold?
Put on a fucking sweater.
When is Busmalis
getting married?
- Tomorrow.
- That's what l thought.
Shouldn't we
be doing something?
- Like what?
- l don't know.
- A bachelor party.
- A bachelor party here in Oz?
Bachelor parties
are one part alcohol,
one part strippers.
We're in short supply of both.
Okay, fine.
l just thought
tomorrow's a big day
for Busmalis--
forget
l brought it up.
- He misses Keller.
- l don't.
So, Rebadow,
you're the best man, huh?
This marriage
is doomed.
Let's go, Cyril.
Come on.
Just think,
by nightfall tomorrow,
l'll be an old
married man.
You don't think
l am, do you?
- Am what?
- Too old to get married.
No.
You don't think
l'm crazy doing this, do you?
You got to be a little crazy
to tie the knot,
But it's
a good crazy.
Sure.
But like you said when l first told you.
How's it going to be,
her outside, me inside?
l mean, we can't even
consummate the vows.
l've been saving this
as a surprise.
l've arranged with Sister Pete
for you and Norma
to have use, on the evening
of your nuptials only,
of one of the old
hospitality suites.
But conjugal visits
aren't allowed anymore.
Sister Pete
pulled a string or two.
Wow.
Norma and l are going to ''romp
through Cupid's grove.''
- There's only one thing.
- What's that?
You're going to have to
tell me what to do
with Norma in bed.
You see, l'm a virgin.
O'Reily's right.
This marriage is doomed.
l'm sure she'll be here
any minute.
Yep, any minute.
Any second.
- She's not that late.
- No, 45 minutes is not late late.
lt's fashionably late.
Plus, l'm sure that
with snow flurries,
the traffic's--
it's just got to be snarled.
The snow flurries.
Of course.
She might have even gotten
a flat tire.
Or a faulty
carburetor.
She told me she's been hearing
a strange ping in her engine.
Well, see,
there you go.
Pete, did you reach her?
l called Norma's home
and got the voice mail.
So l called the studio where they make
''Miss Sally's Schoolyard,''
and a very nice man
there said,
that he hadn't seen her
all day.
My sweetie took off
from work to marry me.
l'm sure she'll be here
any minute.
Right.
But with the snow...
Pete, we've been there.
Aha.
Well, you look very nice.
Thanks.
This is the happiest day of my life.
Are you sure you want
to convert to Catholicism?
Yes, Father.
l don't want you
or anyone else to think
that l'm rushing you
into this decision.
Does it matter what
anyone else thinks?
Father, l know in my heart that
l want to be baptized a Roman Catholic.
The Reverend Cloutier--
l no longer care what
the Reverend Cloutier says or does.
Okay.
All right, Samuel,
we'll have the ceremony
next Saturday.
Thank you, Father.
Thank you, Samuel.
So Daniel was taken up
out of the den,
and no manner of hurt
was found upon him,
because he believed
in his god.
And the king
commanded that--
they brought those men
which had accused Daniel,
and cast them
into the den of lions.
Reverend?
Yes, Father?
l hope you're not upset
that Samuel Gougeon
has decided to become
a Catholic.
Well, if by upset you
mean angry, no.
But l am fearful
for his soul.
His soul will be fine,
believe me.
Believing--
that's the bottom line, isn't it?
You are one cool customer,
l will give you that.
Well, how would you
have me behave,
red-faced with anger,
gripped by jealousy?
No, that's your game.
My game?
When Timmy here left your church
to join mine,
you started keeping a tally--
whoever saves the most souls wins.
That is not true.
l think that your head hasn't accepted
what your heart already knows.
You're baptizing Samuel Gougeon
to get back at me.
Robson,
l need you to take care
of a little something for me.
- You got cash?
- Uh-huh.
Start talking.
- The patient's name is Samuel Gougeon.
- What happened?
He's been severely beaten,
possible head trauma.
- l need you to get me some combines.
- Right away.
Okay, turn to me.
Let me see.
How could you?
How could you have
Samuel Gougeon beaten?
Mukada, l would never
do such a thing.
What has happened to Samuel,
it's anathema to me.
Are you saying this
attack is a coincidence?
l pray that it is.
But if not,
and a member of my congregation
is responsible,
- he will be punished.
- Yeah. Well, do me a favor,
leave the punishment to me.
You understand?
Of course.
Tim, tell me the truth.
Tell me if you are involved.
Yes.
Yes, l am.
Why? Why would you
have him beaten?
Matthew 26:24,
''Woe onto that man by whom
the Son of Man has betrayed.
lt had been good for that man if he
had not been born.''
You told us
those very words.
But you are misconstruing
their meaning.
Gougeon had to be punished
for turning his back on the Lord.
l just wanted to give you
the schedule that l worked out
clearing the cafeteria
for Ramadan.
You came just to give me
the schedule?
Yes.
And there's
nothing else?
l made an assumption
about the Reverend Cloutier--
- that he was a phony.
- But he's not.
This all started when Timmy Kirk
decided to convert.
l thought that Kirk
should be celebrating Christ
through the
one true church.
But if he finds his bliss
somewhere else,
should l fight to keep
his soul in my corner,
believing as l do,
that the faith
that he's choosing is wrong?
Or should l just be happy
that he's found God's love,
no matter where?
The prophet says,
''Let there be no compulsion in religion.
Each soul journeys alone.''
So you must lead
and you must follow.
That's impossible.
lf serving Allah were easy,
everybody would.
Reverend,
l've been thinking,
this might be a good time
for an ecumenical service.
Extraordinary. l was thinking
exactly the same thing.
Father, l accused you
of being consumed with envy.
l was.
But l was, too.
Our sins
are our bond.
The house of God
has many rooms.
lf a person chooses to move
from one room to another,
we who are left behind
must rest assured
the room that we're in
is not empty.
God's presence
fills every room.
God's love shines
through the entire house.
Let us pray.
Currier & lves,
Norman Rockwell--
they created images
of America in winter--
ice skating on a lake,
sleigh rides
along a country road,
fluffy white crystals
of newfallen snow.
Maybe there was a time
when life was idyllic
and children didn't go to school
and kill other children.
We see the paintings now
and we grow nostalgic,
nostalgic for a place
we've never seen.
We long for a time
that we've never actually been part of.
l feel like l've hit
rock bottom,
another trapdoor opens
and l plunge further into despair.
God only gives us as much suffering
as we can endure.
You mean he piles on the shit
to see if we'll break?
- Why?
- To test our faith,
and to make us appreciate
the good that we do have.
Well, forgive me
for saying so, Reverend,
- but God is a sick fuck.
- Vern,
Hank's wife, Carrie,
is about to show up.
She's been to see me regular
since the day Hank disappeared,
since the day she told me
l'm going to be a grandpa.
Every visit l tell her,
''Don't worry,
Hank'll be home soon.''
Well, now l get to tell her that he's
coming home tomorrow in a box.
Here she is.
Hi.
Oh, l'm sorry
l'm late.
l had to scrape ice off the windshield
all by myself.
You feeling okay?
l'm feeling fat.
What does
the doctor say?
That l might deliver
earlier than my due date.
Carrie, l got some news,
and it's not good.
But l need you
to be strong,
for the sake
of the baby.
- Okay?
- All right.
Hank...
was killed.
H-he's dead?
Yes.
Fuck--
oh, fuck.
Jesus, no!
No, no, no!
No! No!
Oh, God.
- lt's going to be okay.
- lt's not going to be okay!
How's it going to be okay?
You tell me, huh?
How am l going to live with a baby
and no fucking husband?
Oh, God.
Fuck!
Oh, God!
- What's the matter?
- l don't know.
Get a goddamned
doctor down here fast!
Central, this is 41.
We need a 68 in the visiting room.
Oh, fuck! Ow!
- Carrie--
- lt fucking hurts!
Come on, Carrie, keep breathing.
Remember your breathing.
- Just pant. Keep breathing.
- lt's not coming out.
lt's coming out.
l can see the head.
On three, l need you
to give a big push. Okay?
One, two, three,
push!
Fuck, it hurts!
- Keep pushing.
- Fuck you!
l can see the head, Carrie.
l can see the head.
Oh, here it comes.
Here it comes.
There you go.
No. No. No!
Please get off of me.
No. No!
Prisoner 01G359,
Colonel Edward Galson;
Convicted
February 16th, 2001 ;
Rape, assault.
Sentence: 15 years,
up for parole in seven.
This is
Tobias Beecher.
He's going to help you acclimate
yourself to your new life.
Beecher, this is
Edward Galson.
- Hey.
- Which way?
This way.
So l saw a thing
about you on the news.
You raped a fellow officer
at a military convention?
l've been in the Marine Corps
since l was 16,
and l have lived
by its code of ethics.
One night,
l failed that code
and l'm being
properly punished.
Well, you may not feel that way
after a couple of days in Oz.
l'm used to being
in the company of men.
l'm used to
a strict regimen.
l won't have
any trouble adapting.
Okay, then.
Do you like
to be called Ed,
Edward, Eddie?
Actually,
l prefer ''Colonel.''
All right, Colonel.
You want to tell us
about your addiction?
l don't think it's an addiction, really.
l don't drink that often.
l see. But when you drink too much,
what happens?
This one time l lost control.
lt won't happen again.
That's easy to say.
lt's harder to do.
For a weak man, yes.
Okay, yeah, l was weak,
and for more than one time.
l probably still am a weakling,
but at least l've got
the balls to admit it.
That's enough, Tobias.
Okay, everybody.
See you next week.
John Carpenter, in fact,
playing for $100,000.
- John, welcome.
- Thank you.
Well, we've got
somebody here to help you,
whose character
''Miles Silverberg''
in the sitcom
''Murphy Brown''...
Hmph-- ''Murphy Brown,''
funny show.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Grant Shaud. Grant, welcome.
- l loved Candice Bergen's tits, man.
- The other girl was cute.
Lily Tomlin?
And the question is:
What country has the most number
of people who speak English?
America!
No, England, dummy.
...the good ol' US of A,
but for $100,000 it--
it can't be that simple.
- Grant?
- My hint is this:
''Redbook'' gave this country
a rave review.
- China.
- l didn't know that.
l'm a big believer
in fake TV newsmen, Gordon.
So l'm going to have to go
with China.
Well, John, it may not
surprise you
that more Chinese people
than Americans
will understand when l say,
you've won $100,000.
Fucking Beecher
always gets the answers.
Maybe you should
go on the show.
Yeah, right.
''Hey, l'm Tobias Beecher.
l'm in prison
for killing a child.
Okay, let's play
'Up Your Ante.'''
Tobias, l'd like you to meet
Katherine McClain.
- Hello.
She's a lawyer with the Alliance
for Prisoners' Rights,
and she'd like to discuss something
with you. Come in and sit down.
Mr. Beecher, are you aware
that you're up for parole?
Well, when l was sentenced,
l knew l had to serve
minimally four years.
But all things considered,
l figured my record
would pretty much cancel out any chance
of getting released early.
Well, you may be right.
But l've reviewed your case,
and l think the extenuating
circumstances--
l mean, the death of both
your wife and son;
your daughter,
her genuine need for you;
your improved behavior
over the past six months;
the commendations from
Sister Peter Marie and Dr. Nathan--
might motivate the parole board
to look kindly on you.
They'll let you go free.
l--
Tobias?
l'm okay.
- What do l have to do?
- Give me permission,
and l'll set the wheels
in motion.
ln the meantime,
keep out of trouble.
l hear you're a faggot.
Whether l am or not,
what's it to you?
Lights go out, l don't
want you getting any ideas.
Trust me, Colonel,
l'm never going to get that horny.
As long as we
understand each other.
Fucking faggots
are ruining the military.
''Don't ask,
don't tell,'' my ass.
l agree.
You know, l think the military should
stay the way it's always been,
a bunch of redneck he-men
who murder children and rape women.
You making
a joke of me?
lt seems like you're doing
a pretty good on your own.
You son of a--
Wait.
Fuck, no.
Guards-- shit.
Wait, you don't understand.
Wait.
Look, l'm sorry.
Will you just fucking let me
explain, you fucks!?
God fucking--
Fuck!
God damn it!
Fahrenheit and Celsius,
two ways of measuring
the same thing.
Of course, most of the world
is on Celsius,
but we Americans remain
defiantly committed
to Fahrenheit.
We'd like to learn the other way--
we'd like to change.
But we just can't seem
to accept
that zero degrees is actually
warmer than we think.
So, Jackson,
why were you sent
to prison?
The file's right
in front of you.
You don't want to say
the words?
- Assault.
- What else?
This is bullshit.
lt's not easy
to verbalize, is it?
- So?
- So that's good.
That means you're not proud
of what you did.
No, it means l didn't do
what the bitch says l did.
l didn't try to rape her.
She came on willingly.
Okay, l want to schedule you
for another appointment tomorrow.
Why? This shit
is not helping me.
Well, it's helping me.
You see, Jackson,
l have quotas to fill.
And l have to see a certain
amount of prisoners every day
or the State
just won't pay me.
Jackson, you were
tested for drugs
just before the parole hearing,
and you came out clean.
Do l need to have you
tested again?
Nah.
l believe you...
for now.
Hey, Redding,
l got a complaint.
The shit Poet sold me yesterday
been cut with something.
Shit, l can't even
get my usual high.
The problem ain't with the product,
nigga, it's with the consumer.
Am l talking to you?
Yo, l need some better shit.
What Poet's trying to tell you
in his own surly style
is that you've been
snorting so much every day,
combined with the size
of your body,
you've developed
yourself a tolerance.
At least he's tolerant
about something.
Shut up!
Look, give me some more.
More is only going
to kill you.
No, you need
a better way to--
- what's that word?
- lngest.
lngest.
Only be careful
where you stick it.
You don't want to be leaving
yourself any marks.
- So what, in my tongue?
- Or behind your knee.
Lights out!
Number 17 Jackson Vahue.
As a basketball player,
my legs are what made me.
l know l'm never going to see
another pro game,
so fuck it, right?
What's it matter?
But it does matter.
These legs took me out
of the projects.
l made something
out of myself.
l don't want
to forget that.
l'm proud of these legs.
What's up, fool?
Prisoner number 01D251,
Carlton Daniels,
aka ''Tug'' Daniels;
Convicted
February 20th, 2001 ;
Attempted murder
in the first degree.
Sentence: 28 years,
up for parole in 14.
The time for action
has arrived.
Tug,
you waste Pancamo.
Done.
l want Morales.
Why are you so hell-bent
on killing him?
l made a promise
to avenge the death
of Bian Yixue.
Augustus, l want you
to get word
to Omar White
in the hospital ward
that he's to finish off
Supreme Allah.
Hey, Burr, listen,
l've been thinking
about this little war we activating.
A lot of good men
will die.
A lot of them going
to die in any case.
But assuming you win,
what you gonna gain?
The hacks will lock down
this whole prison.
Can't keep a lid
on it forever.
Warden finds out
you're the ringleader,
he going to send you
to Solitary.
Augustus, what the fuck's
your problem?
You were my father's
best friend, right?
You and him went off to Vietnam
together, and you came back alone.
And since then,
l have followed you.
l have done your bidding,
never questioning, right?
So now you've got
questions.
When l was 10 years old,
l wanted a real job.
- You wanted a paper route.
- Right.
But instead,
you had me selling smack.
- Well, you got to learn the business.
- Why?
Why did l need to learn
how to sell drugs?
Because we didn't have
any other options back then.
Let me tell you
something.
l ain't going to apologize
for who l am or what l done,
all right?
Do l wish things
had been better? Sure.
Do l wish we'd been born
in one of them fancy mansions
up there on Kellogg Boulevard?
Sure.
But l don't hope
and l don't dream.
l take a shit
in this world,
l see reality
and l make the best of it.
You ain't got to tell me
about reality.
l live in Oz.
l live
in this chair.
And l wouldn't be here
if you'd let me have
the goddammed
motherfucking paper route.
The man is like
a father to me.
Well, there comes a time for every son
to leave his father's house,
make his own way.
Even so,
l can't betray him.
Do you believe what he's
instigated is wrong?
For the most part, yes.
And do you believe that many people
will suffer as a result?
Yes.
You know, l've always
admired you, Augustus,
for being
your own man,
for keeping-- especially
in this place--
a sense of decency
and honor.
What good
has it ever done?
You get to sleep
through the night.
l need
to talk to you.
- So talk.
- ln private.
- Yo, bro'.
- What you want?
- A sip of water.
- l ain't no nurse.
Come on. l'm so thirsty, man.
Please.
Mmm, it's so good.
lt's so good.
Up-- up, baby!
Yo, throw the ball.
- Do not resist.
- Okay, okay, okay.
Lockdown!
When l was a kid, l used to love
reading Jack London.
You know, ''Call of the Wild,''
''White Fang.''
l remember one story where a man
was in the middle of Alaska,
or somewhere,
isolated and cold.
He lost his dog team,
his legs were broken,
he realized he was going
to freeze to death.
So he buried himself in the snow
and simply went to sleep.
Terrifying
and yet beautiful.
Acceptance of one's fate,
the way
any man should die.
Giles, get up.
We're a month away
from the date set by the Court
for your execution.
You'll have to decide
which way you want to go.
Die old...
sleep?
Yeah, well,
that's not an option.
Peter Marie.
l'll ask her
to see you.
Hey, don't you be
crying, man.
Your crying's
gonna bring me down.
Stop your fucking crying!
And then there's gas.
They put you in
a little room
and drop a pellet
of sodium c-cyanide...
your lungs fill up,
and that's the end.
S-stoned?
Gee, l don't know
if that gas makes you high.
No... rocks.
l don't understand.
- Throw.
- Wait a minute...
you want to be stoned
to death?
Shirley Jackson?
Moses,
listen to me.
As your lawyer,
l have to tell you
there's a very good chance that you're
looking at another death sentence.
So we'll appeal
that one, too.
Yes, but
Congress has placed
a lot of limitations
on death row appeals.
Which means?
Which means that you will
probably be executed
for one or both
of these crimes.
You have to prepare
for what might be coming.
Huh.
You see, l ain't thought through
that part of the situation,
because--
l haven't given up hope.
l'm a man of principles,
you understand?
And l believe down
to the bottom of my soul
that a man
with principles will--
will be exonerated.
lt's always good to hope.
But just in case,
you might want to make
some plans,
you know?
Get your house in order.
The State Attorney General
has refused your request
to be executed by being
stoned to death.
Law-- right, mine.
An anti-death-penalty group has
decided to take up your cause.
They're-- they're going to sue
the State on your behalf.
This mess will probably
drag out for decades.
Peter--
Peter Marie.
Lights out!
Giles?
Psst, Giles?
This whole time l thought
you were a damned idiot
talking in flash cards,
but now l see
you're a fucking genius.
No-- genius, no.
Yes, genius, yes.
You were supposed to die in two weeks.
All your appeals dried up.
But by asking to be stoned to death,
you threw a wrench
in the works.
Everybody's suing everybody.
And like the warden says,
this could take years
to sort out.
Die old...
sleep?
Oh, Giles, you are an inspiration
to us all, brother.
l'm curious as to why you asked
the warden to see me.
l just finished reading
your book.
- lt's awesome.
- Thank you.
The section on Jefferson Keane,
being on death row
and giving his kidney to his sister,
it really got to me.
l still hear
from Grace.
She's very happy,
very healthy.
Well, l want to do
the same thing--
give my organs away.
Let others make use of my insides
when l'm done with them.
The only thing is...
l want to meet the people
l'm going to help.
l'm not sure
that's allowed.
You can
make it happen, Said.
l know you can.
Power through faith.
l'll see
what l can do.
Well, brother,
l stood where you are now.
And, yo, l know
the need to be a man,
but being a man ain't fueled by drugs
or fists or banging your bitch.
Being a man starts here.
- Ah, Salah's making another convert.
- Yes.
He has a way of talking
to people on their level.
You did a great job
guiding him.
Leroy.
What you want, Robson?
l'm a patient man,
a tolerant man.
but my friend
Jaz here is not.
- That's right.
- We had a deal:
Half the cash in advance
for you to whack Kareem Said,
but Said's still walking.
You said you had a long-term plan
to get close to him.
Well, Jaz is feeling
the clock has run out.
''Tick-tock,'' Leroy.
First, my name ain't
Leroy Tidd no more.
My name's Salah Yudin.
Second, l know l said l promised
to kill Said, but l've changed my mind.
First, in order to change your mind,
you gotta have a mind.
And, Leroy...
you got shit for brains.
Second, you don't back out
on the Brotherhood.
As-Salaam Alaikum.
Don't give me that fucking
hocus-pocus bullshit.
Robson, you looking for
jerk-off time in the hole?
- Uh, no.
- Then goose-step your butt out of here.
This shit ain't over.
Salah, you seem
troubled.
- My soul is heavy, Minister.
- So talk to me.
l'm afraid, afraid
to speak the truth.
Never be afraid of the truth,
my brother.
l lied to you.
You see, when l
first approached you
saying l wanted
to become a Muslim,
l had vengeance
in my heart
'cause of what you did
killing Adebisi.
But then the bliss of Allah
replaced the vengeance,
and now l'm
a true believer.
l knew the day
that l embraced you,
that you were lying.
- You did?
- Mm-hmm.
Then why?
The ways of the Almighty
are wondrous, indeed.
He brought us together
at this time and this place
so that we could
learn from each other.
You learn
from me? How?
That day l went to Adebisi
and l swore my loyalty to him--
Since his death, l have been
struggling with my demons.
Still do...
but you've taught me
the world has many possibilities.
Robson and Hoyt
want you dead.
- l know.
- What are we going to do?
As with
everything else...
we'll leave this
in the hands of God.
lf you take care of this,
l'll bring you into the Brotherhood.
lf you don't,
l'll feed you to them.
- Take that!
- Fuck you, man. l told you--
l'm ready to do
whatever you need.
No! No!
lmam...
Salah is dead.
l killed him, you know.
l killed him just
like l killed Adebisi.
l might has well have
had the knife in my hand...
in these bloody hands.
- Kareem--
- No, say nothing.
- But you can't blame yourself.
- Leave me...
because my demons
need feeding.
Leave me!
They say that every
snowflake is different,
but how can they
really be sure?
l mean, think about all the snowflakes
that have fallen
all over the world
throughout Earth's history.
Law of averages dictates that at least
two of them had to be similar.
Like human beings,
like the men in Oz--
even if they
start out unique,
they end up the same.