Every person on the planet was raised
to believe some version of the truth,
about God, about morality, mortality,
about the purpose of life.
We usually call
those beliefs religion.
And if over the course of living
those beliefs break down,
if they prove themselves
not to be true,
we search for a new religion
to follow and we convert.
Now that conversion
can be traumatic,
not only for ourselves,
our souls,
but for those around us.
Can l have
your attention?
Everybody's
attention, please!
ln my ongoing effort to improve
the quality of your lives,
l'm instituting
a couple of new programs.
Starting today, once a week,
we're going to show you
an instructional video
for one half-hour of TV time.
Yes, yes,
And attendance is mandatory.
Hey, hey,
l wanna hear silence.
Over there is
another idea of mine.
Now, when you
violate the rules,
instead of sending you
to the hole,
we're going to stick you
inside that cage
in full view of your adoring public.
- Any questions?
- Yes, Mr. McManus, sir.
How big is your penis?
Funny. Keller,
you get the honor of being
the first slug inside the cage.
- Keller!
- Way to go!
You faggot.
Hey, you need to take a shit?
Hey, fella,
it ain't that bad.
All right, everybody else
find a seat.
Here's the first video.
Let her rip.
Life is like a house.
Sure you can paint
and decorate it alone,
but then only you'll
appreciate it. Others won't.
And don't you want them to?
That's what community is for.
- Hey, you outta here?
- Mm-hmm.
Hey, yo, you tell everybody in Emerald
City that Supreme Allah is not done.
You hear me? Tell them Supreme Allah is
coming back, he's coming back strong.
- Quiet down, Ketchum.
- The murderous bond. Let them know.
- Let's go.
- l got you out of solitary
- because you said you want to change.
- Mm-hmm.
Well, l'm giving you
that chance, Omar,
and l'm going to do
whatever l can to help.
- But l need you off the drugs.
- Mm-hmm.
You screw up again, l'm going to send
you right back to solitary.
Do you understand?
Uh-huh.
Okay.
Shit, he called me
a drug abuser, man.
l ain't no drug abuser,
Jack.
l mean, truth be told, son,
l treat my drugs better than most.
Now he wants me
to go to rehab.
Rehab is cool, man.
You get to talk about
yourself a lot.
Well, l'm doing--
what, 17 to life?
By the time l get out of this,
there ain't be shit to recover.
You know what
l'm saying, son?
Miguel Alvarez, a fugitive from
the Oswald State Correctional Facility
for the past six months,
has been captured.
Customs agents near
Nogales, Arizona,
found Alvarez
late last night as he tried
to cross the border
into Mexico.
- ln other news...
- Alvarez is coming back.
- So?
- The motherfucker tried to kill me.
Yeah, only because
you tried to kill him.
Or did l get
the story wrong?
You let it go, Chico.
How you doing, Glynn?
You miss me?
No.
You know,
l almost made it.
l almost made it
into Mexico.
We would have
found you there.
l don't think so.
You know, l would have made my way
to Guatemala, Nicaragua, Colombia,
walked the Andes
through Chile
to light this little spark
called Tierra del Fuego.
You know about
Tierra del Fuego?
- lt's the end of the earth.
- That's right.
You would have gone
that far to capture me?
The end of the earth?
Probably not.
Next time.
Take him to solitary.
What's up, man?
Keep moving.
- Who's that?
- What's it matter?
l just like to know the quality
of criminal l'm neighboring with.
He's a wank job,
just like you.
Shit.
- Put something in Alvarez's food?
- Like what?
l don't know, rat poison or something.
Look, the point is,
you kill him, Omar,
l'll see that you get
all the fucking tits you need.
Huh? What do you say?
- No.
- No? Why no?
l just don't like you.
You don't like me?
l can't put
my finger on it.
l don't know if it's
the way you look...
the way you smell,
your breath, the way you talk.
l don't know, but there's just something
about you just rubs me the wrong way.
Yeah? Well,
fuck you, nigger.
Oh, fuck!
- All right.
- Call the warden!
- Do not resist.
Don't let-- don't let--
help me!
We've got a 66
in the kitchen, a code 66.
- You back?
- Uh-huh.
Fuck, nigger, that got to be some kind
of record or something.
- You Alvarez?
- Yeah.
You owe me, dog.
lnside.
- Claire?
- Yeah?
- Hey, how much do you love me?
- Plenty.
- Yeah? Enough to do anything l ask?
- Yeah.
Yeah? Thattagirl.
Come on.
Wait a minute,
wait a minute.
- You fucked Howell?
- Mm-hmm.
You just don't drop a nugget like that
without a few details, O'Reily.
We had sex maybe five times in the
ladies' toilet off the interview room.
She got weird.
What do you mean weird?
Weird, like possessive weird?
Yeah.
So when McManus came back
and took over Em City
and shipped her off to Unit J,
l was, to say at the least, relieved.
l haven't seen
much of her since.
My esteem for you
has risen 69°/%,
but tell me, as one
manipulative turd to another,
did you fuck Howell for the sex or get
her to do some other kind of nasty?
Just the sex.
Check.
Fuck.
- Don't you be winking at me!
- What?
- Claire!
- The fucking bastard's winking at me.
- Take him to the hole!
- That's bullshit!
Take him to the hole.
- Mineo.
- Joe.
All right, all right.
- But you're filling out the paperwork.
- Mineo.
What? You fucking dyke!
- Ryan, have you missed me?
- Oh, Christ.
- Dr. Nathan, welcome back.
- Thanks, it's good to be back.
Oh no, l wanted to put these
on your desk before you arrived.
Oh, Pete.
- Hi.
- Wow! You look great.
- Thanks. l feel great.
- Yeah?
You know, renewed, ready to jump back
into the job with both feet.
Listen, l've got six seconds
before group.
So let's meet later and review
the current cases, okay?
- Bienvenida!
- Gracias.
Dr. Nathan, we need you.
- This guy took a shank to the face.
- Uh, gloves.
The other guy
wasn't as lucky.
- Cyril O'Reily.
- l heard what he did to that news guy,
Jack Eldridge,
nearly beating him to death.
Cyril's condition is only
getting worse.
We can't find the right balance
of medication.
Hmm... l'd like
to examine him.
Can you arrange that,
Tim?
Sure.
So who's next?
l think that's it.
Okay, l'm off to group.
- Okay, see you.
- Bye.
What are you doing?
Want to have some dinner?
Nah.
Well, l really
only mean dinner.
l know.
Rain check, okay?
- See you.
Okay, good.
Put your shirt on.
Dr. Nathan,
where you been?
l took a few months off,
a little vacation.
- After you got raped?
- Ah, yeah.
- l wish l could have.
- Could have what?
Taken a vacation
after l got raped.
lt was okay, though.
l had Ryan to help me.
Yeah, he's a very
helpful guy.
l wish l could
help him.
He's sick.
When he was in the hole,
he got a cold.
You can take him back.
For Christ's sake, O'Reily,
quit coughing on the food.
You're going to get
the whole fucking prison sick.
- Relax, l'm not contagious anymore.
- Yeah.
Fuck.
Hey, on second thought...
l'm not feeling so hot after all.
l got to go to the infirmary.
Deep breath.
Again.
Yeah, you do
sound congested.
Give him a hit of albuterol.
Let's keep him overnight.
Follow me.
- Welcome back.
- Huh?
- Oh thanks, Claire.
l just wanted you to know...
l've been taking good care
of Ryan O'Reily for you.
- What do you mean?
- You know, giving him a helping hand.
Get back in bed.
No, that's okay, Benny.
l want to talk to him.
But stay nearby.
- Are you feeling better?
- Uh-huh.
Did you send me this?
Yes.
You killed him,
didn't you, Keenan?
Yes.
You admit to murdering him
even though you know
l could tell the warden
that you confessed,
and you'd probably
end up on death row?
Keenan raped you.
He didn't deserve to breathe.
lf l have to die
because of that--
okay, kill me.
Go to bed.
l love you.
Benny, Carl,
we're finished.
l've hated Ryan O'Reily
for so long,
so deeply.
He's responsible
for the death of my husband,
but he did it
out love for me.
And Keenan, too.
All for me.
He loves me more
than Preston ever did.
Ryan's love is...
enormous, overwhelming,
unconditional, undying.
Am l crazy
to push him away or--
Gloria, listen to yourself.
His love is anything
but unconditional,
and often anything but love.
Now look, the feelings
he has for you are dangerous.
He is dangerous.
And for you to encourage him,
given that you don't
share those feelings--
But l do.
l do share his feelings.
God help me.
l love Ryan O'Reily.
When Christopher Columbus
landed in the New World,
a Catholic priest
was right alongside him.
From then on, priests kept coming over
to this continent
trying to convert the lndians, trying
to get them to kiss the crucifix,
to stop smoking peyote,
to cover up their nakedness.
The lndians responded
with great enthusiasm.
They maimed, tortured
and burned the priests...
and then offered
the bodies up their own gods.
What's this?
James Devlin is about to get inaugurated
for his second term as Governor.
Hey, change the station.
lt won't do no good.
The scumfuck's
on every channel.
Yeah, we need to petition the warden
to get us some cable up in here.
Augustus, he's got
wheels like you.
Will you look at that?
l do solemnly swear,
to execute the office
of Governor
to the best of my
abilities,
and to preserve,
protect and defend
the Constitution
of this state,
with equality and justice
for all, so help me God.
Wishing you were up there?
Neil Bourne will make
a great lieutenant governor.
That's not what l asked.
Do you regret
dropping out of the race?
- Nope.
- Good.
Warden?
Barry Levine
on line two.
- Who's Barry Levine?
- l don't know. He says he knows you.
Barry Levine?
He wants to talk with you
about the warden's conference.
Oh, you mean
Barney Levin?
Oh, maybe that's
what he said.
Look, tell him
l'll call him back later.
And use
the goddamn intercom.
Yes, sir.
Man, Busmalis is
driving me crazy.
He's the worst
assistant l've ever had.
He gets numbers wrong,
he-- he screws up appointments,
l'm hosting the regional conference
of the Wardens Association next week,
and he has managed
to mangle every detail.
- Get another prisoner to assist you.
- Who?
How many drug dealers
can use Excel?
Hire someone from outside.
Every time l do they
end up quitting.
They get jumpy
working here.
l need to find
somebody who's...
smart, funny,
diplomatic...
and fearless.
l may have
the perfect person,
a woman l met doing volunteer work
at a homeless shelter.
Her name
is Floria Mills.
- l'm not late, am l?
- No, you're right on time.
Oh my car broke down
on the expressway.
l don't know why they call
that road expressway
cause the traffic
moves like snails.
Then l managed to hitch
a ride with a trucker,
only we got to talking
so we missed the exit ramp,
and then he didn't want
to come all the way up here.
Turns out he served four years
for armed robbery,
so l had to walk, which is why
l must look like yesterday's gumbo.
Here's my resume.
Do you always have
this much energy?
Actually, you caught me
on one of my slow days.
Congratulations, Floria.
- For what?
- You just got the job.
- Oh, l did?
- Yes.
Yeah, l understand the warden's former
assistant said we needed food for 20
but he made a miscalculation,
which l hope you'll help me correct.
Now, Carl,
nothing's impossible.
The governor is going to be
at the conference.
You know if he likes
your catering,
you'll be working
state functions for years.
Oh thank you, Carl.
You're a sweetie.
Yeah?
Well, if it's okay,
l'm going home.
Sure. Good first day.
Oh, thanks,
l had fun.
Fun?
''Fun'' is not a word
l'd associate with Oz.
Warden, have you ever
thought about redecorating?
- Not really.
- Well, with your permission,
l'd like to make a few changes,
brighten things up,
- get new furniture.
- Okay.
Unless, of course, you think
your wife would mind.
l don't know the woman,
but l know that there are some wives
who take their husband's offices very
personally, if you know what l mean.
Mary won't mind, Floria.
At this point, she doesn't seem
to care much about what l do.
The fact is...
this morning, my wife and l
decided to separate.
Oh, Warden,
l am so sorry.
She asked me
to move out.
Do you have
somewhere to go?
No, l hadn't thought
about it.
Well, l'll call
you a hotel.
There's a Hyatt right over
on Bartlett and Third.
Don't bother. l'm going to sleep
on this couch tonight.
Do you think
that's wise?
You know, this may
sound odd, but...
sometimes the walls
around Oz
make me feel safe.
l don't know why
l'm telling you all this.
l haven't told anybody else.
- Good night, Warden.
- Call me Leo.
You go easy on
that stuff, Leo.
The warden fired me.
No thank you, no pat on the back,
just clear out your desk.
- Maybe it's all for the best.
- Best?
l'm back mopping floors,
scooping up poop, piss and vomit.
Do you think l love what l do?
Answering Miss Sally's e-mail,
forging her autograph
on photos?
l don't think it matters what we do
as long as we do our best.
Oh Norma, you have the best
perspective on the world.
These past few months,
you coming to visit,
they've meant
everything to me.
l'm glad, Agamemnon.
l want you to be happy.
When l'm with you,
l'm delirious.
l love you, Norma.
Will you marry me?
- Yes.
- Oh, boy.
l want you to be
my best man.
Have you thought
this through?
Marriage is a big step,
a big commitment.
What kind of life
can you two have together,
you in here,
her out there?
l won't be in Oz
for long.
While you were in the hospital,
l started digging another tunnel.
You and me, old friend.
We'll dance the Hasapiko
at my wedding.
Saul was a soldier riding
his horse to Damascus
when all of a sudden
he saw a huge cross in the sky.
lnstantly, he changed the first letter
of his name to P, becoming Paul.
Why? l don't know.
Most of us ain't that lucky
seeing a cross in the sky.
For most of us, signs from God aren't
quite that clear.
''Put not God
with other gods,
for thou will sit
despised and forsaken.
Thy Lord has decreed that ye shall not
serve other than Him.
And kind--''
- What do you want?
- l need to talk to Minister Said.
Continue.
''And kindness
to one's parents,
- whether one or both of them--''
- Minister, please.
l want to become a Muslim.
Tidd, go away.
l know in the past that l've been fierce
hanging with Adebisi and stuff.
But when l saw him bleeding,
and you with that shank
in your hand,
l knew l had to change.
- l want to join you.
- Get up.
- Save me, Minister Said.
- l said get up!
Hey, hey!
What's going on?
- This man is harassing me.
- You causing trouble, Leroy?
- No.
- Then get your ass gone.
You know l've never
liked Leroy Tidd.
The man's done nothing
but flex since he came into Oz.
- But if his conversion is real, then--
- lt's not.
How do you know
for sure?
Now, you of all people,
you're going to question
my ability to judge others?
- You?
- No.
- Things are as you say they are.
- Good.
And l don't want
no more talk about Leroy Tidd.
l am a fiend.
l'm also a liar,
a thief, a--
l just want to turn my life backwards.
You know what l mean?
But 'cause l've been hard,
no one fucking believes me.
- We believe you, Leroy. Don't we?
- Oh yeah.
l believe him.
This guy, Leroy Tidd,
l think he is genuinely sorry.
l think he genuinely
wants to change.
And you came to this
conclusion how?
He was in rehab today.
Many in Oz have used rehab,
have used lslam
for their own agenda.
Tidd is one of them.
You've embraced a lot
of men far worse than him.
Jefferson Keane,
Poet, Adebisi.
No! Not Adebisi!
- Oh, l see.
- Oh, you see?
- You see what?
- Tidd hung with Adebisi.
- You feel guilty having killed him.
- No!
l do not feel guilt!
l did the right thing.
l did what had to be done.
Jesus Christ.
That's what l said about
Andrew and Hank Schillinger.
Taking a life is acceptable as long
as it's excusable, right?
Beecher...
Get away from me.
So he says, ''Don't eat me.
Eat the nigger.''
What's the matter?
You don't think that's funny?
No. But you,
you're a joke.
- Get back!
- Fuck this!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
You fucker!
You motherfucking nigger.
Fucker!
Yo, Schillinger,
l want to talk to you.
Somebody tell him
l don't talk to--
what is the politically
correct term--
Jungle bunnies.
Oh you gonna want
to talk to me.
l saw the dust up
between your pals and the Muslims.
And l know
Said's to blame
for your boy Robson spending
a few days down the hole.
Now what l'm offering is
to take care of Said.
For the right amount of cash,
of course.
Will somebody tell him we can
take care of Said ourselves?
We don't need to subcontract.
And will somebody tell him
l'm going to get close to Said?
Close enough
to cut his throat.
Here, drink that.
So the doctor says
everything's okay?
Yeah, we did a sonogram.
- Do you want to see?
- Yeah.
- God.
- Mr. Schillinger, l'm worried.
lt's been five months, we still haven't
heard a word from Hank.
lt's like l told you, he just loves
to disappear for long periods of time.
Got the soul of a wanderer.
Just like his mother.
He's gonna be here
when that baby's born.
ln the meantime, l'll
get you whatever you need.
You positive
Hank'll come back?
l believe it
with all my heart.
And that's what
you got to do.
Okay? You gotta believe.
Prisoner number 00C966,
Jeremiah Cloutier;
Convicted
December 27th, 2000;
embezzlement
and petty larceny.
Sentence: nine years,
up for parole in five.
He's one of them
TV evangelists.
One of them? Until this scandal,
he was bigger than Falwell.
He cured
my sister of leprosy.
- Liar.
- Pneumonia?
Gentlemen.
- Mr. Schillinger?
- Yeah?
l bring you greetings
from Calvin Anderson.
- Oh you know Cal?
- Oh indeed, l do.
When you have some time,
l'd like to talk to you.
About what?
Life in general...
here in Oz.
My schedule's pretty clear.
How 'bout right now?
''Jack came down out of the bean stalk
as fast as he could,
and he ran and he ran until he got
to his mother's house.
Once there, he gave her
the golden harp
and all the other treasure he brought
back from the giant's castle.
And they lived
happily ever after.''
- Do you believe in Jesus Christ?
- Yeah, of course.
Good.
l want to ask you
another question, Vern.
l'd like you
to answer me honestly.
- Are you happy?
- Sure.
Honestly.
All your life, you thought that
your way was the right way,
the best way,
the only way.
And yet as a result,
your wife is dead,
one son dead,
the other missing,
and you are stuck
in this miserable hellhole.
How could any man be happy?
Let the joy of Jesus Christ
fill your heart.
Let him who suffered
take away your suffering.
Open up to the Lord.
Get your
fucking hand off me.
How's law school, Angus?
l'm in a constant state
of chasing my own ass.
- l remember that feeling.
- No.
l mean, not only do l have to become
the perfect lawyer,
l have to be
an ideal husband and father.
Because l fucked it all up.
Jesus, that's not
what l meant.
That's the way
Mother and Dad feel,
especially
since the kidnapping,
especially since l told them
l was fucking another man.
Toby, they're
old fashioned.
l mean, none of this
makes any sense to them.
What, do you think
it makes sense to me?
Well, let's play the game.
And the category
is literature.
And William Shakespeare
once referred to this act
as ''the beast
with two backs.'' John.
l'm not real confident when it comes to
Shakespeare, so l think l need a hint.
- Robert.
- Shakespeare, Shakespeare.
lsn't that the guy that made it
with Gwyneth Paltrow?
- The beast with two backs.
- Sex.
Oh, sex.
Sexual intercourse.
Beecher, is that your little brother
l saw you with in the visiting room?
- Sex is correct.
- He's cute. He fool around?
The last time l made it, my girlfriend
fell asleep in the middle.
Evil Marduk,
King of Babylon,
in the year that he became king
released Jehoiachin from prison.
And he spoke
kindly to him.
And Jehoiachin took off
his prison clothes,
and he took
his meals with the king
all the days of his life.
This is bullshit.
Who said that?
Come on, loudmouth.
Have the courage to face me.
l said it,
and it's true.
Step forward.
- What is your name, my friend?
- Jim Burns.
And why are you
in Oz, Jim Burns?
They say l murdered my brother,
but l'm innocent.
You see before you
a sinner.
a man possessed by demons.
The demons of fear,
guilt and hate.
l say, demons, be gone.
l cast thee out in the name
of Jesus Christ the Savior.
Demons, be gone!
Leave this man.
Sink back into the eternal fires
of damnation.
ln the name of God,
l command it!
be gone.
Now you rise.
Rise up, Jim Burns.
You rise and praise the Lord.
Praise him.
Praise the Lord.
Praise the Lord!
''By mercy and truth,
inequity is purged.
And by the fear
of the Lord, men depart.''
- May l?
- Please.
l do want to be happy.
Come on,
what's the scam?
There is no scam.
You're serious about
going through with this?
lt's been months
since Beecher's kid died.
l kept thinking he was planning
something, some way to retaliate.
He hasn't done anything.
Yeah, but you and this prag
sitting together
in one of Sister Pete's
interaction sessions?
- That's crazy.
- Why?
l'm just sick
of all this horseshit.
l want to concentrate on the birth
of my first grandchild.
You know, l just want
a little taste of happiness.
Vern, you're starting
to scare me.
Tobias, l believe that
Schillinger is genuine
in wanting to put this ugliness
between you to rest.
l tried to do that by trying
to find his son Hank.
What did l get in return?
My son's dead,
my daughter's traumatized.
Yeah, but this time,
for the first time,
the need for reconciliation
is coming from Schillinger.
So what?
This could just be another one
of his plans, some sort of revenge.
You'll never
know if we don't try.
Prisoner number
01B784, Ronald Barlog;
Convicted January 1 2th, 2001 ;
car theft.
Sentence: 1 3 years,
up for parole in six.
This is your sponsor,
Tobias Beecher.
He's going to help you
acclimate to your new life.
- Beecher, this is Ronald Barlog.
- Ronnie.
- Hey.
- All right.
Let's go, Ronnie.
Holy shit. Holy fucking shit!
Keller, man!
Look at this motherfucker.
Hey, man, how are you doing?
- How you doing?
- Real good.
- How long has it been?
- Last time l left, you had Tommy F's.
You were screaming for Leila.
''l got to meet Leila at the pier.''
- Who were you screaming for?
- l'll tell you what.
Get yourself settled,
then we'll catch up.
- All right.
- All right, Cool. You winning?
No, l'm getting
my ass kicked.
He's cute.
Does he like
to fool around?
So l guess
l'm on the bottom?
Unless you want
to be on top.
No, no, l'm good
with the bottom.
- You knew Keller on the outside?
- Oh, yeah.
Yeah, we were--
we were partners for a while.
You two ever fuck?
What?
- You need anything you ask, okay?
- Okay.
Prisoner number 01R289,
Burr Redding;
Convicted January 11th, 2001 ;
murder in the first degree,
seven counts
of attempted murder.
Sentence: life without
the possibility of parole.
Ever since Adebisi died, the homeboys
have been in complete disarray.
Redding is just the guy
to galvanize them.
And you would like me to--
l would like us both
to gain his confidence,
make him a partner
instead of a foe.
l'll do what l can.
Mr. Redding,
l'm Tim McManus.
This is Kareem Said.
Salam Alaikum.
You the cat that wasted
Simon Adebisi?
- Yes, l am.
- Outstanding.
l heard he was
one mean motherfucker,
which makes you even worse.
l guess l'm gonna
have to watch my step.
l killed Adebisi
in self-defense.
- The court exonerated me.
- No doubt.
But motives are
less important than outcome.
He's dead, and you're not.
- May l go now?
- No.
Burr, l think it's important that you
grasp how things work around here.
l grew up in the ghetto.
Pops died when l was 10.
l had to quit school, support my family
by doing some of everything,
from shining shoes
to shooting craps.
l went to Vietnam,
where they taught me
how to kill
small children and women.
l've been in all kind of penitentiaries
from Arizona to Alabama and back.
And l say all this
not out of pride or shame.
l just want to make sure
that you grasp
that l already grasped
how things work around here.
- May l go?
- Yes.
Yo!
Augustus.
Oh man, l'm glad
you're here, Burr.
Hmm.
You know, man,
l ain't glad you're here.
l got it.
- Yo, how's Delilah?
- Delilah died, man.
Ovaries went sour on her.
Oh man, l'm sorry
to hear that.
So lay this situation
out for me.
Who's the players
around here?
Which one of these brothers
needs some talkin' to?
Okay.
First off, there's
that dude, Poet.
They say since Adebisi died,
you've been running the homeboys.
That's right, man.
That's right.
They also say you
been doing a shit job.
Look, old man, let me
tell you something--
You think ''old man''
bothers me?
Boy, l done had a whole lot
of men tougher than you,
you that called me worse
didn't make it to old.
My age is my honor
and my strength.
Shit, you think you can just come up
here and take control?
Some people are born leaders,
others are not.
A wise man knows
his own limitations.
You think on that.
We've got a nice
operation going.
- We don't need you fucking things up.
- Chucky, relax.
Now we'd value
your friendship.
We'd even be willing
to cut you a slice.
Be extremely generous.
l'll get back to you.
Back to us?
You take the deal now
or there is no fucking deal.
Pancamo, Morales, l told you dinks
before this classroom is for classes
not your board of directors meetings.
Come on, let's go.
Let's go, move it!
What you waiting for, an engraved
invitation there, Redding? Come on!
Red, man, you know them motherfuckers
is plotting against you, right?
Good, that's what
l want them to do.
You want them to kill you?
l want them to try.
Last night
a Chinese freighter
ran aground off
the Jeb lsland Sound.
When the US Coast Guard
went to evacuate the crew,
they discovered 36 illegal aliens
stowed on board.
Until the State Department can determine
the legal status of the refugees,
the 18 men,
1 2 women, and six children
will be housed
in various state buildings,
including the Oswald
Correctional Facility.
Leo, this is insane.
The state's got 40 other prisons.
Put these men somewhere else.
l got a call from
the Secretary of State.
The Secretary of State asked for help.
l'm not inclined to argue.
What are you looking for an appointment
in the new administration?
- Don't be snarky.
- My question is,
where are we gonna house them? We're on
the brink of overcrowding as it is.
Since this is
a temporary situation,
l thought we might set up some cots
in the common room of Emerald City.
No way. l have only just re-established
some order in there.
You're not gonna
upset the apple cart.
This isn't a matter for discussion.
We have an emergency.
And everyone,
including you, will bend.
- You mean bend over.
- Tim...
l know from a practical side
that this is a pain,
but we cannot lose sight
of the humanitarian issue.
These men and their families
fled repression in China,
paying a sizable amount of money
to book passage on this boat.
From what l read in the papers, the
conditions were worse than slave ships.
They sailed for months,
they crashed, they got arrested.
They're separated from their wives
and their children.
So if we must have them,
let's at least embrace them.
Warden, this is Gao Liu Xio
from the State Department.
- Ms. Gao, a pleasure.
- Thank you.
We have the men
in a bus outside.
Okay, let's get them
to Receiving and Discharge.
Hi, Tim McManus.
They'll be staying in my unit,
so anything l can do to make them
more comfortable,
- you just let me know.
- Excellent. Come with me.
l'm not going to lie to you
and say that life will be easy.
The prisoners in Oz are amongst the most
violent criminals in the country.
But we have added extra correctional
officers to the unit,
and they've all been
instructed to watch over you.
Do any of them
speak English?
l-- l do.
Good, then l'm going
to be relying on you
- to help keep communication going.
- l'm at your service.
Thank you. All right, you all need
to follow Officer Armstrong.
This is America, Gongjin.
Speak English.
Never volunteer.
We are in danger of being
sent back to China.
l will do everything l can
to prove that l belong here.
These people
are our guests,
and l expect you to
treat them as such.
lf any harm comes to them,
the repercussions will be severe.
Now they're going
to be arriving shortly, all right?
Now until they get familiar
with their new surroundings,
we're going to put
the rest of you on lockdown.
Oh come on, what?
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
my heart's breaking.
Lockdown. Let's go.
Move it!
- So are you staying in town tonight?
- Yes.
Doing anything for dinner?
- Are you asking me out on a date?
- Oh no, no,
but we've both
got to eat.
There's a little diner
l know, very informal,
where we could grab a quick bite.
lt's nothing fancy.
Your grandfather is right.
These are bad men.
You got a problem
with the cuisine there, Hop Sing?
- No, no.
- Then move along.
You're holding up
my regular customers.
l wonder how Wan Wa
and Jia Yu are doing.
Mai Shoo Ying is tough.
She look after Wan Wa.
But my son-- they put all
the children in the orphanage.
He's never been
apart from us before.
Hey, guys, this is
my table.
- You say what?
- This is my table.
Get your Chink asses up
and move. Chop, chop.
Oh, hey! No, no.
Stop! We're sorry.
Chuck, that's no way
to treat these poor fellows.
- You their leader?
- No.
- Well, they listen to you.
- Yes.
That makes you
their leader.
You come and see me.
We'll talk, okay?
- All right.
- Okay.
- Do not go.
- How can l not go?
He's a powerful man.
We may need his help.
l wish we had never
got on that boat.
l wish we were
in Tong Du right now.
Starving? You watch our crop
burn in the hot sun.
You watch your daughter die.
l cannot do that.
- lf they send us back--
- l will not go!
l would rather die here
in America.
- Jiu shi.
- Jiu shi, what does that mean?
''Chairman'' like Mao.
l love that.
Jiu Shi Morales.
ln fact it would be
Morales Jiu Shi.
The family name
is always first.
See, now that's what's fucked up about
your side of the world.
The names, the way you read,
the funny alphabet.
- You people do everything backwards.
- Or you people do.
Right.
Mr. Bian, the reason l asked to see you
is because l want to warn you.
You see that man
over there?
- Yes.
- Burr Redding is your enemy.
He hates you
and all your friends.
Why? We have done
nothing to him.
He served in Vietnam.
We are Chinese.
He don't know
the difference.
All he sees is
your yellow skin.
And he has vowed to kill
each and every one of you.
l will go to him.
l will reason with him.
Does he look like
a reasonable man?
Then you must kill him.
Not you necessarily,
but one of your men.
We are simple folk--
farmer, factory worker.
We left China
to escape the killers,
not to become one.
Then from now on l will
call you ''Hombre Muerto.''
- What is that?
- Dead man.
One of the Chinese came to me telling me
that you threatened him.
What are you talking about?
l haven't said two words to any of them.
l've got a lot more reason
to believe him than you,
so l'm gonna
tell you something.
Anything happens at all,
l'll hold you personally responsible.
- That's bullshit.
- Regardless, that's the way it is.
You steer clear,
you understand?
That's wonderful.
Have you heard from Jia Yu?
Tell him that--
that l love him.
And, Wan Wa...
l love you, too.
Okay.
- How does she sound?
- She-- she miss me.
She says Shoo Ying
is bossing everyone around.
Thank you for
the phone call, Jiu Shi.
lt's the least l could do.
Work detail.
What-- what is that?
Oh, we all have
jobs to do.
Oh l-- l would like
to work.
- Yeah?
- You sure?
l would.
l want to do my part.
- Okay, let me go talk to some people.
- Okay.
What's going on, Ousi?
- lshu.
- lshu, sorry.
Not that l'll need to know how to
pronounce your name for much longer.
What is going on?
Well, you see, lshu, you've done
everything l've needed you to do,
and l'm grateful,
but there's just one last thing
l must ask of you.
What?
What's that?
Dying.
My wife, my son.
They will mourn you forever.
Help!
l warned you.
- What?
- Put him in the cage.
- What the fuck for?
- Come on, let's go.
- What the fuck's going on in here?
- Come on, move it!
Oh, you motherfucker.
Come on.
Get-- come on.
Get the fuck in there!
Open up the goddamn door!
Open it up!
No! No!
Any convert, whether he goes
from communist to capitalist
or from six packs a day
to smoke-free
ends up condemning
his former practices.
Because those beliefs didn't work
for him, they can't work for anybody.
His vision becomes narrow,
blinded by the light.
Whether he's transformed
into a Hindu or joins A.A.,
he becomes a fanatic.
lf you ask me, it's the fanatics
who fuck up the world.
lt's the fanatics who think
they've got God on their side.
The rest of us?
We don't need divine light.
ln the dark of night,
all we want is enough light
so that we don't stub our toe
on the way to the toilet.