Mercy is the compassion we feel
for someone else's misfortune.
Mercy compels us to alleviate
that misfortune.
Mercy is a child of charity,
but the sister of justice
because both are about
the invisible link
that exists between people.
Mercy is spontaneous because
misery is involuntary.
At approximately 3:15 P.M.,
as your children were walking home
from school with four classmates,
a blue van pulled up
beside them.
A male Caucasian
stepped out.
The man approached Gary and Holly
saying that you, Mrs. Beecher,
had asked him
to pick them up.
Gary was reluctant at first,
but eventually,
the man persuaded him...
using Pokemon cards.
The van then drove off
to the East side of town.
So what's being done to find them?
Kidnapping is
a waiting game, Sister.
We have to wait
to be contacted.
- And what if you're not?
- Milk cartons.
- Toby.
- Come on. Schillinger did this.
- We have no proof of that.
- Oh, for fuck's sake. Who else?
You come from
a wealthy family.
Most likely we have
a ransom situation.
You are fucking this up,
you asshole.
Find my goddamn kids!
- Oh, my God!
- Find my goddamn kids!
Get him out! Out!
Find my kids!
l don't know anything
about a kidnapping.
Beecher seems
to think you do,
that you're behind this.
He and l have had a lot of shit
happen between us,
so l can understand
him saying that.
But Beecher and l have
one thing in common, too.
We're both fathers.
l lost a son.
l know what he's going through.
l'm sorry about
what happened in the library.
l just got so frustrated.
l know. l know.
You might want to call your mother.
She's pretty upset.
We talked about it in the car.
Toby, the reasons
you're in here, the--
the alcoholism and the hitting
the little Brockwell girl,
your mother and l can't help
but think that we're...
to blame for so much of it.
- Dad, no.
- We failed you growing up.
Look, as much
as l'd like to blame you
for the miserable shithole
my life has become,
what's wrong with me
is inside me.
l own it,
and either l have to control it
or it will control me.
Right now, l just want
to hold my babies.
So our sweet young things
are safe and sound?
- Yeah.
- All right.
Time to kick this thing
into overdrive.
l want you
to send the package.
Dad, you sure?
- Yes.
- 'Cause l been thinking.
Like you know l've never had
a problem with breaking the law.
l'm talking about at most
a couple stolen Çamrys.
This kidnapping...
Keep your voice down.
This kind of thing
is really not my style.
l'll pay you double.
Okay.
- Are you Les Hibitz?
- Yeah.
Tobias Beecher.
Mind if l join you?
- You want to sit with me?
- Yeah.
Nobody ever wants
to sit with me.
l understand you did some
fed time for kidnapping, right?
- Yeah, l was framed.
- Yeah, l'm sure you were.
But l don't know
if you've heard,
but my two children were
abducted recently.
- l had nothing to do with it.
- l know.
What l'm asking is--
l was wondering if you might
be able to look into it.
Find out if somebody
was hired to do the job.
l could ask around,
see what l could find out,
but l wouldn't
hold out much hope.
So, do you like Def Leppard?
Years and years
and years ago,
the Catholic Church made a list
of all the ways we can show mercy.
Feed the hungry,
give drink to the thirsty,
clothe the naked,
shit like that.
Another of them was
ransom the captive.
ln those days,
pirates and infidels and such
would abduct fair maidens
and Christian pilgrims.
God-fearing people were expected
to pay for their return.
Who gets to ransom the captive
in this day and age?
lnstead, we're expected
to visit the imprisoned.
That's right.
Come on down.
Break it up, you two.
- Are you ok?
- Oh shit yeah.
Hey, man, they stab me,
they shoot me,
l ain't going down.
How you doing?
- My kids.
- l heard.
That's fucked up.
l'm sorry.
l feel so goddamn helpless.
l bet.
At least the baby,
Harry, is safe.
Toby, they're gonna
be all right, you hear me?
They're gonna be ok.
They're gonna be fine.
Oh, man.
l missed you.
Me, too.
Keller's back
in Emerald City.
Two love birds
have reunited.
And l hope they enjoy
their evening together.
lt's gonna be
the last night of sleep...
or peace...
that Beecher's gonna have
for a long, long time.
Chris?
Sorry, did l wake you?
Hey.
What's the matter?
Toby, l died...
and there's no white light.
l was there,
but they brought me back.
But l was there, Toby.
l was in hell and l felt everything.
l felt the pain and l felt
the fire for all eternity.
Hey. Hey.
lt's gonna be ok.
No, it's not gonna be ok.
Don't fucking lie to me.
l was there, Toby.
They're bringing me back.
You know what's funny?
You got pissed at me
for talking to Said about God,
but that's what l was
talking to him about.
'Cause if all that's left
for us in this life is Oz,
we better start thinking
about what's next,
what comes after.
Don't let go.
Okay, okay.
Tobias.
l didn't expect to see you here today,
given what's going on.
Well, work helps keep my mind
from caving in on itself.
Oh, l hear that.
lt's a madhouse outside,
though the crowd
of protesters is smaller.
l'm afraid people are getting
used to capital punishment.
Sister Pete,
l need to ask you a favor.
lf l can, you know l will. What?
Talk to Chris.
Now how is it that you ask me
the one thing that l won't do?
He feels terrible.
Tobias, he tried
to use me to get to you.
Now he's using you
to get to me.
l will not play his game.
He's afraid that
if you leave the convent,
he's gonna burn forever.
He's gonna burn all right,
but not for that.
He's gonna burn for all
of the other people he's hurt,
all of the other lives
he's destroyed, including yours.
We've been going
through the records
of various prisoners
at Emerald City.
One pops out as a potential
connection to the kidnapping.
- Who?
- Christopher Keller.
No. Chris is my friend.
Let me see that.
Keller broke every bone
in your body.
- He's the one?
- He saved my life from Schillinger.
l'm telling you,
Schillinger is responsible.
Armed robbery,
assault, kidnapping.
- He wasn't convicted.
- Police suspect him of raping,
torturing and murdering
several homosexual men?
lt can't be him.
lt's not him.
How can you be so sure?
l know Chris, Mother...
intimately.
lntimately?
He's my lover.
Holy shit.
Vern, you better come see this.
What you got?
A package for Tobias Beecher.
Look.
Jesus Christ.
Officer Howell?
We got a problem here.
What the hell is that?
A child's hand.
Leave us alone.
How you holding up?
A few days in the hole
only increases my credibility
with Pancamo, Adebisi and Morales.
Ever spend any time in here?
No.
Good.
You look like shit.
- So l'm in?
- ''So l'm in.''
Adebisi ain't convinced, man.
Looks like you're gonna
have to take another test.
Oh, yeah.
We going to box?
We want to see
if you can take a punch...
or two.
You got a problem
with me, man?
Yeah, you're weak.
Give me gloves.
Well, actually
we're not gonna spar.
- No?
- No.
l'm gonna use you
for a heavy bag.
And the rest of us bet
on how long you stay standing.
Ready?
- Yeah.
- Ding, ding.
That was it.
Fifteen seconds.
l win. Pay up.
Ow!
Yo, real impressive.
Yeah, thanks.
- Your bruises must hurt.
- Uh-huh.
Brought you a little something
to soothe your wounds.
Later.
Yo.
What the fuck is you doing?
The breakfast of champions.
You wanted to see me?
We just took
a straw poll on you.
l voted yes.
- l voted no.
- l abstained.
- A tie.
- How do l break this tie?
There's a final test.
Which is?
You gotta kill somebody.
- Who?
- Anybody.
We don't care.
All right. l'll do it.
Pete, l have terrible news.
- Oh, my God. What?
- The Cardinal is coming.
Cardinal Abgott
is coming to Oz?
He wants to say a mass,
meet with the staff
and then with some prisoners.
You're friends
with him, right?
l worked with him in his office
until he transferred me here.
l... disagreed
with him once too often.
l'm taking the day off.
Oh, no. You can't.
Ray, l have one foot
out of the convent door.
l think hobnobbing
with the Cardinal
would be just a little
hypocritical, don't you?
Yeah, well, he specifically
asked to meet you.
Me? Why?
Apparently this whole thing
started because his eminence
received a letter
from a prisoner.
Which one?
Chris Keller.
Of course.
Raymond.
Cardinal Abgott,
it's good of you to come.
lt's a pleasure
to see you, son.
Let's suit up.
Do you know why
l transferred you to Oswald?
l had too many opinions?
You had too big an ego.
Probably.
Something tells me
that's changed.
- Body of Christ.
- Amen.
- The body of Christ.
l spoke to the head
of your order
Sister Liocarria.
She says you're questioning
your own vocation.
Yes, l am.
Welcome to the club.
You?
My first parish was way out
in the country,
a desolate area.
The pastor was old,
the housekeeper even older.
When winter hit,
it was lonely.
l cried...
and l prayed.
l cried some more...
and prayed even harder.
Well, that's what l'm doing.
Good.
Then whatever you decide
will be the right thing to do.
Thank you.
God bless you, Sister.
As you already know,
the jury has ruled in our favor.
They recognize that
the State was guilty
in all injuries and deaths
caused after the riot.
So they have made
recommendations
that we receive
the full settlement.
45 million.
Oh, yeah!
Before you all go spending
that money, know this,
the State has appealed
the decision.
- Appealed?
- Yes, appealed. lt is an election year.
There is no way that Devlin
will write us a check,
not before November.
Said, you can't goose
this thing along?
As we are all aware,
the legal system moves very slow.
There's no way
we can know when our case
is gonna be coming before
the appellate court.
Took almost 30 years for
the prisoners of Attica to win.
30 fucking years?
Christ.
l'll be ancient.
Like you, Rebadow.
Look, l know
this is frustrating,
but l want you all to see
the court decision this week,
it was a huge hurdle,
a huge victory.
We must remain resolved.
l'll inform you
of anything else.
Yes?
Have you ever
killed anyone?
No.
An extraordinary experience
watching the life fade
from someone's eyes.
Even as he was dying,
Hernandez's instinct
was to kill me
for killing him.
Survival meant less to him
than revenge.
And this preamble
is taking us where?
Jason Kramer. You've successfully
gotten him a new trial.
Yes.
l know you've been under a lot
of pressure from the other Muslims
not to get involved
with the case.
- Yes?
- l think you should listen to them.
And you think this
because...
Last night l had a premonition.
Kramer will go free.
Rebadow, l'm gonna
tell you something.
l'm gonna explain to you.
Jason Kramer is guilty
of murdering his lover.
l have seen the trial transcripts
and all the evidence.
He will be convicted again.
Then why did you fight
to get him a new trial?
The jury voted against Kramer
because he was gay.
So this whole thing
is theoretical for you.
There is nothing theoretical
about justice.
And if Kramer goes free...
That's not gonna happen.
You'd better pray
you're right.
We have a request for a meeting
regarding your case.
Yeah?
A meeting with who?
The homicide detective
who arrested you.
Robert Stransky.
Here's the deal.
You got this cocksucker
a new trial, right?
My doctor tells me l got three
or four more months to live.
Now before l die,
l want to make certain
things straight.
l want you to know
l tampered
with the evidence.
l couldn't find the murder weapon,
so l went to the kitchen.
l opened a drawer
and took out a kitchen knife,
l smeared it
in the blood
and l dropped it
next to his body.
His fingerprints are
all over that knife.
No.
No, they weren't.
My pal in forensics
doctored up the tests.
And you would be willing
to give a deposition?
To go into court
and say this?
l know this fucker's
guilty as shit,
but l want to buy back
a piece of my soul.
Yeah, if you want me to,
l'll yell it
from the prison roof.
Ok, sweetheart?
We go public
with this information,
the press will get
a seven inch boner.
Yes.
And you say the only witness,
the guy at airborn, is dead?
Yes.
l don't know, man.
l'm feeling like
maybe this could swing in my favor.
Yes. Kramer...
l'm recusing myself
from the case.
What's that mean?
lt means l am resigning
as your lawyer...
immediately.
To instruct the ignorant,
counsel the doubtful,
to admonish the sinners.
ln order for these
works of mercy to happen,
you need two things:
someone in distress
and someone with the capacity
to help them.
ln other words,
an ignoramus can't instruct
another ignoramus,
and a sinner
can't admonish a sinner.
Today in the retrial
of Jason Kramer,
who had previously been
convicted for the murder of his lover,
the jury reached a verdict,
finding Kramer not guilty.
The Adamsville native, who has
served nearly two years,
is expected to be released
from the Oswald Correctional Facility
sometime this week.
ln other news,
the state's jobless rate fell
slightly over
the past month 3.8°/%.
Preliminary figures
released yesterday
by the state's
labor department
show that employers created
nearly 1,000 new jobs.
Allah is not
listening, brother.
He is deaf to you.
Warden, a word?
l know that you've been
having meetings recently
with members
of the local community
regarding possible replacements
for Tim McManus.
- Yes.
- l also know that you talked
about hiring an African-American
for the job.
- What, you got my office bugged?
- l want to come
and see you, warden.
Discuss with you
the kind of man
who you should consider.
Well, l'd love that, Said,
but l've already hired someone.
ln fact,
he's on his way in now.
His name is Martin Querns.
l want to thank you
for this opportunity.
l've heard about Emerald City
for years now.
Well, the place started out
as an experiment,
but unfortunately
it pretty much failed.
Well, l don't know.
Maybe the first stage failed,
but like any
worthwhile experiment,
we need to try different methods
till we figure out what works.
Well, for me the most
important elements are,
one, keeping a lid
on the racial tension;
and two, keeping a lid
on the violence in general.
Those are my priorities
as well.
Do l have your permission
to do what l feel is necessary
to keep the peace?
Yes. l'll let you have
a fairly free hand...
until you fuck up.
Well, l can't ask
for any more than that.
Okay, everybody, listen up.
l want to introduce you
to Martin Querns,
the new unit manager.
He has a vast range of experience,
having worked in both
federal prisons
as well as
state detention centers.
The warden is correct.
l have served in many
correctional facilities,
but what he didn't say
was that, like most of you,
l come from the streets.
l'm not some candy-ass,
white liberal
looking to turn you
into better citizens.
l intend to meet with
each of you individually,
but until that time,
keep one principle in mind:
don't fuck with Querns.
That's all.
l wanted to meet with you first
because as l understand,
you're one of the leaders
around here
in terms of the drug trade.
As a teen-ager l worked
for Slim Sam Colby.
You know him?
Slim Sam weighed
about 300 lbs, of course.
l worked my way up through
his organization
until Ricky J. Lee
blew Slim sam's head off.
l decided the moment
had come to retire.
And the point
of all this?
To let you know
l know every trick you got.
l'm smarter than you.
- You smarter than me?
- Oh, yeah.
'Cause unlike you,
l never got caught.
How do you keep that thing
on your head?
Now what are you
gonna do? Hit me?
Sit down.
l want you to listen to me good,
Simon Adebisi.
To my mind,
drugged-out prisoners
make for a quiet cell block,
so you can sell whatever
the fuck you want
to whoever you want
to sell it to. l don't care.
l'm gonna be looking
the other way.
On one condition, man.
Jeez, you are smart.
One condition: no violence.
l mean none, zero.
Agreed?
- That's it, no violence?
- Yup.
He just want me to make sure
that everybody
obeys all the rules
all the time.
This could be a trick.
- Yeah.
- l don't think so.
Like the way things were
back in the old days.
We Sicilians controlled our own streets
so the cops backed away.
Little ltaly was
the safest place in the city.
- Look, l vote yes.
- Me, too.
All right.
l'm glad you called.
l've actually been meaning to call you.
Well, Leo...
after the shooting
and after Diane left,
l admit that l went south.
l mean, singing at Officer
Howard's memorial service,
that was just crazy.
But l've had time to rest
and relax and think.
- Tim--
- l'm ready to come back.
- Come back?
- To run Emerald City.
You can't.
The job's not available.
- What?
- l've hired someone to replace you.
- Well, unhire him.
- No.
Leo, l took the heat
for that gun coming into Em City,
but l read in the papers
it was actually Clayton Hughes,
your little protege,
that brought it in.
Yes, and he's been charged.
He's out on bail
until his trial starts in a few weeks.
- l want my unit back.
- How many times you want to hear no?
Leo, this is my life.
l'm well aware of that.
l do have another offer.
Holt's retiring.
l need someone to run Unit B.
l'll take it.
Well, well. Look who's here
to join the party.
The arrest of Busmalis
and the Cardinal's visit
can clearly help
the situation.
Our most recent poll shows
that 42°/% of the public
now believe
the prison system is well run.
That's up 16 points since
after the Em City shooting.
We're not getting any backlash because
of Bellinger's execution?
A little.
But capturing Miguel Alvarez
would balance it out.
Unfortunately,
there's still no sign of him.
Our biggest concern
right now is Clayton Hughes.
He's out on bail
and he's been making
a lot of speeches
condemning the Governor.
l know.
You have a relationship
with Hughes, don't you?
Clayton's father and l
were both rookies at Oz.
His dad died in my arms,
killed by a prisoner back in 1982.
Well, we could use that.
You need to talk
to the man, Leo.
Tell him to shut up.
Time for me
to charm the D.A.
Desmond...
get me Clayton Hughes.
What l'm asking is for you
to cool the rhetoric.
Rhetoric?
l speak the truth.
Devlin represents all that
is evil in white society,
l can't understand
how you could even think
of running with him
as Lieutenant Governor.
Clayton, you lived a very
protected childhood.
Oh, here we go.
Not everything is tied
to my father's death.
Yes, it is.
You only see the world
as black and white.
Trust me, life is gray,
as gray as these fucking walls.
Now, l don't love
James Devlin,
but l don't see him
as Satan either.
Somebody must stop him,
and soon.
lntegrity.
lt's what sets real leaders apart
from typical politicians.
One man running
for governor has...
You Americans think just
because you have democracy,
you're better
than everybody else.
Elections are not what makes
a country great.
Yeah? And what does?
Vodka?
How do you say it?
To be ruthless.
- Who's Ruth?
- Huh?
l don't know
anybody named Ruth.
Listen, Nikolai,
l've been thinking.
You and me,
we can make a lot of money
renting that cell phone
out to the slugs around here.
- ''We?''
- Yeah. We're partners now, right?
No. The phone
is mine, O'Reily.
The more people know about it, the
sooner someone blabs to the hacks.
So just keep
your mouth shut tight.
God, l wish l could find where
his fucking hiding place is.
Fuck.
- Like a treasure hunt?
- Yeah.
Yeah, like a motherfucking
treasure hunt, Cyril.
Listen, l want you to search
every square inch of Em City,
see if you can find
that cell phone.
But the trick is,
you can't let anyone know,
especially Stanislofsky,
what you're doing.
- Okay?
- Okay. Can l start now?
Right now. Go ahead.
l did just what you wanted.
l didn't say anything
to anybody.
Good boy. You didn't
find the cell phone, though, did you?
- Nope.
- And you looked all over?
- Yup.
- Where does he keep that fucking thing?
Hi, how you doing?
l'm gonna kill
that motherfucker.
l'm gonna fucking kill him.
Yes?
- Dr. Nathan is here.
- Send her in.
Gloria.
May l hug you?
Yeah.
- Sit down, please.
- Thanks.
Can l get you anything,
do anything?
Yeah, you can stop being
so goddamn nice.
All right.
No, l didn't mean that.
Leo, l know you know
what i'm going through,
with your daughter
getting raped.
Well, she's better now.
ln time you'll get better, too.
l want to come back to work.
So soon?
lf l don't come back now,
l never will.
Gloria...
l don't want you to quit,
but l also don't want you
to rush yourself.
Healing is a process,
a slow process.
Not for me.
There's only one thing
l need to do to make myself feel better.
And what's that?
Confront Ryan O'Reily.
l know you're responsible.
For what?
For me getting raped.
- No way!
- Don't deny it. Don't fucking deny it.
- Gloria.
- l know.
l know.
You called somebody
and asked them for a favor.
Why would l do that?
Because the session the other
day didn't go your way.
Because you couldn't
manipulate me.
Because you're
a twisted fuck.
You want me to say
that l called a pal of mine
and l had him beat you
and rape you?
ls that what you want
me to say?
Yes.
Fine. l did.
You happy?
Yes.
The one thing through
all this shit
you've said over and over again
is that you love me
and all you wanted was for me to say
l love you back.
Well, l came today
to tell you,
to see your face
when l tell you
that'll never,
ever happen.
ln fact,
it's the opposite.
l hate you.
l will always hate you
until we're both dead
in the ground.
l will hate you!
Fine.
Then tell me
something else.
When he was fucking you,
did you think of me?
- Gloria!
- Stop it!
Stop!
Back off!
Officer!
Did you think of me, huh?
Did you fucking think of me?
Come on, Gloria!
Were you thinking
of me? Huh? Huh?
Another work of mercy:
to comfort the afflicted.
But you see,
there are a lot of ways
to comfort somebody,
and a lot of afflicted
just don't want to be comforted.
Gloria Nathan has decided
to press charges against you,
so you might be looking
at another five years
added onto your sentence.
Five years. Gee.
And l have to file a report.
Fine.
l know you pretty well, Ryan.
And it may seem crazy,
but l have to tell you
that l think you're lying.
l don't think you had anything
to do with Gloria's rape.
l said l did it.
l did it.
Okay?
Okay.
When do we see Dr. Nathan
and those nice people again?
We're not.
lt's over.
Oh.
They still hate me?
No, Cyril,
they don't hate you.
They hate me.
Listen, that man
that you killed...
- Dr. Nathan's husband?
- Yeah.
That wasn't
your fault, okay?
Okay.
And Hamid Khan,
that was my doing, too.
All right?
You gotta know that, Cyril.
l'm guilty,
not you.
l remember
when l was little
Mama used to take us
to confession
and we'd go
in the big wooden box
and tell all our sins.
And Mama said
by telling God,
our sins were washed away.
Remember?
Yeah.
Yeah, l remember.
Bless me, Father,
for l have sinned.
Today, l lied.
l told someone l did something
that l didn't do.
Why?
Because it's what
she wanted to hear.
Because it's what she needs to know
to make herself whole again.
Fugitive Miguel Alvarez
continues to evade capture
as police widen their search
across the state.
Alvarez,
along with another prisoner,
Agamemnon Busmalis,
escaped...
Look who's out
of the hole.
Agamemnon
was recently captured
and returned to Oswald
earlier this week.
- How are you?
- What are you doing?
Anybody here from Cleveland?
All right.
Being free,
even for a few hours,
was so wonderful.
l mean, l had no money,
no overcoat,
it was cold out there,
but man, oh man,
l was so happy,
l stopped in the middle of the street
and did a little dance.
Of course,
that's when they caught me.
You were standing outside
Miss Sally's house.
Yeah, l was hoping to catch
a glimpse of her in the flesh,
maybe even exchange
a word or three.
- What the fuck happened to Alvarez?
- l don't know.
Soon as we crawled out
of the tunnel, he vamoosed.
You know what l miss
more than anything about being free?
Taking a bath.
l hate showers.
To sit and soak
in a hot tub,
- Bubbles everywhere.
- Bubbles.
l'll bet you even had a little
rubber ducky, huh, Nikolai?
Rubber ducky?
- Yeah.
- What is rubber ducky?
Product of capitalist
imperialism.
What do you miss most, Bob?
l have nothing
to say to you.
Bob, please, talk to me.
This silence is grueling.
Why are you mad at me?
The fact that you don't know
makes the offense worse.
You're pissed off
that l tried to escape?
l'm pissed off that
you didn't ask me to go with you.
- Oh.
- That you never ever told me
you were digging
another tunnel.
- Oh, well. l had my reasons.
- Which were?
- Well...
- What?
l thought
you'd slow me down.
- Slow you down?
- l'm sorry, Bob.
- l'm as vital as l ever was.
- l know.
- l killed a man.
- l know!
Fuck you.
Oh, shit.
Tomorrow at dawn,
Shirley Bellinger
will be executed for the drowning of her
eight-year-old daughter.
State law allows Bellinger the right
to choose her own means of death,
and Bellinger, the first woman
executed by the State
since 1841,
has asked to be hanged.
Man, l can't listen
to this fucking shit anymore.
Yeah, depress
the fuck out of me.
Adebisi, weren't you
in love with Bellinger?
No.
Yeah, you had a little
crush on her.
She had a crush on me.
lf l had to die,
l'd go lethal injection, man.
Me, l'd O.D.
An ounce or two of heroin,
straight up.
The State is not going
to give you drugs.
Ain't lethal injection a drug?
They get a doctor to decide where
the knot on the noose should be,
depending on the person's
height or weight,
so that the noose snaps
the neck in the right place?
l remember the day of my execution
l was terrified.
But then when l didn't die,
l felt like such a coward.
Anti-capital punishment
protesters continue to march
outside the prison,
though officials claim
the number is considerably
smaller than was expected.
Bye-bye Bellinger, huh?
Yeah. l was kind of hoping
to see her one more time,
but the hacks have delayed
all mail deliveries to death row
till after the execution.
She was quite a gal.
Reminds me of my late wife.
My Arlene.
She showed me her cunt.
l was mopping up the floor
outside her cell and wham, bam.
Showed me her cunt.
Next item:
Shirley Bellinger's execution
is scheduled
for dawn tomorrow.
- Bye.
- Peter Marie...
No, no, no, Leo. l agreed that l
wouldn't protest publicly again,
but that doesn't mean l have to sit here
and listen to the grim details.
But Bellinger has asked you
to do something for her.
What?
After she's dead, she wants you
to collect her personal possessions.
She doesn't want anyone else
touching her things.
What am l supposed
to do with them?
Well, she says dispose
of them as you wish.
Okay. Can l go now?
Yeah.
Ray, she's asked for you
to pray with her.
Right.
Shirley, have you
any thoughts
- as the hour approaches?
- Thoughts?
Of course l have thoughts.
How could l not?
- Would you share them with us?
- Sure.
l'm wondering why anyone cares
what my thoughts are.
Sure as hell didn't care when
my husband was drunk and beat me
or when my father-in-law
raped me.
No, it wasn't until
l killed my daughter,
till l did something horrific
that what l think matters.
All l wanted was for someone
to pay attention,
and now that you
finally are,
l see that my life,
then or now, isn't worth shit.
Oh, if l say shit,
you can't use this, right?
l'm not supposed to say,
''shit,'' on the air, am l?
Aren't you curious to know who got
Shirley pregnant here in Oz?
No.
lt's time.
Good morning, sugar.
How you doing?
Woke up with a crick
in my neck.
Must've been sleeping funny.
- Maybe it's stress.
- ln any case,
the hanging'll
take care of the crick.
- What'd l-- what'd l miss?
- Nothing yet, Natalie.
- And Miles is sleeping?
- Yeah.
Man has no sense
of propriety.
So what'd you have
for your final meal?
A nice Slim-Fast milkshake.
Girl's got to
protect her figure,
even if she's a corpse.
Ready?
Quite.
Sorry to get you up
so early, Father.
Warden, Officer Lopresti
has been coming
to my cell every night
and fucking me.
- That's a lie.
- You and l will talk later.
Yes, sir.
- Bitch.
- You know that--
- Would you mind solving a mystery?
- lf l can.
When you got pregnant
here in Oz, who was the father?
- Was it Lopresti?
- Oh, no.
He wasn't working
death watch then.
My lover was Satan
in the form of a man.
Which man?
A lady never reveals
such secrets.
But l'll give you a hint.
Neither rain nor snow...
- Goodbye, Moses.
- So long, Shirley.
See you around, kiddo.
Save me a seat
at the beauty salon.
- The Lord is my shepherd...
- l shall not want.
He makes me lie
down in green pastures.
He leads me beside still waters.
He restores my soul.
He guides me in the paths
of righteousness
for His name's sake.
Even though l walk
through the valley
of the shadow of death,
l will fear no evil...
You prepare a table before me
in the presence of mine enemies.
You anoint
my head with oil.
l will dwell in the house
of the Lord forever.
Amen.
No. No, no.
l changed my mind.
l don't want to die this way.
- l don't want to die.
- lt's too late.
- No. No.
- Shirley!
Please, please! No!
Please! Please.
No! Please, please!
Oh God, oh God!
Not yet!
Not yet, not yet,
not yet!
Oh, sweet heaven.
Oh, sweet Jesus.
l'm sorry for all l've done.
Please, please, please,
intercede for me now.
Oh, sweet Jesus.
Help me, sweet Jesus.
Help me, sweet Lord.
l'm sorry
for all l've done.
Please, please,
please intercede for me now.
Oh, sweet Jesus.
Oh, help me, Mary, Jesus.
Hey, Sister.
Can l have her mirror?
Sure.
l'm the next one to die,
you know.
Yes. l know.
The final act of mercy,
to bury the dead,
to pray for the dead
and the living.
We are merciful,
not just for
humanitarian reasons.
We are merciful because
we ourselves want to be saved.
God expects mercy from us.
God demands it.
And how much mercy
does he show us?
''Kyrie eleison.''
That means
''Lord have mercy.
Christ have mercy.
Please.''