"Neither snow, nor rain, nor heat,
nor gloom of night...
"stays these couriers from the swift
completion of their appointed rounds."
So says the United States Postal Service
in their sunshine motto...
adapted from the Ancient Greek
historian Herodotus.
Back then, "swift" could have meant
a year and a day.
Now it's 10:00 a.m.
The next morning anywhere...
from here to Cochabamba.
People all over the globe
every afternoon stand at their mailboxes...
wondering what might be inside.
You never know what to expect.
And in Oz, most times...
the best part is the expectation.
Prisoner number 99C124, William Cudney.
Convicted February 10, '99.
Murder in the first degree.
Sentence: Life without the possibility
of parole.
She got an abortion behind your back,
without telling you.
I forget what abortion is.
It's when the baby goes to Heaven
without ever getting born.
Let me get this straight.
You aim for the doctor,
but you got the son instead.
- No, I aimed for the son.
- You took out the kid on purpose?
Yeah. Now that doctor knows how I feel.
He killed my baby, I killed his.
What are you gonna say to him
when you see him?
Who?
The doctor's son up in Heaven.
I already know what I'm gonna say
to Dr. Nathan's husband...
if they let me in.
Where the fuck have you been?
Come on. We don't got a lot of time left.
Put these on.
- No.
- Cyril, don't start with me.
- I don't wanna box. I don't have to box.
- Yeah, you do.
No, Mr. Cudney said I don't have to.
- Cudney?
- Yeah.
God doesn't want me to box.
Okay, no boxing today.
- You're not mad?
- No.
As a matter of fact, I think
you should listen to what Mr. Cudney says.
It's okay.
O'Reily. You come to join
our prayer meeting?
Yeah.
"Woe is me.
This is a sickness and I must bear it."
First you go tell my brother it's okay to box.
Then you promise me
you'll never talk to him again.
Got that?
I never had much use for the Bible before.
Mind if I keep this?
- No.
- Yeah, I didn't think so.
Gloria.
- Watch yourself, O'Reily.
- Cocksucker.
- Yo, Bricks.
- O'Reily.
You're the only one that get that shit right.
You're checkin' out the competition?
Man, they better pray.
My man Bricks
about to wipe the canvas with them.
I don't know, man. I saw Khan
working out in the gym. He's peak.
- So is my nigger here.
- Let's go get high.
Hold on.
You think you ought to get high
on your first fight?
Shit, yeah. I'm Mike Tyson, man.
I party, then I fight, then I party some more.
See you.
Pancamo.
Put me down for five Grovers on Khan.
- It's a big bet.
- I got money to burn, man.
Hamid?
Yes?
You should know that Wangler's
been talking trash about you and Said.
It's time you taught that heathen homeboy
a lesson.
Don't worry, I intend to win.
In the name of Allah.
Yeah, whatever. Just kick his ass.
Yeah, right.
Kenny "Bricks" Wangler!
And in this corner, Hamid Khan!
Listen to me at all times.
Touch gloves and go to your corners.
Ready! Ring the bell!
Stick a punch, Khan!
Bricks, nice one, man.
You're like Tyson, all right. Cecily Tyson!
A package arrives unexpected. You open it.
Sometimes, it's a gift...
bottle of vintage wine,
let's say, from a relative.
Sometimes, it's from the Unabomber.
An innocent-looking box that goes boom.
Yo, those Muslims fuck with us,
now it's our turn to fuck with them.
I got a poem. I got a poem, man.
Ever since I got back in Oz,
I ain't been writing no poetry.
But I got inspired by something I saw
the other day.
So, this poem right here
is dedicated to Minister Kareem Said.
"That's it
"I figured you easy
"All you wanna do is get your palm greasy
"Capitalize
"See, fucking America been in your eyes
"For more than 450 years
"And now you wanna hide your tears
"In your so-called Allah-given mission
to help your brothers
"Well, Allah gave me a vision
and I'm gonna tell all the others
"Talking about revolution
What I saw, that was revelation
"You frolicking with the Devil's maiden
"Now you happy
'cause now you can manipulate her think
"Well, I'm gonna put you on to something
while we locked up here in this clink
"While you trying to get us all
into the Heaven above
"When she forget
about your contradictorial ass
"Make sure you hide them bloody gloves"
This has gone from a private humiliation
to a public one.
- You disgrace us all.
- You have a choice, Said.
Her or us.
You either promise
to never see that woman again...
or you are finished.
Finished?
We'll choose someone else to lead.
Tell me what's wrong.
I've been getting these phone calls...
threatening phone calls,
demanding that I stay away from you.
Stay away from me?
I saved the tape from the machine.
I thought maybe...
you might want it,
or the lawyer or somebody.
- Did you change your telephone number?
- Yeah.
But I can't just move.
What if they find out where I live?
I just don't understand.
Why are they telling me
to stay away from you?
Don't you worry about that.
I'll speak with Zelman.
He'll know best how to handle this.
- How to protect you.
- I don't want to stay away from you.
Fuck them. Oh, God, sorry.
No, you're right.
Fuck them.
Tell me neither of you know anything
about threatening calls to Tricia Ross.
Tell me.
Because whoever it was will pay.
In this life or the next.
When I got married,
I got my wife's name tattooed on my arm.
Pretty stupid, huh?
Like a marriage is ever gonna last
as long as a fucking tattoo.
I told Shannon that I wanted a divorce...
'cause of what I feel for Gloria.
I still love Gloria,
and I try to fight it but I can't.
She's under my skin, man.
She's under my fucking skin.
Come on, man,
I'll kick the shit out of that motherfucker.
- All right? One love!
- You'll have fun getting your ass whipped.
You ask us to help you take out
Wangler, Pierce, Poet...
then you say wait.
I don't want to kill them...
or there will be a war between us
and the other homeboys.
- Just want to slow them down.
- He's right.
We got to make the deed
look like an accident.
Poet and Pierce first.
I have my own plans for Wangler.
Bricks! Damn. Bricks, man!
- I need to talk to you.
- What?
It's bad news.
- Your wife's dead.
- What?
She was shot, execution style.
- Oh, shit.
- That's too bad, yo.
Real sorrowful, Kenny. Real sorrowful.
- There's more.
- What?
She was found in the apartment
with another man. A Ronnie Smith.
Oh, damn. Ronnie. That was my boy.
They were found in bed together.
I've scheduled some time for you
to see Sister Peter Marie.
My baby. How's my son?
He's fine.
He was at your mother's at the time.
Amen.
- Anything I can do?
- No.
Do the cops know who did this shit?
They think it was drug related.
Can I go to the funeral?
I'll see what I can do.
I thought I was gonna die
to keep from laughing.
Hold on, wait.
What about when I gave him this face?
No, don't.
Yo, Kenny, you wanted that bitch dead
and Ronnie dead...
now they dead. Who loves you, baby?
- Y'all do, yo.
- Handle it, right?
Let's go get high.
Of course, any kind of letter from
the outside is a potential bomb...
blowing up in your face with memories
of what life was like...
before the gates slammed shut.
Before someone,
definitely not your momma...
screamed, "Lights out!"
Sometimes the sweeter the letter,
the more bitter the aftertaste.
"My dear son...
"I woke up today dreaming of
what life would be like when you are free.
"Telling myself that every day
is one day closer to you coming home.
"One day closer to us being together again.
"Everything here is the same.
"The neighborhood is the same.
"Even the faces, everyone looks the same.
"Is everything there okay?
"Is there anything we can do?
"We miss you.
"We love you."
I can't stand the pain.
- I didn't see a thing.
- What about you?
Lockdown!
Junior, what up?
Junior, why we in lockdown?
Welcome back, Kenny.
Pity what happened to Poet and Pierce.
- They gonna live?
- For now.
- But you know life is fragile, man.
- What about me?
How you doing with that program, man?
You meet with Rivera yet, face to face?
No. Just, you know,
mostly talking to Sister Peter Marie.
- About?
- This and that.
As long as "this" doesn't connect to "that"...
you're safe with me.
I want to warn you, Miguel,
there's no way to predict...
the outcome emotionally
of facing Officer Rivera or his wife.
When you blinded him, you hurt them both.
And they may have no sympathy...
for any pain or guilt you're feeling.
So why don't you tell me what you did
to Eugene Rivera?
You know what I did.
I don't see why we gotta
waste time rehashing it.
We have all the time we need.
It's very important to articulate
what you've done.
So, when was it?
Last summer.
- Why did you do it?
- I don't know.
You know, I was all fucked up and shit.
Some stuff going on, and I got tense.
I don't know, you know. It just happened.
What just happened?
- What did you, Miguel Alvarez, do?
- Shit!
- I cut his eyes really bad.
- How bad?
I stabbed them. You know, I stabbed them.
His eyes, you know.
The scalpel...
I dropped it.
When it hit the floor...
it made this ringing sound.
Okay.
Would you like to sit down?
Why did you do it?
I already told you.
- It's 'cause of tension and shit.
- No, Miguel.
Why you did this. Something so deliberate.
You're gonna have to tell Eugene why,
and he's going to ask.
I will.
Why can't you tell me?
Because I don't owe it to you.
This is who I want to sit down with.
Face to face and ask why.
- He's here now, Eugene.
- Really?
So what's his answer?
I don't hear his voice.
All I hear is voices that sound like my own...
but they don't say why Alvarez did this.
They don't tell me why I deserve it.
What happened was not your fault.
And God is not going to answer
your questions...
in a big booming voice.
He's going to answer you
through talking to Alvarez.
So why don't you tell me
what you want to say to him.
I keep thinking
someone is gonna open a door...
and let me out of this dark room.
What else?
- What else do you wanna say?
- I can't. Not in front of you.
Come on, I'm a big girl.
Go ahead, whatever it is. Say it.
I hate you, Alvarez...
you fucking motherfucker.
'Cause of you I gotta carry around
all this shit in the dark.
If it wasn't for Tina,
I would have killed myself already.
Sometimes I think I should kill myself
for her sake...
so she could start a new life without me.
Some days, Alvarez, I wish you would have
killed me instead of doing this.
I can't cry anymore. Did you know that?
You made it so I can't cry.
Junk mail.
Selling you this, promising you that.
Publishers Clearing House...
you got
your American Family Sweepstakes...
You got Ed McMahon warning you
to open that envelope...
because you could be a millionaire.
And you know you can never win...
so you toss it.
But what if you made the wrong choice?
What if this was
the one-in-a-trillion time you win?
Man, this sexual harassment thing
is eating away at me.
State settles out of court,
reinstates Howell to her job...
which implies my guilt.
But I'm not fucking guilty.
You're a victim of the times, my friend.
Years ago, a woman complained
of workplace harassment...
no one believed her. No one even cared.
Today, it's assumed that every guy
in every office is an ass-grabbing pig.
- Which, of course, we are.
- No, I'm not!
Come on. You said you fucked every woman
that worked in this place...
except for Sister Peter Marie.
So I slept around.
It's always been mutual.
I would never force my way on a woman,
use my position to get laid.
- Prove it.
- How?
Don't let the state settle. Take her to court.
Get Nathan, and Wittlesey,
and Sister Peter Marie...
to testify on your behalf.
- You know, fight Howell.
- The odds are against me.
When are they ever in your favor?
For the media,
this is like a seven-course meal.
Meaning, if I wanna take this any further,
I better be prepared to see my face on TV...
- and in the headlines.
- Yes.
And if the public only half listens,
only retains half of what they read...
the story will burn hot for a few days...
you'll look guilty at first,
regardless of the facts...
then the story will cool.
By the time we win, no one will know.
But you'll have to carry the stigma
of those first few days with you...
for the rest of your life.
Gloria, what have you heard
about this harassment case against Tim?
Claire Howell in solitary
says that Tim had her fired...
because she stopped having sex with him.
I don't believe it, do you?
No.
But?
I dated Tim.
You know, when I was separated.
When it comes
to sex and relationships he's...
I don't know. Today, anything's possible.
Pete, Gloria, I'm glad you're both here.
I'm putting together my case...
and I'd like you both
to be character witnesses.
- Sure.
- Thanks.
- Gloria?
- Yeah, I'll let you know.
What? You don't believe Claire Howell,
do you?
No, I just want to talk to her, hear her side.
Her side?
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
That you think
what she's saying might be true?
Which means I'm lying, which means
you think I'm capable of abusing women.
No, I didn't mean...
Thanks a lot. Thanks for the vote
of fucking confidence.
Tim, wait a...
How's Dee Dee?
She misses her grandma. So do I.
We got all manner of men in here.
Men who've raped women, beaten them,
murdered them.
Ryan O'Reily had Gloria's husband killed
because Ryan loved her so much.
I remember thinking at the time:
"Such passion...
"Could I ever feel such passion?"
You know,
I was gonna fight this harassment charge.
I was gonna ask you and Gloria
to testify on my behalf...
build a case because Howell is lying.
I didn't force her to do anything.
- Then why not fight it?
- Because I am guilty.
Of using her, her body.
Of not giving a shit about her...
about her feelings for me,
about her feelings for herself.
Now I know I did the same thing
to my ex-wife.
To Gloria.
To you.
Diane, if I asked you to testify on my behalf,
would you have done it?
Sure.
'Cause what we had was real...
if only for a moment.
Prisoner number 99K87 1, Yuri Kosygin.
Convicted March 23, '99.
Eight counts murder in the first degree,
four counts attempted murder...
illegal possession of a firearm.
Sentence: Life imprisonment
without the possibility of parole.
Nikolai Stanislofsky, Yuri Kosygin.
Are you here to kill me?
Okay...
according to your work assignment...
you're to be here in the library
from noon till 3:00...
helping out the librarian, you know...
Rearranging books on the shelf.
You're also to take the book cart
to the hospital ward...
and to the AIDS ward, and Unit E.
- You understanding any of this?
- Yes.
Breathe or something every once in a while.
Sit over there till Mrs. Hubble comes back.
You're Kosygin, right? I heard of you.
The most brutal hitter in Little Odessa.
Antonio Nappa.
I'm extending my hand to you in friendship.
I don't need your friendship.
Fine.
Let me tell you something.
My boys control everything that goes
in and out of this joint.
Drugs, cigarettes, gambling.
You decide to start your bullshit here,
you won't live till morning.
You Italians.
So melodramatic.
Yes?
Got word from Mr. Nappa.
Your pal, what's-his-name...
needs to learn a little respect.
Kosygin is no pal of mine.
I'm a Jew. He's Cossack.
In my community,
he's feared for his savagery.
You Sicilians think you're so tough.
He would cut out your heart,
eat it, and not think twice.
Yeah, well, you better talk to him.
Before I do.
- So what do you think?
- About what?
The new guy, Kosygin.
I tried to chat with him during dinner.
He sat there frozen like the tundra.
- He scares the living shit out of me.
- Me, too.
Lights out.
- What you got there, Busmalis?
- I wrote Miss Sally a fan letter.
Oh, my God! Look.
- Fucking thing's autographed.
- They're fake.
- What?
- They're fake, the autographs.
- They're done by a machine.
- How do you know that?
All right, Miss Sally's may be real,
but not the puppets'. Especially not Nooter.
- Why not?
- He's got no hands. How's he gonna write?
With his mouth.
If he can swing a mallet with it,
he can certainly write with it.
There's a letter.
"Dear Agamemnon, thank you for writing.
Nooter, Pecky, and I are happy...
"that you like our show.
Keep watching, Miss Sally."
Form letter.
You're a cynical bastard.
Do you think Miss Sally sits and reads
every piece of mail she gets?
With a rack like that,
she'll be getting a million letters a day.
- They got a secretary to send that shit out.
- No. Really?
Live in your fantasy world.
What the hell do I care?
I got an idea.
We should write Miss Sally
and ask her to come visit.
- Visit?
- Sorry, bro. Miss Sally ain't coming to Oz.
She might. Who knows? I'll write her. Now.
Man, I'd still like to fuck her.
I wouldn't mind a four-way
with Nooter and Pecky.
What?
Visiting hours.
- Now I'll go see my family.
- Man, your people don't quit.
That's okay, bro.
Long as they keep bringing them goodies.
- No shit.
- One of these days...
I'm gonna have to tag along
just to thank your mom myself, okay?
Where's Papi?
What happened?
Papi had a stroke.
A stroke?
- When?
- Two nights ago at home.
Mommy was off from work, thank God.
- He's in intensive care.
- Shit. He's gonna make it?
They're doing what they can,
that's what the doctor said.
- I called him the other day to say sorry.
- For what?
Cursing Isabella.
But before I could...
we started talking about something else.
Something stupid. What was it?
God damn it, what was it?
- Don't worry about it.
- No, I can't remember!
I called to say sorry, but before I could
he asked me something first and I...
- Fuck!
- Keep it down, Ricardo.
Did he say anything to you guys?
After the last visit?
- About what?
- Stuff I said. Was he mad?
Carlo, it's okay. I don't think he was.
He loves you.
You wanna sleep, go back to your cell.
Yesterday, a letter arrived in Oz
postmarked May 7, 1965.
Thirty-four years. Must have got stuck
in the sorting machine or something.
Anyway, the inmate it's addressed to
is long dead.
So they take the envelope...
throw it in the dead-letter box,
without even opening it.
Now nobody's ever gonna know
what was inside.
Clayton, what are you still doing here?
Where did it happen, Leo?
I wanna know the exact spot
where my father died.
- Clayton...
- Show me.
Here. Right here.
You know, I've been wondering.
You think whoever killed Dad is still alive?
Still in Oz?
I got to wonder, is the guy
I'm standing over in the library...
the same animal who stabbed my dad?
Rebadow.
Seventeen years ago,
a CO was shanked during lunch.
- Do you remember?
- So many years, so many killings.
- They all blend into one.
- The CO's name was Samuel Hughes.
Your father?
Yes. Do you remember him?
I'm sorry.
- You have to remember something.
- I don't, I swear.
That's just not good enough.
I want you to think.
- Do you hear me, Rebadow? Think.
- Please, I...
You think about my father,
you goddamn son of a bitch!
Officer.
I don't know what to do.
Should I tell Leo what I saw?
Hughes has made a couple of big mistakes
since he started.
When he was working with me
in Emerald City...
he kept mixing it up with the Latinos...
then he pulled that knucklehead move
with the stun gun.
Still, there are extenuating circumstances.
His father was killed here.
That's got to be weighing on him,
and the warden.
I think your first instincts were right.
I think you should sit down with Clayton,
sort it out.
Father Mukada, I'm sorry for what you saw.
- I overreacted.
- You don't have to apologize to me.
Rebadow, sure.
All I want for you to know
is that I know how you feel.
So the next time
you wanna fly off into a rage...
you come talk to me.
And maybe together we can...
I don't know, maybe we can work through it.
The only thing that's gonna
get me through it is knowing who.
Who killed my dad.
Unless you can help me with that,
we got nothing to talk about, Father.
Dear John
Then, of course, there's the Dear John letter.
Or Jane, as the case may be.
When your loved one,
or ex-loved one by that point...
tells you how much you fucked up her life
and hurt her...
how much she gave to you
and tried to help you...
and all you did in return
was leave her swinging in the wind.
And yeah, she's found someone else.
Someone other than you
who really understands what love is.
Dear John
Let's talk about your pact with Schillinger.
You met him at Lardner, right?
How would you describe your relationship
with him there?
What's that thing you become
when you first go into the nunnery?
- A postulant?
- Yeah. I was a postulant.
He was Mother Superior.
You know, I got to tell you, Sister...
until I met you, I'd always thought
nuns were a bunch of old maids...
that had always just given up on life.
How'd you know?
Know what?
That God had called you,
you were supposed to be a nun?
I felt His love.
- What's the love of God feel like?
- You'll know when it comes.
I doubt that.
Don't you got to take those vows, right?
Obedience, poverty, chastity.
At the end of the day, you go home
and your bed is empty.
It's not empty.
I forgot.
God's waiting there for you.
You're the bride of Christ.
Yes.
Still, there's got to be nights
when God's love feels cold.
When you're lonely, when you wonder
if you made the wrong decision.
Have...
- Visiting hours. I got my ex coming.
- She's very beautiful.
That's Kitty. That was Kitty.
She's my first wife. I got Angelique today.
- How many ex-wives do you have?
- I got three.
Four if you count Bonnie.
I married her twice.
I was married, you know.
You never stop amazing me.
I'd like to hear more about that next time.
Yeah, next time
we're gonna talk about you, okay?
I look forward to it.
I like being in the same room
with you, Sister.
You give good aura.
Oh, my.
Withdrawal?
Okay, I've been there.
Here's what we do.
- Come on, just talk.
- About?
- Anything.
- I don't know, man.
You know,
when I went through withdrawal...
I tried to figure out why I was taking drugs,
why I was being so self-destructive.
Yeah, and?
Where did you get that?
Your father.
On my first night here, he burnt it on.
Then he humiliated me.
Hurt me.
He hurt me real bad.
I got to tell you the truth, Andrew.
I hate your father.
You and me ain't that different.
We don't have to, you know.
We don't have to take drugs.
We don't have to kill ourselves
to pay that cocksucker back.
He doesn't deserve to have
that kind of control over our lives.
I was all alone
when I went through withdrawal.
I was like a little kid.
I just wanted my mother.
I just wanted my mom to hug me.
I miss my mom, too.
I know.
Come here. You're gonna be all right now.
It's all gonna be all right.
- Come in.
- I'm sorry we're late.
It's okay.
I'd like to apologize to you all...
for the way I acted the last time I was here.
You see, I'm an addict...
and I'm hoping that with all of your help...
maybe I can take some control over my life.
Because I don't think
I've ever had control before.
Welcome, Andrew.
It's all right, man.
- Hello, Dad.
- Andrew.
You did it. You're clean.
Yeah.
How'd you do it?
A little help from God and my friends.
- Yo, Vern.
- How you doing?
Came to get some exercise.
Work up a sweat.
They're gonna teach me how to wrestle.
That's fine. We'll just stand here and watch.
Get down on all fours.
Head up.
You been looking for me?
No.
Really?
I thought you'd be wanting to thank me
for what I did for him.
For getting your son off drugs.
I mean, I did accomplish the one thing
you could never do. I saved your boy's life.
Fuck you.
You need to adjust your attitude. If not...
I got no reason to keep being
the good friend to you that I am.
- Good friend?
- Yeah.
If not for what I have done,
then for what I haven't.
What's that?
I haven't fucked him. At least not yet.
You see, because I was there for Andrew...
when he needed someone,
holding him, comforting him...
I think he's developed
a little bit of a crush on me.
I have been tempted to at least...
deep-tongue him a couple of times...
but I knew that would upset you
so I haven't, even though...
he wants me to stick my dick up his ass.
And I'm afraid one of these nights,
he and I alone in our pod...
I'm not gonna be able to control myself.
You'll be dead before you get the chance.
You better hurry. Keller's getting horny...
and O'Reily's been talking about a three-way
with Cyril and Andy.
I need to speak with you.
- Go ahead.
- Over here.
Andy, I'm very proud of you.
Kicking your habit like that.
And I'm hoping...
that now you and I can maybe start to have
more of a relationship.
What? You mean get closer?
Be a real father and son?
Yes.
Not a chance.
I got to get back to my pals.
Those are not the kind of men
you should be hanging out with.
As opposed to who?
Those standup individuals that make up
your merry little band?
I gotta tell you something.
My whole life, you crammed into my head
how superior we white folks are.
I don't see the truth in that.
I look around this room
and I see white faces...
and black faces, every color in between...
and the only thing that I know for sure
is that we're all shit.
You know, shit don't come in degrees.
White or black, shit is shit.
So fuck everything you believe in,
fuck everything you stand for, and fuck you.
Don't you dare talk to me like that!
Man, you hit me way too many times
growing up!
Get the fuck back!
- You fucking liar! Fuck you!
- Take him to the hole.
Fuck, you're an asshole!
A man does everything he can
for his children.
He provides for them...
worries about them...
sacrifices everything for their happiness.
- What's this?
- It's a little present from your father.
But when your own flesh and blood
renounces you...
you have no choice but to renounce them.
My son, Andrew, is dead to me.
My son...
is dead.
Phase 4, this is Radio 320.
We got a problem here.
Prisoner has OD'd.
We're too late for the medics.
Send the morgue boys.
It worked.
Your plan worked perfectly.
Yeah.
The worst day...
is when you wake up and realize...
you'll never get another piece of mail again.
Your family can't take it anymore,
your friends forget...
even the folks at charity correspondence
start to back off.
Soon, you'll give anything for
another piece of mail with your name on it...
to let you know you still exist...
to let you know you still matter...
even to Ed McMahon.