The name on the street for
the Oswald Maximum Security Penitentiary.
Only, big news: They've changed the name.
It's now called the Oswald State
Correctional Facility, Level Four.
L don't know what the difference is.
Leo Glynn is still warden.
Sister Peter Marie is still in psych.
Tim McManus is still unit manager
of Emerald City.
And l know for damn sure
none of us have changed.
Beecher is still in the hospital
after Schillinger and Keller broke his bones.
Alvarez is still in solitary
after blinding a CO.
Adebisi, still in the loony ward,
after changing hats.
Maybe it's truth in advertising.
Maybe by getting rid
of the word "penitentiary"...
the state is finally admitting
that nobody's penitent.
Nobody's sorry.
Nobody.
In an ongoing crusade
to curb state spending...
l have initiated a policy
to put some government services...
in the hands of outside contractors.
Today l am pleased to announce...
that Weigert,
a private-managed care corporation...
will take over health maintenance
in our prison system.
A move that will save taxpayers $28 million.
Fuck you.
But cutting costs will not cut quality.
And so l'd like to introduce
Dr. Frederick Garvey...
who will head the Weigert team. Dr. Garvey.
Thank you, Governor Devlin.
Weigert is dedicated
to giving the best possible care...
to the 36,000 inmates
currently serving time in our state.
We will do that by securing
the best talent available.
And though we can't guarantee
everyone a job...
our hope is to keep
as many staff members as possible...
offering competitive wages and benefits.
Thank you.
Solitary confinement.
In 1831, Alexis de Tocqueville...
visited this country
to study our penal system.
American penitentiaries were considered
the ideal, enlightened way to rehabilitation.
Putting a criminal in solitary
allowed him time for quiet reflection.
But no man wants to think
about himself all day...
face the truth about himself every day...
for the rest of his life.
"Alvarez, Miguel."
He's on 200 mils of Zoloft.
He has a history of depression
with suicidal tendencies.
- Sister Peter Marie make this diagnosis?
- In consultation with me.
L mean, Zoloft... It's just wasteful.
Alvarez is in solitary,
probably for the rest of his life.
What's the point
of stuffing pills down his throat?
- The man is no danger to anybody.
- Except himself.
Like l said, he can be self-destructive.
As of tomorrow,
l'm taking Alvarez off the antidepressants.
Sorry, my hands are tied.
When the Governor made this deal,
the contract stipulated...
that Weigert was to run the medical side
without any interference from me.
Yeah, but, Leo, there's no one you can call?
The president of the company?
But, see, Weigert
is a subsidiary of Medmore...
which is owned
by a large conglomerate in Berlin...
and mein German is none too good.
So this is it?
We just let Miguel Alvarez
sink into depression? Ls that it?
L guess l better get these meds to him
while l still can.
Yeah. You better hurry.
Listen, Miguel...
l want to explain something to you.
These pills that l've been giving you...
to make you feel better, to calm you down...
l'm not going to bring them anymore.
You're not gonna come see me?
No.
Not as often.
My grandpa told me this.
What do you mean?
He told me yesterday you weren't going
to come and visit me no more.
Your grandfather?
Yesterday?
Miguel, your grandfather's dead.
Don't go.
L have other patients.
Miguel.
You know, I...
l liked working in the ward as an orderly.
L liked working with you.
You cared.
He told me
that he spoke to his grandfather...
yesterday.
Anyway, Sister Peter Marie
will still be monitoring him.
But you and Miguel have had a special
relationship since he first came to Oz.
So we just thought you should know.
L appreciate that. L was just about to go over
to solitary to distribute Holy Communion.
L know a hundred barrio boys like Miguel.
L watched a lot of them end up in a place
like this. L watched a lot of them die.
L'm not sure how much longer l can do this.
Thank you.
Miguel?
L came to offer you the Holy Sacrament.
L already told you
that l can't go to Communion...
'cause before l go to Communion,
l gotta go to confession...
and l can't confess.
Why not?
Could you leave us alone please?
What you tell me is between you and God.
L'm not compelled to tell anyone.
You know, it's the same drill, you know.
L jabber on about how Rivera got blinded...
and you tell me that l gotta do what's right.
And l gotta rat on everybody else
who was involved?
L won't do that shit.
You won't, or you can't?
You took your vows
going into priesthood, right?
L took mine going into El Norte.
You know, l came to visit your grandfather
in this cell. Or maybe the next one.
This one. And he's still here.
We talked about you and Maritza
having a baby.
Remember how sad you were
when the baby died?
Them wafers, what are they made out of?
Flour.
Fuck it. Give me one.
No, l can't give you a wafer. L can't just...
Miguel! L said...
Don't hurt me. Please, don't hurt me.
Why did you do that?
What's going on?
Not unless you make this a confessional...
and you fucking promise me
that you ain't gonna say nothing to nobody.
All right.
All right. With what happened
with Rivera, right?
He's a hack. So all the other hacks,
they forget to feed me.
How often do they forget?
L eat about just twice a week.
- Shit! Miguel, you have to...
- You promised me.
L don't get any water.
So what have you been drinking?
Stuff from the toilet.
My own piss.
- 88P217.
- 96J522.
98A498...
In Emerald City, you will follow the routine.
We'll tell you when to sleep, when to eat,
when to work, when to shit.
You will follow the rules:
No yelling, no fighting, no fucking.
These are your sponsors.
They will help you get adjusted to life in Oz.
Kareem Said, Hamid Khan...
Raoul Hernandez, Carlo Ricardo...
Kenny Wangler, Malcolm Coyle.
Prisoner number 99C122, Malcolm Coyle.
- Yeah, motherfucker! What?
- Drop it!
Convicted: January 17, 1999.
Grand larceny, armed robbery,
assault with a deadly weapon...
assault of a police officer.
Sentence: 50 years.
Up for parole in 20.
- Yo, yo, this is my nigger right here, Coyle.
- What's up, man? Call me Snake.
- Yo, yo, Snake.
- All right, Arnold Jackson.
Arnold? Who this, Willis?
Yeah. That the Arnold
formerly known as Poet.
L don't write poetry no more.
Even so, partner, you got to
get a better name than Arnold.
What the hell are y'all doing,
watching some little kiddy show?
- No, this ain't no regular kiddy show.
- This is Miss Sally's Schoolyard.
Miss Sally's Schoolyard?
Looks like a bunch of stupid puppets.
Wait.
Jesus, look at them melons!
God, mama! Damn!
- Mama!
- Lucky fucking puppets!
- Hey, Wangler.
- What?
Mr. Nappa wants to see you.
- Nappa.
- Kenny.
No. Bricks. L told you a million times, Bricks.
That Kenny Wangler shit is dead.
- Bricks.
- You show Mr. Nappa some respect.
It's all right, Chucky.
He and l are business partners.
We don't stand on formalities.
Tomorrow everybody gets healthy.
So l don't want this Snake
to hear too much about our operation.
That's my road, dog.
He all right. He seems all right, at least.
"Seems" isn't good enough.
Tell him nothing
until we're sure he's not undercover.
- How you wanna be sure of that?
- Put him to a test.
A test? What you want me to do?
On the corner, don't you have some way
to measure a fellow's loyalty?
Yeah, we got something like that.
All right, stop!
Look, motherfucker. Get up, nigger.
Look at that.
One love.
Yo, he down with us.
Jailhouse confessions.
You always gotta take them
with a grain or two of salt.
Of course there is the chance
that the inmate doing the confessing...
is actually telling the truth.
But more likely, it's a half-truth.
"Half-truth."
How come it's never called a half-lie?
- No.
- You used to be so neat and clean.
Come on.
Tapiro, he was working psych that night.
L won't hurt you.
He couldn't believe his fucking eyes.
Adebisi protecting Schibetta.
And then washing the kid's face.
Go figure that one out, skipper.
Adebisi fucks Schibetta up the ass...
and now he's his goddamn
fucking guardian angel?
Yeah, we keep hearing
how Adebisi's a changed man...
but l wonder.
Tapiro thinks he's getting out
of the psych ward soon.
This could be useful.
Simon, l've decided to send you back
into the general population.
You think that l'm ready?
For the past month
l've reduced your dosage of Xanax...
and you haven't demonstrated
any violent behavior.
So, yeah, you're ready.
The question is,
do l put you back in Emerald City?
L hope, yes.
But if you don't, l understand.
It's because of the trouble l caused.
There are plenty of guys in there
who have issues against you.
L will apologize
to each person that l've hurt...
starting with you, McManus.
L'm sorry.
Apology accepted. Let's go.
- Look, Adebisi's back.
- What's up, Africa?
- Is he okay?
- Back from the bush.
L thought the road to my salvation
was Africa.
But there's nothing pure in Africa.
It is backward, diseased, corrupt.
L was dancing in circles.
L don't want to live in a hut.
By taking Jara's life...
you saved mine.
Thank you.
L'd like to work back in the kitchen, please.
Okay.
But we have an arrangement with Wangler.
L don't want you selling tits.
Trust me...
l'm done with drugs.
All right, what the fuck?
L know you don't believe him, do you?
Maybe l do, maybe l don't.
Come on, all that bullshit
about Africa and trust? He's setting us up.
- That remains to be seen.
- Fuck that. L'm twisting the shit...
No, you don't touch him
unless l give the say-so.
- Bullshit! Fuck what you say.
- No, this is not bullshit.
You take a walk.
Skipper, why not let him kill Adebisi?
Lt's no skin off of us.
You know, Wangler's very cocky.
If our Nigerian friend's
change of heart is real...
he could be worth plenty to us alive.
Come on, guys, move it. You guys are
moving like a bunch of turtles this morning.
- Adebisi, what are you up to?
- Nothing.
This is me you're talking to.
You gonna tell me you're not gonna
get revenge on the wops and Wangler?
That's right.
Whatever drugs they had you on
in the psych ward...
l hope you brought some to share.
Come on, man, watch where you're going.
Excuse me.
He don't look so fucking tough to me.
Move it, Adebisi.
Okay, boss.
- They changed the name?
- Yeah, catchy. Sign in, please.
My father used to work here.
Maybe you knew him. Samuel Hughes.
Sammy Hughes, sure. You're Sammy's kid?
Your dad, he's still missed.
- Thank you.
- So, what brings you back?
L'm here to see Leo...
The warden, about applying for a job.
No. Absolutely not.
Why? L completed CO training.
Came in second in my class.
- Does your mother know about this?
- I want to surprise her.
You'll surprise her, all right.
You'll give her heart failure.
Not if l have your support.
Leo, after Dad died you were always there
for me. Be there for me now.
When the hell did you grow up?
Last time l looked, you were seven.
Look, Leo...
Clayton, look, l promised your father
l'd watch out for you.
L want to be a CO.
Like you. Like Dad.
- Clayton...
- Leo...
if you don't hire me, another prison will.
L want to welcome you all
to Oswald Correctional.
As a Level Four prison, we handle some
of the most dangerous men in the state.
L myself stood where you're standing,
30 years ago.
Only, in those days, we were called guards
and we had to wear hats.
Bad hats.
The warden back then gave us a piece
of advice that l'd like to pass along to you.
"Be aware and beware."
My own little addendum is "Be fair."
Again, welcome.
- Some speech.
- What, you didn't like it?
Sounds like you said the same thing
100 times before.
So where are you assigning me?
Unit B, solitary, death row?
Somewhere you'll be safe.
L understand that, sir,
but l can't let you in without permission.
One second please.
Could you just get into one line?
Just your entire name there.
Thank you very much.
One second.
Your entire name.
- You're the new girl.
- Girl?
Yeah, you know.
L'm Diane Wittlesey.
Claire Howell.
- How was your first day?
- Uneventful.
That's good.
L don't know. L like a little action.
Just wait.
Speaking of action, who's the cute guy
who's running Emerald City?
- Tim McManus?
- He available?
Yeah, as far as l know.
What, you used to fuck him?
Yeah, actually l did.
So, if there's anything you need,
don't hesitate to ask me.
Don't you worry about me, honey.
L can take care of myself.
Yes, l'm sure you can.
Hi. Claire Howell. We met earlier.
- Yeah, hi.
- Working late?
No, l'm just finished, as a matter of fact.
Wanna have dinner?
Would you like to have dinner with me?
Don't tell me you're the kind of guy
who can't handle a woman asking him out.
No. As a matter of fact,
l find it kind of ballsy.
So, what do you say?
There's a Romanian restaurant
around the corner l've been dying to try.
Romanian?
Well, why not?
L'll meet you at the parking lot.
Okay.
Now, you see, love...
Love is the ultimate half-truth.
We missed you. Hi.
Sit.
Where's Mommy?
- She couldn't come.
- Yeah, she's got the flu.
- She sends her love.
- And this.
- This place is fucked up, man.
- It doesn't look so bad to me.
You're in that special unit, right?
Yeah, but it's nice, you know.
Clean. They call it Emerald City.
- They had the riot in there.
- That was, like, two years ago.
- Even so...
- Not a word!
He's gonna be fine.
Don't worry about me. Okay?
Don't worry about me.
Carlo, you had a good visit
with your family?
- Yeah, they brought these.
- It's good to have family, man.
L don't know.
You don't know what?
- You don't know what?
- I don't know what it is to have a family.
Wait. You saying a guy don't need a family?
Yeah, l didn't need one.
Got sent to juvie when l was 9 years old
for five years.
Got out, got sent back up...
till l was about, what, 18.
Then l got sent to Lardner, 15 years.
So by the time l got out,
my family was either dead...
gone, or they didn't want
nothing to do with me.
You spent your whole life...
You were raised by the system.
Guess what, man? L'm proud of it.
- You're proud of it?
- You wanna play? Here.
L swear to tell the truth, the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth. So help me God.
So help me God.
- What do you got there?
- What?
That letter you just pocketed. What's in it?
What letter?
- I saw you.
- Get glasses, man.
- Give it to me.
- Got nothing to give.
Listen, Hoyt...
you wanna start pulling scams in here
behind my back...
l'll get you transferred out of here
faster than you can fucking spit.
You have to do something for me. For me.
Ryan!
Lt's okay.
Did you have that bad dream again?
Yeah? Did you?
Lt's okay, come here.
It's okay. Don't worry about it.
Fuck off.
It's your job to serve me.
What is your problem, man?
- Leave me the fuck alone.
- I wish l could. L got potatoes to peel.
L see. This little hissy fit's about Schillinger.
Ain't got a chance to make him pay
for porking your brother?
Fuck you, Arnold.
Why don't you throw ground glass
in his food, like you did to Nino Schibetta?
He's still dead.
- Adebisi killed Nino.
- Yeah.
L'd fucking airhole him but he's always got
the Aryans or the bikers around him.
L just can't get fucking close.
Unless...
Unless.
Who knew? You think like l do.
That's a scary thought.
Hey, Jaz, l need an ask.
Don't do asks.
All right, then how about a trade?
Tits for tat?
Talk to me.
This'll get you in deep shit
with Schillinger, man.
Fuck Schillinger.
All right. L got a package
coming in on Thursday.
L need it slid through the X-ray
without Big Brother seeing what's inside.
No problem.
What, that's it? You don't wanna know
what l'm bringing in?
Your business.
Besides, you'll know
when you scan the box, right?
Right.
L cleared it with Hoyt.
He'll make sure our package gets through
without anyone knowing, okay?
- Brass knuckles?
- Yeah, they're a birthday gift from my aunt.
L didn't ask her to send them.
She's a fucking nut job.
Right.
And, Hoyt, when you saw these come up
on the screen, why didn't you tell the CO?
- Didn't see them.
- You didn't see them?
Sitting there looking at the screen
all day, your vision gets blurry.
Yeah, blurry.
Good news then.
L'm changing your work assignment.
You're out of the mail room,
and up making ladies' dresses.
And O'Reily...
tell your aunt, next birthday, socks.
Yeah, that's funny.
In the meantime, no gym privileges
for a week. You can both go.
- We got off easy.
- Yeah.
No thanks to your pal Vern Schillinger.
- Thought you two were jigtime.
- Yeah, me, too.
If l was you, l'd teach that fuck a lesson.
Open the fucking door, motherfuckers!
- You hear what happened in the gym?
- No.
Bikers attacked Schillinger.
Is he dead?
Escaped without a scratch.
Damn it. Fuck!
Want some pretzels?
Hi there. L'm Shirley.
Yeah, l know. Shirley Bellinger.
Only woman on death row.
Looks like l'm the only man.
Adam and Eve.
No. This ain't no Garden of Eden.
What's your name?
Richie. Richie Hanlon.
Who'd you kill?
No one.
Me neither.
My daughter...
she died in a terrible accident.
L lost control of the car and she drowned.
And you?
L'm a victim of circumstances.
You're appealing.
The verdict.
- Sure. You?
- Mine comes up next week.
The lawyer says
judge might overturn on a technicality.
Fingers crossed.
Show me your prick.
What?
You show me your prick,
and l'll show you my pussy.
L'm gay.
L don't care if you're Portuguese.
L don't want to die
with never having seen another prick again.
You and me, we're all we've got now.
We have to help each other.
Show me. Please, show me.
Show me.
Stick it through a little farther.
Well.
You must have made some boy
very, very happy.
White America believes
a black man is criminal by nature.
That's why we're six times
more likely to get sent to prison...
for the very same crime
committed by a white man.
While we are in Oz, we must remember
the most important jihad:
Jihad bin nafs.
That is the battle within, my brother.
The striving inside for purity.
Hamid, you are new to us.
So it is essential that you understand.
Violence is only to be used
in the most extreme of circumstances.
Do l make myself clear?
L've read your books, Mr. Said.
L know you are resolved
to overthrow the system.
By using the system against itself.
Using their laws to expose our truths.
During the riot...
8 prisoners were killed.
20 more were injured.
The State Commissioner
absolved the Governor of any responsibility.
But since that time,
l have been quietly contacting...
the family members
of all the dead inmates...
in order to bring a class action suit
against the administration.
Our hope is that the courts will rule
in our favor...
declaring the Governor guilty
once and for all.
- And you will serve as the lawyer?
- Yes, my brother.
Along with one of the country's
top litigators, one Arnold Zelman.
A Jew?
You rein that in.
It's important at times like these
that we remain ecumenical.
Besides, l'll be handling
the heart of the case.
L must go.
L have a meeting with Scott Ross' sister.
Scott Ross? Who's he?
He's one of the inmates
that was killed in the riot.
- Miss Ross?
- Yes.
L'm Kareem Said.
Thank you for coming.
L feel terrible.
L never visited Scott here.
Not even once.
Meant to, of course.
Started and stopped
a couple of times, but...
You know, Scott and me...
we were never close, really.
We came from different mamas.
Even so...
he was my brother.
L'm sorry.
L promised myself l wouldn't do this.
Thanks.
L'm sorry. Thank you.
No need to apologize, Miss Ross.
This is a horrific place.
You have every right to feel emotional.
L got your letter...
about the lawsuit.
- You said the guards used...
- Excessive force.
In other words, they went way beyond
what was necessary to end that riot.
Miss Ross, your brother's life
was needlessly lost.
Will you join us?
No.
- No, Miss Ross? May l ask why?
- I grew up with Scott.
He was a mean boy,
and he became a mean man.
L don't know much about how things work,
about how...
the other prisoners behave.
My guess is if the guards used excessive
force on Scott, he probably deserved it.
Why are you staring at me like that?
Sorry.
Miss Ross, of course
l respect your decision, okay?
But l do hope you will reconsider.
This is not just some frivolous lawsuit.
L am trying to stop brutality.
L sure know what it's like
to get treated badly.
Yeah, l can see that you do.
Once again, thank you for coming.
It's called "miscegenation."
Mixing of the races.
That's M-l-S-C-E-G-E-N-A-T-l-O-N.
Did l get that spelling right?
- What exactly are you after, Schillinger?
- It's not about what l'm after, your holiness.
It's you. L saw you in the visiting room
with that piece of trailer-park trash.
That was a business meeting.
What kind of business? Monkey business?
Shit, sorry. Forgot l'm not supposed
to call you people monkeys.
Everybody sit down.
Yeah, sit, boys.
Ask your minister how come
he's making goo-goo eyes at a white gal.
That is not true.
Go ahead and deny it. L know what l saw.
There are some confessions
that you can't even make to yourself.
Yearnings, desires...
that if you admitted to having,
you'd have to stop being who you are.
And the facade you've built so carefully...
would crumble,
exposing to those around you...
what really makes you tweak.
Busmalis, move your big, ugly ass.
L'm almost done, sir.
Yeah, perhaps you are.
What are you doing?
How does that feel?
That's how Mark Mack felt
when your tunnel collapsed on him.
That's right. L haven't forgotten
that you killed Mark.
L never believed that was an accident.
Are you suffocating?
Get him to the hospital.
You want to see me, Rebadow?
Some kind of emergency?
Busmalis. How is he?
He's still having trouble breathing.
We've got him hooked to oxygen.
The man's a Nazi.
Busmalis?
Metzger.
- He is tough, l'll give you that.
- McManus, even you can't be so blind.
Even me?
Metzger is one of them,
the Aryan brotherhood.
Since he arrived, too many things
have happened favoring the Aryans.
Robert Sipple crucified, Tobias Beecher
getting his arms and legs broken.
L know.
If you know,
how does Metzger keep his job?
He won't for long.
L may be blind, but l'm not dumb.
- What's the word on Busmalis?
- Do you really care?
Wouldn't ask if l didn't.
You care, why?
Because you used excessive force,
you're afraid it'll look bad on your record?
L did not use excessive force.
The man almost died.
But he didn't.
Yeah, 'cause you knew
exactly when to let go.
What's the motto?
"Choke them till you smell shit"?
- Nice tattoo.
- Souvenir of a misspent youth.
Metzger, l know who you are.
L know what you are.
All l am is a highly trained...
underpaid member of the Correctional
Officers Benevolent Association.
But if l am what you think l am...
you should tiptoe.
Is that a threat?
L'm merely reminding you
who your friends are.
Remember who you want
standing next to you...
when one of these fucks
comes after you with a knife.
So before Metzger came to town...
he lived in Montana where he was
part of the White Supremacy Warriors.
You sure of this, Tim?
L got a friend who works in the FBI
who verified it.
Even so, you can't fire a man
for what he did 15 years ago.
L need proof that he's in cahoots
with Schillinger...
that he's responsible for what happened
to Busmalis, Beecher and the others.
Nobody will testify against Metzger.
The union's not gonna let us do anything
without evidence.
He's also very popular with the other COs.
L don't need any more morale problems.
So we let him stay on board
till maybe he kills somebody?
- I have no choice.
- Even though he thinks of you as a nigger?
- What did you say?
- A nigger.
If you're trying to piss me off,
you're succeeding.
L don't want Metzger in this building
one minute longer than you do.
But if l'm going to take him down,
l'm gonna need ammunition.
All right. L'll see what l can do.
Tobias, it appears
all your bones have healed.
L'll keep the brace on for a couple of days,
but l'm sending you back to Em City.
- Use this till you're feeling steady.
- Yeah, that'll come in handy.
- You need to cut those fingernails.
- I will. Soon as l get back to my pod.
- Hi, Tim.
- Hi, Gloria.
Listen, l know that Karl Metzger
was at least partially responsible...
for both of your accidents.
Beecher, l want you to testify against him.
You, too, Busmalis.
L don't know what you're talking about.
Yeah, Metzger escorted me to the gym.
Then he left me there.
Then what happened?
L don't remember.
You know, the human mind
has a wonderful ability...
to erase the unpleasant parts of life.
- Hello, Tobias.
- Dude was in a fucking body cast, yo.
- Is he okay?
- He's gotta have painkillers.
Beecher.
Yeah.
L know there's no reason
for you to believe me, but...
You're sorry?
Yeah.
And you promise you'll never do it again?
Toby, l'm serious.
No doubt.
Three months you were in the hospital,
l had a lot of time to think.
Of me?
What l did was wrong.
L've been trying to figure out a way
to prove to you that l'm truly sorry.
And l do love you.
How about l fuck you in the ass?
- How about you break my arm?
- L'm gonna do a shitload more than that.
Break my arm, both my arms. Bend my legs.
Break every fucking bone in my body.
L'm not gonna tell the hacks nothing.
How stupid do you think l am?
You let me break your legs...
and then you snitch on me.
L won't, l swear.
Swear, promise, take an oath, make a vow...
then go fuck yourself.
There's gotta be something l can do.
There is.
There is one thing that you can do...
that'll make me believe
that you are truly sorry.
What's that?
Confess.
Tell McManus that you, and Vern,
and Metzger attacked me.
L do that, they're gonna cut off my balls.
Yeah. That's right.
Okay, motherfucker,
what, you want a confession?
You want a confession? Okay, but l'm
leaving Metzger and Schillinger out of it.
Not good enough.
All right, l'll tell McManus everything.
- L'll hold my breath.
- Fuck you, you fuck.
L gotta see McManus.
L wanna see McManus.
Just take me to McManus.
Beecher, what the hell is going on?
L don't know.
Come with me. Come on.
You don't need it, come on.
Tell me what the fuck is going on.
What did you say to Keller?
Why is he going to see McManus?
L don't know.
You know, you cocksucker.
Tell me.
Schillinger, come on.
What's up?
McManus and Glynn
wanna have a little chat.
About what?
Your little pal, Keller, confessed.
Put you and Metzger in
for the beating on Beecher.
Horse shit. He'd never do that.
He did. Now the piper's
looking for his paycheck.
- Nice try.
- You fucked up, Vern. You trusted him.
Keller knows if he fucks with me
he's a dead man.
Not if he's in protective custody, sweetheart.
Truth is a powerful thing.
It can right a wrong...
or make a bad thing worse.
But in Oz, the truth is...
if the facts don't fit the truth...
fuck the facts.
Lights out!