Napoleon Bonaparte.
A poor Italian boy who grew up to be
the emperor of the French...
and almost the whole world.
Maybe "grew up" is the wrong way to say it,
since he was never taller than 5'2".
But you don't have to be a big man...
to make a big difference.
- I'm telling you, Metzger's dead.
- What happened?
Someone cut his throat.
- Who?
- Nobody knows.
Then you find out.
- I'm glad Metzger's dead.
- He beat me for no reason.
We may be glad the fucker's gone
till somebody worse takes his place.
Leo, you know the relationship between
the unit manager and the CO supervisor...
- has to be one of mutual respect and trust.
- Yes.
So I don't want to promote someone
who's already working here.
Someone who already has
their loyalties, their prejudices.
I wanna bring in a CO from the outside.
- You know a guy?
- Yes, Sean Murphy. We grew up together.
He's been working the last eight years
at Attica.
I trust him with my life, Leo.
In this job, you'll have to.
So is that a "yes"?
- Do I ever say no to you?
- Good...
because he's already on his way.
I don't get these fucking hacks.
One of their own gets offed,
and it's, like, no big deal.
No lockdown, no inquiry,
no memorial service.
Maybe they knew Metzger was with us.
Maybe we gotta start
an investigation of our own.
Watch your step, asshole.
You spit in my food.
Yeah, no shit. Now sit down here and eat it.
Here we go.
Ryan, come on. We're late making breakfast.
I told you, we're not working in the kitchen
this morning.
- I have to go see my lawyer.
- I'm hungry.
I can go myself.
- No, you can't.
- I'm hungry.
Would you quit sweating me, Cyril?
Come on, O'Reily, I need some tits.
- Cyril.
- Hello.
Jim Robson. Remember me?
No.
I was in Unit B when you first came into Oz.
I'm buddies with Vern.
First time since then
I seen you without your brother.
- Ryan's coming.
- He's no fun.
But you and me, we can have some fun.
Why don't you give me some of
that sweet pussy I been hearing about?
Knock it off!
- He hit first!
- Get him to the hole!
Back to your unit!
Hey, Gloria.
I just met with my lawyer.
Because I confessed
to having Cyril kill your husband...
the D.A. Agreed to only add on 40 years
to my sentence.
Life plus 40 fucking years, Gloria!
All for you.
I wanna see my brother.
Tim, when you called me
about working here, I was...
Apprehensive?
Oz doesn't exactly have the best reputation
these days.
Yeah, but that's why I want you here.
I think you and me together
could turn this place around.
Hey, McManus!
- You gotta get my brother out of the hole.
- He hit another inmate.
Come on, you know what that's about.
These Nazi fucks. They taunt him.
Cyril wouldn't provoke a fight,
and you know it.
- Okay.
- This is fucking bullshit!
I said okay. I'll look into it. Now get lost.
- Jesus Christ.
- Who's that?
Ryan O'Reily.
- Good Irish mug.
- I don't know about good, but...
I actually saw that little brouhaha,
and it got me thinking.
At Attica, you organized
a boxing program, right?
- Yeah.
- Maybe we could try that here.
Great.
All we need is time, gloves,
and a good insurance policy.
Each group, the Muslims,
the Irish, the Italians, whatever...
will promote one boxer.
Then we'll have a series of elimination bouts
until there are two finalists.
- Then we'll have the big championship bout.
- Organized violence?
- It's worked in other prisons, Ray.
- No, he's right.
Whether it's rodeo or baseball...
sporting events focus the inmates'
aggression in a very positive way.
It's not their aggression
I'm concerned about. It's the gambling.
You start this, the bets will be all over.
It's already all over the place, Leo.
These guys bet on everything
from the Super Bowl to tic-tac-fucking-toe.
I mean, it's not like drugs.
It's not hurting anyone.
Let's see if the Commissioner signs off.
- I've done some boxing before.
- Me, too.
Where, at the Special Olympics?
My brother Cyril
was a Golden Gloves champ.
- There gonna be a purse?
- No.
- Then what's the point?
- For the greater glory of your tribe.
That's right. Hit that fucker! Hit it! Harder!
Jab-jab-right.
Napoleon once said...
that men are more easily governed
by their vices than their virtues.
One, two, three...
five, six, seven, eight...
That's it.
He also said:
"There is only one step
from the sublime to the ridiculous."
Napoleon must have known Tim McManus.
Yo, McManus.
Coyle, got your new work assignment.
Barbershop.
What's up with that, McManus?
Snake work in the kitchen with me.
Gee, I thought I was still running this unit.
I told you to stop calling me Kenny.
My name is Bricks.
Bricks. Right.
This is Nappa's doing.
- Think so?
- I'm sure.
Dago's got a hair across
his wrinkly ass for me.
- Yo, Nappa.
- Get those bottles out of here, pronto.
Yo, Nappa. Italiano.
It's Mr. Nappa.
- Why you take Snake out the kitchen?
- Wasn't me.
McManus had his own plans for the boy.
Get him to change his mind.
There are some things
not even I am capable of.
Get the fuck outta here. That's bullshit.
Okay, I don't like him.
I don't trust your little pal Coyle.
I do.
Then the two of you can cuddle
in the privacy of your cell...
but he's not working in my cafeteria.
Are we clear on that, Bricks?
Now get to work.
So your father was a barber?
Yeah, I cut my teeth watching him cut hair.
Good. I could use some real help
around here.
The guys they send me...
don't know the difference
between a Princeton and a bowl cut.
How's that?
- Nice.
- Yeah? Good.
- Anything else?
- Wouldn't mind a shave.
I wouldn't mind a blowjob
from Neve Campbell.
Yo, I'll shave him. I need the practice.
Suit yourself, chief.
I'm going up to the roof and have a smoke.
White folks, man, they're so dumb.
Daddy wasn't no goddamn barber.
You paralyzed, right?
I don't want you running away on me.
- Sharp.
- Coyle.
- Call me Snake.
- I changed my mind, man.
What? Ain't nothing like a clean shave,
a close shave.
Don't squirm,
you're gonna make me nick your neck.
So what you in here for, Augustus?
Murder. I killed a cop.
Sweet. But I got you beat.
I whacked a whole family:
Mama, daddy...
two little sweet, adorable kids...
sweet old gramps.
What'd this family do to you?
Not a thing.
- Then why you kill 'em?
- For fun.
- And how you kill 'em?
- Take a guess.
You slit their throats.
- Why you fucking with me, man?
- I ain't fucking with you.
You up in Oz for armed robbery.
That I am.
I never got caught for the murders.
- And never will.
- Give me my wheelchair, man.
Yes, sir. Yes, master. We aim to please.
You clowns remember
a couple of months back...
a family named Ciancimino
getting slaughtered?
Yes, as I recall,
the murders were particularly brutal.
And they never found the killer.
- I think I have.
- Who?
Never mind who.
He told me he did it, the fuck.
- You know the family?
- No.
Then why you so bent out of shape?
Listen, I ain't no saint. Not even close.
I killed somebody.
I did one wrong thing, taking a life.
And I'm doing time for it, you know.
Seth, toss that down here.
This fuck has got no remorse.
He took those lives for pure pleasure.
He had no reason to kill.
And he's getting away with it.
Kids today.
There's no honor, no ethics, no values.
That's 'cause no one's willing
to stop the erosion.
No one has a vested interest
in justice anymore.
Those two kids...
One was only 18 months old.
Lunch!
I got conflicting codes here.
Number one: I'm not a rat.
And two: I keep thinking about those kids
not having a chance at a life.
If those were my kids,
I'd want somebody to speak for them.
Then you have to be sure. And are you?
Are you sure that he murdered them?
Yeah.
I haven't spent that much time
around Coyle.
He doesn't strike me as a man that's honest.
As a poser, as a braggart, yes.
A man that's trying to get credit
he hasn't earned.
Just like Jiggy Walker. You remember him?
Then I should what?
Talk to him.
Get him to tell you the full story.
- And if I think he's telling the truth?
- That's when it gets hard.
You have to convince him to confess.
I'm fucking the wife, right?
Her throat gurgling for air...
the baby over here, crying in the crib.
So I gots to pull out of the bitch,
blood everywhere. I mean, all over.
So I go lean into the little fucker...
Stabbed it right in the heart.
Goddamn! You sick motherfucker, damn!
Yo, you should turn yourself in.
No, think about it. Think on it.
Your shit'd be famous, yo.
You'd be name in the paper, picture on TV.
You'd be like Manson up here.
Yeah, and I'd be moving
straight to death row.
- No thanks, homey.
- Nigger, you full of shit.
You doubting my word, nigger?
There used to be a nigger up here,
what's his name, Jiggy Walker?
Big-ass talker. He came here saying he sold
drugs to the governor.
The whole nine, lying through
his gold-ass teeth. Look at you.
Fuck you, fuck this Jiggy nigger.
I don't care. I ain't lying.
All I'm saying is,
you ain't lying, give me proof.
- I got proof.
- Right.
I got a videotape.
Get the fuck outta here.
Remember my homey Franklin,
up there in Polo Ground?
He came with me,
minicamed the whole dark deed.
- Sick motherfucker.
- When I do it, I do it!
Goddamn!
Yo, that's a tape I wanna see.
- Me, too, yo.
- Goddamn.
- I'd like to see that shit.
- Your ass need to be in here, motherfucker.
There's no deal to be made here, Hill.
- You get nothing out of this.
- He knows.
Coyle will deny everything.
His word versus yours.
- There's a videotape that a friend of his has.
- Christ.
I'll call the D.A.
What you're doing takes balls.
Still hope I have mine after this is over,
you know what I'm saying?
Damn.
Our man Napoleon
conquered a lot of places...
created a lot of laws that we still use today,
and made his mark on history.
And what does he get for it?
They name a dessert after him.
They named a beef after Wellington.
Fucking Caesar got a salad.
But Napoleon? He's on the tray with sweets,
next to the crème brûlée.
On behalf of the 8 inmates
who were killed, and the 20 injured...
I am filing a class-action suit
against the Governor...
the Department of Corrections,
and the Oswald Correctional Facility.
Yeah, motherfucker!
We believe excessive force was used
by the prison administration...
violating my client's civil rights.
We are therefore looking for damages
at $45 million.
From the state courthouse,
Rick Donn for Channel 2 News.
- The ghost of Scott Ross rears its head.
- Nobody knows you shot him.
But if there's a trial,
they'll be digging up shit again.
- Maybe this time they'll find out.
- Maybe the state will settle out of court.
- Devlin won't settle. That will admit guilt.
- Maybe it's time to tell the truth.
Tim, if they find out I murdered Scott Ross,
I go to jail.
Maybe.
Yeah, maybe.
Maybe because of the circumstances...
'cause I got a 10-year-old daughter,
a dying mother...
Maybe they'll only fire me.
And you, for lying.
Do either of us want to take that risk?
Respect.
- Can you feel it?
- Yeah.
- Everyone is recharged.
- Dinner!
- Let's go eat.
- Actually, I can't. I have a visitor.
Who, the lawyer?
Tricia Ross.
Again? She's already agreed
to be part of the lawsuit.
- Why do you need to see her a second time?
- She asked for spiritual counseling.
Then send her to a priest.
Minister Said, with all due respect...
Schillinger's telling everyone
you're attracted to the girl.
Don't you think seeing her again
might get misconstrued?
Then let it be misconstrued.
I know my heart is pure.
- What's that mean?
- It's just a greeting.
I gotta tell you,
ever since the announcement...
I've become sort of a celebrity.
Yes. Everywhere I go...
beauty parlor, Wal-Mart...
people I know say they saw me on the news.
I have something for you...
somewhere.
I wanted you to have this.
I can't accept that.
No, in Emerald City we're not permitted
to have such personal items.
Maybe you could...
just hide it under your pillow then.
"Tell the believing men...
"to lower their gaze
and guard their sexuality.
"That is pure for them.
"Indeed...
"God is aware of what they do."
Sexual desire is a powerful part
of human nature.
Am I right, Minister?
Yes.
Such desire needs only the slightest
encouragement to become ignited.
Am I right?
Yes.
In Islam, we believe eliminating temptation...
is more effective than trying to resist it.
Yes.
That is why men and women
who are not married, or mahrem...
are forbidden to interact with one another...
or be alone together.
Am I right?
Yes, Arif.
You are right.
We Muslims believe
that appetites of the body...
such as food, drink, sex...
can tie us to a dependency on,
or preoccupation with, our physical desires.
Therefore we fast,
denying ourselves those needs...
while we strengthen our spiritual nature.
If you're asking me for permission to fast,
I don't care.
- Stop eating.
- It's more complex than that.
According to the revelations of the Prophet,
praise be on him...
I am only allowed to abstain
during daylight hours.
At sunset, I must break my fast.
I must also have a pre-dawn meal
before resuming my fast the next day.
But at sunset and pre-dawn
you're in lockdown.
Exactly.
Which is why I need your consent
to have food in my cell.
This isn't Burger King.
You can't have it your way.
You don't deserve special treatment.
- Of course.
- But I would be willing to make a trade.
- Drop the lawsuit.
- I'm not alone in the lawsuit, McManus.
Not up to me.
Bullshit. You instigated this.
You convinced them to sue.
Now tell them not to.
Why do you care, McManus?
You're not even named as a defendant.
I want to put this riot behind us.
We must never allow anybody
to forget those three days.
Right now, we're on the edge of oblivion.
We're on the brink of disaster.
Now before we all join hands and jump...
I want another chance. Wait.
I won't allow you
to forget the promise you made.
I haven't.
Then you permit me to fast
according to the tenets of my faith?
No.
Denying me my rights
to practice my religion is unconstitutional.
Yeah? What are you gonna do?
File another lawsuit?
No.
You won't permit me to fast...
I will go on a hunger strike.
You were right about Tim McManus.
He's dreamy.
I don't recall ever saying
Tim McManus was dreamy.
- We've been going out.
- Yeah?
Let me guess.
First he took you to Al's Diner on Chisholm.
He told you that his dad owned a diner
up near Attica...
how living outside that prison
changed his life.
Second date he canceled, too much work.
And then he took you to Ma Plume Blanche,
at Top of the Tower.
The two of you sat
watching the city all sparkle.
He said he had feelings for you.
And then you went back to his apartment
and fucked.
Actually, we fucked after the diner.
- Speak of the horny little devil.
- Diane, can I talk to you alone?
Sparkle, why the long face?
I just talked to the hospital.
They've been trying to reach you all day.
Your mother died.
I'm sorry.
It's okay. She's been sick a long time.
You know, we've been expecting this.
Boy.
Is there anything I can do?
No, I gotta go over to the hospital
and start funeral arrangements.
Can you get someone to cover my shift?
- It's already done.
- Thanks, Tim.
- Can I drive you?
- I got my car. I gotta pick up my daughter.
- I can do that.
- No...
I think she should be with me.
I want to tell her.
Napoleon was a great seducer
of beautiful and taller women.
He once said, "In war, as in love...
"one must meet in close quarters
to get things over with."
There ain't no closer quarters
than in Oz, baby.
Hey.
Hi.
- Hear from Diane?
- Yeah, she called a couple of minutes ago.
How's she doing?
How do you think? She's a mess.
Strange, given the fact
her mother's been dying for what, a year?
I found a great restaurant for us.
- Rubiletta. It's a new Italian place.
- I'm gonna have to cancel.
I promised Diane
I'd come by the funeral home.
Okay.
You said it was over between you two.
It is. We're friends.
Doesn't seem that way.
Today, in the lounge...
Her mother had just died.
I saw the way you were holding her.
That was more than comfort.
Don't laugh at me!
Claire, what the fuck
are we talking about here?
- You and Diane, you and me.
- There is no me and Diane.
And to be perfectly honest,
there is no you and me!
- We went out twice!
- No, we fucked twice!
- So what?
- You said you had feelings for me.
I did, but if you're gonna turn into
some cloying bitch...
I'm a fucking cloying bitch, is that it?
And they're fucking...
- Calm down!
- Let go of me.
- Stop it!
- Get off me!
Let go of me!
- Are you gonna calm down?
- Let go of me.
Let go!
- You're gonna get yourself fired.
- Fuck you!
- Yeah, can I help you?
- We're here to see my son, Carlo Ricardo.
Okay. Step through to the admitting office.
Where's Mommy?
She doesn't still have the flu, does she?
No, she's at choir practice.
You know how Father Annas is
about missing practice.
You're in the choir.
I quit. I've been busy with the baby and all.
Sergio?
He's working.
Sergio doesn't want
to come here anymore, son.
Mommy?
I'm not gonna lie to you.
She doesn't want to see you like this.
I understand.
Come on,
it doesn't mean she doesn't love you.
I understand.
Isabella, you got any pictures of the baby?
So Cohn says to me,
with the shank in his hand:
"I stuck it in his head, but I didn't kill him."
Was there ever a time you were afraid?
One time? How about every time?
Just because I'm not down on the floor
anymore with you men and women...
it doesn't mean I don't whisper a prayer
every time I walk through the fucking gates.
I'm going home. If I'm late for dinner again,
my wife's gonna tan my ass.
Thanks for the drink, sir.
- Good night.
- Everybody, travel safe.
- Want something, Clayton?
- I should drive you home.
- What are you saying, I had one too many?
- Two too many.
I also want to talk to you about something...
and since you got a buzz going,
now's my best chance.
What, you gonna complain?
You just started.
No, the salary's fine.
It's being in the lobby all day.
I didn't train to be a CO
to sit behind a reception desk.
- I want to be assigned to a cell block.
- No.
What'd I tell you
when you applied for the job?
I promised your father, as he was dying,
that I'd take care of you.
I'm not letting you
anywhere near the prisoners.
Then I quit.
I'll go get a job in another prison
where they'll let me deal with the inmates.
What are you trying to prove?
That you're as tough as your dad?
He died in here,
his heart bleeding in my arms.
- I'm not going through that with you.
- I'm not 10 years old anymore, Leo.
You can't stop me.
We'll figure this out tomorrow, okay?
Give me the keys.
No, I can drive myself.
This conversation just sobered me up.
What the fuck you doing? Stop that!
You ain't so bad now, huh?
- Come on.
- Get back there.
Now who's the man? Fuck you!
Who?
Take him to the hole!
You okay?
- Go to the hospital, get yourself checked up.
- I'm okay.
- What's this about?
- Motherfucking spic is crazy.
Mumbling some shit about his mother, man.
What the fuck you looking at?
Napoleon's final defeat came at Waterloo.
Must've been embarrassing.
You're the fucking emperor.
You conquered Europe...
only to lose in a place
with a stupid name like Waterloo...
or Watergate, or Whitewater.
Note to politicians: Stay on land.
Larry, ever since we reinstituted
the death penalty...
the courts have been clogged
with needless appeals...
by convicted murderers
trying to escape their rightful punishment.
So the legislature has agreed...
to reduce fees paid
to court-appointed lawyers in murder cases.
And some of these lawyers,
who are against capital punishment...
have been padding their bills
in order to say:
"You see, it's too expensive."
I say let them take advantage of taxpayers
somewhere else.
The court rejected our appeal.
So what's the next step?
Normally, the next step, the last step...
is the State Supreme Court.
Let's do that then.
What's the matter, Lawrence?
I'm recusing myself as your attorney.
What?
Why? Was it something I said?
Something I did?
Not at all.
It's just that with these new lower fees
that the state's paying...
I can't afford to work on your defense.
Murder cases are complicated.
They take a lot of time...
and I've been neglecting
the rest of my practice.
- What'll happen to me then?
- The court will appoint you another lawyer.
One that won't be as good.
Because the ones that take the jobs
at lower rates...
- are the ones that no one else will hire.
- I'm sorry.
- Oh, my.
- What's the matter, Shirley?
It just hit me for the first time.
I'm gonna die.
- Hi, Dad.
- Vern, I've got bad news.
It's the only kind of news you ever got.
- Andy has been arrested.
- Christ. For what?
I don't know.
Drugs, beating up some nigger.
- The lawyer's trying to sort it out.
- Which lawyer? Don't use Zanger.
No, the court-appointed lawyer.
What, a public defender?
Hire a real fucking attorney, Dad!
I don't have the money, Vern.
I talked to the P.D. On the phone.
She sounds smart.
She?
- What's her name?
- I don't know. I think it's Goldberg.
Jesus fucking Christ, Dad.
I need you to take care of this.
What the fuck do you think I'm doing?
And I'm gonna tell you one thing,
I ain't throwing good money after bad.
And your two boys are bad.
The apple doesn't fall very far.
You wanted to see me?
I gotta get out of this place.
There's a reason
you're in protective custody.
We want you to live long enough
to testify against Schillinger.
Warden, I stay in here, I die of boredom.
You wanted magazines, I sent magazines.
How many times a day can a guy jerk off?
- I don't know. Depends on the guy.
- I gotta go back to Em City.
I ain't worried about Schillinger.
I'll take care of myself.
I want that fuck to see that
I'm not punking out.
- What the fuck is she wearing for a bra?
- Hey, Keller. Back so soon?
Ain't no Miss Sally in protective custody.
Don't.
You realize we've only kissed once?
In all these months, once.
All I've been thinking about
is kissing you again.
I said don't.
I did what you asked!
I ratted out Schillinger and Metzger.
Do you know what that means?
Toby, you know what that cost me?
Unless this is just another scheme
you and Schillinger cooked up.
How am I supposed to trust you?
Put myself in that position again?
Be that vulnerable again?
Keller knows if he fucks with me,
he's a dead man.
Yo!
If you're coming, motherfucker,
come on and bring it!
I need that plasma right away.
We need to start an IV. I need
some vaseline gauze and some combine.
Jesus. I think he may have
a punctured lung.
Mr. Keller's got about
three or four assholes now.
You asked to be assigned
to the kitchen again.
Now you're saying
you don't want to work there?
There's too many bad memories,
bad feelings.
Nappa, Wangler...
They don't trust me. I don't trust them.
I don't want to fall back into my old ways.
The dress factory
is always looking for new workers.
No.
If I can,
I would like to work in the AIDS ward.
We don't get many volunteers
for the AIDS ward.
In Africa, AIDS is much worse than here.
I would like to learn something
about the disease...
so maybe someday...
I can help my people.
These men
are in the final stages of the disease.
You can't do more
than make them comfortable...
and treat them with dignity.
Robbie Garth needs his medicine, Bed 7.
- Who are you?
- Adebisi. Take this.
Yummy.
I didn't come to Oz with AIDS.
I caught it like the brass ring.
You ever fuck anybody up the ass?
- Yes.
- Were you protected?
No.
Dr. Nathan asked me
to take some more blood from you.
- She just took my blood a minute ago.
- She dropped it.
Adebisi, you just pinch me?
No, boss.
History tells us
that Napoleon was the first guy to utter:
"If you want something done right,
do it yourself."
But how can we be sure?
What if old Napoleon's butcher said it
to him, while slicing up some salami...
and Napoleon, being no dummy, said,
"I gotta write that down"?
Miguel Alvarez is showing
increased signs of agitation...
- since Dr. Garvey took him off Zoloft.
- That's no surprise.
And I can't say for sure,
but he really looks thinner.
I doubt that's a reaction to the withdrawal.
You don't suppose
Dr. Garvey would change his mind...
and put Alvarez back on anti-depressants?
No. He's not a doctor, he's a walking ledger.
Every decision he makes is based on
maintaining the HMO's profit margin.
I have an interview with him
in a few minutes...
during which he'll decide
whether or not he wants to keep me on staff.
What are you saying?
I'm saying it may be time to go.
- Dr. Nathan, Rebadow's awake.
- Thank you.
What's going on with Rebadow?
He went into insulin shock.
He's got diabetes.
Diabetes?
- I don't have diabetes.
- You do now.
This happens sometimes, later in life.
Body starts shutting down.
You'll have to take injections regularly,
go on dialysis weekly, and alter your diet.
Mom's fudge.
My mother makes the best fudge.
She sends me a batch once a month.
I guess you'll have to be satisfied
with the food in the cafeteria.
Let's see...
you've worked here at Oswald
almost two years.
Do you like working here?
If you're asking me whether I enjoy myself,
I'd have to say no.
- Then why do you want to stay?
- Because what we do here is important.
There's a real need for proper health care.
Yeah, proper health care. Not excessive.
I know you don't support
the privatization of the system here at Oz.
But by paying Weigert a fixed rate...
no matter what care the inmate requires,
the state reduces its costs.
But because Weigert gets paid
the same amount...
no matter what treatment we prescribe...
wouldn't you limit my ability to call in
specialists, or to use expensive tests?
This is no different than HMOs
in the public sector.
There is a difference.
The state has laws to protect consumers
against cuts in medical services.
There are no such laws for inmates.
Weigert has no incentive
to provide quality care.
We're both doctors.
I took the same oath you did.
Then why cut Miguel Alvarez's
anti-depressants?
Because, as I told you,
I consider this unnecessary care.
And if you hadn't spent too much money
on unnecessary care...
the state wouldn't have had to bring us in.
- Alvarez is suicidal.
- Maybe it's all for the best.
What?
God knows he's not doing anyone
any good alive.
Fuck you.
This interview is over.
I'm hereby giving you two weeks' notice.
Knock yourself out, asshole.
Hi.
- What's going on?
- Nothing.
Do I look especially gullible to you today?
You hide a sandwich under your vestments,
which you never wear...
- and I'm supposed to think it's SOP?
- Pete, I can't talk about it.
Some confidentiality
between you and a prisoner.
I'm doing solitary.
There's four Catholics
currently residing in solitary.
There's O'Brien, there's Bevilaqua...
Hevern...
Alvarez.
You're bringing food that he likes
to cheer him up.
No, because then
there's no confidentiality problem.
You're bringing food to Alvarez...
because he's not being fed.
Because of what he did to Officer Rivera...
the COs in solitary are trying to starve him.
You should've been a cop.
Did Alvarez tell you this?
How do you know he's telling the truth?
Why would he lie?
Some prisoners, particularly in solitary,
become delusional, paranoid.
How do I find out if they're feeding him?
If I ask them, and it's true...
they'll just find another way
to fuck with him.
I have to give him the benefit of the doubt.
What's with the dress?
High Holy Day or something?
Give us some privacy.
Here, eat.
I'm not hungry.
What do you mean you're not hungry?
You said you haven't eaten in two days.
Take the damn sandwich!
I don't want the fucking sandwich!
Fuck you, you fuck!
Come on. Out!
Stop it. Open this door!
For God's sake!
I think Keller will live.
I'll start an inquiry,
try to figure out who stabbed him.
I got a guess. Schillinger.
- We need proof.
- Leo, excuse me.
We need to do more than that.
We need to deal with the ongoing violence
we have here between inmates...
- and between inmates and COs.
- Good luck.
Wait a minute.
What if we were to initiate a program...
where victims of violence,
prisoner or staff...
get to interact with the offender.
- Sorry I'm late.
- Interact? That sounds a little New Age.
Hear me out. The process has to be initiated
by the victim.
We can't force either party to participate
unless they want to.
If both parties agree,
I will meet with them separately...
and talk about what they might be getting
out of this eventual interaction.
And only then, when they're both ready...
do they actually get to meet face to face.
And then what? Talk about their feelings?
Yeah, the victim expresses his fear,
his anger, whatever.
And the offender gets to express
his remorse, or whatever.
And, hopefully, they can both move on.
I think it's a great idea.
I just wish that I'd thought of it.
Alvarez, what?
Leo, I want Sister Pete's new program
to start...
with Eugene Rivera and Miguel Alvarez.
Really?
She'll talk to Alvarez,
then she'll contact Rivera...
and see if he's interested. And if he is...
I want you to release Miguel from solitary.
You know,
I heard about what happened today.
I'd think that'd be enough to convince you
that Alvarez is where he belongs.
Besides, the other COs wouldn't like it.
- You can override them.
- I agree with them.
Alvarez blinded a fellow officer.
He should rot.
The next act of violence that he commits
will be to himself.
We are a heartbeat away
from having no heartbeat at all.
So be it.
Leo, I know that you and Miguel
had some rough moments...
after your daughter was raped.
He knows who did it and he won't tell.
I thought you'd put those feelings aside.
So did I, Father.
I guess we were both wrong.
When Napoleon died in exile,
the doctors cut off his dick.
They put his dick in an ornate box
and gave it to his priest.
Don't ask me why.
Over the years, Napoleon's dick was sold
and sold again to the highest bidder.
To this day, at least three people
claim to own Napoleon's dick.
But you see,
it's not important who owns the real dick.
The big question is:
Who the fuck
do those other two dicks belong to?