"'Twas the night before Christmas
and all through the house...
"not a creature was stirring,
not even a mouse."
The rats, on the other hand,
is a whole different story.
Said, I got a little gift for you here.
- Okay, what've we got?
- I was bitten by a rat.
Jesus! Can you take that?
Lie back.
Christmas Eve.
I think it's snowing.
When I was a boy,
this was the best night of all.
Our house was full of music,
lights, food, cousins.
- Em City is so empty.
- Sure it is.
We're in the middle of a lockdown
because the Aryans attacked the Muslims.
I'm getting a premonition like I used to
when God would talk to me.
God would talk to you?
- He'd tell me what was going to happen.
- And is he talking to you now?
So what's he saying?
He says:
"Be afraid."
Eugene, Miguel asked you a question.
Can you forgive him?
I talked to Eugene and Tina yesterday...
and they've decided they don't want
to continue with the program.
Too bad.
You know, I had a lot of things
that I wanted to say to them.
- You could say them to me.
- It's not the same thing.
Of course not. I understand.
There are certain things you should only say
to certain people...
like the warden.
He's expecting you to tell him
who raped his daughter.
- Are you prepared to do that?
- No.
- Miguel, do you want to go back to solitary?
Then my advice...
is that you take this day...
pray to God...
Iook within...
and make a choice.
May Almighty God bless you in the name
of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
The Mass has ended.
Go in peace to love and serve the Lord.
- Hallelujah, hallelujah.
- Thanks be to God. Hallelujah.
- Merry Christmas, everybody.
- Merry Christmas, Father.
Yo, hermano.
I hear Glynn is letting Hernandez, Guerra,
and Ricardo back into Emerald City.
- Lf I was you, I'd watch my ass.
- Why is that?
I saw how when they got busted,
you walked away.
That's not too cool, bro,
deserting your amigos like that.
Why don't you leave me the fuck alone?
Hernandez is gonna be in a nasty-ass mood,
looking to take it out on someone.
- My sister will be here to see me.
- Yeah, you sure?
Yeah, she knows how much
I love Christmas.
- Miguelito, feliz Navidad.
- Where'd you disappear to, man?
What do you mean, "disappear"?
All four of us are together,
only three of us are cuffed.
Come on, guys. Back up, man.
You gotta forgive them, Miguelito.
They had a lot of time to themselves
to wonder about things.
But me, I don't wonder.
I know.
You're not one of us.
You never will be.
Why is it I get nervous seeing the four
of you huddled in this pod together?
Whoever don't live here, come on, vamoose.
Let's go!
Hernandez, for Christ's sake, it's Christmas.
Take a break from being a tough guy.
He's right.
Enjoy the day.
It will be your last.
I made up my mind.
I'm not gonna tell the warden
anything about his daughter's rape.
Are you sure about this?
Have you really thought it through?
I wanna go back to solitary.
I'll make the arrangements.
Transfer you out first thing tomorrow.
- No, not tomorrow. I wanna go right now.
- Transfers take time.
- Fuck that. I wanna go right now.
- Why, Miguel, are you in danger?
Because if you are,
we can put you in protective custody.
What difference does it make?
Alone is alone.
It's the way I've been my whole fucking life.
I just don't belong in the world.
Belong by myself.
Solitary.
- She coming?
- She's not on the list.
Check it again.
Ricardo, I double-checked it.
Your sister didn't schedule a visit.
Nobody in your family did.
Carlo, it's time.
- You leaving us, Alvarez?
- Before that, we wanna give you something.
First day I got here, I got stuck.
Remember, you fucking cocksucker?
Drop it! I said drop it!
Ricardo's dead.
Lockdown!
Let's go, come on! Move it!
Seasons Greetings, fuckwad.
Alvarez is back in solitary.
I guess the circle is complete.
- Ray, I am so sorry.
- Sorry?
Is this an official confession?
I should never have excluded you.
Maybe if you had attended the sessions...
with Alvarez and Rivera,
things might have ended up differently.
I doubt it.
There goes the baby Jesus,
back in the box for another year.
And the wise men:
Larry, Curly, and Moe.
Pete, have you absolutely decided
to stop being a nun?
The process of getting out
is just as hard as getting in.
So by the time I'm done, who knows?
I admire your courage.
Sometimes it takes
just as much courage to stay...
- as to go.
- Maybe.
But if the Magi had stayed in Persia...
did what they were supposed to do,
followed all the rules...
they never would have seen God.
Thank you.
I got word at home
that you wanted to see me...
that you wanted to talk about
Ardith's attacker.
So you wanna know who raped her, right?
Yes.
Why?
So they can be punished.
What if I told you that the one who did it
has already been punished?
The name. I want the name.
Carlo Ricardo.
He's been here the whole time.
I'm sorry about your brother.
- Did you know him?
- No.
Carlo could never rest.
Maybe finally now he'll get some.
God rest ye merry gentlemen
Let nothing you dismay
Remember Christ our Savior
Was born on Christmas day
To save us all from Satan's power
When we were gone astray
O tidings of comfort and joy
Comfort and joy
I was supposed to die this Thursday,
the last execution of the millennium.
But the Governor heard that I'm pregnant,
and an hour ago he issued a temporary stay.
Knowing Devlin, he's just trying...
to sort through the political ramifications
of putting to death...
a woman who got pregnant while in prison.
- You do know who the father is?
- Yes, of course.
- But you won't tell?
- No.
- The list is easy to pare down.
- The father doesn't matter.
I want you to go to the Governor and
tell him to go forward with the execution.
- You want to die?
- I have to die.
- Why?
- I did kill my firstborn.
I've said it.
Some things aren't real
till you say them out loud.
I know.
My daughter.
My precious.
When she was born, she was a joy.
But bit by bit, I began to see that there was
something not quite right about her.
Something not quite human.
Otherworldly.
I'd go into her room, and above the bassinet
there'd be flashes of fire.
Fire?
Or she'd speak in tongues.
One day, she even made a plate levitate.
That's when I began to see
she was possessed of the devil.
- Did you ever talk to anyone about this?
- Who could I tell?
My mother? The child's father,
that lying bastard?
- Your minister? Pediatrician?
- They would have thought I was crazy.
No, I knew the only way
was to kill her myself.
But every time I went to strike,
I didn't see the devil.
I only saw my daughter's sweet face.
So I put her in the car...
and drove into the lake and let her drown...
half hoping, half expecting...
to see her rise up out of the water
on Lucifer's back.
- All right. I'll see what I can do.
- God bless you.
In three hours, I'm hosting a party
at the mansion for close to 400 people.
- What's all this about Shirley Bellinger?
- She wants to be executed.
Good. That solves all my problems.
- A little something extra under the tree.
- Excuse me, Governor, but there's one hitch.
She's insane.
- She drowned her daughter. We knew that.
- The woman does not belong on death row.
She should be in the state asylum.
But if she wants to die,
who are we to stand in her way?
Governor, she is not fit
to make that decision.
She is certifiable and she is pregnant.
And if you execute her, you will be
committing murder. Two murders.
Transfer Bellinger.
And, Warden,
I want you to end this lockdown.
We don't have the situation under control.
It's Christmas.
I'm getting heat from the clergy...
including the Cardinal,
who will be at my party tonight.
Let the inmates out!
And so in the spirit
of this blessed holiday season...
I commute Shirley Bellinger's sentence
to life imprisonment...
without the possibility of parole.
This action in no way affects my
long-standing support for the death penalty.
- You betrayed me.
- I protected you and your baby.
I want an abortion,
and if you all won't give me one...
I will kill this monster inside me myself.
You're going to the Connelly Institute,
where you will be on 24-hour watch.
You're making a mistake!
Mark my words. Next year, this time,
you won't be celebrating Christmas.
You'll be bowing down before Satan.
The next millennium belongs to him.
Satan is the father
and I'm the virgin mother!
There's only one thing
that's gonna make this all okay:
You dead.
- You're back.
- Yeah. So are you.
Feeling better?
I'm alive.
Thanks to you.
Keller...
I just asked McManus
to let you be my roommate again.
Oh, boy. Schillinger's home.
He's not such a bad guy, Diane.
What drugs are you on?
- He's a shit load better than them.
- Them, as in "niggers"?
Yeah.
- Diane, wanna go to lunch?
- Sure.
That's the thing about an accusation
like sexual harassment.
There's nothing I can do.
I can't prove it, I can't disprove it.
- It just hangs there in the air.
- Becomes its own reality.
Cream puff?
Howell.
Diane, don't!
Fucking bitch! Come on, you cunt!
Let's see about your problem! Come here!
Come on, you fucking bitch!
Come on, stop it!
- Tell me if this is too tight.
- Okay.
What the hell happened?
Howell and Diane got into a fight, over me.
Christ!
Don't, okay, Leo? I don't want to hear
any of your sanctimonious bullshit.
I don't care what you want to hear.
It's time you started taking responsibility...
- for the shit storms you create.
- What?
That's all I do all day, every day,
is take responsibility, Leo.
For every fucking thing in Em City. All I've
ever looked to you for is a little support.
- I supported you.
- Yeah, like with the thing with Wangler?
- You took his side right away.
- I did not.
Yeah, you took his fucking side!
Like you always do.
Like you do with Hill, like you do with Said,
and even Clayton Hughes. All the brothers!
No matter which side of the law.
Are you saying I do that
'cause they're black?
Read the scorecard, pal,
and add it up for yourself!
- Fuck you, McManus!
- Yeah, fuck me!
Guys, everybody's listening.
Okay, you've healed sufficiently
for me to remove the bandages.
I want to remind you both
that there are gonna be some changes...
in your pigmentation,
but they're only temporary.
Your skin should return to its normal
appearance in six months to a year. Okay?
Go ahead.
- Damn!
- I might be able to get a cab now.
- What's up? All right?
- What up, dog?
- Damn, look at y'all. Y'all fucked up.
- Yeah, can you believe this shit?
So what you doing out of Em City?
What the fuck we all doing
out of Em City, that's what I'm talking about.
It's only temporary. You know what I mean?
- Adebisi got a plan.
- Get the fuck out!
I'm telling you,
Adebisi gonna pay for what he did...
I'm with you. He gonna pay, but later.
Right now, y'all need to listen
and let me tell you what's what.
In England, the day after Christmas
is called Boxing Day.
I'm not exactly sure why. But in Oz...
every day is a boxing day of sorts.
I heard a rumor that Glynn's thinking about
canceling the championship boxing match.
Not canceling, postponing.
- For how long?
- Indefinitely.
- Man, that sucks!
- Life's full of disappointments, O'Reily.
I think you would've grasped that by now.
Bismillah, I need to talk to your man.
You got two minutes.
Warden, people have been looking forward
to this final bout for months.
- Lf you postpone this, there will be unrest.
- I know.
But last week, we had a major confrontation
between the Muslims and the Aryans...
- which you were a part of.
- Schillinger attacked Said first.
I don't wanna get into who's responsible.
You're all fucking responsible.
Schillinger attacked Beecher, too,
and he's white.
You trying to tell me
it had nothing to do with race?
Nothing? No.
But there were other things at play.
This is just two fighters fighting.
Right, Hamid?
The best man should win.
All right. I'll let the bout take place.
- But without an audience.
- What?
Just the fighters, the sidemen,
the referee, and the judges.
- No way.
- Take it or leave it, gentlemen.
Khan! Check this.
Even though you beat me down,
we betting on you to win.
That's right, baby. Nothing can stop him.
Strike that pretty white boy's face.
Kick his black ass, Cyril.
He ain't gonna let us down.
He's the king. Show them.
He better win, O'Reily,
or you're up shit's creek with no paddle.
Hit that fucking bag, Cyril.
Harder, come on. Hit that fucking bag.
Officer Murphy.
I was wondering,
do you know where Ryan O'Reily is?
He's at the gym.
Funny how he always asks for permission
to go to gymnasium just before a fight.
Why's that funny?
Forgive me.
We Russians,
we are suspicious of everyone.
What're you doing?
- Fuck!
- Chloral hydrate?
Spiking Khan's spritzer with this shit?
You been doing this all along?
- Drugging whoever Cyril boxed?
- I had to make sure he didn't get hurt.
I had to show the rest in here
that the Irish still matter.
If the others find out about this,
there'll be a fucking riot.
Who says they have to find out?
Maybe you never saw me...
- maybe you never even came in here.
- But I did.
You wave the flag of Ireland all you want,
me brother, but that fact does not change.
So what happens next?
The fight goes on, fair and square.
No drugs.
Cyril wins or loses by his own hands.
This I'm gonna keep a secret.
But if I find out you fucked with Khan,
you're going to solitary.
- How the fuck is Cyril gonna beat Khan?
- That's not my problem.
Come on, let's go.
- How're you doing, bro?
- I feel good, Ryan.
- I feel good.
- All right.
Those other guys you fought...
they were kind of pussies, you know?
- Pussies?
- Yeah.
But this Khan kid's... He's tough.
- I'm tough.
- Yeah, I know you are.
You're gonna have to be extra special tough
when you fight him tomorrow.
Cyril, I got a surprise for you.
- A surprise?
- Yeah.
Dad's coming to visit.
Goddamn it.
Fucking piece of shit.
This goddamned thing just ate my quarters.
I'm here.
What's so fucking urgent?
You told your Aunt Brenda it was life
and death. I don't see anybody bleeding.
It's been a long time, Dad.
I've been in Oz for over three years.
- You've never come to see me.
- What's to see?
I've been inside, I know what it's like.
Even so, after Cyril got thrown in
you could've come.
What good's me being here
gonna do any of us?
- I'm boxing.
- What? Talk English.
- Why are you laughing?
- Who's he boxing, another retard?
- No, he's in the finals to be the champion.
- Jesus.
I thought Oz had balls. If a stooge like you
can be a champion, Christ!
Why do you always got to shit on
everything that we do?
- Maybe because everything you do is shit.
- Look who taught us.
Don't start with that.
I provided a good life for you.
I gave you a good home,
and you fucked it up!
Couple of two-bit wiseass punks...
drinking and whoring
just like that bitch, your mother.
- Shut up.
- Fuck you.
Shut up!
Thanks, Dad.
Came through for me just like always.
Be smart. Come on.
That's it, stick the jab!
- Cover up, Cyril.
- Finish him off!
That jab, Hamid.
One, two, three...
- four, five, six, seven.
- He's all right, come on.
- All right, breathe.
- Come on, Cyril.
Come on, take a breath. Let's go.
Let's go, baby, keep it up.
Keep your hands up.
Keep working the body.
...three, four...
- Breathe.
...five, six, seven, eight.
- Slowly. Take your time. He's all right.
Let him fight.
- Defense.
- Come on, let's go.
Stay on him! Keep on him! That's it.
- Sit down.
- I wanna stop.
There's no way you're fucking stopping.
This is nothing. Stay to the body.
Come with to head...
- I want to stop.
- No, you're not stopping.
Don't think of him as Khan, all right?
Look at me. Think of him as Dad.
This guy's got nothing.
- Dad?
- Yeah, Dad. All right?
Be serious, okay? You got it?
Be thinking of Dad right there.
- Now get out there.
- Second bell.
You got it. Let's go.
Round two, gentlemen.
Come on. Get him, baby.
Be careful.
Dad!
- Hamid, watch him.
- Come on, Cyril, Dad!
Come on, Cyril.
Shit!
That's it. Stay on him!
Look what you did.
- Clinch!
- Come on!
Come on, now.
You did it! You fucking did it!
Come here, baby. Come on.
I'm the champion!
There's something's wrong with his leg!
He's not moving! Get somebody!
Get someone!
Khan, can you hear me?
Come on, Hamid. Get somebody!
Khan, can you hear me? Come on.
- Khan, can you hear me?
- What happened?
Get back.
Get a doc!
- I hurt that man.
- No, he'll be fine.
No.
I hurt him bad.
Why, Ryan? Why'd you make me hurt him?
Just get ready to go to bed, please, Cyril.
Come on.
Tell me. Why'd I have to hurt him?
Would you just shut up, please,
and get ready for bed? I'm tired.
No, you answer me now.
Why'd you make me think of Dad?
And Mom? Why?
To survive.
Don't you fucking get it yet?
To survive in this fucking hellhole.
You want the goddamn truth?
Khan is brain-damaged.
- No.
- Yeah.
I saw it when he went down.
His eyes went all vacant and shit.
You mean I made him just like me?
No.
Worse.
No! Cyril, no!
Is there any chance
of my husband coming out of this?
We had a specialist from Benchley Memorial
verify Dr. Nathan's diagnosis.
He agreed Hamid is irreversibly brain dead.
He's on life support now.
My husband wouldn't want
to be kept alive by a machine.
- Please take him off life support.
- Unfortunately, we can't do that.
State law requires us to maintain treatment.
But I'm his wife.
Ma'am, in this particular case,
because he's a prisoner...
your wishes, his wishes...
would not be taken into consideration.
You're the one who molested
a young black inmate, aren't you?
I've been accused. It's not true.
I find it unseemly...
to talk about my husband's life
with him present.
- Mrs. Khan...
- It's all right.
I'll go. Again, I'm very sorry
about what's happened.
You're gonna be more than sorry, sir.
I intend to sue this prison.
First, to get Hamid off life support,
and second, for negligence.
For allowing this boxing match
to happen at all.
Mrs. Khan, your husband knew the risk.
He agreed voluntarily.
He pushed for the fight.
So you say.
We'll let a jury decide what's true.
Everybody's worried about
this Y2K problem.
Come 2000, the computers are gonna have
a nervous breakdown.
Planes will fall from the sky,
the water supply will dry up...
and the Pentagon will start
shooting nuclear warheads at Canada.
Some predict that prison doors
will automatically spring open.
But I got the solution:
A do-over.
At the stroke of midnight, it's 1900 again...
and we get to do
the whole fucking century over.
I mean, let's face it. We didn't do
such a hot job the first time around.
New Year's Eve.
Can you smell that?
What?
Hatred.
There's hatred in the air.
- It's just an ordinary day in Oz.
- No, my friend, this is much worse.
Look.
Adebisi sitting with Arif.
And all those white faces...
just clumped together.
I'm very afraid of what might happen.
Then do something about it.
I can't.
Three years ago, I made the riot happen...
and all those deaths.
I accept my guilt in that. Now, finally.
But this...
I don't want any part of this.
You fucked up Khan. We gonna fuck you up.
Back off, bitch. That was a fucking accident.
- Back the fuck up and get out of my face.
- Feeling tall, little man? Bring it on.
Fucking cock, get the fuck out of here.
My father was also killed in this room.
- Keep moving.
- Last year, I found my guide. He found me.
Taught me my life, my soul, my heritage.
And just like your father,
they cut him down like an animal.
- Right over there, Jara died.
- Walk away, Adebisi.
Yes, be angry. Be angry!
'Cause these things are no coincidence.
The waters run deep.
- I know who killed your father.
- What?
You send Mukada to find answers.
You get what they want you to hear.
- I got my answers from Glynn.
- I ask around. I get truth.
- Which is?
- Whose prints were on the shank?
You have to wise up, my brother...
because they want you, too.
I'll watch yours...
and you watch mine.
Adebisi, move your ass!
Man, I wish I'd been there
to see fucking Khan go down.
Yeah, maybe Allah was out of town.
I told you,
the best boxers aren't always Negro.
Fuck you both.
I'm concerned about the agitation
that's out there since Khan got flattened.
I know what you mean, man. I hear
a lot of shit coming out of your mouth.
It's not shit.
I ain't saying you cocolos
haven't been fucked all your life.
I have been, too.
But all these noises you're making
will fuck things up around here.
You can't move tits
if you're in lockdown 24l7.
There are some things
more important than tits.
More important than money.
More important than money?
He's in his loco mode again, man.
What do you want?
The niggers are up to something.
The "niggers" are always up to something.
So are you.
I know there's been a lot of shit
between us all over the years...
but we gotta put that aside. At least for now.
We gotta be bound by the one thing
that joins us all together:
The color of our skin.
I am not gonna listen to this shit.
- Come on, Chris.
- Wait. I wanna hear what he has to say.
I'm Russian, and I'm a Jew.
But I'm also white.
So Schillinger, do you accept me
as a part of your group?
- Yes.
- Fuck.
Hold on, man. Here.
What's up with you?
First you're all buddies with Adebisi
and now you're being nice to me?
You've been wanting to stick me
since Coyle got killed.
Coyle is history, you know what I'm saying?
I'm living in the right now.
And what now is telling me,
is if we don't get together...
we gonna die apart.
All is going well.
Things are bad.
So what do we do next?
So what do we do?
We wait.
We act first.
An opportunity will arise.
The first opportunity, we let everyone know
that we're still in charge.
Are you sure?
I don't know.
Yes.
Trust me.
Would you tell those jerk-offs in the
mail room not to go through my magazine?
Part of the job.
We inspect everything that comes into Oz.
Inspect is one thing. Beating off is another.
I paid top dollar for Hustler.
- I don't want my pages all stuck together.
- Keep moving.
Line up!
What's he doing now?
It's the holiday season, so I try to be nice.
What do I get?
Place turns into a shithole.
Garbage everywhere, unmade beds,
turds in the toilet.
No more. No fucking more.
You clowns know the rules.
Emerald City is supposed to be spotless.
Cleanliness is next to godliness.
And so until this place
is up to my standards...
I'm gonna have to clear your minds
of the clutter.
I'm confiscating all skin magazines.
Gentlemen, you got a choice.
You can either clean up your act...
or you can kiss the girls goodbye.
Not that one, man.
This is what I'm talking about.
- What they do to us.
- Adebisi, what you after, man?
You want another riot?
All it's gonna do is get more brothers killed.
- We are the majority.
- Yeah, but we don't have guns.
Some who wear uniform are still
our brothers, and may be willing to help.
I'm gonna say this now. You fucking crazy.
You're either one of us...
or one of them.
Did it work?
I think, yes.
What you got there, Hill?
You want a trip to the hole?
I want a little fucking skin.
Bad enough the Governor got rid
of conjugals, and now this. It's shit.
- You are shit!
- All right, that's it, the hole.
Again and again and again!
First it's Wangler, then Khan, and now Hill.
How many more of you before you wake up?
We must not let this brutality
go unchallenged.
The Qur'an tells us so.
"Permission is given to those who fight
because they have been wronged.
"And indeed,
God is able to give them victory."
Why don't you finish the quote, Arif?
The Qur'an is a book of love, not hate.
It speaks to what is good in all of us.
Allah knows no color.
You are using the words
for your own needs.
My needs? I suppose I made up racism?
Arif, I lived on the same streets you did.
I know what prejudice tastes like.
I know what it is to walk into a room
and be the only black man.
Yes, we must right the wrongs
that have been done to us...
- but not this way, my brother.
- Then how?
We try and understand them.
No white man can truly understand
what it is to be black.
Nor us, them.
The Qur'an says...
I don't give a shit what your Qur'an says.
What exactly
do you give a shit about, Adebisi?
Justice. Just like you.
Set Hill free!
- Set Hill free!
- Shut the fuck up!
The SORT team is in full readiness.
I've decided to keep the entire prison
in lockdown for the immediate future.
I ask you to be careful
and be ready for any possibilities.
That's all.
- I can't go through this shit again.
- It's going to be all right.
No, I'm gonna take my vacation time.
If they don't let me do that, I'm gonna quit.
- Diane...
- No, I'm serious. I will quit.
- You afraid, Murph?
- Yeah, sure.
Yeah, me, too.
- Leo.
- Yeah.
- We can't hide behind the badge anymore.
- What do you mean?
All these years you've been in the system...
all these years you've worked for them,
caging in your own kind...
don't you ever feel sometimes
like you've betrayed your own people?
- No.
- No?
The men who are locked in here,
they're not my people.
My people are the ones who obey the law.
Go home, Clayton. You're fired.
Lots of folks think the world's gonna end,
come the dawn of this new millennium.
They think we'll see
the Second Coming of Christ...
the Apocalypse, Armageddon, Doomsday.
They tie it all to God's great plan.
But ask yourself,
"Does God know it's January 1?"
Does he have his watch set for midnight?
And if he does, which time zone is he in?
Man invented hours, days, and minutes.
Man invented calendars and clocks.
God's got his own timetable and it's stupid
of us to think that we can set it for him.
All we can do is watch the clock run out,
and hope for the best.
Happy New Year.
Yeah.
- Happy New Year, motherfucker!
- Eat me, you little prick.
Happy New Year, little brother.
A bunch of men sit in cells
on the brink of a new year...
a new century, a new millennium...
1,000 years.
They stare into the future and all they see...
is themselves in those same cells.
Black or white, here we are on the precipice.
We either hang on or we fall off.
Together or separately.
It's our choice. It's up to us.
It's up to you and me.
Happy New Year!