L used to be a runner.
Not a marathoner, a runner.
Marathons are bullshit. They're all hype.
Some official picks a random day...
and rain or cold,
you're out pounding the pavement...
alongside 50,000 other dumb fucks.
No, there are some things
that's better to do all by yourself.
O'Brien.
Bevilaqua.
Alvarez.
Holy shit!
Alvarez, can you hear me?
L told you this would happen!
Yes, you're very smart.
We'll miss you when you're gone.
The question is, will Alvarez live?
- Yes.
- Then let's all relax.
Relax?
Leo, just because Alvarez
is going to be okay...
doesn't mean we're going to be
so lucky next time.
Dr. Garvey, the next inmate
you deprive of medication...
simply because it's expensive, may die.
The Weigert Corporation was contracted
to provide health care...
to the state prison system
for the purpose of keeping costs down.
My job is to make judgment calls.
According to the deal Weigert made
with the governor...
l have complete autonomy.
And l will not have that autonomy broached
under any circumstances.
Well...
Leo, this is bullshit.
He's right. L have no authority over him.
So what do we do?
Go public.
If there's anything else l can do,
let me know.
- I will.
- Thank you.
Who's that?
Rick Donn, Channel 2 News.
He wants to interview you about Alvarez.
- You didn't tell him anything about...
- Yes, l did.
L figure since you gave me
two weeks' notice, l got nothing to lose.
L'll tell them you're nothing
but a disgruntled employee.
You can do that, sure.
Maybe they'll believe you,
maybe this will all blow over.
But when l'm gone,
and the next screw-up happens...
maybe this time someone dies,
you won't have anyone to blame then.
If l were you, l'd switch to a red tie.
It'll look better on camera.
Hello. Is he in?
This is an emergency.
Come in.
Dr. Nathan.
L have a problem, Gloria.
This situation with an inmate,
Miguel Alvarez.
Rick Donn called my office
wanting an interview...
wanting to ask how l thought
things were going with Weigert.
L then received a call from Ross Tavoli,
the CEO of Medmore...
which is the parent company of Weigert.
Ross is an old friend.
A very generous friend.
- Governor...
- You haven't gone on camera yet, have you?
- No, l haven't.
- Good. Here's what l propose.
You keep your job,
Alvarez goes back on the medication...
and Weigert agrees
to loosen up the purse strings.
And Garvey?
He's gone.
Turns out, in the '70s
he was a back-alley abortionist.
A woman he was servicing died on the table.
He moved here,
sued to have his license restored, and won.
Don't ask me how.
In any case, l'm sure Rick Donn will be more
than satisfied with that exclusive...
and allow the rest of the story
to die a natural death.
People tell me you're a reasonable person.
Be reasonable now.
Give me your cooperation.
L want to stay...
but l need to know
that things are really going to be different.
You have my solemn word.
Garvey resigned today
amidst the controversy.
Governor Devlin said he would hold Weigert
Corporation accountable for its actions.
A spokesman for Weigert said they had
no knowledge of Garvey's prior record...
and have promised a re-evaluation
of their policy...
for correctional facilities nationwide.
Miguel?
Am l dead?
Am l in heaven?
Not quite.
Shit.
You should have let me die.
Prisoner number 99S233...
Nikolai Stanislofsky.
Convicted February 14, '99.
Possession of stolen goods
with intent to sell.
Sentence: 15 years.
Up for parole in 5.
- You a Russian?
- Yes.
- From Russia?
- You were born in Russia?
- Yes.
- First time in Oz?
- Only time.
You'll get used to it.
L was seven years in Soviet gulag.
This place is cake.
Who's the girl?
That's Miss Sally.
Look at those fucking tits.
Tell me, are we anywhere close
to death row?
Yeah, why? You know somebody
on death row?
A man l knew...
Alexander Vogel, was killed.
L would like to shake the hand
of the man who murdered him.
That'd be Richie Hanlon.
Richie Hanlon.
Richie.
Hon? Hold up your arm, will you?
For the sweater.
What do you think, about four bars?
Three.
Mail!
Long time no see, Vern.
- Did you miss me?
- Breathlessly.
Got that teapot you ordered.
Thanks, darling.
My, you are turning this cell
into quite the little nest.
My new lawyer is taking my appeal
to the State Supreme Court.
- I figure l'll be here a while longer.
- That is good news.
Yeah.
Hello, Richie. Nothing for you today.
Guess all your little fag friends are too busy
getting their legs waxed.
- Fuck you, "Schillinjer."
- "Schillinger," asshole.
What's this thing between you and Vern?
Every time he comes around here,
you boys snarl at each other.
Long story.
L've got no other appointments today.
That bastard is the reason l'm on death row.
He and another Aryan creep
killed a Russian.
Hung him by his ankles in the gym...
carved "Jew" on his chest...
and then told me if l didn't confess
to the murder, they'd kill me.
Death sentence either way.
But if you know you're gonna die,
why not tell the truth?
The other one, Mark Mack, is already dead.
Besides, why should the hacks listen
to me now?
L tell them Schillinger did it,
they'd say, "Prove it."
- I have no proof.
- Unless you say you did it together.
- What?
- Lie.
Tell them you and Vern
both killed the Russian.
- How does that save me?
- It doesn't, honey.
But it does mean his ass will be sitting up
here in the cell next to yours.
Something to consider, Richie.
Just something to consider.
Coyle, how you doing? You comfortable?
The fuck you care?
Why did you tell Hill
you murdered that family?
Why didn't you just
keep your fucking mouth shut?
You might as well be asking me why l had
Frankie go videotape me doing the deed.
Then you might as well ask me
why l even do the deed at all.
If you can't figure none of that shit out,
you don't belong here, McManus.
Fine, l don't belong here.
- Why did you tell Hill?
- Hill.
L mean, he different
than the other niggers in this place.
- I wanted his respect.
- Respect.
Now l want him dead.
You happy, McManus?
You got everything you came for?
You see, l wanted his respect,
now l want him dead.
It's a thin line between love and hate.
You got that, McManus? You bastard!
Channel 2 News brings you
shocking evidence...
presented as testimony
against suspect Malcolm Coyle.
Brutal home videos of the
Ciancimino family murdered one by one.
Jesus Christ. Why they gotta show that?
Don't be a vag, O'Reily.
L'm no vag,
but why they gotta put that stuff on TV?
Lt's evidence in Coyle's trial.
Evidence, fine.
Show it in the goddamn courtroom...
but not on the fucking local news.
How would you like it if you came home,
you put the tube on...
there's your grandmother with her guts
spilling out for everyone to see?
L want to put on Miss Sally's Schoolyard.
- Yeah, Miss Sally's got big bazooms.
- Big bazooms.
Settle down, Cyril.
You gotta jab her right there.
- They put Hill in protective custody.
- That ain't gonna save his rat ass.
He gonna pay for what he did to Snake.
The grand jury had me
going around in circles.
You did great.
Besides, they saw the videotape.
Coyle's gonna get indicted, then convicted.
You know the best thing
about this whole thing?
Being outside. Getting driven to the city.
The energy, the ladies.
City's got two new skyscrapers, too.
But mostly, the sense of freedom.
You know, being out of harm's way.
Wangler and those guys,
they're gonna kill me.
L don't blame them.
Still not sure ratting on Coyle
was the right thing to do.
L mean, those people are dead.
This trial won't bring them back.
Meanwhile, l'm in some deep shit.
We'll take care of you.
You all right?
Yeah. L got the flu. Go on with
what you were saying about Hill.
Nobody likes a snitch.
That's true, but we're going to put that aside
for the moment.
What l am doing
is appealing to your sense of conscience.
All of you here,
you have committed murder...
but in the course of conducting business.
It's true, this is different.
You're all family men.
Coyle's murdering of an innocent family...
threatens your families on the outside, too.
What do you want, Said?
Help me protect Hill.
All of us together.
We make it clear to Wangler...
we will not tolerate any harm coming to him.
L know the Ciancimino family a little.
Nice people, never hurt a soul.
And the father, he died in Nam.
Nam? Count the Brotherhood in.
You?
Sure.
Nappa?
Not only will no one touch Hill...
but l'll do you one better.
Nappa air-holed Snake.
We got to air-hole Nappa.
And that cripple snitch
bitch-ass nigger Hill...
we got to whack his ass, too.
Chill, yo. We can't fuck with
either one of them right now.
We have the fucking Sicilians...
the Muslims, the Aryan motherfuckers...
and the spics all over our dicks.
We gotta chill.
So what we gonna do?
Let them disrespect us like that?
Disrespect? Fuck that.
We just gotta wait for the right time...
and then we'll nail both their asses
to the fucking wall.
- You heard?
- Word.
Okay, Ricardo...
you think you could behave yourself now?
- Where's lsabella?
- The baby's keeping her busy.
She thought maybe he was coming down
with the flu.
Yeah, the flu.
Papi, you told me you'd never lie to me.
The baby has been sick.
It's nothing serious.
Juan told her she had to stay home.
That cocksucker never liked me.
- Since l fucked his cousin at the wedding.
- You fucked his cousin?
She gave me a little head in the men's room.
Juan walked in.
- They've been arguing a lot.
- I told her not to marry him.
About her coming here.
She said for now
she won't be visiting you anymore.
She doesn't want to end up divorced
and with a baby.
Fuck her then.
No, fuck her and that cabrón she married.
No, Pop, l'm dead to them.
Okay, she's dead to me.
You tell that bitch
she's fucking dead to me...
and l don't want to hear
her fucking name again!
"Hitting the wall." That's what they call it.
The moment when you can't take it anymore,
when you've pushed yourself...
and strained every muscle,
when you think if you go one more step...
your body will implode.
- What do you want?
- Sometimes it's good to pray.
When you're unhappy, ask God for his help.
We can pray together.
Pray l don't cut you right now.
- Drop the knife!
- Why don't you come and take it?
L got a Code 19.
Give me that!
You got no balls. You got no fucking balls!
You writing poetry?
- Man, l don't do that shit no more.
- Why?
'Cause l don't feel like it, all right?
L just don't feel like it.
Too bad. You wrote good.
Adebisi, leave me the fuck alone, please.
- Here you go, Brother Minister.
- Thank you.
You've been on this hunger strike
for four days now.
We've had no reaction
from McManus or Glynn.
That's because they think l'm bluffing.
But soon they will see.
Don't worry, brother.
This hunger strike won't last much longer.
The judge has accepted
our class action suit.
That is excellent.
- So when does the trial begin?
- Two months.
- That long?
- Justice moves slowly.
If it moves at all.
Wait. There is one more thing.
L want you to pay a visit to the warden.
This hunger strike started
because you wouldn't allow Said...
to have food in his cell at night
so he could fast during the day.
L won't grant him special status.
As of tomorrow,
two more Muslims will stop eating.
Day after that, three more will stop...
and so on until every Muslim in Oz...
until every Muslim in every prison
in this state is on a hunger strike.
L'm not the State's Attorney,
but l guess he'd say...
that the last thing you need right now
on top of a class action suit...
is a prison system full of men
dying for their faith.
Bad press, bad karma, gentlemen.
L say we let Said have his way.
Leo, you give in now...
what'll stop him from using a hunger strike
the next time he makes demands?
We'll deal with "the next time" the next time.
Hopefully, this lawsuit will be settled.
You let him win, his stature only grows.
We lose.
Sometimes the only way to win is to lose.
What l don't get are these treadmills.
These people that just want
to run on a machine.
Sure, you drop a few pounds...
you tighten some sinews,
but you still haven't gone anywhere.
It's like being a hamster
in one of them circly things in a cage.
Me?
L don't wanna be a hamster no more.
Hi.
Tim, about the other day...
- You don't...
- Let me.
L completely overreacted.
Diane Wittlesey's mother died,
you comfort her...
and l make it into this big thing
like you're still in love with her.
L'm a fucking cloying bitch, is that it?
- Let go of me.
- Stop! Calm down.
L was wrong. L'm an idiot. L'm sorry.
All l want is for us to be back
to the way we were.
Don't you see? We weren't anywhere.
L'm sorry if l misled you...
but you came on to me like gangbusters.
L didn't think the sex would mean that much.
L'm not looking for a serious relationship.
The truth is l'm shit at commitment
except to my job.
If l wanted to be married,
l would still be married.
Walk away!
- L'm not asking you to marry me.
- I know.
- I just wanna be friends.
- Okay, friends.
And the sex will just be the sex.
- I don't think that we should fuck anymore.
- Why not?
- Because fucking complicates things.
- It doesn't have to.
Yes, it does. It always does.
L promise, it won't.
- That's not a promise you can make or keep.
- I can.
- No.
- What?
You don't think l'm any good in bed?
Oh, shit!
- Claire...
- Don't!
You know, you're not so amazing yourself.
Maybe the reason you can't commit is
you'd rather suck off one of these guys.
L'm sorry, am l hitting a nerve?
- No, you're boring me.
- Cocksucker!
Giles.
Bevilaqua.
- What are you doing?
- Come in here, Howell. Nice tits.
Twice in one week, Leo. On her watch.
Alvarez almost offs himself and now this.
- She's new.
- She's dangerous.
Bevilaqua may have
permanent brain damage.
- L'll transfer her to another unit.
- No, Leo.
Fire her now. Fucking fire her!
Can l have your attention, please?
Gentlemen.
This is Officer Sean Murphy,
the new supervisor in Emerald City.
L've read the files on each of you.
L know you're tough. Life in Oz sucks.
This l also know.
Don't force me to make the days even worse.
"Sean Murphy."
- He's a mick, like us.
- That's good?
Little brother,
things are definitely looking up.
- Hello, buttercup.
- Fuck it! You're fucking dead, man!
You're dead, Schillinger.
You are fucking dead.
You are fucking mine, motherfucker!
L'm gonna need a refill there, sweet cheeks.
You send me to the hole,
my brother's fair game for Schillinger.
Boo-fucking-hoo. You should've thought
of that before you lost your temper.
L'm sorry.
- Tim, mind if l handle this?
- No, go ahead. L can't reach him.
All right, let's go.
Okay, O'Reily, l'm gonna let this pass. Once.
You fuck up again,
l'll personally stomp your ass.
- Why are you being so nice?
- Your file.
L know all about you and your brother.
L got brothers, l know what it's like.
Besides, you and me,
we're both Black lrish, right?
Black as they come.
- You were Golden Gloves.
- How did you hear that?
You read my file, l read yours.
L bet you pack quite a punch.
Yeah, l had my day, sure.
My face hit the canvas just as often.
You know, my brother Cyril, he's a boxer.
And l entered him into this competition
that McManus is organizing.
L thought your brother was slow.
Yeah, day to day, but in the ring...
Man, he's so fast.
It's like his instincts just come right back,
you know.
But the problem is,
l don't know dick about boxing.
So l was just wondering,
maybe you might wanna coach Cyril.
- Me?
- Yeah.
No way, O'Reily.
That would be showing favoritism.
L don't mean like full-on coaching...
but l mean maybe just kind of watch him
at a distance, you know. Give me pointers.
- For lreland?
- We'll see, kid.
Quiet!
Everybody shut up, please.
Quiet down so we can get started.
It's the first Oswald boxing championships.
We've eliminated weight classes.
In this corner in the blue trunks,
Chucky "The Enforcer" Pancamo.
And in this corner,
"Throttling" Steve Pasquin.
L want you to keep it clean. No punches
below the belt, no rabbit punches.
You obey me at all times.
Protect yourselves, go to your corners,
shake hands.
Ring the bell.
Hey, Ryan, how's Cyril?
Officer...
- get these two fucks away from me.
- He is so touchy.
L was just coming over to tell you
how excited l am that Cyril's first fight...
- is gonna be against James here.
- That's right, Cyril and me.
And you can't do a fucking thing about it.
Beecher bit off the tip of your dick.
How would you like to lose the rest?
Move along, O'Reily.
COs, odds are 5-to-1 in your favor.
- Ryan.
- Aunt Brenda.
- What did you bring?
- Your favorites.
No!
- You're in training.
- In training? For what?
A fight. They organized a boxing match.
Ryan, no. You can't have the boy boxing.
Why not?
His brain's rattled enough.
Sweetheart, do you want to box?
What are you asking him that for?
'Cause l know how you bully him
into doing the things you want.
Fuck you.
No, fuck you!
What, all of a sudden now
you're worried about Cyril?
L've always been worried about him.
L worry about both of you.
Oh, yeah? Then where the fuck were you
when we were growing up?
Where were you when that shithead
was beating on us? On Ma?
You were off at your goddamn Mass
while l protected Cyril. Me!
You took care of him all right.
You took care of him good.
'Cause of you his mind is muddled.
'Cause of you he's in this hellhole.
Listen, do us a favor, you old bitch,
and drop fucking dead.
Come on, Cyril.
You got the devil in you, Ryan.
Just like your father.
Come on, Cyril.
Move it!
Cyril's got the next fight.
- Who's he up against?
- Robson.
Watched Robson train. He's tough.
But he keeps his left real low.
- Tell your brother to hook him.
- Yeah, but is that gonna be enough?
L mean, l don't want Cyril
getting any more damaged.
Pull him out.
No fucking way. There's gotta be something
else l can do to give him an edge.
- You know the story of the Black lrish?
- No.
Back in the 1600s,
after the Armada was defeated...
Spanish sailors washed up
on the shores of lreland.
Couldn't speak a word of English.
They figured out how to survive.
Survival. It's in your blood, O'Reily.
You'll figure out something.
So how come you Christians
don't got nobody boxing?
We made a decision not to participate.
Morally wrong.
Right.
You still working bedpan duty
in the hospital ward?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
You want to make a little extra cash?
Maybe.
What are you doing?
Shut the fuck up.
How you feeling? Feeling good?
Good round. Gotta keep jabbing.
Don't rely on that right all the time.
Watch your body, work your jab.
It's all good, man. Come on.
Come on. Sit down.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
You got 15 pounds on this guy.
He's treating you like a rag doll.
Take a drink.
James, one more drink.
Looks good. Come on.
You got your ass kicked.
What the fuck are you looking at?
Get your eyes off the ring. Take a drink.
Nice, man.
You're fucking kicking the shit out of him.
One more round for the Brotherhood.
Let's go.
When you're in a race, you wanna win.
You wanna win no matter what it takes.
Win at all costs.
Fuck you.
L was a sprinter.
Yeah, l was great with the short distance.
Man, you shoot that starting gun off
and l would go! Fast!
Man, l could travel the 50-yard dash
in 6.5 seconds. No shit.
L came at it natural.
In my 'hood, you had to learn to run
before you learned to walk.
Officer Murphy?
L'm supposed to have
a dialysis treatment now.
You're wrong, Rebadow.
It's not listed on today's sheet.
When l had my last appointment,
Dr. Nathan told the medical assistant...
- to schedule another one for this morning.
- Maybe Nathan changed her mind.
L'll call, check it out.
All l got down here
is you having visiting hours at 3:00.
- My mother is coming.
- Your mother?
- Are you sick?
- No, mama.
- You were never a very good liar.
- I have diabetes.
We seem to be getting our share
of bad diagnoses these days.
What with little Alex's leukemia.
L got the picture you sent of him
in SeaWorld.
That trip. L can't tell you,
it did him so much good.
After SeaWorld, he was glowing.
Now he's starting to falter again.
L wish there was more l could do.
There is. Meet him.
- No.
- He's your grandchild.
Mama, no.
L told them the truth about you.
- What?
- I know.
L broke my word.
But for Christ's sakes, you've never seen
your own son, your own grandson.
All these years, all the lies...
telling them you died years ago.
L don't want to go to my grave knowing that
some promise l made 30 years ago...
kept you from your family.
Meeting them won't do any good.
Not meeting them
hasn't done any good either.
Here you go, Rebadow.
Diabetes Diet Delight.
Hurry, Rebadow.
- L'm going as fast as l can.
- Hurry before Schillinger shows.
Every day, every meal,
he spits in my food and makes me eat it.
- So spit in Schillinger's food.
- Are you kidding?
He'd yank out my salivary glands.
Busmalis.
Too late.
Wanna trade?
He's in shock.
IV bolus of DF-50.
- Did he go to dialysis today?
- He...
What? Didn't l tell you to schedule him?
- I forgot.
- You forgot?
He could have died, you asshole.
You feeling better?
Quite a scare.
Is there anything else l can do for you?
May l use the phone?
L've changed my mind.
- Adebisi, you just pinch me?
- No, boss.
L know what you did. You said
Dr. Nathan wanted to take my blood...
but l know you used it to infect someone.
You know it's true.
You pricked some prick with a needle,
hoping to give him AIDS.
Who is it?
Come on, Adebisi, tell me. Who?
You are delirious.
Adebisi, l don't get it.
Why would you want
to transfer out of the cafeteria...
to take care of a bunch of fags?
- Don't like fags?
- What do you think?
Out there, l hated them.
But here...
sometimes you need your dick sucked.
That's one of the many differences
between you and me.
L got self-control.
L wish l was more like you.
To me...
a fag is a fag.
A perverted sick animal.
L can't stand having one of them near me.
But you Sicilians,
you kiss each other on the cheek.
- That's respect, not sex.
- Respect.
L got you, boss.
L got the results back from your test.
- I don't know how to tell you this.
- Be straight.
You're HIV-positive.
- What?
- L'm sorry.
Doctor, that is not possible. Correct me
if l'm wrong, but the only way to get AIDS...
is by having sex or sharing a needle.
L haven't done either, and l'm not Haitian.
- You don't have AIDS, you're HIV-positive.
- The tests are wrong.
- I double-checked.
- Triple-check.
- I know this is hard for you to accept.
- It's impossible.
Antonio, l'm going to schedule you
for counseling.
- And make arrangements for your transfer...
- Transfer?
State policy.
All inmates who test positive for HIV
have to be isolated in one place.
L want to talk to the warden.
All right.
This isn't happening to me.
Skipper, l don't get it.
Somebody must have monkeyed
with the tests.
All l know for sure is
Glynn says l gotta move to E.
- You mean we're not gonna see you?
- That's what isolated means, Chucky.
Inmates in E,
they don't mingle with gen pop.
Until l get back, you're in charge. Okay?
See you, boss.
Fuck.
Lights out!
Dr. Nathan says you'll be back
in Em City by the end of the day.
Good. My bedsores got bedsores.
You know, given the fact that
you had two stab wounds in the back...
l'd say your recovery is miraculous.
They'll need a lot more than
some shank to take me out.
- You still have no idea who they are.
- No.
It was dark. They came at me from behind.
They're chicken shits.
The problem is...
we know Schillinger stabbed you.
Or had somebody do it.
- But we have no proof.
- Don't you just hate that?
- You don't seem very torn up by this.
- You got shot in that riot, right?
That little handshake with death...
kind of changes your perspective on things.
L have every right to snitch out Schillinger,
he's got every right to come after me.
- Mail.
- Ain't that right, Vern?
Nothing for you today, Keller.
No get-well cards, no floral bouquets...
not even a funeral wreath.
- We know you're responsible, Schillinger.
- Me?
L'll admit metaphorically it fits.
He stabbed me in the back,
so l stabbed him.
But l didn't.
L wish to Christ l had.
Of course, if it had been me, you'd be dead.
Godspeed.
- Thanks for seeing me, Sister.
- That's why God made office hours.
- Beecher's not around?
- No. Why? Ls this about him?
You know what went on between us, right?
L know that Tobias was in love with you
and that you broke his arms and his legs.
Jesus Christ, you put it that way
it makes me sound so cold.
So why don't you rephrase it
so you come out the hero?
L am sorry. What l did was wrong.
And l want to make it up to him.
L hear you've got this victim-offender
interaction program starting up.
L wanna sign up.
It takes two to swing dance.
Tobias has to be willing to participate.
L know that.
That's why l'm here. He likes you.
He respects you. If you suggest it to him...
he'll come along.
Do you really care about him?
You've got no reason to believe me,
but yeah.
Okay. L'll see what l can do.
L don't know what your scam is,
but l'm not buying it.
Seeing Sister Pete today,
asking her if we can be in her program.
No scam. It's like l've been saying,
l want to make this right between us.
How? L can't trust you.
L can't trust myself anymore.
My fucking feelings are...
The only thing l know for sure is this:
L'm gonna get Schillinger.
- I can help you with that.
- I don't need your help.
What are you gonna do,
you gonna get that jizzbag all by yourself?
Ask Metzger.
Yeah? What, you killed Metzger?
You know, when l hit Kathy Rockwell...
when l realized l had taken her life...
l was full of remorse, full of self-loathing,
because l hadn't intended to kill her.
But Metzger.
That was sweet.
You know what else was sweet?
Sticking that shank in your back.
- It was you?
- Never considered that?
Lt could've been me,
standing in the dark in that storage room...
watching you stack copying paper.
And then...
boom, boom, baby!
Toby, was it you?
No.
But for a second,
you believed it could have been.
It could have been good old Toby.
- You didn't kill Metzger.
- No.
How can a little pussy bitch like me
hurt anyone?
Lf you weren't in the storage room...
how did you know
l was shelving copying paper?
L don't know.
Shit, maybe it was me.
L gotta pray.
Pray that God shows me the way
to fuck Schillinger.
Number?
Nine, nine...
"S"...
three, three, three.
That boy's last name, know what it was?
Schillinger.
Prisoner number 99S333.
Andrew Peter Schillinger.
Convicted February 16, '99.
Murder in the second degree,
possession of narcotics.
Sentence: 50 years.
Up for parole in 20.