Life in Oz sucks, and only a fool
or a Republican will tell you different.
But the punishments here are nowhere near
as fucked up as in the olden days.
Example, the guy who drank too much.
The constable would make him wear
a drunkard's cloak...
which was a whiskey barrel with holes
for the head, the arms, and the legs!
Then they'd make the drunk
walk around the town square...
where everyone would call him names.
Yo, retard! You're next.
Keep punching. Fuck him.
Let's go. Punch it.
Ribs, head. Come on, fuck him.
Pancamo's tough, man.
He's got heavy hands, a good chin,
and he's a mean son of a bitch.
The only advantage your brother has
is speed.
- You don't seem too worried.
- I got faith.
Faith's a good thing.
But I'd put my money on Pancamo.
- Cudney.
- What do you want?
- You working bedpan duty today?
- Yeah.
Great. I need you to steal me
some more of that chloral hydrate...
- and then put it right in here.
- No.
We had a deal, remember?
You sneak drugs out of the hospital...
- I give you nice green fed notes.
- Stealing is wrong.
Today, I confessed to the Lord in front of
my brothers and promised to sin no more.
Fine. You're not the only fish
in the Sea of Galilee.
I figured out what you were doing
with the chloral hydrate.
You spike the fighter's spritzers,
so they're drugged in the ring.
That's crazy talk.
I've made an appointment with the warden
to tell him.
My soul is in jeopardy. So's yours.
By turning you in, I'm gonna save you.
Not if I save you first.
I don't got a lot of time.
Rumor is you're the most ruthless hitman
in Little Odessa. That's got to mean a lot...
because you Russian mob guys
are crazy fucked-up motherfuckers.
I need a job done, I need it done pronto.
Just tell me when to stop, okay?
97B752.
98B526.
99B131.
99C124.
99C124!
Cudney!
- What's the problem?
- I don't know.
Cudney, get out here!
Shit, look at the blood.
- He's dead.
- Look at these two small holes.
Stabbed in the neck.
In this corner,
Chucky "The Enforcer" Pancamo.
Put this on.
Let them fight!
Come on, tough guy.
Fight!
He doesn't want to fight.
Come on, Cyril.
Let's go, come on. Use your head.
What the fuck is that?
Don't worry about that fucking fat
dago motherfucker. He's all yours.
You okay? You feel good?
What did I tell you?
You gotta believe in yourself.
When you focus, when you put your mind
to it, you can do really big things, Cyril.
Here's the money I owe you
for betting on Pancamo.
- Good fight.
- Thanks.
Cyril, would you mind if I talked to
your brother alone for just a moment?
Go downstairs.
It's almost time for Miss Sally.
- Close the door, please.
- Sure.
What's up?
I understand Yuri Kosygin
did a little job for you.
- Job?
- Kosygin is a dangerous man.
Unpredictable, unreliable.
He's making sounds like he's going to tell
the authorities about killing Cudney.
He killed Cudney?
Ryan, I'm here as your friend.
I'm telling you, Kosygin must be eliminated.
You know, we got a little saying in
this country. Maybe you've heard it:
"You can't shit a shitter."
You want Kosygin dead. You come here,
you say he's making sounds.
You're hoping that I'm gonna
take care of it for you. No chance.
I do like you, O'Reily.
Then like this:
Here's some free advice for you.
You want Yuri's balls?
Have the Sicilians do it.
Sicilians?
- May I approach?
- Sure, approach.
Recently, you and I had a conversation
about Yuri Kosygin.
He's very disrespectful.
He is also...
I bet on you.
I lost very heavy. He won very heavy.
He told me
he spiked your water with heroin...
in order to, how do you say...
fuck you up.
I knew it! Goddamn, I fucking knew it!
- I hope you don't mind me telling you this.
- No, I don't mind. I appreciate it.
In fact, I owe you one.
- We gotta do the fight over.
- Bullshit.
- I was drugged out.
- What's your proof?
Have me tested.
I'm not gonna spend time or money
to have you tested...
just because you're a sore loser.
Now get the fuck out!
Come on, you heard the man. Let's go.
- Dumb move, man.
- What?
Letting the hacks know
you know Kosygin did the dirty.
- Lf Kosygin dies, they're gonna blame you.
- That's right.
I know you're pissed off
that my brother won the fight, all right?
But in the name of good sportsmanship,
I got a small suggestion for you.
What's that?
The next best thing
to having someone killed...
is having them sent to solitary for the rest
of their lives. Or better yet, death row.
When Kosygin finds out that Stanislofsky
snitched on him, your problems are solved.
In the 1600s, snitches and gossips were
made to wear something called a brank...
which was an iron helmet that was placed
on the head, enclosing it in a kind of cage.
There was a front plate
covered with spikes...
which was placed inside the mouth,
so that if you tried to talk...
You get the idea.
You learn to keep your mouth shut.
You're in America now, Nikolai.
- Let's speak American.
- All right. We speak English.
Unlike you, in Russia I was not a criminal.
I was an educator.
After the Soviets fell,
things got so bleak in Moscow...
I decided to leave, to come to America.
For a better life, right?
Yes, for me and my wife.
But we did not find a better life.
I couldn't get employed teaching.
Must have been terrible.
Then I got this job painting a house,
the house of Leonid Rodzinsky.
- He was in the Organizatsya.
- Yes.
He treated me like shit, always making fun.
Calling me "professor"
and ordering me to clean his toilets.
One day, he kicked me with his boot
in front of my wife.
I strangled him on the spot.
- It's closing time?
- Yes.
All right, I'll go.
Not till I finish my story.
Strange. All this time,
you've barely said two words.
- Now you're a regular bottum.
- It takes me time to warm up to people.
I feel very close to you.
I was possessed by guilt
for killing Rodzinsky...
but I got a reputation for being ruthless.
The Organizatsya hired me
to exterminate someone else.
- The second time was easy...
- Yuri, please.
I don't want to hear this.
The third time, no problem at all.
- Yuri, please.
- At last count, I murdered at least 49 people.
- You have the honor of being my 50th.
- No!
No, you wait now!
Guards!
I need to get his record
to find out what his blood type is.
Let's start an IV, get me a suture set,
and let's give him Demerol, 50 milligrams.
- I need you to stay still.
- No, please.
No hard feelings?
About?
- Nooter's a fag.
- What makes you say that?
- Look at how he's always grabbing Pecky.
- They're fighting.
All I'm saying is
it's a lot of body contact, man.
That's the stupidest thing
I ever heard of, a gay puppet.
- One of the Teletubbies is gay.
- What?
Falwell, the Reverend somebody, says that
Twinky Dink, or whatever his name is...
is a butt pirate.
That's nuts!
You gotta have a cock to be gay.
Teletubbies don't have cocks.
The puppet doesn't have a cock.
Where's it say you gotta have a cock
to be gay?
All you need is a mouth,
so you can suck cock.
- Hernandez wants to see you.
- Right.
Alvarez, what am I always saying
about our friend O'Reily here?
- That he's no dummy.
- That's right, he's no dummy.
- Feeling's mutual, Raoul.
- That so?
Then how come you're always acting
like I'm an idiot?
You know Adebisi and me
are working with the Sicilians now.
We're running the tits everywhere in Oz.
Yeah, I know.
But you sell on your own.
What's up with that?
Me? No, man. A little, sure.
But there's no way I compete with you guys.
Man, I don't care. I want you to stop.
Have you talked this over
with Adebisi and Pancamo?
My word ain't good enough, man?
No, man, your word is plenty good.
I'll stop, right away. Finito.
- Give us what you got.
- Now?
- Can I keep a little for my own personal use?
- You don't use no more, man.
Bullshit.
- Assume the position.
- What?
- I completely forgot about that one.
- No shit.
- No more, O'Reily. Comprende?
- Yeah, comprende.
You wanna bust Hernandez? Now's the time.
Hernandez, turn around.
Empty your pockets.
Thank you. Cuff him.
- Take it fucking easy, man. Shit!
- Come on, let's go.
That there's a real heartbreaker, Alvarez.
I've been thinking.
I wanna see what I'd done to Rivera.
You will, when you see him face to face.
When I stabbed him, I walked away.
I didn't look at him in the eyes.
I wanna see what I did that day.
I wanna see what it looked like that day.
You mean like a photograph?
I used to work in the hospital
and they used to take photographs...
of all the prisoners that came in
with serious shit...
just for the courts, and whatever.
I wanna see a picture of Rivera.
Miguel, I don't know if that's a good idea.
You asked me what happened,
and I couldn't tell you...
because everything
was just a blur, you know...
and it was all shouting.
Every fucking day that I get up,
I look in the mirror...
and I don't see me.
You know, I don't see me.
I just see this other guy who did this.
And a photograph will do what?
I don't know.
Just make me forget about that other guy.
Just let me...
be alone with myself again.
I'll see what I can do.
There you are.
- Tina, what's the matter?
- You gotta stop this.
- You gotta stop Eugene from coming here.
- What's wrong?
It's like I said,
bringing up all this shit from the past.
- It's made him crazy.
- Okay, let's go to my office.
He's not acting normal anymore.
I'm really surprised to hear you say that.
Because when Eugene is with me,
he seems very calm.
He seems open and ready to face Alvarez.
No! It's an act, I tell you.
At home, he says nothing.
He just sits there all quiet.
Are you sure it's he who's not talking?
Maybe he's afraid that since you didn't
want him to be in the program...
you might not be supportive.
Don't tell me I'm not supportive.
I have been there for him.
Through the surgeries,
by his bed, day and night.
I rearranged the house,
my whole fucking life!
I know what you've done.
Eugene told me he could have
never made it this far without you.
He also told me
he's thinking of committing suicide.
- What?
- So that you can have a life.
Sweet Jesus!
Years ago, I was married,
and my husband was murdered.
So for a very long time...
I wallowed in grief and anger...
until that's all I had.
Eugene knows
that he only has two choices now:
To move on or die.
You've helped him this far.
Go the rest of the way.
We take Ponoma down to the piers.
He knows what's up.
He don't beg, he don't struggle.
I tell him, I say, "Sonny...
"you got a pair of balls."
And then I blew them both off.
- Who the fuck are you?
- Nat Ginsberg. Your new roommate.
Okay, new roomie,
you listen up and listen good.
- This is my cell. You just sleep here.
- Got a name, tough guy?
Nappa. Mr. Nappa.
- I love to eat Italian.
- I ain't no fag.
Don't worry. I won't hold that against you.
- You a writer?
- I'm doing my memoirs.
Are you Antonio Nappa? The mob guy?
That's gonna be some book.
You naming names?
Names, places, felonies.
You don't, by any chance,
need a Boswell, do you?
Secretary.
Sure. What's your name again?
Nat.
Short for Nathaniel?
Short for Natalie.
What do you got for me?
Yeah, he's writing some fucking book
about his life.
And from what I hear, he tells everything.
He wants to get the book.
We take care of Nappa.
- Fuck.
- Yeah, fuck.
Why don't you just kill me?
Kenny...
You know, in Africa...
the elders of the tribe...
used to teach the young warriors
not just how to fight...
but how to live.
I am the chief of this tribe.
I'm gonna teach you
the right way to behave.
You're a sick motherfucker, Adebisi.
Oh, shit!
First lesson is in respect.
God, I do respect you. I respect you.
Yeah? Get ready.
We have to prepare breakfast
for our brothers.
Your wife is murdered.
You find out she's been cheating on you.
That's a lot to handle emotionally.
We grew up in the same 'hood...
went to the same grade school,
same junior high together.
I was supposed to take her to her prom
but I got arrested the day before.
I had the tux rented, corsage bought.
I feel bad that she missed out 'cause of me.
There's something else
that we're gonna have to deal with:
Your son.
Now that he has no mother,
he's gonna depend on you.
He's gonna need more from you as a father.
What you saying? I love my kid.
Sure. But the time that you spend with him
needs to be more focused.
I want you to join the parenting program.
Establish an ongoing relationship
with your son...
so that when you get released,
he'll know who you are.
What do you say? Will you join up?
I guess. Anything for my kid.
- Hey, Ma.
- Hey, how you doing?
- Hi.
- Hi, it's your daddy.
Jordan, come here.
What's up? How you been?
You been with Grandma?
Why he act like he don't know me?
- He hasn't seen you for a while.
- Take your time.
Jordan, how's your Grandma treating you?
Stop, don't cry. Stop crying!
No, stop crying. Be a man!
It's okay.
Honey, it's all right. It's okay, sweetie.
- Where you going, Kenny?
- I got things to do.
McManus was just fucking with your head,
little brother.
The way all white men fuck with our heads.
But I got a plan, Kenny.
- A way to break McManus.
- What good is that gonna do?
We force them to bring someone else
to run Emerald City.
- Who will be just as bad.
- Who will be one of us.
All right, SORT, we're gonna work
on cell extraction. Non-cooperative prisoner.
Get down!
Stay down!
...and the governor said
the crime rate is down...
because of longer prison sentences.
- You ever think about going SORT?
- They're not big on women.
Besides, when you sign on to SORT...
they remove
all the human parts of your body.
Don't you think
that's the way they gotta be?
We're supposed to have a
day-to-day relationship with the prisoners...
but the SORT guys...
their job is to go in
and shut an ugly situation down.
I know that, and I appreciate that.
But it takes a special kind of hardness
to be SORT.
And I don't have it?
We out of Sweet 'N Low?
You all deaf?
What you did to Tim McManus sucks.
What I did to Tim McManus
was suck his cock.
And for that, he treated me like a shitball.
Accusing him of sexual harassment?
That's an insult to women
who have been abused.
Like you?
Yeah, like me.
You know what your problem is, Diane?
You wanna be everybody's best pal.
And your problem?
You wanna be everybody's worst nightmare.
Look, Sweet 'N Low.
She's the right type for the SORT team.
O'Brien.
Bevilaqua.
Giles. Giles?
Phase 4, this is Radio 24 requesting backup.
Drawing and quartering.
A man was tied to the tail of a horse and
dragged along the ground to a gallows...
where he was hung till he was half dead.
Then, brought down, his body cut open...
his entrails taken out and burned...
then his head cut off,
and his body sliced into quarters.
After all that indignity, the hangman would
hold up the dead man's heart and yell:
"Behold! The heart of a traitor!"
- Leo.
- Yeah?
I just wanted to talk to you
about Clayton Hughes.
- Yeah?
- Well...
- What'd he do now?
- Nothing.
I just had a little conversation with him...
and he seems to need to know
if the guy who stabbed his dad is still in Oz.
I told him to let it go.
He's young, he won't listen.
I dug around the files a little.
There are 26 inmates who were here 17
years ago, who may have seen something.
- I wanted to tell you I'll talk to each of them.
- What good will that do?
We interrogated them all at the time.
We got nowhere.
I'm not telling you
that I'm gonna find anything out.
After all these years, maybe someone's
willing to give up some information.
- Hi, Glo.
- Hey.
I hear you have William Giles here.
Yeah, he suffered a mild heart attack.
So I have him under observation.
Is he still talking in Morse code?
He seems to do well
with yes-and-no questions.
- May I?
- Yeah.
Thanks.
William, remember me? Father Mukada.
How are you feeling? Better?
Yes.
I've been meaning
to come and see you in solitary.
Would you mind if I asked you a question?
No.
Do you remember 17 years ago,
a CO named Samuel Hughes?
Yes.
Do you remember
that he was killed here in Oz?
Yeah.
Were you there in the cafeteria
when he was killed?
Yes.
Do you know who killed him?
Do you know who killed Samuel Hughes?
Tell, bye-bye, die.
No, you won't. I swear.
You'll be back in solitary
where no inmate can hurt you.
No.
There's a young man,
Samuel Hughes' son, Clayton.
He needs to know
what happened to his father.
I've talked to all the other prisoners
who were here then...
and no one will tell me anything.
William, please.
Which prisoner killed Samuel Hughes?
- No. No prisoner.
- Not a prisoner?
Then who?
Leo Glynn.
This is Radio 320, we got a problem here.
Prisoner's OD'd.
We're too late for the medics.
Send the morgue boys.
- Morning, Glen.
- Yeah.
It's so nice and quiet.
I wish we could leave them like this.
Especially now since Schillinger's son OD'd.
Yeah, I heard.
I thought Andrew was in the hole.
- He was.
- So how did he get the drugs?
Beats the shit out of me.
- Is Glynn investigating?
- Yeah, but on the QT.
Doesn't seem all that anxious to find out.
See you tomorrow.
How you doing there, Vern?
I knew a guy who had one arm.
He told me when he dreams,
he still had both arms.
Every morning, he'd wake up...
and have to realize all over again,
one arm was missing.
Every morning, it was like the first time
they told him his arm was gone.
My son is dead.
What you did, giving him the heroin...
that was the right thing.
You put him to the test.
He was weak.
He was not one of us.
No.
The way I figure, it was euthanasia.
Keller and Beecher
were gonna fuck with my boy.
By killing him...
I saved him.
I'm asking McManus
to put me back in your pod.
Don't.
Why? Andy's dead.
He ain't coming back anytime soon.
You and me, Beecher.
Please take your hand away.
- Beecher.
- Please.
Take your fucking hand away.
What the fuck are you looking at?
You wanted revenge on Schillinger.
I helped you get that.
You did it for us?
Yeah.
When are you gonna figure it out?
You and me. We're never gonna happen.
You love me, Toby.
Fuck my ass.
Sister Pete! I'm gonna see you today, right?
3:00. You visiting one of your ex-wives?
- Yeah.
- Which one? Kitty or Angelique?
Bonnie. Wife number two and number four.
She's the best.
There she is, there she is.
- A redhead.
- No, the other one.
- Chris, she's...
- Huge.
Did she gain some weight after the divorce?
No, she was that way when I married her.
Both times.
Bye.
You and Schillinger were together
at Lardner when you were how old?
17.
He saved your life?
- Did you have sex together?
- Yeah.
Did he force himself on you?
Vern likes the power part of sex,
so I let him think he did.
- Do you enjoy sex with men?
- I enjoy sex. Don't you?
You told me you were married
before you became a nun.
Did you and your husband have great sex?
I can tell you did. I bet you were wild.
Lint.
Do you miss it? Sex?
- I miss my husband.
- Sure.
You ever have sex with anyone
other than him?
Chris.
You know, every time
we have a session together...
and we get to a topic you want to avoid...
you somehow manage
to turn the discussion around to me.
You noticed?
I just want to get to the heart...
of why you did what you did to Beecher.
You saw my ex, Bonnie?
When I met her,
she was all alone, very unhappy.
So I knew it would be easy
to get her to fall in love with me.
But what I didn't know...
was after I broke her heart...
would she still love me?
See, I'm a piece of shit.
I am worthless.
As bad as they come.
And to have someone keep loving me,
no matter how bad...
You happy now?
You got me to open up
and spill my guts all over your table.
Breakthrough.
So you went along with Beecher
not in the name of the Aryan brotherhood...
but to see if he would love you,
no matter what.
At first, I wanted unconditional surrender.
Then I wanted unconditional love.
But Beecher don't love me.
And that's killing you inside.
Yeah.
"And forgive us our trespasses...
"as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
"And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
"For Thine is the kingdom..."
- This room is reserved.
- I know. For your Muslims.
Our daily study group.
Pull a chair.
I was raised Episcopalian.
Which means we thought about God
once a week for an hour.
But you, you think about him all the time.
- Yeah.
- Why?
I want to know him.
Me, too.
I want to know God.
I want him to know me.
To know I'm here.
I'm still in this place.
He knows.
When I came to Oz...
I read the Bible from Genesis to Apocalypse.
Great book, the Bible.
May I borrow this? The Qur'an?
Of course.
Beecher...
would you like to stay?
- Listen to our discussion?
- Yes.
Have a seat.
Come on in, my brothers.
What are you doing, allowing a non-believer
into our study group?
A non-believer?
You mean "white man."
He doesn't belong.
Beecher is a lost soul
searching for the truth.
He has every right to be there
to receive instruction.
No!
No?
Ever since I came to Oz,
I've listened to you rationalize your actions.
You are no longer fit to lead us.
We need an imam who's above reproach.
And who's that, Khan? You?
Yes.
Never.
Nasim, come.
Oh, poor Said!
So it's true, what I heard?
Yes.
I still want you to teach me about God.
I'm not sure that I can.
Said's out.
Beecher came to my office, asked me
if he could move Said into his pod.
- And you said?
- Sure.
We need to set up a meeting
with whoever took Said's place.
- What's his name?
- Hamid Khan.
Prisoner number 99K515, Hamid Khan.
Convicted March 6, '99. Aggravated assault.
Sentence: 10 years. Up for parole in 5.
Moving in with the white folk, Kareem?
Hey, lovebirds...
My all-time favorite punishment?
It's called "riding the stag."
The wittiest person in town
would be put on a chair...
carried around the streets
by his fellow townspeople...
while he banged on a bucket,
and yelled out dirty limericks...
condemning the accused.
Being made fun of...
being humiliated in front of everyone else
in your community...
that may be the cruelest punishment of all.