"Know thyself." That's what Socrates said.
Or Aristotle or one of them dead white men.
To know yourself.
That's the hardest thing
anyone of us can ever do.
...except that I felt very guilty.
So that was very much a Catholic thing.
- Keller.
- Yo.
I got you scheduled for a 10:00 a.m. Session
with Sister Peter Marie.
- Yeah.
- It's almost 10:00 now.
You know something, I don't wanna go.
I want to check in some gym time.
Suit yourself. Take him.
Keller gone?
Never came.
Second appointment he's missed.
- Is he okay?
- Yeah.
Seems okay. We don't really talk much.
When you do talk...
has he ever said anything
about our sessions?
Nope.
Sister Pete, are you all right?
Yeah.
- You're lying.
- I swear the truth.
What's going on with you
and Sister Peter Marie?
Going on?
You missed two appointments
and she's a mess.
I don't know what you're talking about.
If you're gonna fuck with her, Keller,
I'm gonna fuck with you.
Fucking bitch.
What was that about?
It's his time of the month.
All right, let's go.
Miguel's on his way.
Hello, Miguel. Thank you, officer.
Eugene and Tina Rivera. Miguel Alvarez.
All right, everybody.
Our purpose here today
is to provide an environment for discussion.
Sit down, Miguel.
To ask and answer questions...
to share experiences.
A few ground rules.
Allow me to lead the meeting.
Refrain from interruptions.
Tell the truth.
No profanity.
And most importantly, listen.
Why don't you begin, Eugene?
I can't see you, Alvarez.
I'm looking right at you and I can't see you.
Can you see me?
What?
Yeah.
Can you see my wife?
Yes.
You're a lucky man.
I asked Tina to marry me
'cause I wanted to wake up every day...
for the rest of my life,
and see her face first thing.
But instead...
'cause of you, I'll never see her face again.
Do you know something about me
which I don't?
A reason I deserved this?
No.
Have you thought about
what this might be like for him?
- Kind of.
- Kind of?
So why go after me?
Not Metzger, not Wittlesey, not Glynn...
or McManus or Sister Pete.
Me, Alvarez. Why?
- Answer him, God damn it!
- Tina.
No. He's asking why.
Why do we have to live with this?
Why do we have to argue
about having a kid?
We shouldn't have to argue about
having a fucking kid.
Please, sit down.
Yeah, honey, sit.
You see, Miguel,
that's why Eugene and Tina are here.
Tell them why it happened.
I can't.
Was it a gang thing?
Did you do it 'cause of Hernandez?
You earned your cojones by blinding me?
It started out that way, yeah.
But, you know, this place...
I hate this fucking place.
What it did to my grandpa, my dad, and me.
I don't know you, you know.
I had nothing against you.
It was your uniform, bro.
It was a hermano in that uniform, man.
I want my eyes back.
I know.
- Sorry.
- You're what?
I'm sorry.
No! I said I want my eyes back.
Give them back to me.
- I can't.
- Why not? You took them.
- Forgive me.
- Fuck you.
Miguel asked you a question.
Can you forgive him?
- Not today.
- All right.
Let's leave the door open
for the possibility of another meeting, okay?
Maybe.
Clark Kent is the secret identity
of Superman.
I never understood why Superman
needed a secret identity.
Listen, if I'm invulnerable,
if all the chicks want me...
why would I disguise myself
as a four-eyed wimp?
The truth: Superman is schizophrenic.
Superman's id is fucking with his superego.
The man's conflicted, no doubt about it.
- Hello, Chris.
- Hiya, Sister.
- Can I talk to you?
- Sure. Let's go in here.
Sorry about this.
You missed our last two sessions. Why?
Ever since our last time together
when you got me to open up...
I've been afraid to come back.
Afraid to expose any more of myself to you.
The reality is, Sister, I hate myself.
All the more reason
why you should have come to me.
You're probably right.
Do you know what it's like
to want somebody?
To long for them?
And I'm not talking about sex.
Just to touch them.
Yeah.
Of course you do.
You're a psychologist, you're a nun.
But you're a woman first.
You know about desires.
- Everything all right in there, Sister?
- I'm fine.
- I can help you, Chris.
- I know you can. Talk to Beecher.
Counsel him. Convince him.
Tell him that you love him?
And that he loves you?
And that's what this has all been about,
hasn't it?
The sessions,
the questions about my personal life...
getting me to care.
So I can help you reach Beecher.
You can do it. He trusts you.
You still don't see it, do you?
That's the whole problem.
He trusted you. You broke his trust.
Now he can't trust you again.
Yeah, but I've changed.
Have you?
You've manipulated me
the way you did him...
and I don't trust you anymore.
Wait a minute.
Let go of me.
Hell hath no fury, Sister?
Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.
I had lust in my heart.
You haven't acted on this lust?
No.
- But...
- You may.
No.
Then?
It's opened up all these feelings in me.
Feelings that I thought
I had paved over years ago.
Now that I'm back in touch
with these feelings...
it seems wrong to shut them off again.
I owe it to my soul...
to be all of the things that I am...
all of the parts of myself.
And so?
I've decided to leave the convent.
To stop being a nun.
Come on, help yourself out.
We found the heroin on you, in your pocket.
Where'd you get it?
Don't fuck with me, Hernandez.
I can tack on another five
just for obstruction...
and think what I can do
with the possession charge.
I got two more of your compadres
to talk to...
and I'm willing to bet at least one of them
values his ass over yours.
Get him the fuck out of here.
- Carlo, wanna help me out?
- Help? How?
I know you think you're a badass
like Hernandez and Guerra...
but I've been watching you. You're not.
Your family visits regularly.
You come from a better place
than those two other fucks.
I can make life a lot easier for you.
Where is Hernandez getting the drugs?
Take him back to the hole.
Till you talk,
you will not see an inch of daylight.
If I find out what I need to know
from anybody else, you'll never see it again.
I'm here to see my brother, Carlo Ricardo.
No, sorry.
- It is visiting day, isn't it?
- Yes, but your brother's in ad seg.
- What's that?
- He's been segregated from the others.
He's had his privileges taken away,
including visitation rights.
- But I have to see him.
- Sure. Not today.
- You don't understand.
- Lf I had a nickel...
for every time I didn't understand,
you'd be talking to an empty chair.
- Where's your superior?
- Miss, I'm really trying to be pleasant.
I'm not leaving
until I talk to someone in charge.
In Oz, we don't really take
too well to demands.
I have to see my brother.
He got caught dealing drugs
and he refuses to talk...
so we don't have any choice
but to keep him in the hole.
- Could I see him in there?
- No, you'll come back when he gets out.
You don't understand. I am all he's got.
Luis is disappearing, days at a time.
Isabella, fucking baby crying.
Juan is an asshole.
Mami goes between the apartment, work,
and the hospital.
- I'm sorry, but...
- I got a job in Oakland.
It's good money.
I have to take it to support my family.
I leave tomorrow.
I can't get there and right away say I gotta
go home to see my brother in prison.
They don't even know
I have a brother in prison.
I don't want him to think that
I've abandoned him, that he's dead to me.
Just for one minute, to tell him.
Just one minute, I promise.
I'm sorry.
I can't. There's just no way.
But you can write him a note...
and I'll see that he gets it.
This'll kill him.
Lopresti, I gotta split.
Do me a favor
and take this to Carlo Ricardo in the hole.
- Okay.
- Thanks a lot. See you tomorrow.
Since when do you take messages
to that fucking spic?
Yeah, fuck that.
You ain't so bad now?
- Hello, Roger.
- Lenore.
- Long time, huh?
- Look at you. You look great.
Thank you. I'm just dropping Clayton off
and I wanted to say hi to Leo.
- He was supposed to meet us down here.
- My car is still in the shop.
Clayton's embarrassed.
- I am not, Mom.
- It's all right.
It's good to see you
and it's good to have Clayton with us.
Oh, my.
It's so strange being back in here.
Yeah, I can imagine.
I told your wife this morning that
I didn't think I could come in this door...
but Clayton's never been happier.
- He loves his job.
- Mom.
I have something for you.
Found it in the attic.
You and Sammy were so young.
Yeah, we were.
Thanks, Lenore.
Keep him there, close to your heart.
And this one, too, keep him safe.
- Of course. Don't you worry.
- Bye.
- Happy birthday, Clayton.
- Happy birthday?
- I got it.
- I can't find them.
- It's the drawer on the right.
- Right.
No.
We can't have a birthday cake
without candles.
- I'll go into town and buy some.
- No, Hughes' shift starts in 10 minutes.
I got everybody meeting
at the library at 12:00.
This is a really great idea, Diane,
throwing Clayton a surprise party.
Yeah, my heart goes out to the kid.
One, because I know what it's like
starting work here...
everybody thinking you don't have the balls
for the job. Two, his dad.
I've been checking into that...
the circumstances
surrounding his dad's death.
- Did you find anything out?
- I talked to William Giles...
who was in the cafeteria
when Hughes got stabbed...
and he claims...
I don't know whether to believe him or not.
If I do believe him, I don't know what to do.
If I do something about it,
who knows what'll happen.
You're raving.
He says that Sam Hughes was stabbed
by Leo.
Leo who? DiCaprio?
- Glynn.
- Leo Glynn?
- Yes.
- Giles is delusional.
I know. I dismiss it and then I think...
maybe that's why the murderer
was never identified.
Something tells me
that Leo has never told the whole truth.
What about a votive candle?
- What?
- For the cake.
Can't we steal those candles
you use at Mass?
Yeah, I guess. I'll get some.
I'll meet you in the library.
If you seriously doubt Leo,
you owe it to the man to tell him.
Leo, you got a minute?
- Sure. Walk me to my office.
- Okay.
Like I told you,
I'm talking to people about Sam Hughes.
Yes, what did you get?
Did you come up with something?
- Maybe. William Giles.
- That loony tunes?
I don't think that he's so much crazy
as just afraid to be sane.
- And he claims... Well, he says...
- What?
...that you killed Sam Hughes.
Leo, you have talked to Clayton
about what happened.
You have told him the truth.
But if there's more to that truth,
then he has a right to hear it...
however hard it is for you to say.
God damn it, Ray.
I don't have to explain myself to you.
No, you don't.
But you do to Clayton.
It's like a confession.
It needs to be made once...
and only to the person
who can absolve you.
Get the fuck out of my office.
- It's time to open up.
- Go ahead, we're almost done.
- Thanks for this, Diane.
- Sure.
Promise me when my birthday comes,
we don't celebrate it.
- Hey, O'Reily!
- "Hey" what?
Your brother fight like a girl, man.
Yeah? You wanna go
a couple rounds with him, homey?
- I'll take you and your brother.
- You and what fucking army?
Knock it off!
- Don't talk to me. Talk to the brother here.
- Sit down.
- I didn't come to sit down.
- Sit the fuck down.
What are you gonna do, spank me?
- You got a problem?
- Get your fucking hands...
Fuck!
It's okay.
Don't.
- She gonna be okay?
- A few stitches, mild concussion.
- What the fuck were you thinking?
- I was trying to maintain order.
The way I hear it,
there wasn't much to maintain.
- I've warned you before.
- So, what, are you gonna fire me?
Sit down.
I wanna tell you
about the day your father died.
Your dad and I were both on duty.
I made up my mind,
when I first walked into Oz...
that I was going to treat each situation
as a worst-case scenario.
Sam knew better...
and he tried to hold me back. Tried.
But I was too young...
too determined...
too stupid.
A fight erupted.
I tripped or slipped on the slop on the floor.
I was stunned, losing control.
Then all my wind left.
Your dad had to get involved.
You okay?
He fell right next to me.
I didn't know what the fuck was happening.
By then, other officers responded.
I just held him till he died.
In my arms...
at the hands of my stupidity.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
It's just I have to go home
to my daughter looking like this.
Diane, when I heard you got hurt,
I went crazy.
- Tim, don't.
- Don't what?
Don't be honest?
I've been thinking or feeling...
I know I've been all over the place
and back with this thing.
But maybe we could try it again. Together.
If I didn't have this golf ball on my head...
I would think that was more political
than romantic.
What do you mean by that?
If it isn't the lovebirds.
I knew a man who worked on Wall Street...
wore a bra and panties
under his Brooks Brothers suit.
Every day, he'd sit in meetings...
making harsh decisions
and cold business deals.
Yet underneath, he felt pretty. Oh, so pretty.
- Done.
- And?
I'm telling you, Mr. Nappa,
and I'm not prone to hyperbole...
but this may be the greatest true-crime book
since In Cold Blood.
Really. I never read that.
It was chilling. This is better.
We're gonna send this
to that literary agent right now.
Be careful.
If any of the other wiseguys find out...
I wrote a book about the Mob, we're dead.
I'll be careful.
And to celebrate, I want to make dinner.
And I think we should
get dressed to the nines.
- Come on, please.
- We'll see.
Officer, I'm not feeling very well.
Would it be possible for me to go to the ER?
Give him the coin.
Your friend's gonna take care
of that other matter for me, right?
Fucking rat.
- Did I overdress?
- Jesus.
- You look a lot like my ex-wife.
- Thanks.
That's not a compliment.
- Sit.
- That's nice.
- Pour this.
- Wine.
You're not the only one
who can move merchandise.
There you go.
And me.
To your book, to your life,
and the successful completion of both.
- I ain't dead yet.
- No, you're not.
Pretty good.
In his day, Antonio Nappa was a great man.
He was like a father to me.
- Well, more like an uncle.
- Lights out!
Good citizens of Gotham City
have to be the dumbest fucks on the planet.
They got Batman and Robin
saving their asses...
from the Riddler, Joker and such.
They also got millionaire Bruce Wayne
and his ward Dick Grayson...
in the headlines every day.
Batman and Robin. Bruce and Dick.
You mean to tell me
nobody ever put two and two together?
I wanna see the warden.
- What for?
- My business.
Adebisi, you ought to know by now
that your business is my business.
- I wanna file a complaint.
- About?
Tim McManus.
You're accusing McManus
of sexual harassment?
That's right.
What'd he do to you?
Not me. Kenny Wangler.
Yesterday, he touched Kenny's penis.
Officer...
bring Wangler in.
Sit down.
This is a very serious charge.
- And if I find out you're lying...
- I ain't lying.
The burden of truth is on you.
It ain't like I ain't had to deal
with guys in here groping on me.
I just been all fucked up lately,
sad about my life and whatnot.
McManus puts his arm around my shoulder
like a friend...
only it's not like a friend.
I was gonna just blow it off,
but Adebisi was like, "Don't."
He says what goes on with us prisoners
is one thing...
and what goes on with McManus
is something else.
- He said what?
- That you fondled him.
That is complete horseshit.
I tried to comfort him.
You're not taking any of this seriously,
are you?
Claire Howell accusing you
of sexual harassment.
- But she's full of shit, too.
- Yeah.
I'd like to know when it stops.
When it stops
being everybody else's problem.
- You make it sound like I'm a sex addict.
- Maybe you are.
Since the day you came to Oz,
I've watched you jump in and out of beds.
I held my tongue, even though I thought
what you were doing was pretty disgusting.
Wangler's lying.
Probably. But then, maybe there are other
inmates who never stepped forward.
You know what, I don't know.
And I don't know how to find out.
But if this is true...
you're finished here.
- Rick Donn?
- Yes.
I'm a big fan of your news program.
Very hard-hitting.
Thank you. You said on the phone
that you have a story for me?
Yes. It's all about sex.
Can we get a comment from you
about this sexual harassment charge?
Get out of my office!
In an exclusive, Channel 2 News
has learned that Tim McManus...
the unit manager
at Oswald Correctional Facility...
has been repeatedly accused
of sexually harassing both inmates...
and correctional officers.
McManus was initially accused
of harassing a female officer, Claire Howell.
The State's attorney has confirmed that
the Howell case was settled out of court.
Oh, boy, Miss Sally.
Do you think her boobs are real?
They're taking Wangler to gen pop now.
- Called your lawyer?
- Yes.
- And she said?
- Be patient.
Go about your life.
Act normal.
Acting normal is what got me into trouble
in the first place.
- It's gonna be all right, man.
- Yeah.
Hello, I'm Tim McManus.
Yes, hello. I really appreciate your coming...
taking time out of what I know
is a busy, busy schedule.
To tell you the truth, I'm very curious
as to why you asked me here.
Please be seated.
- Would you like some tea?
- No.
- May I call you Tim?
- Sure.
Tim...
in the past few weeks
I've suffered a series of stunning blows.
- Richie Hanlon's murder.
- Yeah, we're still investigating.
And yesterday, my new lawyer,
who is court-appointed...
and who I do not like at all...
told me that the State Supreme Court
rejected my final appeal.
Next Thursday is the date set for...
the execution.
It's the first time
I've said that word out loud:
"The execution." My execution.
The warden informed me
I may choose the means in which I will die...
and I was hoping you might help me
pick one out.
Me?
Richie always spoke so highly of you.
Said you were a good man.
Did he?
If you were going to die,
which way would you choose?
I'm not sure.
They say that lethal injection
is the least painful.
Pain is definitely part of the consideration.
- I would say the only consideration.
- No.
The style in which I die...
must have a sort of lyricism,
if you will, some significance.
There's the gas chamber.
They say the gas turns your skin green.
How about a hanging?
When you die, your feet do a little dance...
a little dance of death.
Richie was right about you.
A hanging, that's perfect.
I want to go out of this life dancing.
Thank you, kind sir.
You know, Richie had a little crush on you.
Did he?
And I can see why.
Officer.
You mustn't despair
over this sexual-harassment thing.
You know about that?
Even on death row, rumor lives.
Next item, puncture-resistant vests. Diane?
We all know
that attacks on COs are on the rise.
One every hour, 10,000 a year.
These vests, they're similar to the Kevlar
ones worn by the cops on the street...
except these are shank-proof
as well as being bulletproof.
They also cost $400 apiece. I don't have
that kind of money in the budget.
You ready for this?
Gloria Nathan just examined
Shirley Bellinger. She's pregnant.
Holy fuck.
Cyril, could you please
settle the fuck down?
- I'm boxing.
- Yeah, I know.
- O'Reily.
- Yo, slow down.
Cyril, isn't it about time
for Miss Sally's Schoolyard?
- No.
- Cyril, go outside and wait, all right?
Cyril, please.
O'Reily, who you betting on
in today's fight, Khan or the faggot?
Neither. I'm sitting this one out.
You've been on the winner
every match so far.
How come you decide to sit this one out?
'Cause whoever wins today's fight...
has to fight my brother next week.
I don't want to bring on a jinx.
Never took you for superstitious.
I'm a man of logic, I'm a man of planning.
I consider every detail,
I factor in every possibility.
Then I flip a coin.
Okay, if you were gonna bet,
who would you bet on?
All right.
Khan, he's got the power and discipline.
So you're saying the Muslim?
- Cramer's got the speed and the style.
- So you're saying the faggot?
Look at that fucking retard, Cyril!
Yo, Cyril.
Cut it out, man!
- Knock it off!
- Cyril, stop it!
Fucking fruitcake.
- Stop.
- What?
I'm boxing.
Sorry about that, Officer Murphy.
Ever since he beat Pancamo,
my brother's been a little frisky.
- You, save your fists for the ring, all right?
- Yes, sir.
Watch your brother, O'Reily, okay?
You don't want him disqualified
from the championship...
'cause he ended up in the hole.
What the fuck were you thinking?
When I fight, people cheer, right?
- Yeah?
- I like when they cheer.
I'm not scared anymore.
That's good, Cyril,
but you don't have to fight all the time.
- I don't?
- No, you don't.
But, Ryan, you do.
The man you're boxing today...
represents all that's repulsive to our faith
regarding sexual desire.
Your victory over Jason Cramer
will be a victory for purity.
For righteousness.
For Allah.
Hello, boys.
Go away.
We're in the middle of our study group.
How do you know
I don't want to learn about Islam?
Be serious.
Plenty of things have happened.
Beecher and Said.
Adebisi, get to your point.
My point is simple.
We all share the same skin...
they don't.
Don't beat Cramer because he likes boys,
beat him because he's white.
What do you want, Schillinger?
What I want is for you to focus
on something other than your dick.
You know, all this time
we've been in Unit B together...
you've never given two shits about me.
Now that I'm boxing that Muslim,
you're my best pal.
Must have been kind of hard
deciding who to root for.
Let's see, the fag or the nigger?
Then again, you know a lot more about
what it's like having your cock sucked...
than having an Afro.
You better watch your mouth, Tinkerbell...
or Khan's gonna win by default.
Kill that white bitch!
Come on, man, you ain't tired.
Great work. Good job, Jason.
All right.
From the judges' scorecard,
we have from Judge 1:
30-29, Khan.
Hell, yeah!
Judge 2 has it:
29-28, Cramer.
And Judge 3 has it, 30-29.
The winner by split decision:
Hamid Khan.
You see that?
People live their whole lives
thinking they know who they are.
Husband, mother, son, lawyer, doctor...
pizza delivery boy, Baptist, Jew...
Muslim, Italian, Irish, WASP, black...
white, yellow, male, female.
Then something comes along
and blows all those illusions to shit...
and you're left with the truth.
The lonely, terrifying truth.
Beecher, you are Said's bodyguard.
Sort of.
Not really.
I want to see him.
Up and down...
life in Oz.
First I was king, then I was loony,
now I am king again.
Congratulations.
You and me,
we come at the world from different paths.
But there's something about you
I've always admired.
And me, you.
You are alone.
But it doesn't have to be that way.
Join me.
- I am very honored.
- But you refuse.
- They will kill you, you know.
- Probably.
Beecher can't protect you.
Probably not.
But I am ready to take whatever journey
Allah has chosen for me.
We could never hurt Said because
he always had goddamn bodyguards.
Now we get to kill him and Beecher.
- Can I sit here?
- No.
That's kind of stupid.
You need firepower.
Fuck you both.
You came to me wanting to learn
how to get closer to God...
because of your part
in the death of Andrew Schillinger.
The guilt you carry
can only be lightened by forgiveness.
- I want to be forgiven.
- So you must forgive...
Schillinger and Keller.
- I can't.
- Beecher, you must.
What about you?
Don't you have to forgive Hamid Khan?
You'd better stay here.
Peace be unto you.
As salaam alaikum, my brothers.
Let him in.
So what do you want, black man?
Five years ago, I was a very different man.
Selfish, ambitious, manipulative, arrogant.
One day I'm in Mecca, and the words
of the Prophet, praise be unto him...
filled me with the grace
and the glory of Allah.
I wanted nothing more
than to show others...
the visions I had seen, the possibilities.
I studied, became a teacher and a leader...
but despite all my righteous intentions...
I was still selfish, ambitious, manipulative...
and even more arrogant.
What's happened
over the past few months...
has humbled me.
I have been humbled.
But not by you.
By God.
Stripped of everything else...
I have nothing left but Allah.
And that is more than enough.
Peace be unto you, my brother.
What the hell is that?
In the name of Allah,
the magnificent and merciful...
I have witnessed that there is but one God.
Allah, I confess my faults.
Guide me to the right path.
My prayers, my life, my death...
are all for Allah.
Fuck!
That's not how you do it.
Oh, fuck.
I loved Said's floor show out there.
I wanna talk to you.
All right. What?
Said has helped me see things
a lot more clearly, Chris.
- And...
- Chris?
I forgive you.
And I ask that you forgive me.
- I love you.
Kiss me.
Faster. Come on.
Stop fucking around. This is important.
Faster, Cyril.
- O'Reily, come here.
- I'm busy. Faster, Cyril.
- There's money in the air.
- Keep working.
- I want you to help me kill Said.
- Said? He's nobody anymore.
Even so, I gotta think
of a way to bring him down.
Without Beecher suspecting, right, Keller?
Truth is you don't got to do nothing.
Rumor has it the
Aryans are gonna whack Said.
- You know when?
- I'd say right now.
I know you're gonna think this is bullshit...
but I feel badly
about my part in Andy's death.
I'm so sorry.
Losing a kid...
there's nothing worse.
And I wanna make it up to you.
How?
How the fuck
can you ever make that up to me?
You had another son,
you don't know where he is.
Through the private investigators
at my old law office, I could find him.
And that's supposed to even the score?
To make everything okay between us?
It's a start.
Beecher, you're crazier than I thought.
There's only one thing
that's gonna make this all okay.
You dead.
Lockdown!
Come on. Move it.
People are defined by three things:
Their heads...
how they think...
their hearts...
what they feel...
their dicks...
who they fuck.
At the end of the day,
each of us has to answer one question.
One, not so simple question.
Who am I?