Some people say the Bible
is the greatest story ever told.
The best story is:
Boy meets girl, boy loses girl,
boy gets girl.
Yeah.
Boy meets girl.
That first moment
when every corpuscle in your dick
is percolating.
Of course, not everybody
has the same impulse.
What are you doing in my room?
Richie boy,
where you been hiding all day, huh?
Get off my bunk.
- l want you to suck my dick.
- Get lost.
You're a fag. You suck dick.
So what's the problem?
l suck the dicks l wanna suck,
so fuck you.
Richie, Richie.
You shouldn't be talking that way
to me.
- ls there a problem, gentlemen?
- No.
- Get the-- Get off me, damn it.
- Keep your mouth shut.
You better watch it, Richie.
What happened to Alexander Vogel
is gonna happen to you.
You're gonna wake up tomorrow
hanging by your ankles,
- dead.
- You killed Vogel?
Yeah. Me and Schillinger.
Now, suck my fucking dick.
Prisoner number 98H462,
Richard Hanlon.
Convicted June 3rd, '98,
possession and distribution
of controlled substance.
Sentence, eight years.
Up for parole in five.
Hey, Richie.
Yeah?
- Me next?
- What?
l was watching you
play Markie's pud horn. Me next.
Fuck you.
- Oh, shit.
Man, did you see that?
- Who pushed him?
- Hanlon.
McManus, l swear,
he was coming on to me.
l shoved him away.
You're gonna be charged
with murder.
- Fuck.
- Officer.
Shit, shit. Wait.
lf l give you some information,
what kind of deal
can l get in return?
Well, that depends on
your information.
lt's about a murder. A real murder.
- A murder here in Oz?
- Alexander Vogel.
- Vogel?
- Yeah.
lf l tell you who killed Vogel,
can l get a lesser charge?
Well, that depends on
if your information sticks.
Here we are again, Schillinger.
Only this time,
l got proof that you killed Vogel.
- Proof?
- Your friend Mack confessed.
Horseshit.
He told another prisoner
that you and he did the deed together.
Oh, a jailhouse confession?
Please. Mack will deny it.
And it's the two of us, our word
against whoever the jabber is.
Mack's in the other room right now
spilling his guts out.
Like l said, horseshit.
And even if he was,
do you think l would admit to you
that l did it?
ln your wildest fucking dreams,
would l ever give you that satisfaction?
No.
Take him out.
- Yeah?
- Listen up and listen good.
Some friends of mine
are very upset
that you tried to pin
a certain murder on them.
- For that, you're a dead man.
- Oh, Christ.
However,
they're offering you an alternative.
Since you're already in here
for one killing,
they suggest you also confess
to Alexander Vogel's murder.
Take your chances with the court.
At best, you get life.
At worst, you get the death penalty.
lf you get life,
my friends will let you live.
lf not, you're a dead man anyway.
So choose.
Tell Glynn l wanna see him.
l have a confession to make.
Good boy.
Augustus.
- lt's almost time for the hearing.
- l got lost in my head, man.
What were you thinking?
l was thinking that
if all goes well,
l might actually be rolling out of Oz.
That by sundown,
l could be home with my wife.
l could be in my house
drinking a cold beer,
watching the Yankees and the Orioles.
You know what l'm saying?
You know, by sundown...
...l could actually be free, man.
Hey.
Formal hearing
of case number 9661 33,
Hill v. the State.
Mr. Said.
Your Honour.
lt is already a matter of public record
that Richard Kibler,
while serving as a judge
on the state criminal court,
took money in exchange for
giving out more lenient sentences
to three convicted murderers.
Mr. Said claims bias
against his client
because he neither gave bribes
nor knew of that possibility.
But that in itself is not bias.
The defendant has got to show
the actuality,
not the appearance of bias.
Well, at the same time
that Kibler was accepting bribes,
my client came before him.
Now, my client was found guilty
and sentenced by Kibler
to life imprisonment
with the possibility of parole
in 20 years.
Your Honour, Augustus Hill
murdered a police officer in cold blood.
Objection.
The nature of his crime
has direct bearing on his sentence.
Overruled.
Mr. Said has asked the court
for an automatic reversal
of Hill's conviction
due to the circumstance
of Judge Kibler's conviction.
Due to the circumstances
of corruption,
that my client was denied
his fundamental right to a fair trial,
presided over by an impartial judge.
And that therefore, Augustus Hill
is entitled to an automatic reversal
of his conviction.
But there is no precedent
for the court to make such a ruling.
ln fact, to do so would, in effect,
create a rule of law
that is beyond
the court's jurisdiction.
Mr. Said, call your first witness.
Augustus Hill.
Do you swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth,
so help you God?
l do.
How's it going?
l can't tell yet.
This guy, Fortunato,
he's tough, he's good.
- And Said?
- He gets overruled a lot.
l don't know. lt's funny, man.
l'm more nervous now
than l was at my first trial.
Makes sense.
Then you'd never seen
the inside of a prison.
lncarceration was merely a concept.
Now you know the reality.
You know the price
if the verdict goes against you.
Augustus,
we need a smoking gun.
We need to find a convicted felon
who was asked to give a bribe, didn't,
and then was sentenced unfairly.
- How do you know that one exists?
- And if he does, how do you find him?
lt's a needle in a haystack.
Quickest way to find the needle,
burn the haystack.
What the fuck does that mean?
Here you go, my brother.
A list of names of all the murderers
convicted by Kibler.
Now, if one of them testifies
that they didn't offer a bribe
and we show
that they were sentenced unfairly,
we prove bias.
We ain't got time
to contact all these people, man.
We in the middle of the trial.
We should've thought of this
a week ago, man.
We've already told you,
no special phone privileges.
Let me use the fax
to contact the men on the list.
No.
You think l'm gonna help you turn
this prison into The People's Court?
You win this one, you'll be reopening
the case of every prisoner in here.
And is that wrong?
To strive for justice?
- Justice?
- Yeah.
Crooked judge or not,
Hill shot a cop.
Officer.
Whether l win or lose this case,
warden,
l am never gonna stop
helping my brothers fight for freedom.
He said no. Again.
So l'm gonna call my publisher,
get him to contact the lawyers
of all the men convicted.
Still gonna take the one thing
we ain't got: time.
Then we create time.
lf the decision goes against us,
l'll appeal.
On what grounds?
The only reason Judge Lema is
overruling all my objections is racism.
lt couldn't be because most
of your objections are stupid, right?
No. lt couldn't be because
maybe, you know,
you not as good a lawyer
as you think you are.
You wanna replace me?
You wanna get Beecher
to take up our cause?
Our cause?
This is not our cause,
this is my fucking life.
l am not you, man.
l don't wanna be a martyr
or a fucking saint.
All l wanna do
is get out of here and be free.
Either you can do that
or you leave me the fuck alone.
Goddamn it!
Does anyone else have anything to say
before l give my ruling?
Yes, Your Honour, l do.
Make it snappy, Mr. Said.
l've got a long ride home. Rush hour.
Because my client and l
are prisoners
and certain restrictions are placed
upon our time and our resources,
we do not have the opportunity
to obtain further evidence.
- Duly noted.
- One more thing, Your Honour.
We'll probably never know
what Judge Kibler thought
about Augustus Hill.
But we have a pretty clear picture
about what he thinks about justice.
Thank you.
To the State's argument
that because there is no precedent
for reversing the conviction,
that this court would be ruling
beyond its jurisdiction,
l say, ''Bunk.''
How do precedents
become precedents
unless some judge sets one?
However, the State's view
that the defendant must show more
than the appearance of bias
rings true.
l have reviewed the transcript
of Mr. Hill's trial thoroughly.
At no point did Judge Kibler,
in word or deed,
act beyond the limits
of the rules of judicial procedure.
And the sentencing,
given the severity of the convictions,
does not appear to be unduly cruel...
...or unusual.
Therefore,
l rule in favour of the State
and deny Augustus Hill's motion
for a reversal of his conviction.
Do not lose faith, my brother.
This is just the beginning.
No. lt's over.
- Augustus--
- No.
l can't handle this shit anymore.
l told you before,
these things take time.
- The law is very--
- lt's not the law, man.
lt's not the law that l can't handle.
lt's the hope.
The hope is crushing me, man.
Hope? Hope is all we have.
No. All l have is Oz.
All right, who wants to go next?
- Hey, can l read a poem?
- Yeah.
Something l wrote.
The inside of my cell
See me be seduced by its serenity
ln my search for privacy
Behind the locked cages
The makers of the rules rise
But peace dies
Curses is kisses
And adoration is disses
ln this beautifully disgusting place
Where l see my forever
Call it Emerald City
Ex--
- Faggot, you done with your faggotry?
- Who you calling a faggot?
l'm calling you a fucking faggot,
you faggot.
- Hey, guys.
- Hey, hey, hey.
Now, you already started
one fight in here.
Next one's gonna be in gen pop.
Step back.
Go on, get out of here.
Wangler needs attitude realignment,
you know?
Well, he's pissed off because
l'm forcing him to come to class.
l don't get it. He was doing well
learning how to read.
- Now he's shut off completely.
- Adebisi's giving him heat.
So l'm trying to give him
room to move.
What about Poet?
- Kid's got talent.
- Listen.
Here's a tape recorder.
You record five or six of his poems,
give this back to me.
- Why?
- l got a plan.
Thank you.
- Have a seat.
- What do you want, McManus?
- l finished your book on the riot.
- l suppose you want my autograph.
l wanna talk to you about Poet.
There's some of his work.
l want you to contact your publisher,
show him those poems.
Do you remember the first time
l stood in your office, McManus?
You told me that my, quote,
my celebrity status wouldn't give me
any extra advantages inside of Oz.
And you reminded me of that
last week.
And now here we are,
with you taking advantage of me,
of my status.
This isn't about you, Said.
This is about Poet, his future.
No, it's also about you.
Having one of your students published
will get you press coverage
for your educational programme.
You'd look like a hero.
You have the opportunity
to help someone here, a fellow inmate.
l don't need you to tell me
when to help a brother.
Look, could we just put aside
all the bullshit between us for once?
Once.
- Let me get some, Adebisi
- No.
- l'm looking out for--
- Let me get some tits.
Come on, man, let me get some tits,
man. Come on, man.
- Hey.
- Let me get some tits.
Hey, you haven't paid us in weeks.
Fuck off.
Come on, man. Just hook me up.
Yo, yo, go write something, Du Bois.
All right?
Do you realise
you've beaten the odds in here?
- You've held on to your gift.
- Say what?
l've spoken to my publisher
about you.
- Publisher?
- Oh, yeah.
Very interested in your work.
--poetry-reading faggot.
Yeah, come on.
Come on, recite something, bitch.
Nice fucking life.
- Don't doubt yourself, my brother.
- Yo, Shakespeare.
- Come on, teach me poetry.
- They are a lie.
- Get up on that table and read.
- Sit.
Bitch.
- Let them mock you.
- Fuck.
- Bring your poetry-reading ass.
- ln the end, they will see.
Not if l jack
one of them motherfuckers first, man.
You listen to me.
You look at me, Poet.
You have a responsibility.
You have a calling.
Man, don't feed me
none of that bullshit.
Just tell me
what the fuck l gotta do.
Nothing.
Do nothing...
...except trust me.
Yo, Kareem, you was right.
You was right.
l'm about to get published.
- Congratulations, my brother.
- Hey. That's great.
- Yes, yes.
- Where?
lt's an anthology of poems
called Unheard America.
They're giving him
a featured appearance.
- That's terrific.
- And they're giving me cake.
Look at that.
Now you got two.
Tit me, man. Tit me, man.
What did you do to get this, bitch?
Hey, where did you get this?
- Poetry.
- Poetry?
Who the fuck pays for poetry?
Hey, yo,
a publishing house
put some of my work in their book.
No shit? Wait, wait.
Teach me to write.
Oh, yeah, teach me to write.
l can't teach you to write.
l want to write rhymes
about Nigeria.
Don't nothing rhyme with Nigeria.
Bitch, give me that.
My, my, my, my, my, my-geria
What was the other one?
Help me, help me, help me.
- Cafeteria.
- And Nigeria
- To release my ''diarrhoearhea''
- Cafeteria
- Get diarrhoea
- My ''diarrhoearhea''
Nigeria
Geria
Oh, shit, yeah.
Yo, what's happening, man?
You know,
l have seen Adebisi destroy others
with his own self-destruction.
Man, we was just--
We was just doing laundry, man.
We was doing laundry, man.
What the fuck?
You know--
You know, you're so fucking clean
and righteous, man.
You know what l'm saying?
l got demons clawing at my ass.
So do l, my brother,
but they can't take me down.
You must learn to fight with your will.
That is the shield of Allah.
- Man, they just keep coming.
- Delusions.
This is your reality.
Believe in his power.
Believe in his power to keep you.
Man, that's that bullshit, you know?
That's that bullshit.
- That's that--
- Believe.
Why?
l have taken it upon myself
to rally a network of eminent writers
calling for your parole.
- My parole.
- l'm telling you, my brother.
We're gonna turn you
into a symbol of justice in America.
You're gonna be like the phoenix,
rising, through your poetry,
from the ashes of a crack house.
- A symbol? Me? Shit.
- Yeah.
A crowd has gathered outside Oswald
Maximum Security Penitentiary
in growing support for Arnold Jackson,
an inmate whose poetry
has fomented a movement
of writers and artists
demanding that he be granted
a parole review.
The campaign to free Mr. Jackson
started with Foster Perry,
the publisher of an upcoming
anthology of marginal literature
titled Unheard America.
Many critics are saying
this is a commercial ploy
to create a sensation around the book,
but several figures in the arts
have committed their efforts
to Mr. Jackson's case,
claiming he is a rare talent lost inside
our country's barbaric prison system.
- Fuck.
- Damn right.
Boy meets girl, boy loses girl,
boy gets girl.
And that's the best part, right?
After all that shit that's come before,
the two lovers finally stare
in each other's eyes,
and...the story ends.
Only...
...what happens
after boy gets down with girl?
Well, he starts to get at her,
she starts to get to him.
Boy makes girl crazy and vice versa.
Man, this is great.
No work detail, no COs hassling me,
no punks up in my face.
l'm telling you,
there's an upside to dying, doc.
You're not dying.
The surgery was successful.
The lump in your breast
has been removed.
The chemo's doing the rest.
Yeah, so, what are the chances
of the cancer coming back?
Ninety percent of stage-two men
are alive after five years,
and 63 percent are alive
after ten years.
l'm up for parole in 1 1 years.
The way things go for me,
l'll get released
and...the tumour's back.
You're young.
You're otherwise healthy.
You'll be okay.
Ryan O'Reily's coming back
to Emerald City today.
Oh, yeah?
Been in the hospital
a long fucking time.
Must be something
really wrong with him.
l hear O'Reily had surgery
at Benchley Memorial
and now he's going through
chemotherapy.
Chemo, that's bad, man.
That shit does bad shit to you.
lt can also save your life.
What the fuck you looking at?
- Nothing, Ryan.
- Get the fuck out of here.
Hey, l want back in the kitchen.
- Forget about it.
- Schibetta, l'm not fucking around.
He says forget about it,
cancer boy.
- Faggot.
- O'Reily, you trying to look like us?
Yeah, l'm trying to be ugly.
People have been wondering
what exactly is wrong with you.
Scatz here says
it's cancer of the balls,
that the doctor cut them off.
But l say that can't be it.
Because you never had any balls
to begin with.
You know the rules, O'Reily.
You get in a fight, you go to the hole.
So send me to the fucking hole.
l've been there before.
l ain't afraid.
Yeah, well, in your condition,
you know, you're likely to get a cold,
then you die, and then
l got a shitload of paperwork to do.
That's funny.
Look, Ryan,
you've got six weeks of chemo left.
Okay? So we decided
you can stay in the ward until then.
Take him to the hospital.
Hey.
How are you feeling?
Physically, fine.
But l gotta tell you, ever since riding
in the van on the way to surgery,
you know, being on the outside.
Since then, that's all l can think about.
You know, being free.
Doing the things that l miss.
Things that l can't do in here.
Like what?
What do you miss most?
Kissing.
- You miss your wife.
- l miss affection.
Any kind of affection.
Like just before the operation
when you took my hand,
the heat of your skin...
...it sent a brushfire
through my body.
Funny, huh?
A simple thing like that.
Fingers touching fingers.
l wanna touch you.
l wanna kiss you.
Well, don't.
- Hello, Gloria.
- Hey.
What's wrong?
What makes you think
something's wrong?
Well, l'm a psychologist and a nun.
Usually, between the two,
there's something wrong.
You know, in med school,
the one thing
they keep pounding into our heads:
Doctors don't show emotion.
Doctors keep their distance.
Doctors don't get involved
with a patient.
Oh, my.
May l ask which one?
Ryan O'Reily.
Why him? Why are you attracted
to him specifically?
l don't know.
He's handsome.
He's got the bullshit lrish charm.
And breast cancer.
My mom had breast cancer.
My aunt, my sister.
l'm probably gonna get it too.
l know what he's going through.
That's not love, Gloria,
that's empathy.
Want my advice?
Go home to your husband,
make love to him.
Stomp these feelings for O'Reily
into the ground.
Because unless you do,
you're gonna have trouble.
Well, it doesn't look like
there'll be much scarring.
- How's the nausea?
- Gone.
- And your appetite?
- Back.
- Fatigue?
- Kiss me.
- No.
- Please? Hey.
You know what l know,
and you feel what l feel.
Ryan--
Ryan! Officer.
- Take him back to Em City.
- Fine.
Fuck.
Hey, girl, take a look at me
Let me dirty up your mind, yeah
l'll strip away your hard veneer
Let me see what l can find
You're peeing.
- l'm trying.
- l have to pee.
You're serious about escaping from Oz
by digging a hole?
That's why they call me the Mole.
l once dug my way into a bank vault
with walls 20 feet into the ground.
And your offer
to let me follow you out?
- When l go, l won't be looking back.
- l see.
lf two people dig, it'll go faster, right?
- Sure.
- l used to be an architect.
l know about structures.
Let me help.
Hello, William.
Sorry about the restraints.
Peter. Peter Marie.
- Peter. Peter Marie.
- Yeah. Yeah, that's right.
l thought l'd come by
so we could talk.
Broom.
Yeah, you said that last time to me.
Sick.
You said that too.
What does it mean?
Sick and broom.
What are you trying to tell me?
Sick, broom, amour.
- Sick--
- No! No!
- lt's okay.
- lt's all right.
- No!
- No! No!
- lt's okay, it's okay.
Calm down, calm down.
lt's okay. William.
lt's all right, William. Calm down.
Okay.
We'll just take it as slowly
as you want, okay?
We have all the time
that you need, okay?
Street.
Street?
Avenue?
Street.
Okay.
l can't do that.
l don't see why we can't
start these meetings with a prayer.
- Come on, man.
- Guys.
- Said, don't you agree?
- A prayer in itself is meaningless
unless those who offer it
do so from true belief.
Oh, man, enough of this shit.
Can we just talk about sex?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We wanna bring back conjugals.
Yeah, l'm working on it, fellas.
We're a long ways away.
- Next.
- Yeah, l got a grievance.
Go ahead.
- Certain guys stink.
- Oh, Adebisi.
l know some people come
from far-away places
where they don't bathe,
but in America,
l think washing should be mandatory,
if only for health-code reasons.
Take a fucking bath once in a while.
You wanna bath me up,
eh, little Nino?
- Oh, shit.
- You'd like that, huh?
Soaping me up, eh?
There's your fucking bath right there.
There's your fucking bath.
All right, l guess this meeting
is adjourned.
Adebisi, go back to your pod.
Schibetta, to my office.
This is why we'll never come
to your meetings again, McManus.
Miguel.
- Sit?
- l ain't staying too long.
- You and me, we got a lot in common.
- l don't think so.
Well, we both have Latin blood
and we both peddle tits.
Me, l'm strictly a street-drug guy.
Heroin, marijuana.
You, because you work
in the prison hospital,
you sell pharmaceuticals.
So l'm thinking we should combine.
- No, thanks.
- l'm willing to divide the pie 60-40.
And you know
l make a shitload more than you.
Why you wanna be
so generous with me, man?
l want Adebisi dead.
What, do l look like a mook to you?
You're offering me 60-40
and all l gotta do is kill Adebisi?
Shit.
Why don't you have him do it, huh?
Everyone knows l hate Adebisi.
He turns up dead,
no one suspects you.
That's bullshit. That's bullshit.
No, l'll tell you what you're thinking.
You're thinking, a spic kills the cocolo,
they end up at war.
No offence, no offence,
but drop fucking dead.
Hey, Papi, l been thinking, eh?
Yeah? That must be
a new experience for you, huh?
About me and you in business.
Shit. l should have read
my horoscope, you know?
Today's my lucky day.
Everybody wanna share the wealth.
Don't tell me, let me guess, right?
You want me to kill him, right?
You know the rules.
We don't whack Wiseguys.
Fuck the rules. Schibetta ain't Nino.
This one got no balls...
...and neither do you.
Yo, you gonna let him
fucking disrespect you like that, man?
Look, he and the wop are
two breaths away from going down.
Us, we're gonna pull up a lawn chair,
we gonna sit back, we gonna relax,
and we gonna watch them go.
You got me?
Then we'll pick up the pieces
of whatever's left over.
- All right?
- All right.
All right, baby.
Come on, boys.
Be all that you can be.
Now, you probably saying:
''Boy meets girl,
that's one boring fucking story.
lt's always the same.''
But there are variations
on the theme, like:
boy meets dog, boy loses dog,
boy buys new dog.
Or girl meets psychiatrist,
girl goes to therapy
for the next ten years.
Or in Oz, there's always...
...boy meets boy.
Prisoner number 98K51 4,
Christopher Keller.
Convicted June 1 6th, '98.
Felony murder,
two counts attempted murder,
assault with a deadly weapon, robbery,
driving while under the influence,
reckless driving.
Sentence, 88 years.
Up for parole in 50.
Hill, gather your stuff.
- You're moving to another pod.
- What? Why?
McManus wants
to keep mixing things up.
Doesn't want roommates
getting attached to each other.
- Who's moving in here?
- New guy.
Chris Keller, Tobias Beecher.
He'll be your sponsor in Emerald City.
He's gonna show you the ropes.
So you a fag?
No. You?
l do what l have to.
Rats in the garden
Catch them, Towser
Cow's in the cornfield
Run, boys, run
Cat's in the cream pot
Stop her now, sir
Fire on the mountain
Run, boys, run
You the new prag?
lt's gonna cost you $1 0
to use the phone.
What?
lt's gonna cost you 1 0 bucks
to get in there.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Broke my fucking nose.
Whoa, what's going on?
What's going on?
Hey, better get to the ER.
l owe you.
l didn't do it for you, pal.
l hate those Aryan fucks.
Come in, Beecher. Sit down.
The other day, before Hill's hearing,
l met Judge Grace Lema.
- Oh, really? How is the cunt?
- She asked about you.
The cunt put me in here.
The cunt gave me
the toughest sentence possible.
She asked if she could
come and see you.
What a cunt.
You know, my trial lasted 28 days.
And every single one of those days,
l had to stare up at that cunt's face
while she banged her cunt gavel
and instructed the jury to fuck me over.
l didn't have a choice.
l had to see the cunt.
- Now l don't have to.
- Yes, you do.
You gonna force me?
Yes.
Why?
Because l think it'll be therapeutic.
Ultimately, you'll thank me.
You know what?
You're a cunt too.
Mr. Beecher, l appreciate
your taking the time to see me.
Well, you know, it's a nice break
from getting fucked up the ass.
- Beecher.
- lt's all right.
You can speak freely.
l'm afraid, in court,
you never had that chance.
Would it have made a difference?
No.
Lady,
what do you want?
l've been a judge for 1 6 years.
l've made over 2500 decisions.
Most of them were good.
But only one
has haunted me. Yours.
You see, l've always prided myself
on being fair.
That in my court,
justice was truly blind.
But in your case,
that little girl,
her parents crying,
you being a member of the bar,
your prior arrest for DUl,
the senselessness of it all,
it caught up with me.
l was quick-tempered and spiteful
to the point where...
...l can't tell if l gave you a fair trial.
Now seeing you like this, l--
l think maybe the punishment
exceeded the crime.
And l'm...
Well...
You're what? Sorry?
Your Honour, you used all your power
to crush me.
But the truth is,
l did kill Cathy Rockwell.
And as much as l tried to manipulate
the legal system to get off,
to get out of it, l took her life.
According to the law, each crime
is worth a certain number of years.
You gave me a maximum
of 1 5 years in this fuckhole!
ls that too much? Too harsh?
Not enough? l don't know.
You say you're haunted
by what you did? Well, so am l.
And if you came here
for me to forgive you...
...you've come to the wrong man.
He ceased to exist
the day Cathy Rockwell did.
And you're not gonna get
any more peace out of him
than l do out of her.
Yeah, this was very therapeutic.
Thanks.
l'm sorry.
Mr. Beecher?
No.
No!
- Hey. Hey. Hey, you--?
- Don't touch me.
- l was just wondering what happ--
- Keep your fucking hands off me,
you fucking faggot!
All right.
- Hey.
- How's it going?
Showering with this baby on
is a bitch.
About last night,
calling you a faggot, l--
Forget about it.
l've had my share of nightmares.
Look, when you helped me out the
other day by the phones, l told you...
...l owe you.
See, the way l figure it, you and me,
we're not like the rest of them.
The Latinos, the Homeboys,
the Aryans,
see, they all got each other.
You and me...
You and me are standing out there
with our dicks swinging in the wind.
We should be able
to rely on each other.
You know?
Trust each other.
Well, it's hard for me
to trust somebody.
Me too.
But we got
a long fucking time together, so...
...why don't we see what happens,
all right?
All right?
All right.
Good.
- There you are, you cocksucker.
- Hey, hey, calm down, Mark.
He broke my nose.
You broke my motherfucking nose!
Hey. Hey, give it your best shot.
All right, back off.
We're okay here, officer.
Come on, go work it off.
So how goes Operation Toby?
lt'll take some time.
But don't worry, sooner or later,
Beecher will be mine.
Boy meets girl, boy gets laid.
What makes us
wanna fuck somebody?
ls it the colour of their eyes,
the shape of their legs,
the spike of their heels?
Or is it what the poets tell us?
That there's something deeper,
a shared loss.
A longing to find someone
who knows the depth of our sadness.
Some people search their whole lives
for that someone.
Some find them, some don't.
Some fool themselves
into believing they're in love.
And in Oz, most times,
the illusion is better than reality.