Oz, the name on the street
for the Oswald
State Correctional Facility
Level Four.
Oz is filled with murderers,
rapists, racists, drug dealers
with the most common
of criminals.
But what is it
that makes a man common?
Better yet,
what makes him unique?
Winning wars,
winning awards? No.
What lifts a man
out of the ordinary
is who he loves...
and who loves him.
Today this great state of ours
can once again stand proud.
We have the finest,
most modern
correctional facilities
anywhere in the country.
Let the word go forth
to friend and foe alike
that we will spare
no expense,
no time, no effort
in housing
and punishing
the bottom feeders
of our society.
Can I have your
attention, please?
I'd like to welcome you all
to Our Lady of Fatima Parish.
Now I know that due
to the recent renovations
resulting from
the gas explosion,
visits to oz
have been severely limited
and this is gonna be
the first chance
that many of you've had
to visit your family members.
When your name is called,
line up here.
We're walking single file
back to Emerald City.
As you know, today is also
the first visiting day in months.
Many of you are anxious
to be together with your families,
so, the quicker
you follow instructions,
the sooner
you'll be together.
Call the numbers.
#96A214,
Adams, Phillip.
Carrie Schillinger.
Hello, Carrie,
how are you?
- How's Jewel today?
- She's fine, thanks.
- Eugenia Hill?
- How are you, father?
I'm fine, Mrs. Hill.
How are you today?
Excited to see my son.
It's been way, way too long.
Of course.
Sonsyrea Arif?
- Welcome.
- Salaam alaikum.
- Annette Osorio?
- Right here.
I'm coming.
You're cute.
Here we go.
- My god.
- Wow!
All right, all right.
- Looks good.
- Looking good.
Oh, God damn.
Wow, check it.
It's bigger,
but not necessarily better.
- I like the new color.
- It's the same color.
- I miss the old place.
- Don't be daft.
All right, Officer Murphy will now
give out your cell assignments.
- I want a room with a view.
- And maid service.
#96A214 Adams, Phillip,
cell number six.
Over the course of history
many famous people
have joined the infamous
in prison,
extraordinary human beings
with noble characters
who for one reason or another
ended up on the wrong side of the law.
Take...
Thomas Paine.
He was arrested for treason,
for fostering rebellion.
Yet without
his fiery writings,
America might never
have been free.
Or Thomas Moore,
the statesman,
scholar and saint
who was sent
to the tower of London
for being honest
with his king.
Moore's reward
was to be beheaded.
Help! Help me!
Help me! Help!
Help!
"And Samson sayeth
onto his brethren,
now shall I
be blameless
when I do harm
the Philistines."
My friends,
there are times
when we are guilty
for our actions
and should be punished
accordingly.
But there are times
when our actions,
however cruel,
leave us blameless...
because we have punished
the guilty.
Amen.
Now let us pray.
Dear Lord,
we ask you to continue
the recovery
of the Reverend
Jeremiah Cloutier,
who survived
the gas explosion...
which in turn
freed him
from the wall he had been
bricked up inside of.
Lord, we ask you to bless
the Reverend's journey today
as he comes back to Oz
from the burn unit
at Benchley Memorial Hospital.
Lord, we also ask you
to bless Jaz Hoyt...
who took
full responsibility
for sealing Reverend Cloutier
in the wall.
Jaz is a good man,
Lord,
who suffers needlessly
in solitary confinement.
Look down upon him, Lord,
keep him strong.
Gloria, has Cloutier
arrived yet?
- Uh, yeah.
- I need to see him.
Hoyt was in charge
of rebuilding that kitchen wall.
So I got him in solitary
but he won't say who else is involved.
So I need
Cloutier to tell me.
He can't, not yet. His throat
was damaged during the fire.
He can hardly make
any sounds at all.
- Is he conscious?
- Occasionally.
Then he can nod his head yes or no
when I read him a list of names.
- Where is he?
- In the private room.
Tim, wait.
He was very badly burned
during the explosion.
The fact that he survived
at all is a miracle.
Hallelujah.
I just want to prepare you
for what you're gonna see.
You have any visitors
coming today?
- Yeah, my sister Annette.
- Nice.
Yeah, she's a great gal.
I love her to death.
She's always been there
for me when I needed her.
She's also
a bit of a head case.
- Got a light?
- No, there's no smoking.
Oh. Scootch over.
I wanna sit down.
I hope you didn't mind
when I got on the bus,
me flirting with you.
No, I just...
Ccause I know how you priests
don't go in for girls.
- You know, actually...
- Oh no, I'm sorry.
That came out wrong.
I mean...
You swear to God
you'll never have sex.
- Uh, well yes, but...
- Do you know my brother?
Sure, he comes to mass
every Sunday.
Enrique?
At mass?
Jesus, he must be
bored out of his mind.
Oh no, I'm so...
That came out wrong.
I'm sure you give
a very cheery service, father.
Only my brother
is not like,
You know,
of the churchgoing variety.
I got to admit
that most of the guys
just come because they want
a break the monotony.
I haven't seen Enrique
in three years.
Been in South Beach.
What were you doing
down there?
Bartending, mostly.
I tried to go for some modeling jobs
'cause I got a good figure,
but, you know,
I wasn't willing
to play the games.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah, I think I do.
The guys try to take
advantage, huh?
Exactly, which is why I need
to speak to Enrique.
'Cause one certain guy
took too much advantage.
My fucking husband.
He hurt you?
I loved that Cuban cocksucker
with all of my heart
and he cuts
a chunk out of me.
I need Enrique
to talk to Xavier.
To call him from Oz?
My brother's voice
travels far.
He don't need a phone,
if you know what I'm saying.
No, please don't tell
me any more.
You're a priest.
You can't say nothing to nobody.
That's only
during confession.
We're not in a confessional,
we're on a bus.
- Don't get so technical.
- Uh, annette,
What you're about to ask
your brother is wrong.
Bullshit!
Look at my arm.
I didn't say that what
your husband did was right.
I'm just saying that's not
gonna solve the problem.
Fuck you,
you self-righteous
jizzball.
You don't know
dick about dick.
And that came out exactly
the way I meant it.
Listen up.
When I give the order,
you are to walk
from your cell
and form a single line.
Step out.
- All right.
- Hey, what's going on?
No talking.
- Holy shit.
- New and improved.
No talking.
Okay. During the reconstruction
we discovered
that there are problems in the air ducts
throughout the building.
We need to clean out
the ducts in solitary.
And so, until that job
is complete,
I'm going to put you all
back into gen pop.
- Hey.
- There you go. Awesome.
- No talking.
- I didn't say shit.
Now this is a second
chance for you slugs.
If you behave yourself
over the next few days,
You won't have to return
to solitary, understood?
- Don't fuck this opportunity up.
- Warden?
Exactly what is the problem
with the air ducts?
That's none of your
concern, White.
What air duct?
That's the air we breathe, right?
What part of "no talking"
don't you understand?
I've got a constitutional right
to breathe fresh air.
- I mean, fuck a duck.
- Breathe, brother, breathe.
- Where are you going?
- See McManus.
He ain't here.
Get back in line.
Welcome home, Miguel.
I've been hoping
and praying for this day.
We've got unsettled
business, you and me.
- Oh yeah?
- You killed my boys
Carlo Ricardo
and Jorge Vasquez.
You gotta pay.
Spit, sweat, blood.
What?
Bodily fluids, you know.
Fluids the body produces.
Piss and tears.
Some are voluntary,
some not so voluntary.
When I was in my
cubbyhole, you know,
I had a lot of time
to think about my fluids.
My juices, you know.
My shit.
You're fucking nuts,
Alvarez.
That's right. Right.
That's me, I'm fucking nuts.
You say I gotta pay?
Fine, put this on
my tab, okay?
Hey, what the fuck
is going on in here?
- We're taking showers.
- With your clothes on?
Up against the wall.
Come on, move it.
What, me too?
Naw, I can see
you're clean.
All right, confine these
two dinks to their cells.
Put Guerra in the cage.
Come on, move it.
Got anything else to say, Alvarez?
Man is 80% water.
Hey, Miguel.
You are one lucky fuck.
Oh, yeah, that's me.
You know,
I'm Mr. Lucky.
You know Guerra
wants you dead
and I can yank him
off your ass.
If I do what, huh?
If I kill somebody for you?
Those days are gone, chica.
Those days are long gone.
See, I got no interest
in sniffing the butthole.
You won't survive solo.
You ain't got the balls.
- Ain't got what?
- Balls... cojones, pendejo.
- That's what I'm saying.
- Ah, bolitas, right.
You see this?
I did that. Yeah.
Cut my own face,
you know what I'm saying?
I shoved a shank
in Rivera's eyes.
You know what I'm saying?
I slit Vasquez's throat.
I handle a knife better
than a fucking surgeon.
I got nothing to prove
to you, brother.
Nothing.
Come on, get the fuck
out of my face!
Muévate, muévate,
hombre.
Hey, Giles.
Don't think I've forgotten
about you sticking me.
Little fucking cocksucker.
Yeah!
This incident with Giles
concerns me, Alvarez.
You want to stay out of solitary,
you've got to stay out of trouble.
You and me both know
that I'm going back
to solitary
no matter what I do.
Glynn is not gonna
let me run around free.
And even if you did
convince him to, I'm doomed.
You know?
Attract trouble
like a fucking magnet.
You know what
quicksilver is?
- Quicksilver? Yeah.
- Yeah.
It's like mercury, right?
Stuff they make mirrors with.
Mirrors, yeah.
Reflections, right?
It's just this whole changing mood,
you know what I'm saying?
I mean,
that's just me, man.
It's me, McManus.
You know, I'm just
kind of quicksilver, man.
Whoosh, you know?
Hey, Guerra.
You know, you look
like a fucking gorilla
I seen one time
in the fucking Bronx Zoo.
Fuck you. You better hope
they don't let me out of here soon
'cause your fucking
black ass is mine.
Oooooo!
Hey!
Anybody got a banana
I could feed to the fucking ape?
Omar.
There you are.
I've been waiting to see you.
May I step forward, please?
All right. Yeah.
I know I'm always
saying I'm sorry
for all this nonsense
I keep getting sucked into.
- Kicking you and stabbing you.
- What, man?
When the hacks told me
I was coming back to Em City
I said McManus
is the man, son.
Yo, I mean, he got
a heart as big as...
- I don't know what's as big.
- All right.
- No, wait, I know what I'm saying.
- Don't fucking touch.
Even if I'm not saying
the right words,
I will make good
this time, I promise.
You know, I'm glad that you're willing
to make another effort,
but I gotta ask you
a question.
Why the fuck did you
get so upset with me?
Why did you kick me
in the head?
You know, there I am sitting there
watching TV, right?
And you come up on the screen,
big as day, right?
And Guerra, fucking Guerra,
he starts making fun.
- That's how the fight...
- I know all this shit.
Why did you fucking
attack me?
'Cause you didn't say
nothing to me, man.
About what?
About being a contestant
on fucking "Up Your Ante."
I think I know this.
I mean, here I think
we getting all friendly.
We shared our thoughts
and feelings.
And then I gotta find
out you on TV
the same time as all
the rest of them fucks.
Oh.
As a matter of fact, uh...
you sort of owe me
an apology.
- Me apologize to you?
- Uh-huh.
Work detail.
Go to work, Omar.
Here you go, Burr,
hot and tasty.
- Just the way you like it.
- Appreciate it.
Mericón.
- Stupid fucking spics.
- Don't worry.
You're gonna get your chance
to hack up Chico Guerra soon enough.
That's just the thing of it.
I'm tired.
I don't wanna hack
anybody up anymore.
I'm really, really,
really trying.
I'm trying to keep it
on the straight and narrow.
On the up and up,
you know what I'm saying?
Hey, negro estupido.
Hey, tamale boy,
why don't you shut
your fucking mouth?
What?
Guerra's not the gorilla.
You are.
Get the fuck off me,
you black bitch motherfucker.
I'm gonna fucking get you!
Get off me, you bitch.
What did you say
about a banana?
Back in the day
before the day,
explorers would set out on ships
to discover new worlds.
Adventurers like Marco Polo
and Christopher Columbus
would sail
into the horizon
not sure if they'd
find a place to land
or fall off the edge
of the Earth.
As a result
of their journeys,
both Polo and Columbus
got fame, fortune
and a pair of leg irons.
That's right. The man
who discovered America
was a con arrested
for embezzlement.
After a few months
in a dank, dirty dungeon,
I bet old Chris
started wishing
he had fallen off
the edge of the Earth.
Thanks, Father M.
- She is giggling...
- She's excited to see her grandpa.
We had the blood test done.
Hank was definitely the dad.
- I heard.
- Yeah.
I just want Mr. Schillinger
to be there for Jewel.
And we don't have
anyone else.
- What about your parents?
- My folks are back in Montana.
They don't give two shits
about Jewel and me.
Maybe in time, Carrie.
Maybe.
- It's video games.
- I beg your pardon?
Hank played video games
all day and into night.
Video games and videos.
He watched that
"Natural Born Killers" like 60 times.
I just think that, you know,
maybe if he hadn't he'd still be alive.
I don't think
it's that simple, Carrie.
Hank's upbringing,
family life, education,
they all had a lot to do
with making him who he was.
Can you bless my baby, Father?
Can you take away the curse
that's on her head?
Curse?
The one that killed
Hank and his brother.
The one that put
Mr. Schillinger at Oz.
I just want my girl
to be happy, you know.
Have a happy life.
All right,
I'll say a prayer.
Can't wait to see
my granddaughter.
Christ, you gonna get
all mushy again?
Grub, boys.
Fuck you calling boy?
I'm sorry, Schillinger. I know
you're having a rough recovery
and I don't wanna say nothing
to loosen up them sutures.
Hey, what did you do? Serve everybody
else in this fucking prison
and then bring us
the shit leftovers?
Robson, you been
in Oz all this time
and now you want
to be a food critic?
Oh, you're scary, oh.
We got to get back to
Gen Pop or I'm gonna go stir-crazy.
Dr. Nathan says
we're at full speed.
It's time to take
down Kareem Said.
That fucking nigger's
gonna live to regret shanking us.
Them Muslims got what
they call a jihad,
A holy war.
They ain't seen war
like what's coming.
Jihad?
Yee-ha!
You want to go
to the hole?
You can't put
me in the hole.
I'm recuperating.
Health care,
it's a bitch.
Thank you.
Said. Said.
The warden has decided
to charge you with attempted murder
for stabbing Robson
and Schillinger.
- Want to arrange for a public defender?
- No.
- You intend to represent yourself?
I intent to plead guilty.
Said's in a dark
and ugly place.
Why should he be any different
that anyone else in Oz?
Since he killed Adebisi
I've watched him
becoming more and more
angry, violent.
This thing with Robson
and Schillinger
is just one more piece
in a long decline.
He was defending
Tobias Beecher.
I'm not debating his motives,
Pete, just his methods.
The old Said would have never
resorted to violence,
at least not
as a first step.
I'm releasing Robson
and Schillinger today.
- Oh great.
- Can't you keep them longer?
No, their wounds have healed
and I need the beds.
Give them a little valium, some prozac,
anything that'll keep them calm.
- Why not medicate everybody?
- Okay.
Listen up, I'm not
gonna take any shit
from the Aryans
or the Muslims.
I intend to tell them so.
I want everyone
in the cafeteria at 3:00.
Don't you want
your mail, Kareem?
Hey, Tobias. What do you
think of the office?
It's very snazzy.
- Yeah.
- And they finally upgraded my computer.
I've got 128 megabytes of RAM.
- How is said?
- Seems fine.
There's concern
among the staff
about the Muslims
and Aryans.
For good reason.
In the shower this morning
I had a thought...
about you.
You were thinking about me
while you're naked in the shower?
Oh boy.
You and Said are friends.
And you and Schillinger
were getting along,
at least until he heard
about your possible parole.
What if I could organize
an interaction
between Schillinger,
Said and you?
If you can broker a peace
between these two,
You save a lot of lives.
And, when you're up
for parole again
at the end
of the year...
I'll smell even sweeter.
Yeah.
Imagine that.
Said, Schillinger
and I in a three-way?
No, absolutely not.
- I'm not going anywhere near Said.
- Vern...
My people don't associate
with his kind.
Yet you have
in the past.
Like when you asked
said to represent you
in your conspiracy
to commit murder trial.
- That was different.
- How?
He hadn't shanked me then.
That is exactly why the two of you
have to sit down together
and that's why Tobias Beecher
has to be there.
Vern,
remember when you
came to me
wanting to make sense
of your life
so that you could find
some peace of mind, some happiness?
This is the same.
You'll be able to express
whatever it is you're truly
feeling inside.
What I feel inside...
is rage.
But you're smart
enough to know
that there's
no comfort in rage.
Rage feeds
off the soul
till there is
no soul left.
I call.
- Beecher, I call.
- Huh?
You wanna play cards
or you wanna dick around?
- I'm out.
- All right, good.
- My deal, right?
- Yes.
Something going on, Tobias?
This is Az, Bob.
There's always something going on.
- 216.
- What's that?
Number of days till
my next parole hearing.
Two matches.
Beecher.
I bet two.
Are you in or out?
I am in.
Oh good, uh...
sit down, gentlemen,
sit down.
Sit down.
I spoke to the three
of you individually
to explain what I hope
we can accomplish here.
I know there is a lot
of skepticism on your part
and so I appreciate
you giving this a try.
We must always
chose life over death.
You're the one who shanked
me in the back, pal.
Kareem, Vern, please.
You know the rules.
Each of you will get
a chance to speak.
First, I want to hear
from Tobias.
Yeah.
I do feel a certain
sense of responsibility
about what happened
that day in the library.
You were happy that
my parole got turned down.
Given all the shit that's gone on
between us, I can understand that.
And you saw him and Robson
in my face threatening me
and you wanted to help.
And I can appreciate that too.
So...
you were both justified,
you know, mostly...
in the way you behaved.
- Question.
- Go ahead.
Beecher, would I have been
justified shanking Said?
I wouldn't have been
taunting him.
Kareem.
Do you mean, if the circumstances
were reversed
- and Said was threatening me?
- Uh-huh.
Yes, I think you'd be justified
in stabbing him.
Horseshit.
Here's why
and you gonna
want to...
have Sister Pete send me to the State
Asylum when you hear this one.
You two are exactly alike.
- What?
- You are crazy.
Listen to him.
You're both
powerful men.
Not only natural
born leaders,
but each of you
has a vision of the world.
And even though those visions
are in direct opposition,
they do share
some things in common.
Like what?
You both believe
in your people,
in the rights
of your people
and the god-given gifts
owed to your people.
You both believe that your
people deserve a full life,
happiness,
security
and...
I don't know, l... l...
I guess that's all
I have to say.
That's good. That's...
that's enough for today.
I think we should think
about what Tobias said
and, uh, come back
tomorrow.
Officer.
Rapists, pedophiles,
male hustlers...
We got all kinds
of men in Oz.
Men who've turned sex
into a crime.
And for that they belong
in the deepest recesses of our hell.
But as we also know,
sex is not necessarily love
and there are times
when love itself
will get you incarcerated.
Like oscar wilde,
who loved
and lost two years
of his life
sitting in Reading Jail.
Two lips, maybe
a little tongue
pressed against
two other lips.
A simple kiss
can be more lethal
that a gun.
Addiction is satan's tool,
his evil system
to keep our people down.
He supplies the drugs
to our men and women
and then arrests
them for using.
He locks our sons
and daughters in his prisons
and then walks away,
a smile across his white face.
Mrs. Arif? I hate to...
some of the other passengers
on board have asked me
to ask you if you
could keep your voice down.
Why? Because they don't
wanna hear the truth?
The drug policy
in this country
is excessive, oppressive
and racist.
- Be that as it may...
- Instead of locking young black men
behind bars we ought to implement
substance abuse treatment
which is less expensive
and more productive.
- I agree, but now is not the time.
- When is the time?
Did you know that the number
of inmates in american prisons
has more than tripled
in the last 20 years?
- Yes.
- Did you know
that if the inmate population
continues to grow exponentially
by the year 2053
the United States
will have more people
in prison than out?
So, I ask you, Father,
how long do we wait
to change the way things are?
Her baby's trying
to sleep.
Your husband's
a drug addict?
He was, until he found Allah.
My son Augustus,
he was too.
70% of those arrested test positive
for substance abuse.
- Mrs. Arif...
- Sonsyrea.
Sonsyrea...
Your head's all crammed
with facts and figures.
But a cold hard fact
is never as good
as the simple truth.
Your husband,
did he hurt you and your children
while he was addicted?
Yeah.
He became a thief.
- And now?
- He struggled and he struggled
and he fought
his cravings.
With the help of Allah
he is clean.
- And your children?
- They miss their father.
- But they have allah now.
- Then, girl,
that's the story
you ought to be telling.
That's the stuff
people need to hear.
- You're in a good mood today.
- Yeah, man, my wife's coming to see me.
All right.
Is she bringing the children?
No, Sonsyrea and I need
some time, just the two of us.
O'Reily.
That man is an animal.
He murdered Patrick Keenan
with such brutality
Every time I see him
I wonder how he lives with himself.
How you doing,
Busmilla?
Eat up, Arif.
Move it.
Hey, take over here
for a second.
Where the fuck
is you goin', man?
- Hey, hey, hey.
- O'Reily, relax.
I haven't seen your brother
since he checked out
of protective custody.
We're just catching up.
I don't want you
anywhere near him.
But Ryan, I like Henry.
- I told you, this guy's a scumbag.
- It takes one to know one.
You on some kind of a kamikaze
mission, Stanton, huh?
If I see you talking to Cyril again
you're going down in flames.
Later.
- What'd you say to him?
- Nothing.
Nothing.
- Jeez.
- Hey, you mick fucks.
We're working over here.
You want to join us?
You know I agonize and agonize
over telling you
I saw Ryan O'Reily
murder Patrick Keenan.
Finally Minister Said convinced
me to step forward and yet,
O'Reily's
never been charged.
That's because I haven't
been able to gather
any concrete evidence
against him.
At this point, all I have
is your testimony
and you won't even
speak publicly.
Or have you changed
your mind?
If I do, O'Reily
will have me killed.
Don't expect miracles.
I've been going over and over
that moment in my mind,
trying to remember every detail
and this might not be important,
But I think I saw O'Reily
pull a shamrock off of Keenan's neck.
- A shamrock?
- Yeah, a gold shamrock on a chain.
- I see.
- Don't let this lie, warden.
Justice must be done.
O'Reily
must be punished.
- Stay back.
- But I've got a pain.
- Where?
- In my heart.
I'm heartsick
'cause you keep ignoring me.
I'm busy, Ryan.
I just wanted to know,
did the medical board...
did they rule on your
case of malpractice?
Yes.
They reprimanded me,
fined me,
but I'm
still a doctor.
Well, that's...
that's great, right?
Gloria?
- May I see you?
- Sure.
Let's walk.
Whoever killed
Patrick Keenan
Took a gold chain from around
his neck, a shamrock.
At one point,
when we spoke,
you had a shamrock
in your hand.
- It was his.
- Where did you get it?
Arrived one day at my office
in an unmarked envelope.
When I interviewed you
about the murder
why didn't you tell me
you had evidence?
Leo, I was raped.
After a trauma like that,
you're not always thinking clearly.
There are things I've done
since that night that make no sense.
Just when I think I get
my feelings under control
the slightest thing
sets me off.
I know.
And I am sorry.
Honestly, there's a part of me
that's happy Keenan's dead.
I just want to put
his face behind me.
Of course.
Um, Gloria...
One last question
and I promise
I'll never bring it up again.
Where's the necklace?
Here.
I threw the fucking
thing away.
Come on, Warden,
there's got to be a rule
about the number of times you can
keep on asking me the same questions.
You think I'm screwing
with your civil rights?
You want to consult
an attorney?
I don't need an attorney,
'cause I didn't kill Keenan.
Look, man, check
the assignment records.
I wasn't near
the gym all day.
- My informant says different.
- Your informant's a liar.
Why would he lie?
Look, a lot of people
got issues with me.
A lot of people
had issues with Keenan.
The killer was a scrapper,
he was in fights all the time.
You go through the files,
you'll find a shitload of suspects.
I have.
You're still the nearest
and the dearest.
Take him out.
Glynn wants to nail you
for Keenan's murder, huh?
He's got some witness, only I
don't know who. If I could find out
this fucker's name I'd persuade him
to change his testimony or...
- Kill him?
- Yeah, well.
In any case, I need
to confuse the situation.
Yeah, but how?
This clipping...
it needs to find it's way
into Henry Stanton's trunk
buried beneath
his underwear.
Meanwhile, what are you
gonna be doing?
Encouraging an entirely different
eyewitness to step forward.
Go, Marty, go.
- Go! Go!
- Come on!
Yeah, baby.
- Out!
- What the fuck are you talking about?
You are out!
Prisoner #99M633:
Martin Montgomery:
Convicted March 16th, 1999:
Two counts of assault
in the first degree:
Sentence: Eight years:
Up for parole in five.
Hey, Marty my boy.
- How about another piece of cake?
- Sure. Thanks.
- O'Reily, right?
- That's right.
How come you offering
me extra cake?
I've been here almost three years,
you never even farted in my direction.
Well, you're right.
We're not friends.
Everybody knows we're not friends,
which is why I can offer you
- an exciting moneymaking opportunity.
- Which is what?
I want you to go to the warden
and tell him
You saw Henry Stanton
murder Patrick Keenan.
But I didn't.
Marty, there's a lot more
cake where that came from.
Stanton caught Keenan
with a barbell
right about here.
Keenan went down. Stanton ripped
the necklace from his throat.
- What happened next?
- I ran.
I mean, what,
stick around?
All right, thanks
for coming forward.
Like I said, my conscience
couldn't take the strain
of keeping
what I saw inside.
I'll be damned.
Normally nobody rats
on anybody,
now I got
two different witnesses
Identifying two different
suspects for the same murder.
Montgomery had a lot more
details than Arif. Specific details.
Yeah, and according
to the records
Stanton and Keenan
were constantly fighting.
- But why would arif lie?
- Ask him.
No, first I'm gonna have
a word with Henry Stanton.
Me?
Kill Patrick Keenan?
- I wish.
- At least twice in unit B
Keenan kicked
the shit out of you.
That ain't true.
I got my licks in.
Medical report...
says after the first fight
you had two broken ribs,
the second one
a broken wrist.
Keenan had no
injuries at all.
Mine was
a moral victory.
That day in the gym,
you whacked him, didn't you?
No.
I swear on my children, no.
We found this
in your cell.
I've never even
seen this before.
You're obsessed
with Dr. Nathan, aren't you?
No. I mean,
she's got nice tits and all,
- but other than that I never even...
- Take him to the hole.
- The hole? Why?
- Maybe a few days there
will jostle
your membrane.
Fuck you, fuck you!
Fuck you!
Fuck you, you motherfucker.
Warden, how's
the investigation going?
- Fine.
- When are you gonna charge O'Reily?
Let me ask you something, Arif.
Why are you so hell bent
on Ryan O'Reily going down?
As I said,
justice must be done.
- There's no other reason, no agenda?
- No.
This isn't payback
for some wrong done to you?
- No.
- I've been digging around.
During the riots,
you and O'Reily almost came to blows.
- The riot?
- That was five years ago.
In my experience
cons have long memories.
You think I made
the story up?
You know what?
At this point, I don't know.
And I'm beginning to wonder
if I even care.
Ready for this?
Glynn's suspended
The investigation
in the murder of Patrick Keenan.
Too many suspects,
not enough clues.
- Perfect.
- Bet you could press it.
Bet you could get
Stanton convicted.
- Don't want to.
- Why?
Look.
Henry Stanton gets the death penalty
for Keenan's murder,
Gloria Nathan's not gonna
let an innocent man die.
She's gonna feel compelled
to tell the truth.
No, I win by keeping
the ball in play,
by keeping
the facts murky.
Have that placed
in Marty Montgomery's cell.
- Montgomery? Why montgomery?
- Life insurance.
Ryan, can I tell Henry
about our secret?
That we fooled
the warden?
No, Cyril.
For Christ's sake,
Don't say a fucking
word to him.
Stop yelling.
Why do you always yell?
Like Papa.
Fuck off.
Galileo Galilei
challenged the principle
that had been accepted
for over 1,000 years
that the Earth
was the center of the universe,
that everything
revolved around us.
The mad monks in the inquisition
imprisoned Galileo
And ordered him to repudiate
his theory. Which he did.
How much worse
of a punishment is there
than being forced to publicly
deny your deepest beliefs?
To say that what you
know to be true
is a lie?
I see that baby over there
and I can't help but think
about Augustus
when he was just born,
when he took
his first step.
You know,
you think back and say,
if I had done this
or if that hadn't happened
his whole life
might have been different.
- Allah guides our every step.
- I know.
God is my rock,
but he can't stop the thoughts
from flooding my head,
the memories
from flowing.
Augustus' first shoes,
his first day of school.
Oh, his wedding day.
He looked so happy.
He and Annabella both did.
The sun was shining
so bright,
I had to squint my eyes
as they drove away.
And now I feel
like I lost him that day,
an more ways than one.
His... his world
got narrower,
you know, with the drugs and all.
- Is he still using?
- Oh no, thank God.
My boy's been clean
over three years.
- I'm very proud of him for that.
- Yes, indeed.
That's why I'm worried.
That's why today
is going to be so hard.
L... I've got news
to tell him.
Bad news.
News that I want him
to hear from me first,
because maybe
if I can just
cushion the blow, he...
he won't go back
to the crack.
His wife, Annabella,
- she's divorcing him.
- Oh, my.
I tried talking
to the girl, but...
her mind's made up.
She's got another
fella and now...
she wants to be free.
And yet...
God help me,
I can't stop blaming her
for the darkness
in Augustus' life.
She was with him
the night he shot
the policeman,
the night his spine
got snapped.
She should have taken
better care of my son.
Eugenia?
I'm fine.
The tears are for Augustus,
my little emperor.
Locked in a cell,
down in that
wretched place,
half his body dead.
And damn...
all I keep thinking of
is his first step.
Yo, Burr, how come
you never get in line?
Because ain't nobody
sending me nothing.
See this?
Motherfuckers want me
To donate money
to the United Negro College Fund.
They got be be kidding.
Fuck.
It's a letter
from some lawyer.
My wife's divorcing me.
Oh, this is a surprise?
No, I guess not.
I mean...
No, no, I mean,
she...
she's been visiting me
less and less and you know,
when she does come,
there's...
definitely a distance.
What do you expect?
You've been cooped up here in Oz
for the last seven years.
That's a long time for a young gal
to keep a candle lit.
I know.
It's just that...
You know,
we loved each other.
The least Annabella could have
done was come and say goodbye.
It's tough luck,
Augustus, man.
Tough fucking luck.
You'll survive, son.
You survived this shithole,
you'll survive a divorce.
Maybe.
Losing her...
it's like giving up
my last piece of hope.
It's like admitting to myself
that everything I had out there
is gone.
Just gone forever.
You know, I never
told you this, but...
Dee and I was fixing
to divorce too.
- What?
- Just before she got sick.
'Course after she got sick
I couldn't leave her.
I thought you and Dee
was happy.
You always
seemed so happy.
That was the vodka.
The only woman I knew
that could drink more liquor than me.
That love in her eyes
was always a little bit blurry.
No, you and your moms
was the only real family
I ever knew.
She's coming today.
Eugenia.
Maybe you and me
can visit mom together.
You know,
I'd like that.
I'd like to see Eugenia.
She always had
the sweetest pair of eyes.
Okay, it looks
like we're gonna be
at the main gate of Oswald
in about five minutes.
Sonsyrea Arif,
Charles Ballace,
Eugenia Hill...
Annette Osorio,
Sharon Patel,
Trudy Granser,
Carrie Schillinger...
What about
my granddaughter?
- Jewel schillinger.
- She's at Benchley Memorial
in stable condition.
Dee Swanson,
Pamela Turton...
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
lots of fine people
have sat staring
at the inside of prison walls.
Socrates, Gandhi,
Joan of Arc,
Even our Lord
Jesus Christ.
He spent the last night
of his life not with holy men,
but with scum like the kind
we've got in Oz.
One of the last things
Jesus did on earth
was invite a prisoner
to join him in heaven.
He loved that criminal.
I say, he loved that criminal
as much as he loved anyone.
Jesus knew in his heart
it takes a lot
to love a sinner.
But the sinner,
he needs it all the more.