? It's years like these?
? That make
a young man old?
? Bend his back
against the promises?
? That life should hold?
? They can make him wise?
? They can drive him?
? To his knees?
? There ain't nothin'
comes for free?
? In days like these?
? But you can't reap?
? What you don't sow?
? And you can't plant?
? In hollow ground?
? So let us fill?
? This empty earth
with hope?
? Till the rains?
? Calm down?
? In days...?
? Like these.?
Your face.
This ain't shit.
You should've seen me
a few days ago.
You'd have been proud.
I ain't proud, Omar.
I'm sorry.
Me too.
I fucked up,
and I know that.
Look, if I tell you
why I was selling tits,
- you can't go to McManus, okay?
- You have my word.
Redding forced me.
I tried to tell the motherfucker no,
but he just wasn't hearing no.
And I was too much of an ass
for you to come and ask for help, right?
I needed those things
you said...
just to straighten
me out.
Shit, I even needed some
of that lke Turner treatment.
Look, I'm sorry,
you're sorry,
next chapter, okay?
You know the ridiculous irony
of this whole thing, Omar?
I was the one
with the addiction.
- Huh?
- My power trip.
I was high, 24-7,
being the master
of your recovery.
Power...
it's as evil a drug
as anything else.
You know, I would like you
to call me...
Kareem.
Kareem it is, then.
Thank you.
I must say, I think you're gonna be
nicely surprised by the variety show.
And... Omar White
is the grand finale.
- What, is he that good?
- I didn't say that.
I'm just...
I'm proudest of him
because he has really put
his heart and soul
into this.
As long as he goes through with it,
he will have succeeded.
How well he sings
doesn't matter.
Is there anything I can do
to help at this point?
As a matter of fact...
we need an emcee.
Forget about it.
- Aw.
- I'm not good at ducking rotten fruit.
You think I'm kidding?
The mob at the Coliseum
in Ancient Rome was kinder.
Why don't you try Mukada?
At least he's got God on his side.
You're such a chicken.
? Laughing in the sun?
? Always having fun?
? Doing all those things...?
What?
What the fuck
is that puberty shit?
Don't worry.
You're working out the kinks.
Okay.
Here we go.
Whoa, whoa, hold up, hold up.
I just need a minute, all right? Shit.
There ain't even nobody out there
and my fucking heart is pounding.
Omar, you are
doing fine.
The butterflies
are natural.
But fine means
I'm fucked.
Shit...
these motherfuckers
are gonna eat me for lunch,
motherfuckers!
I can just see them out there
trying to fucking jam me up and shit.
Repeat after me.
Fuck.
- Huh?
- Fuck!
- Fuck.
- Them.
Say it.
Them.
Fuck... them.
Very good, thank you
very much.
Okay, here we go.
Poet, can I talk
to you a second?
I need a little bit
of advice, man.
I be seeing you getting up there,
you know, in front of everybody
reciting your poetry, man.
- Yeah.
- Well, I got this talent show gig.
- Oh man.
- I'm bugging.
Here, sit down.
Poet got the answer.
Sit, sit, sit, sit.
I got the answer.
How you be gettin' up
on stage like that, you know?
Calm and cocky and shit
like you own the joint?
Easy.
Big old titty fuck in the green room
always do the trick.
I can't hold that, man.
Why not?
'Cause McManus and Said
say you can't?
Let me tell you
something, coz,
I already been down
that road with them two.
Said feeding me that bullshit
that I'm gonna be a symbol.
A phoenix, rising
on the wings of poetry
from the ashes of a crack-out?
Man, fuck that.
I'm just surviving
the war, yo.
And me getting up on stage,
kicking them rhymes,
that's me firing back.
And me juicing up
when I need to?
That's me treating
the wounds.
Just in case
you need the medicine,
we'll call that
an IOU.
Just in case,
all right?
Now remember
one thing...
everyone's eyes
will be on you.
My sister is so fat
that she turns around and we
give her a "welcome back" hug.
When she gets on an elevator,
it has to go down.
Okay, thanks,
you're beautiful.
Jesus, that's
a tough crowd.
Agamemnon Busmalis!
I would tell you
to imagine that they're all naked,
but, I guess you've already seen
a lot of them naked.
And finally, Omar White.
? I wanna be?
? Free...?
? Like the bluebirds?
? Flying by me?
? Like the waves?
? Out on the blue sea?
? If your love
has to tie me?
? Don't try me,
say goodbye?
? I wanna be?
? Free?
? Like the warm
September wind, babe?
? Say you'll always
be my friend, babe?
? We can make it
to the end, babe?
? Again, babe?
? I gotta say?
? I wanna be?
? Free.?
Omar, you suck!
? I wanna be?
? Free.?
- You're gloating.
- No, I'm not.
You are. You're waiting
for me to take back what I said,
that you always bet
on the impossible and lose.
Well, let me
get you started.
- I was wrong...
- Timmy, you are so cute.
- Wrong...
- Very few men would find vindication
in the prison version
of "Star Search."
Okay, I'm gloating.
But, you know, indulge me.
Omar White was a lost cause,
but I didn't give up on him.
I stayed by his side,
and you know what?
It's worth all the shit
that hasn't worked
to see one of them,
just one, pull through.
Still ironing
your own shirts, aren't you?
You know, I know
what you're thinking.
Tim loves
his lost causes.
I love when you read
my mind. Try again.
Oh, what's up, dude?
The poet got the cure.
I took a rain check.
I ain't need that shit, coz.
I mean, I went close, man,
but then I said,
"Don't numb yourself.
Feel it. Yeah."
You fucking with me?
You fucking with me, right?
No, it's the tits
that's fucking with you.
Hoo-hoo-hoo!
Once again, with all due
respect, lmam,
we are concerned with who you
choose to spend your time with.
Am I close?
I thought so.
With all Omar White's
put you through in this
so-called sponsorship,
- now you two are buddy-buddy?
- Yes.
Because the alternative
is repugnant to me.
Meaning?
There's been
a largely unknown
but disgusting stain
upon our faith.
It's an issue that I have ignored
in my teachings to you.
Despite the Koran's
forbiddance of slavery,
there's an evil tradition
which continues
to this day.
Our Islamic brothers
of the north,
they capture our African brothers
of the south
all in the name
of Allah,
to Islamicize people
who look like you and me.
But we Muslims of America,
we'll turn a blind eye to that
because it doesn't fit
the neat little package
of white Christians
enslaving blacks.
I finally learned
that, in a sense,
I was capturing people to our faith...
to serve my own needs.
You consider your attempts
at conversion
- a form of enslavement?
- Yes, to the degree
that it has helped me
maintain my self-image.
Sometimes that degree
has been a significant degree.
Then there's Adebisi.
He was a black
African man
who mocked and defied
everything I wanted a black man to be.
The spirit of Adebisi
did not bleed into me.
That's voodoo.
That didn't make me
a violent man.
I am a violent man,
like anyone else.
Failing to win him over,
I got rid of him.
If we as blacks
and as Muslims
are truly gonna fight
for freedom...
Omar White should be allowed
to be who he is...
and I should be allowed
to be who I am.
So I thank Allah
for this so-called
sponsorship
that he has
put me through.
Prisoner #97R492:
James Robson:
Convicted November 7, 1997:
Murder in the first degree,
assault: Sentence: Life:
Up for parole
in 25 years.
- Not much of a meal there.
- Yeah, nothing cold or crunchy.
Why? You on a diet?
'Cause it hurts, dipshit.
Do I look fat to you?
God damn it!
Suddenly ice cream,
croutons...
it's like getting
your gums raked.
What the fuck is that?
They're probably recessive.
My old man
had bad gums.
When's the last time
you got a cleaning?
I don't know,
five or six years.
I hate
the fucking dentist.
Don't fuck around with your mouth.
My old man didn't deal,
his mouth ended up
a train wreck.
If I was you,
I'd see Dr. Faraj.
You don't wanna be slurping
turkey milkshakes in middle age.
Faraj?
I don't want some sand-nigger's
paws probing my mouth.
They wear gloves now,
you know,
since AIDS came along.
Oh.
Jesus, how long
has it really been?
Well, aside
from some cavities,
you can see that 10 and 11 show
significant recession in the gums...
- Meaning what?
- Meaning that surgery is recommended,
and I would say sooner
rather than later.
- What kind of fucking surgery?
- Well, you have two choices.
The conventional method is to take
tissue from the roof of your mouth
- and graft it to your gums.
- Shit.
- That sounds fucking painful.
- It is painful.
The alternative is
an acellular dermal graft,
where we use the gum tissue
from a cadaver.
You're kidding. Some dead person's
fucking gums in my mouth?
You can think of it
as an organ donation.
Sounds fucking creepy.
Well, the use
of your own fucking tissue
would require a longer and more
painful period of fucking recovery.
In the end, your fucking gums
would be healthy either fucking way.
Are you mocking me, Faraj?
Fuck no.
I don't like your Third-World
bullshit attitude.
And whatever
I decide, goonga,
I got a thing
about needles.
Any anesthesia, whatever,
I want gas first.
My pleasure, Sahib.
Oh, and one more thing...
being that I'm Aryan
and you're camelshit,
I'd appreciate it if you wore
two pairs of those plastic gloves.
You know, the less contact,
the better.
So, what do you think?
Well, it ain't a pretty set of options,
that's for sure.
No shit. Now you see
why I hate the dentist?
It's not their fault,
Robson.
You wait years between cleanings,
you never floss.
You brush your teeth
the way you scratch your scrotum.
I'm considering
the acellular thing.
All right,
which one's that?
It's like organ donation.
If I needed a liver,
the donor would be dead, right?
True, but you don't
need a liver.
We don't see
the liver.
Well, he said
it's like a small piece of tissue...
- All right, can we just...
- like right here.
- Talk about something else, please?
- Fuck it.
I'm going graveyard gums.
Holy shit.
Oh, hey, what's up, Doc?
Oh. Hey, how's
this stuff legal?
You know what kind
of killing you'd make
selling it to all
the drug-fiends in Oz?
I mean, they may have tits,
but you've got pussy.
What is it
with you Nazis and gas?
Oh, fuck you.
Hey, I thought I said
to wear two pairs of gloves.
- Open wide.
- No, let me have some more gas.
- I can feel it wearing off.
- You don't need more gas. Open wide.
You know, with all
your warped ideology,
I bet you never gave
much thought
to why Adolf was so
pissed off at the Jews.
One theory is that he was traumatized
by the death of his mother.
She died of breast cancer and she
was in the care of a Jewish physician,
so, of course,
the repressed hatred
erupted itself
into the Holocaust.
Now, another theory
is that Hitler's father
was the illegitimate son
of a German woman
and some obscure
Jewish man,
and so Hitler himself
had impure blood...
Hey, now, now
don't make me slip, because if I do,
we are both in trouble, hmm?
You know, it's amazing.
We don't even know
where these gums
come from.
I mean, this could be
the gums of a kike,
a spic,
or even a faggot.
You could be getting
the beautiful gums
of a big, black nigger.
? Free will?
? Can't seem to get
our fill?
? We are beggars,
we are losers?
? Drunk from lack
of power?
? I believe
in understanding?
? I've got to know
when we're landing?
? I'm taking
my survey now?
? Answer if you're
with me?
? If you want free will.?
Morning, gentlemen.
Check this out.
Fetch.
Come here, Chester.
Come here.
- He fetches.
- That's one thing to unlearn.
I told you, don't teach the dog
recreational activities.
- You brush your teeth with that?
- Today's focus is on control.
Start walking around
in this area.
- What the fuck was that?
- Scared the shit out of me.
I'm sorry, but your
reaction's not important.
The dog's is.
They have to maintain focus
even in the event
of loud or startling noises.
So what are you gonna do,
make them deaf?
Oh, yeah, that's a great idea:
Deaf dog, blind people.
- You're a fucking genius.
- You teach the dog
by standing on his leash
and saying "Chill."
- Chill?
- Chill.
Remember when I first started
I told you about
Officer Rivera,
you know,
what I'd done to him,
blinding him,
and how I just wanted
to do right?
- Yeah, you're doing that.
- Yeah,
but I just want
to do right by him direct.
I want Rivera
to have Julie.
Well, what's
the man's status?
I don't know.
I haven't heard from Eugene
in a long time.
Call him.
Have him come in.
We can talk, assess his want
and need of a guide-dog.
I'll try, but knowing how he feels
about this place, it's a long shot.
Eugene, Tina,
it's good to see you.
You... you're both
looking well.
I'll take your word
for that.
I'm Alicia Hinden.
I appreciate
your coming in.
Hello.
Did you read the literature
on the program?
Yes.
Sounds kind of interesting.
Yeah... if you've got
no other help.
Those dogs
are for lonely people.
Eugene has me.
Actually, a guide-dog
is not just for the person he's leading.
He helps the whole family
by freeing up your time.
I like helping
my husband.
Tina, you would be
helping your husband.
Oh yeah, like those interactions
with Alvarez did.
Look,
I'm skeptical too.
I worked here,
remember?
I can't believe these fucks
are capable of any good.
I mean, who teaches
these dogs?
Well, the one that...
we've got for you,
she was actually trained
by Miguel Alvarez.
- Are you fucking kidding?
- I knew that cabron was behind this.
- He's doing a wonderful job.
- Eugene, baby, please, let's go.
He's personally requested
we give Julie to you.
So, Eugene, if you like,
we can give her to you.
- I don't know.
- No!
No fucking way.
Eugene!
What, you're actually
considering this?
He probably trained
that mongrel to attack you.
No, I can assure you
that that is not...
Come on.
We're leaving.
The last thing we need
is favors from that motherfucker.
Mr. Rivera, please
think about it.
Jesus.
Good girl, Julie.
Prisoner #02M535:
Father Daniel Meehan:
Convicted
February 9th, 2002:
Destruction
of private property,
assault on an officer
of the law:
Sentence: 15 years:
Up for parole in five.
What are you in for, Pops?
It's Santa Claus.
Yeah, boy!
- He won't last a year.
- Don't break a hip.
- I'm on the bottom?
- You got that right.
There was
an O'Reily family
in my last parish,
St. Patrick's...
Well, it wasn't mine.
We only went to church
for funerals.
Oh, I see.
No.
You don't see dick.
Just 'cause I was
baptized a Catholic
doesn't mean I got any use
for a fuckin' priest.
Duly noted.
I've cleared
my schedule
so I can attend
Cyril's trial every day.
I'll be sitting right behind him
in the courtroom.
Mm-hmm.
Ryan, he's not gonna
get convicted.
He is not gonna get
the death penalty.
Hi-ho, hi-ho.
Hey. How you
feeling, kid?
- Scared.
- Don't be, okay?
Ma's gonna be with you
the whole way. All right?
Look, I brought you
a brand-new suit.
I hope it fits 'cause I wasn't
sure about the sizes.
Cyril, we're not allowed to travel
with you on the bus, okay?
So I'm taking Suzanne
in my car.
- We'll see you before the trial, okay?
- Okay.
You're gonna be okay.
- I wish you were coming.
- No, you don't need me.
You'll be fine.
But look, if you...
you know, if you start
to panic, all right,
I just want you
to think of me, okay?
All right.
Doing this...
Let's go. Let's go.
Hey, toss the ball.
Now toss
the fuckin' ball.
This is about the size
of your head, Morales.
You got style, Jia,
I'll give you that.
You had me fooled thinking that you were
worried about Li Chen hurting my ma.
You set me and Cyril up,
only... you thought
your boy would waste us,
not the other way around.
Zou Kai.
I got moves too,
brotherman.
Hey, Shupe. I see they let you out
of protective custody.
- Don't start anything, O'Reily.
- I ain't starting shit.
I'm just wondering
how much money
Jai Kenmin paid you to lie
about Cyril to the warden.
Look at me.
I'm gonna give you one chance
to switch your story to the truth.
- L... I told the truth.
- Okay.
Hey, I made
something special for you.
Eat up.
I'm not hungry.
I didn't think so.
- Glen Shupe.
- What about him?
I need that cocksucker
to have an accident.
- How severe?
- Not dead, just diminished.
And it can't be
traced back to me.
What do I get
in return?
Jia Kenmin dies,
and it can't be traced back to you.
Deal.
- Sean, I need the...
- Get out of the way!
Doctor,
I've got the arm.
The first day of trial
did not go well.
Judge Moore was in a foul mood,
and the prosecutor...
he's tough and smart.
So you're saying
we're gonna lose?
I just don't want
to give any false hopes.
During the jury selection,
Cyril got very agitated
and he kept talking
out loud,
and the judge kept
warning him to be silent.
Moore might eject him
from the courtroom.
Is the judge aware
of Cyril's mental state?
- Yeah, he just... he doesn't care.
- I'll talk to Cyril.
Hello, Cyril.
Hiya.
May I come in?
Sure.
How did it go today?
Lots of mumbo-jumbo.
"I object,"
"Motion to blah,
blah, blah."
Yeah. All those words
confused you, huh?
Everyone seems
so mean.
I was asking questions,
but the guy at the big desk
banged the thing
and yelled at me.
Ma was behind me,
but not close enough
to talk to.
I brought you something.
A puppet!
I want you to take this puppet
with you to court every day,
and when you feel the need
to talk to someone,
I want you
to whisper to him, okay?
Mm-hmm.
But I want you to whisper
to him very softly,
so no one else can hear you.
Show me.
- Sister Pete wants us to be...
- Even softer.
Excellent.
And at the end
of each day,
the two of you can tell me everything
you whispered to each other
and I'll explain
things to you, all right?
We have to give
the puppet a name.
Good. What do you want
to call him?
- Jericho.
- Why Jericho?
'Cause the walls
came tumbling down.
Lights out.
Jesus, you pray a lot.
Well, I need
a lot from my God:
Strength, guidance,
forgiveness.
While you're at it,
ask him to bring back conjugal visits.
- Don't you ever pray?
- No, not since grade school.
What happened?
Why'd you stop?
A priest tried to grope me
in the confessional.
Oh, I am sorry.
- Some priests get lost spiritually...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Father,
give it a rest.
I was just kidding.
Look, I have
a meeting tomorrow
with Father Mukada
and I was thinking...
Lights out means
shut the fuck up.
? Hey, lookie yonder,
tell me what you see?
? Marching to the fields
of Vietnam?
? Looks like Handsome Johnny
with an M-16?
? Marching
to the Vietnam War?
? Yeah, marching to
the Vietnam War?
? Hey, lookie yonder,
now tell me what you see?
? Marching to
the Birmingham Fields?
? Looks like Handsome Johnny
with his hand rolled in a fist?
? Marching to
the Birmingham Wars?
? Yeah, marching
to the Birmingham Wars?
? And it's
a long, hard road?
? It's a long,
hard road?
? Hey, before
we'll be free?
we'll be free...?
? Huh!?
Any word on
Augustus's condition?
Well, I got a call in to Dr. Panitz
at Benchley Memorial.
When he calls me,
I'll let you know.
- What about you? You got news for me?
- Not yet.
- You find out who gave Hill the drugs?
Well, when you do,
you let me handle the rest.
Of course, McManus.
- Of course.
- Hey... hey.
You gave me your word.
And my word is
my bond, hmm?
Count!
Let's go! Move it!
Yo, Burr,
I'm telling you,
it must have been
them Sicilians
that gave Augustus
them drugs.
They mad 'cause
you and Morales
is muscling them
out of the tit game.
- You get me some proof.
- Proof?
Man, proof is hard
to come by, yo.
I need to see
some proof.
Shit.
- Hey, yo, Chico, my man.
- What do you want?
Yo, we got
a problem, man.
Burr thinks that you gave Hill the juice that
sent him into hyperspace,
and he growling
for revenge.
- Me?
- Yeah.
No, man. Yo, the Sicilians
probably did it.
I tried to tell him, but you
know Burr, man. He want confirmation.
So I got a solution.
You got to find somebody
who will say that they saw
the dagos give Hill the shit.
- Who?
- I don't know who, man,
somebody with no... no...
what you call it?
No... no vested interest.
Excuse me.
What?
Salvatore Desanto.
Mmm.
He gave the drugs
to Augustus.
Yeah,
l... I saw
the whole thing.
- Okay.
- All right.
See, I told you.
At dinner tonight,
I want you to do me a little favor
and stick this
in Desanto's food for me.
- What's this?
- A mind fuck.
I say we whack Redding.
We... we tried
killing Redding.
He don't fuckin' die.
That is bullshit, Sal.
Anybody can fuckin' die.
Fuck.
Fuck,
what's goin' on?
Jesus, what's happening?
My... my head is...
- Shit.
- What the fuck?
Salvatore Desanto is brain-dead,
overdose of LSD.
Oh, man,
that's a bummer.
I saw a lot of acid myself
over in Vietnam.
That stuff's more
lethal than the Viet Cong.
It really can
blow your mind.
Yeah.
You know,
I really should have the food
that Desanto was eating tested.
Now that's
a good idea.
Only problem is
ain't no food left.
My boys, they...
they ain't so good at cooking,
but when it comes to the end
of the day, man,
they clean up that cafeteria,
I'm telling you.
- I'll bet.
- Mmm, spotless.
The first time that
I got raped by Adebisi,
I thought, "This was the worst thing
that could ever happen."
But... I was wrong.
How many men
were there?
Three.
Do you know
why they did it?
Does the why matter?
Only to you.
What do you want me
to say, Sister?
Peter, I don't want you
to say anything.
I just want you
to understand
that no matter what you think you may
have done to bring this on yourself,
you did not deserve
to be raped.
Those men,
whoever they are,
had no right
to violate you.
Ah, all right.
Tomorrow.
Same time?
No.
I don't think any of this
is really helping me, Sister.
Peter...
Thanks.
Thanks for trying.
I want to find the three men
who raped Schibetta.
Why?
Why, Leo?
Look, we're doing
everything we can
to keep the number
of reported rapes down.
Reported?
Listen to you.
Your own daughter
was raped.
This is different.
This is Oz.
- Rape is rape, Leo.
- I don't agree.
Here, rape has a...
a leveling effect.
Peter Schibetta,
from the day he arrived,
wanted to be a tough guy, wanted
to follow in his father's footsteps,
running things,
hurting people.
Well, he got
stopped by Adebisi.
- Now he got stopped again.
- What's going on?
Do you have something personal
against Schibetta?
No, no.
It's simply...
survival
of the fittest,
as natural and basic
as Darwin.
You and I have disagreed about a lot over
the years, but this is...
Peter Marie...
"A leveling effect"?
You want rape
to do your job?
You see this medal?
St. Dismas.
He's the patron saint
of prisoners.
Al Capone gave this to my grandfather
in the '20s.
- I didn't know Al Capone was religious.
- He wasn't.
He just liked
to hedge his bets.
Dr. Nathan,
I keep feeling
worse and worse.
I know.
I haven't prayed
since the fifth grade.
I've forgotten how.
Me too.
Hola.
- Hola yourself.
- Well, you're in a mood.
Oh, I am frustrated.
I'm dealing
with Peter Schibetta
and taking
these little baby steps,
and then this morning he tells me
he's done with therapy.
Maybe you should have him talk
to some other guy who's been raped.
Yeah, yeah, I was
thinking about that.
Listen, are you aware of any trouble
between Leo and Peter?
No. Why?
Never mind.
I'm just having one of those days
filled with massive confusion.
I'm having
a day myself.
Chucky Pancamo came in
with a stab wound
- and caught a staph infection.
- Oh.
Yeah, he's sinking
pretty fast.
And you're
blaming yourself.
His wound got infected
on my watch.
Life is dangerous
enough in Oz
without prisoners having
to worry about dying
due to poor
medical treatment.
Look at us.
We're complete
and utter failures at our jobs.
So what do we do
instead?
Form an all-girl band?
- Hey, I want to ask you a favor.
- Sure.
I want you to talk
to Peter Schibetta.
Okay.
Only if...
you teach Chucky Pancamo
how to pray.
Peter.
Come in.
Oh, sit down.
May I take your hand?
Blessed art thou
amongst women...
And blessed is
the fruit of thy womb...
And blessed is the fruit
of thy womb...
- Jesus.
Holy Mary,
mother of God...
- pray for us sinners...
now and at the hour
of our death.
Now and at the hour
Amen.
? Look, I'm standing
naked before you?
? Don't you want
more than my sex??
? I can scream as loud
as your last one?
? But I can't claim
innocence?
? Oh, God, could it be
the weather??
? Oh, God,
why am I here??
? If love isn't forever?
? And it's not
the weather?
? Hand me my leather.?
Hoyt.
Oh, it's nice
to see you, Father.
- Really?
- It's nice to see anyone.
This fuckin' place
is spooky.
Jaz, you confessed to several murders,
including Jim Burns.
But you didn't act alone.
You had help.
I ain't rattin'
on my friends.
No, no, no,
not all of them,
but Timmy Kirk...
- I killed Timmy Kirk.
- No.
As hard as you tried,
he survived.
- He's back at Oz.
- Cocksucker!
You tell the warden
the truth about Kirk,
and he's gonna be
moving in right next door.
Get me Glynn.
I want to sing.
It's Hoyt's version
versus mine.
He killed Burns.
He bricked Cloutier inside a wall.
This is all some kind of weird
revenge thing on his part.
- I'm innocent.
- You liar!
Ray. Ray.
You will burn, Kirk!
Take Kirk
back to Unit B.
You're the one
who will burn.
Hey, Clarence,
- how are you?
- Good.
Ooh, you been
working out?
- Yeah.
- Yeah? I can tell.
Hey, you're in
for arson, right?
- Yeah.
You know
any other arsonists?
I mean,
on the outside.
One or two.
How'd you like
a blowjob?
Hmm?
Our Lady of Fatima Church
and its rectory next door
burned to the ground this evening,
killing two priests.
The two priests, Father John Downing
and Father Jack Hurlbert,
were trapped on an upper floor
of the rectory.
Also injured
was Father Raymond Mukada,
- who suffered from smoke inhalation...
- Holy shit!
And is in serious condition
at Benchley Memorial Hospital.
Arson is suspected
as the cause.
? You creep?
? Into my heart?
? And make my heart?
? Burn!?
? You sneak?
? Into my mind?
? And make my head?
? Ache!?
? Look, it's time
to face the music?
? Bye-bye!?
? Don't slam
the door?
? This is the last duet?
? Last chance
you're gonna get?
? No more harmony?
? For you and me?
? This is the last duet?
- ? I'll ever do with?
- ? Never do with?
? Never ever?
? Never ever,
never do with you.?
Sir, may I speak?
Sure, prag.
Uh, what's the latest
on Adam Guenzel?
And how's your
plan working?
Well, I predict
by the end of the week
he'll be sucking my cock.
Yesterday I deposed
Jerry Heekin.
Who's that?
He's that man who claims he saw you
dump Brice Tibbetts in the field.
He's a very
credible witness.
- Is that so?
- Remember you said that he testified
it was late
at night, so...
it must have been dark,
no lights in the field?
Yeah, well, see,
he had a flashlight.
He saw you...
- clearly.
- It wasn't me.
Look.
A lot of guys running around
look like me, you know.
I got a very
familiar face.
- You know, I'm divorced.
- Mmm.
Yeah.
I was married to Eddie
for 10 years.
One day I asked him where he'd been,
he goes, "Barney's,"
just so fast,
so convincingly,
I knew immediately
he was lying.
Are you calling me
a liar?
Every person in this country
deserves a fair trial,
deserves a good lawyer.
I cannot be
that lawyer for you.
I'll call the Public Defender's
office and find you someone else.
Catherine,
wait a minute.
I need you.
Keller, this is the one time
where your charms are useless.
Catherine...
Catherine!
Toby.
Hey.
Look, I just... I wanted
to let you know
that I won't be representing
Keller anymore.
Why?
What happened?
He's guilty.
You know, I made a promise
to myself the day I passed the bar.
I said I was never gonna
represent a guilty person,
and I'm not gonna start now,
not even for you.
I understand.
Answer me this.
When I'd asked you if he had ever
discussed these murders, you said no.
Yeah.
I lied.
Keller says so many things,
who knows what's true?
But you believe him
when he says he loves you.
Yes.
You do belong together.
Catherine.
Loves makes us all
do strange things.
You don't have
to tell me that.
You have a good life.
You knew
the woman you raped?
We used to date.
We bumped
into each other at this bar,
did some K,
started making out.
Next thing I knew,
Franklin and me
had her in the park,
face down in the grass.
You know, I never raped
a woman I knew.
- Adam?
- Yeah?
- Can I talk to you?
- I'm busy.
Two seconds.
Lovebirds.
You shouldn't be
hanging out with those guys.
Instead I should be playing
backgammon with you and Busmalis?
The bikers are
Schillinger's allies.
They're just being friendly
with you to try and set you up.
Schillinger wants you.
You ought to know, right,
having been his prag.
Hey, Guenzel,
you and Beecher goin' on a date?
While you're down there,
suck this cock, you faggot.
- Cocksucker.
- Ride him, cowboy.
A goal, goal,
goal, goal.
- That's my man!
- All right.
Schillinger.
You made me an offer the other day
that you'd help me get to see Keller
if I gave you
the boy Guenzel.
Yeah.
Is the offer
still on the table?
Jeez, I don't know.
I'll quit Sister Pete. I'll come
to work for you in the mailroom.
I'll call
the Sicilians off.
Please.
Oh, okay.
I no longer want you
to protect Adam Guenzel.
After I seen what he did to you,
I ain't surprised.
The kid's a prick.
- Sister.
- Good morning.
There is something
I've got to talk to you about.
I've decided to quit
working for you.
- What?
- Well, you know,
I've been doing the same job
for five years and I'm...
bored.
You know, l...
I had no idea
you were unhappy.
Well, I'm...
I'm not unhappy.
- If there's...
- I'm not unhappy.
Yeah.
Oh, well, all right.
If you're s...
sure about this.
I am.
Okay.
When do you
want to leave?
Today.
Today?
So you want to go
work with the Aryans?
Uh-huh. Ever since
we started these interactions,
Schillinger and I have been
getting along real well.
Plus working in the mailroom
allows you to see Keller.
It's okay, Beecher,
because I agree with Sister Pete.
You should be
allowed visits.
Yeah, but the real problem
is Adam Guenzel.
I know you're gonna do
whatever you think is best,
but Adam and I just
haven't been getting along.
I think
maybe you were right
when you said you wanted
to transfer him out of Em City.
Well, he's disruptive. I thought
you being friends was gonna help, but...
Me too.
It hasn't worked out.
Okay. I'm gonna ship him
over to Unit B.
- Schillinger.
- Yeah?
The boy is all yours.
Time for you
to deliver the mail.
Hey there, tough guy.
Knock knock.
Keller.
Go away.
I don't want to play today.
Huh?
I don't wanna
fuck right now.
Maybe you're forgetting
who's who here.
You're my bitch,
not the other way around.
I've been bringing you
little extras
and in return,
you've been giving me
little extras.
Don't poke me.
Fucking cunt, I don't want to see
your ugly fuckin' face...
God damn it!
Central, we got a 16,
section 32.
- How the mighty have fallen.
- Fuck you, faggot.
- Guenzel.
- Hey, Vern.
- The boys in Em City send their regards. -
Shut up.
Hey, I was just...
God, what the fuck was...?
- You'll speak when you're spoken to.
- Hey, get the fuck off me!
- Get off of me!
- Sir... sir, may I watch?
Well, if you don't, how are you
ever gonna learn?
Help!
Get the fuck off me!
Get the fuck off!
- I've got mail for Keller.
- He's not here.
- Where is he?
- Benchley Memorial.
In the hospital?
Well, what happened?
He acted up.
I shut him down.
Keep moving,
Beecher.
? On days like these?
? When the rain
won't fall?
? And the sky is so dry?
? That even birds
can't call?
? I can feel your tears?
? Disappearing in the air?
? Carried on the breeze?
? On days like these?
? But you can't reap?
? What you don't sow?
? And you can't plant?
? In hollow ground?
? So let us fill?
? This empty earth
with hope?
? Until the rains
come down?
? On days like these.?