Fact:
2.5 million people die
in the United States
each year.
This, of course, is using
the dictionary definition of dead.
Toe-tagged
and body-bagged.
The number one cause of death
in America: Heart disease.
But not all heart disease
will leave you dictionary dead.
Some will kill you
and still leave you living.
Yeah, we got a whole lot
of walking dead in Oz.
Toby, there you are.
I've been looking everywhere for you.
Get the fuck away from me.
I heard what you've been
telling people.
You honestly believe I would
fuck you over just to get you back?
Don't play the wounded puppy.
I know who you are.
Toby, I love you.
I need you.
Oh, you're only
making it worse.
You've gotta believe me,
I'm innocent.
Okay.
Let's say I give you
the benefit of the doubt.
Let's say you didn't
do it on purpose.
The bottom line is,
I believe you would,
that you're capable of it.
That's the kind of man
I think you are,
and I wish to God
I'd left you on death row.
How's it goin' there, Chris?
Go away.
Ah, I can understand you
being a little testy.
Heard about what
went on in the gym.
It's a heartbreaker.
I'll survive.
I know you will.
You always do.
I remember when we first served
time together back in Lardner.
Christ, you were...
what, 17?
You came walkin'
into that cell block,
strutting really.
I said, "There is one
tough little motherfucker."
Oh, what is this, Vern?
Why the sprint down
memory lane?
Been thinkin' about
how close we were.
You protected me,
I sucked your cock. That was it.
I didn't love you.
I didn't love you, either.
But you gotta admit,
what we had was
more than nothin'.
So what? Too much shit's happened
between us since Lardner.
Yeah, because
of Beecher.
Now that he's done,
I'm saying
let's be friends again.
No cock sucking, just two guys
lookin' out for each other.
What do you say?
Okay.
Cancer.
The scariest fuckin' word
in the English language,
and the second-leading
cause of death.
It might be a zodiac sign,
but more likely
cancer will eat
your insides up.
Do you know why
it's so fucking scary?
'Cause the word itself
is a cancer.
Just the idea of it
can infect you.
The stress of it can spread
through your spirit.
The fear can turn
into the disease.
Yo, Rebadow, over here.
What do you want
today, Pablo?
I want to know what the fuck
your problem is, man.
I mean, why are you treating
Miss C. Like a bitch?
- She's not a bitch.
- That's right, she's a nice lady.
She's helping me
ride out my time
and you're bringing her
the fuck down. And the cancer?
It ain't that big a deal.
That's right, she told me yesterday.
I guess she needed someone
to talk to since you were acting
like my younger fuckin' sister.
Maria freaked when my ma got
breast cancer.
Of course, she was eight.
And mi madre?
She squashed that disease
like it was a cockroach.
I'll bet that's something
you can identify with.
Stella...
could you sit a minute?
I've dealt with a lot
of death in my life.
We all have.
But for me, this place
was never more a prison
than when Alex Jr.
Was dying.
I'm not dying, Robert.
You don't know that
for certain.
I'm sure as hell
more certain than you are.
And you may want to bone up
on your apologies,
'cause this one sucks.
I've been insensitive,
self-absorbed. I'm sorry.
I just couldn't deal with the prospect
of losing someone else,
someone I love.
You don't love me,
Robert.
Yes, I do.
And I promise
to be here for you.
I don't want you here.
Listen, I'm glad you understand
what I'm going through,
but your worries,
your concerns,
don't dissipate simply
because you fess up to them.
My lumpectomy
is in a couple of days.
As much as I appreciate
your feelings for me,
right now, you are just
not good to have around.
Yes.
You're right, of course.
But let me say
one thing before I go.
What, are you nuts?
Requesting a transfer
into gen pop?
Emerald City, especially?
That's where Said lived.
People there loved him.
Not everybody.
I'm tellin' you,
Idzik, this is suicide.
The worst thing
about being in prison,
the thing I didn't
factor into my equation...
we're in lockdown
so early,
I never get to see
the night sky.
I used to go
to the planetarium
every single evening.
Yeah, I'd peer
through the telescope and...
search the universe.
Looking for a sign.
But there never
was one.
Everything out there
is so still.
I didn't even see
a shooting star.
You have got
a lot of nerve!
I mean, bringing that scumbag
to Em City.
Omar, all we've got
in Em City are scumbags,
including you!
I mean, given
everything you've done,
starting with the cold-blooded
murder of Felicia Brown,
I don't exactly see
why you are so self-righteous.
McManus,
the man killed Said.
Oh, oh, I grant,
all right, all right,
you and the minister
didn't always get along.
That's true, but we respected
each other, most of the time.
It's an insult to Kareem's memory,
you bringing him here.
Just a few days ago you were
beggin' me to let you see him.
Yeah, see him, but not to have
to breathe the same foul air with him
- on a continuous basis
and shit, damn!
I want your promise
no harm will come to Idzik.
- Now swear to me.
- No!
Don't give me a reason to stick your
ass back in solitary permanently!
Yeah, okay.
Okay, okay, okay!
I won't hurt Idzik.
Good. Now, I want you
to meet him.
Huh?
Lemuel Idzik,
Omar White.
Omar's gonna be
your sponsor.
McManus only put us together
to fuck with my head,
and maybe yours, too.
Why would he do that?
He's looking to kick my ass
back to solitary, right?
So, he buddies us up
and shit, man, you know,
knowing there's gonna be
motherfuckin' trouble.
Between us, why?
Be... because I'm lookin'
to whack you, man,
for whacking Said.
Ah, I see...
perfect.
As the clock runs out,
the hands of fate
are applauding.
What... what the fuck's
that supposed to mean?
I asked to be placed
in Em city
for one purpose
and one purpose only.
Yeah, what's that?
To find someone
to kill me.
Detective Tarnowski.
Hello, warden,
it's a pleasure.
What can I do for you?
I'm from homicide here,
replacing Detective McGorry
on the Wilson Loewen case.
Replacing McGorry, why?
She was rotated out of the unit,
happens all the time.
Not in the middle
of a major case.
A major case that, for all intents
and purposes, is over.
Let's go to my office.
Willy Brandt confessed to the murder.
What more do you need?
Brandt had no motive to assassinate
Loewen, except money.
Now, he admitted
he was paid to do the crime
- by a C.O., Adrian Johnson.
- Did you interrogate him yet?
Not formally,
but I talked to him
and he's guilty.
I want to find out why Johnson
ordered the hit.
Come on, warden,
the reasons are racial.
Loewen conspired to kill two little black
girls back in the '60s.
That would make
any man angry.
McGorry thought
something else was going on.
Didn't you read her report?
Sure, sure, between you
and the doorpost,
my lieutenant wants me
to wrap this stinker up fast
and that's
what I intend to do.
- So, let's find this C. O...
- Johnson.
Yeah, and put
this baby to bed.
Now, which way?
Do you know a prisoner
named William Brandt?
I know who he is.
I don't know him personally.
You never had
any contact with him?
Maybe once or twice. You know
the way shit flies around here.
- How about Lionel Kelsch?
- Same thing.
Did you ever meet
Mayor Wilson Loewen,
Either before or after he was
incarcerated in Oswald?
Nope.
Where were you
the night he was killed?
Home, in bed with my wife.
All right, officer,
thank you very much.
I'll get back to work.
I'd hardly call that
a comprehensive interview.
You got a problem
with this guy, warden?
No. Until now I considered him
one of my top C.O.'s.
Then why would you be
willing to take
the word of a convicted
felon over his?
I'd say Johnson is innocent.
Hello, Leo.
Ah, Perry, thanks
for coming by. Sit.
You know, I'm just starting
to use the internet,
starting to really
see its potential.
Leo, you said
this was urgent.
I'm a busy fellow.
I know you are.
Taking care of the governor,
that's a big job.
Let's face it,
Devlin is a needy man.
But you have been amazing,
cleaning up all of his
messes, his indiscretions.
What's this about?
Well...
I was just reviewing
officer Adrian Johnson's file.
I noticed he attended
the Middlesex Academy for boys.
Out of curiosity,
I went to their website
where they list the alumni.
You and he graduated
the same year?
Actually, he was a senior
when I was a freshman.
Ah...
we suspect Johnson paid Brandt
to whack the mayor.
What?
When the truth comes out,
it could do real damage to you,
to your career.
"Guilt by association."
I don't believe that Adrian's
connected to Loewen's murder,
but I appreciate
your concern.
Hmm.
Well, I'd just hate
to see a fine man like you
take an unnecessary fall.
What's up, Perry?
There's something
I need you to do.
- Kill Willie Brandt?
- Yes.
And Leo Glynn.
The third leading cause
of death in America is stroke,
or as they like to call it these days,
brain attack.
Serious.
That's a real medical term.
But who the fuck among us ain't had
their brain attacked?
And had some part of themselves
shut down, paralyzed,
which forces us to keep on
attacking back?
After Cutler died,
I started...
from my old ways,
you know,
bullying people
and waving my dick around.
I've crossed a lot of lines
in my life, sister.
But hurtin' my wife,
that was one line
I never thought I'd cross.
I always said I would never
lay a hand on Liesel.
You know,
being in the hole
gave me time to really think about
who I am and who I want to be.
All right.
Let's imagine that you could
do it over, the visit with Liesel.
What would you
do differently?
I'd talk.
Hug her... yeah.
Stroke her hair,
but not put her hand
inside my pants.
What the fuck
was I thinking?
And you would
talk about, what?
I don't know...
life.
Life without her,
how much it sucks.
And?
And that stuff
with Cutler, I guess.
What stuff?
You know what stuff.
Yes, James, but by articulating
what happened,
you accept it.
It's the first step
in healing.
I would tell my wife
that I was raped
and that's why
I didn't call her for so long.
And I would tell her
that I'm sorry
that I turned into
such a fucking fuck-up.
I, um, I came to Oz
nine months ago.
L... I was a virgin,
so, right away
I was targeted.
So, I kept
breaking the rules,
refusing to go to work
or take a shower,
shit like that.
They put me
on Special Restrictions.
I figured I'd be safe,
locked in my cell all day.
But then...
they put this lowlife
in my cell, and he...
he beat me
till I said yes.
As he was doing it, I could hear
the TV in the C.O.'s office.
They were watching
"I Love Lucy."
Thanksgiving day,
six guys come into my cell
while I'm asleep.
They held me down and they put
a razor to my throat.
I asked for a kit to collect evidence
to prove what happened.
The C.O. Waited two days
to take me to the infirmary.
He said, he bought me
for two cartons of Kools.
By the time the nurse examined me,
there was nothing left to find.
L... I tried to ride,
but I ran out of money.
They took turns orally
and anally penetrating.
Someone wrote my mother.
She wrote the warden...
- I was rented out.
- "Please help my son."
- $3.00 for a blow job.
- The hack told me...
$5.00 for anal sex.
"Quit whining,"
to stand up and fight.
I saved the sleeping medication
the sister was giving me,
10 days' worth,
1,000 milligrams.
One night... after,
I took 'em all.
- I had no choice.
I had no choice.
- You want any Morales' stuff?
- No.
I feel bad.
Enrique was really angry
at me when he died.
Well, it's probably
best he's dead.
He would've made
your life miserable.
That's true.
But he's got no family left.
They're gonna stick his body
in Potter's Field.
He ain't gonna know
the difference.
More and more, compadre,
I'm tired of all this shit.
I hear you, man.
Pancamo asked me
who was gonna lead El Norte.
What'd you say?
You.
Fuck that.
I told you, I'm keeping my head down till
my next parole hearing.
- Miguel.
- No.
- Alvarez, you got a surprise visitor.
- My girlfriend Maritza?
No. One Cathy Jo Cutler.
- She's the...
- Wolfgang Cutler's grieving widow.
Right.
Well, that's good.
Now, I can figure out
why he left me all his shit.
Yeah, good luck.
Hey.
Hi.
- Cathy Jo, right?
- Yes.
Thank you for seeing me.
Sure, of course.
Mr. Alvarez,
I'm here to ask you,
beg you...
Wait, wait, wait.
Okay, first of all,
Miguel, all right?
Let me just save you
a little speech or whatever.
I don't want
your husband's crap.
Oh.
I didn't know
you decided that.
Yeah, no, I just did.
I didn't sleep
a wink last night,
thinkin'
what to say to you,
the new owner of the bed
I was lyin' in.
You gotta do somethin'
for me first, okay?
You gotta tell me
why he did this.
Believe me, I've been
wrackin' my brains.
He did like
to fuck with me
when it came
to the purse strings.
Serves me right,
maybe, you know?
Why did I marry him
if I never loved him?
You're not married?
No, no.
Girlfriend...
she don't come around now.
Ah...
Well, um, I guess
that's all, then.
Thank you for being a better
husband than my husband,
if that makes sense.
Anytime.
Maybe I'll see you again?
You know, if I gotta
sign papers, whatever?
Okay, Miguel.
Cathy, all right.
- Say your prayers, Enrique.
- No, don't.
You're just like Martinez,
a nasty man
who deserves to die.
Thy kingdom comes,
thy will be done on earth
as it is in heaven.
Give us this day
our daily bread,
and forgive us
our trespasses
as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
And lead us not
into temptation,
but deliver us
from evil. Amen.
You know, someday,
maybe soon,
these guys are gonna be
carrying my body out.
Nah, you're gonna
get paroled.
I've been thinkin'...
we should set up a meeting
between you and Luis Ruiz.
I hit the motherfucker
in the face.
He's not gonna come by
for afternoon tea.
Steve Dawkins is retiring
from the parole board,
and the rumor is that Ruiz
is gonna get the job.
You're gonna need him
to be on your side.
Fine. I'll do whatever
you two guys say.
I just don't want to end up
like Enrique Morales.
You know, I don't want
to end up as the landfill.
The autopsy report shows
that Enrique Morales
was suffocated, same as Martinez.
What, do you think
Dave Brass did the job?
I'm betting both murders
were done by the same man.
I need a list of all the patients
who were in the ward both nights.
I already checked,
there wasn't one.
Well, Morales had a lot of enemies,
could be two killers.
What about your staff?
Didn't they see anything?
Oh, you know the night shift
is skeletal at best.
Who was on duty?
Carol Grace,
Gerald Lesowski.
Carol Grace...
You know, Morales
said something to me about her,
that I should... check her background.
Where's she from?
Well, I don't know.
She was hired before I got here.
Pull her file.
Breathtaking.
That's a nice way to describe
someone or something, right?
What the fuck's so good
about having your breath taken?
Respiratory disease
clocks in at number four
on our little hit parade
and for good reason,
'cause regardless of who takes
your breath away,
be it four packs a day
or just one chick,
you're dead just the same.
Carol...
would you step into my office
for a minute, please?
All right, doctor.
Oh, hello, warden.
We looked at your
employment record, Carol.
Before coming to Oswald,
you worked at Millard Fillmore
Hospital in Buffalo
and St. Eligius in Boston.
What is this about?
You were fired from both
institutions. Why?
Jealousy.
The patients always
liked me the best.
We checked with the head
of nursing at both places.
A combined total of eight men
died on your watch.
And I checked our own
death certificates.
Three prisoners coded
while you were on duty.
What are you implying?
The police will take you
downtown, to the homicide unit.
All right, just let me
get my things.
Get out of my way, you!
Leave me alone,
you fucking bastard!
you Spanish cunt!
You fuckin' bitch!
Spanish cunt!
Let me go-ooo!
Accidents are the fifth
leading cause of death.
But you know as well as me,
there's no such thing
as an accident.
That's just some bullshit word we used
instead of blaming ourselves,
cause no matter what damn lie
you've been told,
we're the leading
cause of death... mankind...
and there's no cure for us.
It's the wages.
We cannot compete
with Arif.
I'm not worried, Burr.
Yeah, well, I can see that.
Explain why.
This is a prison.
There are 28,000 men sitting around
with nothing to do.
In economic terms, the labor supply
dwarfs its demand.
Yeah, but what makes a prison
is the pride inside,
knowing that
the other inmates
are making 20 times
as much as you are?
I'll say it again,
supply and demand.
You, my good friend, are gonna
do some more recruiting.
I already tapped
all of my soldiers.
They've gone AWOL on me.
Then you're gonna
have to branch out.
We can manage half-staffed
a couple of days, but that's it.
Life is about wherever
you gon' get to...
Suppose you wouldn't want
to trade that service spoon
for a telephone, O'Reily? Come on
over and join our company.
Yeah, that'd be
a dream come true,
pissing off strangers
at dinnertime.
Ain't no money
in the kitchen.
That's why my middle name
is "subsidize."
Hello, boys.
You fellas are new here
in Oz, right?
Haven't really had
a chance to settle in yet.
Well,
rather than get involved
in all the tribal shit
that goes on around here,
you need to know
that these days, Oz has
a better place to turn.
Mm-hmm.
It's called employment.
I heard about that.
You with that guy, Arif?
No. I'm with me,
Burr Redding.
Telemarketing.
I'm gonna try and get seconds
before they shut down.
For all the flak
it gets,
a sales position
in telemarketing
is a fine way to keep
yourself active.
I just remembered, I got
an appointment with Sister Pete.
What about you? You gotta go
jerk off or something?
No, I mean,
I'd take the job.
Oh, good boy.
But I'm dyslexic.
Here, clear my tray,
you squirmy little maggot.
Yo, boss man,
this be payday.
Yeah, l... I know.
Where's my money?
You're gonna have to wait
till the end of next week.
What?
I'm waiting on a check
from one of the publishers,
and when it clears, I'll have
your money for you. Just trust me.
Trust you?
Fuck.
Excuse me.
I'm telling you, poet, except
for the money I've been stealin',
I'm stone-cold broke.
We cannot wait
any longer, man.
We've got to get back
to selling tits.
I'm way ahead of you,
Reggie, way ahead of you.
Got a little contact
on the outside,
my nigger Sky Bar.
Shipment coming in today.
- All right, my dogs.
- All right?
Yes!
Hey, poet, it's too bad
about your friend Sky Bar.
- What about him?
- Oh, you didn't hear?
Got run over by a Chevy...
37 times.
Prisoner number
9-7-G-1-4-1,
Samuel Gougeon...
...convicted August 5th, 1997...
manslaughter.
Sentence: 19 years.
Up for parole in 10.
But let me tell you about the greatest
political campaign of all,
"Jesus is love," and God himself
is running for office.
Put that phone down,
choir boy!
That's just straight-up
fucking dumb,
using my workplace as a front
for your Gospel-mongering.
- I'm sorry, l...
- Oh, yeah, no shit.
And now,
you're going to repent.
Hmm.
I got a special job for you.
I guess this is one of those times
you don't ask,
"What would Jesus do?"
Make it fast.
For I acknowledge
my transgressions and my sin...
...is ever before me.
Bless me, oh Father,
according to thy loving kindness
and according to the multitude
of thy tender mercies.
It was you, wasn't it?
Come inside, Arif.
You're a pathetic,
corrupt man, you know that?
The corrupt part, I do.
I wouldn't say pathetic, though.
Vandalizing my business to repopulate
yours? What do you call that?
Downsizing
for the overall good.
This is your chance to go to Glynn
and tell the truth before I do.
Nobody's going
to anyone, son.
Business wasn't
very good, was it?
How would you know that?
On Wall Street,
we call it reconnaissance.
And you ought
to be grateful to me.
Now, you can collect
your insurance
and get all that money back
your Muslim brothers have lost.
And you can put all that
aggravation behind you.
Hmm?
Don't mention it.
- Did he confess?
- I need time to think.
What's there to think about?
He's guilty, right?
No.
What happened to our machinery
was an accident.
13 years after banging
the opposite side of the gavel,
the Supreme Court
did an about-face
and decided last June
to bar the death penalty
on retarded defendants.
"The large number
of states
prohibiting the execution
of mentally retarded persons
provides powerful evidence
that today
our society views
mentally retarded offenders
as categorically
less culpable
than the average criminal."
So, how's Cyril doing?
He hasn't defecated on himself
again and he's sleeping a lot.
How much is a lot?
In and out, all day long.
Oh, maybe that's a good thing,
you know, I mean...
we're still waiting to hear about
the stay from the State Supreme Court,
but, I don't know,
I mean, if we don't get one,
maybe he can just nap
up until the time
when they put him
to sleep for good.
Ryan,
lethal injection isn't
just falling asleep.
What do you mean?
It definitely makes execution
easier on the public,
easier on the staff,
but we don't really know
how painful lethal injection is.
What I can tell you
is a little-known fact
- that it was invented by the Nazis.
- What?
Hitler's personal physician
devised the procedure
as a means
to kill off children
- and eventually used it on adults...
- Hitler?
Given the concern
those bastards had for mercy...
No, I just... I just want what's best
for Cyril, that's all.
Well...
I was wondering if maybe
the electric chair wouldn't be
the better way to go.
The chair? Why not just feed him
to the fuckin' lions?
Think about it.
I mean, he's had
electroshock therapy,
which isn't such a far cry
from electrocution.
I mean, at least in his mind
it wouldn't have to be.
By now, he's used to the straps
and the electrodes.
Just tell him he's going in
for a special session.
He might never know
the difference.
Fuck.
Hey.
Psst. Come on, Cyril,
wake up.
Hmm.
So...
you want the good news
first or the bad news?
- The good news.
- All right.
The good news is
you're gonna have your last ECT
session in a couple of days.
Why is this
the last session?
Well, because you've been
such a champ so far, you know.
And because
you've been so great,
they're gonna
move you back upstairs.
They're gonna fix up
your cell all special-like
and they're gonna
give you a TV, hmm?
- Really?
- Yeah.
I can watch what I want?
What we want, bro.
I'm gonna be there with you.
- You are?
- Yeah.
And um...
they're gonna make you
this big dinner
where you can eat
whatever you like.
I can have
a Fluffernutter?
You can have
two Fluffernutters.
I can have
So, you want to hear
the bad news?
All right.
They've got to...
they've got to cut your hair.
Why, I like my hair?
I know you do, buddy,
but for this last session,
they've got to cut it, I'm sorry.
Will it grow back?
Homey, you put
Rapunzel to shame.
It's gonna grow back,
right, Ryan?
Yeah, right.
Fingernails gonna grow
down there, too.
Gonna go from
Rapunzel to Elvira.
Yo, homey,
come on, man.
Just focus on the hair,
all right?
We don't need
a color commentary, okay?
Actually,
you know what?
Let me get
a few snips in.
I've been wanting
to do this for years.
Holy shit.
Goddamn it, Cyril,
I can see your face again,
you handsome fuck.
Ryan, look.
Listen...
I haven't been very friendly
since I got to Oz,
but now,
I've talked to Suzanne
and I'm aware
of how hard you've tried
to stop your
brother's execution.
I admire your efforts.
I want you to know
at the hour of his death,
everyone in Em City
will be with him.
Oh, yeah? How?
You'll see.
Let's go, O'Reily.
Any word yet from
the State Supreme Court?
No. You'll stay
in your brother's cell tonight
and when they take him downstairs,
we'll bring you back here.
I was wondering
if at the time of his death,
- you know, I could be alone?
- Stay in your pod.
L... I was thinking maybe I could walk
in your meditation maze.
All right.
Following a particularly
heated trial,
which seems to have only
magnified the disagreement
on the execution of
the mentally challenged.
So, this afternoon
at Oswald penitentiary...
- What was that about Oz?
- Nothing.
Why does that man keep watching me
and taking notes?
It's part of the last ECT session.
They always do that.
I think I have
a stomach ache.
It's all that fluff
and stuff, you big freak.
Hey,
what do you say we lie down
for a little while,
you know, get a snooze in?
I forgot to ask for Rolaids.
Are you okay, Ryan?
Yeah.
As long as you are, buddy.
Each individual state has to decide
if a person is retarded or not,
meaning a murderer could get
a life sentence in Maine
where he's considered
retarded,
but the gas chamber in lowa
where he's normal enough to die.
Same guy,
same problems, same crime,
two opposite fates
depending on which invisible
state line he crosses.
Guilt and innocence,
hell, one's entire identity
is now a matter
of geography.
Uh... one thing
I didn't tell you, Cyril,
there's going to be other people
there today watching.
Who?
Oh, let's see... the warden,
uh, Sister Pete,
Ma, Dr. Nathan,
and a few other people
you probably won't recognize.
Oh.
Are you gonna be there?
No, I want to,
but I can't.
Why?
Daddy said,
"It's not good
for big boys to cry."
Yeah, well, you know what?
Dad was wrong,
and I was wrong.
We were all so fucking wrong,
Cyril. Man, I'm so sorry.
Did I do something?
No.
Dr. Nathan, she said
I got this condition, right?
And...
the only way for me to...
cure myself is to cry.
You know, it's got
nothing to do with you.
I'm sorry.
Don't be scared, okay?
Whoops, I think
I got gas from dinner.
- Mom!
- Hi, ahem...
- Any word from Zelman?
- No.
Hey, hello.
You look pretty.
Sit down.
I want to teach you this little
prayer that I know.
It goes something
like this, it goes,
"Lord Jesus Christ
have mercy..."
Hey.
There's probably not
a chance I can get
a copy of that journal
you're writing in, can I?
Afraid not.
No, just a... you know,
one quick stop
by the copy machine, you know.
No one's got to know, I swear
to God. I won't show it to anyone.
I promise.
Your time is up.
Lord Jesus Christ,
have mercy on me.
Lord Jesus Christ, have mercy
on me.
Lord Jesus Christ,
have mercy on me.
Lord Jesus Christ, have mercy
on me.
Hey, come on,
we have to go.
Amen.
Hey.
Who loves you, man?
- You do.
- Oh, that's right.
More than you'll
ever fuckin' know.
Listen, I just need you
to relax, okay?
You know how
you get scared.
You just think
about me, all right?
Okay.
My boy.
What?
Nothing.
These are the clothes
you asked for.
I didn't ask
for any clothes.
Is that Ryan's shirt?
He said I could wear it?
There's widespread agreement
that retarded people
are less accountable
for their crimes
than those
of average intelligence.
But if so,
something or someone
has to be held accountable,
has to pick up the slack and
take the rest of the blame, right?
After all, these victims
still die heinous deaths
and families still grieve.
If the retarded person
is not fully at fault,
then who or what shares
the responsibility?
God?
Human nature? Society?
Maybe the question is,
who isn't to blame?
Why do I have
to wear these?
Where are my shoes?
- Hello, Cyril.
- Hi.
Don't I need my shoes?
Yea, "Though I walk through
the valley of the shadow of death,
I will fear no evil,
for Thou art with me.
Thy rod and thy staff,
they comfort me.
Thou preparest a table before me
in the presence of mine enemies.
Thou anointest
my head with oil.
My cup runneth over.
Surely goodness and mercy shall
follow me all the days of my life,
and I will dwell
in the house of the Lord forever."
What the fuck
is going on?
(soft rock music playing)
Now is your opportunity
to make a last statement.
Huh?
(music continues)
Dick? Hi.
No, no reason not to go forward.
We're all set here.
(music continues)
Yes, this is Warden Glynn.
Uh-huh.
Right.
Okay.
By the order of
the State Supreme Court,
Cyril O'Reily
has been granted a stay,
based on newfound merit
in his appeal.
- Yeah!
- This sentence's been postponed
until further notice.
What happened?
What about
the special session?
Flashback to 1989
when the Supreme Court
first weighed in on this issue.
"Based on evolving
standards of decency
that mark the progress
of a maturing society,
there is not
sufficient evidence present
of a national consensus
against such executions."
Well, supposedly today,
there is.
Polls show
most Americans agree
that an adult with the mind
of a third-grader
should not be on death row.
But are we
a maturing society
with evolving standards
of decency?
Who's to say
we're any further along
than some cosmic equivalent
of third grade?
Who's to say, we, as a whole,
aren't retarded?
Thank you.