I'm innocent.
I am innocent!
Innocent.
I'm innocent, too.
I'm innocent.
You go to any prison, you ask
any guy who's serving time
and he'll tell you
he's in-no-cent.
"I got a bum rap.
I had a lousy lawyer.
I was in Toledo
visiting my mama."
Yeah, you'll hear
A whole pack of lies.
But what about that one brother
who's telling the truth,
the one who really is
innocent?
His voice is buried
so damn deep beneath the others,
he's gonna grow hoarse
just trying to be heard.
Leo!
Leo Glynn is dead.
I'm sorry, the reality
just hasn't sunk in.
I feel so bad,
you know?
He and I hadn't been
getting along lately.
Well, we all had
our disagreements with Leo.
But, still, he was the best man
for the worst job.
Amen.
I spoke to his ex-wife
at the cemetery.
She and his daughter
didn't want to make the drive...
would I pack up
Leo's belongings.
I don't think she has a clue
about my relationship with him.
Mary knew.
She said she was happy
Leo had someone.
She hated the idea of him being
all alone after the divorce.
Tim, I talked
to the governor
about naming you
the new warden.
I'm sure Devlin jumped.
Well, he didn't say no.
Doesn't matter,
don't want the job.
This place needs a strong,
sensible hand, Tim.
That's you.
Stanton has
some interesting hearsay.
Lionel Kelsch
whacked the warden...
and Willy Brandt.
Before that, he helped Brandt
waste Mayor Loewen.
How do you know this?
Kelsch is a bragger,
and I hate braggers!
All right, take Stanton
into protective custody.
Bring Kelsch to the hole.
All right!
- You ever been in the hole?
- No, sir.
First, you're naked,
so it's cold.
Then you piss
and shit in a bucket.
Worse, you're alone,
utterly alone,
24 hours a day.
Except for the meals,
right?
When you see the hacks?
Theoretically.
See, some of these guys...
they forget
to bring the food,
especially to someone accused
of killing the man they respected.
- Hmm.
- Strip.
Um...
McManus, wait!
What are
my alternatives?
You can give me the name
of the person that hired you.
Well, the governor's eulogy
of Glynn was very moving.
Oh, yeah?
I nodded off.
What does McManus
want to see me about?
I don't know,
he just told me to find you.
Think he'll get
the warden gig?
Never know.
Don't be shy,
Officer Johnson.
I'm gonna have
to read you your rights.
Before they cart
your ass downtown...
just tell me why.
Why-why'd you hire Brandt
in the first place, huh?
Was it because
of those little girls?
I'm not saying word one
until I get a lawyer
and cut myself
a nice, juicy deal.
Leo trusted you!
- Let's go.
- Go ahead.
Tim.
You remember back
five years ago
when you announced
from this very stage
that I was eliminating
all high school
and college
equivalency programs?
I'm gonna give a speech
praising education
as the one last hope
prisoners have...
and naming the new program
after Leo Glynn.
Hmm, how the times
have changed.
Maybe it's me,
maybe I've mellowed.
We've just received a call
from Detective Tarnowski.
Adrian Johnson has
implicated Perry
in the murders of Loewen,
Brandt and Leo.
What?
You're next, Devlin.
- Governor, we need to...
- Shut up, Perry.
Cancel
the press conference.
Let's get back
to the mansion.
These charges
are scurrilous.
It's a vain attempt
to attack a fine young man.
Yeah, who's one step away
from getting fucked up the ass,
unless you can
make a deal, too.
- Hey, I only...
- Shut up!
- I'll handle this.
- How?
See, I don't see
what you can do,
except type out
your resignation.
You know what
the irony is?
The irony is that Wilson Loewen
got you elected!
And now, Loewen's ghost
is gonna bring you down.
My only hope is that
when you go to prison,
they send you here
to "Oz."
Ellie, you coming?
No, I'm not,
you little prick.
I accept
your resignation.
- Yours, too, McManus.
- I'm not going anywhere.
We'll see about that!
Perry!
Thank you all
for coming.
Leo Glynn's untimely death
- has left a void in Oswald's...
- Can the speech, Commissioner.
Just tell us who's
gonna be our new boss.
All righty.
Some of you may already know
him from when he worked here,
More recently, he's been
doing a bang-up job
at Lardner... Martin Querns.
Hello, everybody.
I'm back.
Tim McManus...
come on down.
I don't know what you did
to piss off the governor,
but he sure as shit
wants your head
hanging off a spike
on the north tower.
- So, I'm out.
- Consider this your month's notice.
Fabulous.
Of course, a lot
can happen in a month.
This murder scandal
could mean the end
of Devlin's days in office.
I don't know.
He's skated through worse
and come out on top.
Like I said,
we have to wait and see.
Of course, if he goes,
you may not have to.
I wasn't lying when I said
I was a big fan
of the concept of "Em City."
Did he fire you?
I'm not sure.
Sister.
Get your buns in here.
This is
a restraint chair.
It will be placed
in the hole.
If you disobey,
you will be placed in it.
I wanted you all
to see this monster,
to let you know I will not
take any shit from anyone.
So...
remember...
don't fuck
with Querns.
Here's a story,
and it's true.
Mariano Absun escaped
The Connor Correctional Center
in Hominy, Oklahoma
by hiding in the back
of a garbage truck.
His body was found
two hours later,
crushed to death
in the truck's trash tray.
Now, Absun was only serving
a three-year sentence.
Three years.
That's how desperate he was
to get the fuck out.
Bob, can't sleep?
No.
This is the best time...
when it's quiet,
when the day still
has possibilities.
Today is Stella's first day back
after her breast surgery.
- You're excited.
- And afraid.
Before she went
into the hospital,
I told Stella
that I loved her.
Bob, you old seadog.
But she said I didn't...
which of course means
she doesn't love me.
Stella?
I got your flowers.
- Oh.
- Did I hurt you?
No.
I'm just not used
to the new breast yet.
I can't tell the difference.
Only God can make a tree,
but fortunately,
man can fix pretty much
everything else.
Any problems?
The medicine I'm on
is pixilating my memory,
so, if I start
to repeat myself
or forget a name,
forgive me.
No, it's you who
has to forgive me
for my silliness
for thinking
we both shared
the same feelings.
The same feelings?
I don't know,
But I do love you,
Robert...
in my fashion.
It's all a matter
of perspective.
"To see a world
in a grain of sand
and a heaven
in a wild flower..."
"Hold infinity in
the palm of your hand..."
"and eternity in an hour."
Ms. Coffo!
"Adseg" is
a restricted area.
I want to see
Pablo Rosa.
Oh, he's not allowed
any visitors.
But I work here.
Those are the rules.
How do we get the rules
changed just this once?
I don't know.
- Talk to someone higher up.
- Who?
I don't know.
He pretends to be a tough guy,
but he's not.
Pablo's just another
terrified kid.
And I'm afraid what's going
through his head right now,
sitting alone
in that hell hole.
What would you
like to happen?
At the very least,
get him some books to read.
They'll never allow him
to have books in the hole.
But there's always a way
to finagle something.
How much cash
do you have?
Pablo, can you hear me?
Ms. C?
You're okay?
I'm fine.
And you?
I'm going sort of crazy.
Well...
I'm here to help you
with that.
How?
I'm gonna read to you...
"The Adventures of Tom Sawyer."
Chapter One.
"Tom plays,
fights and hides.
'Tom! '
No answer.
'What's goin' on
with that boy, I wonder.
You, Tom! '
The old lady
pulled her spectacles down
and looked out over them
about the room.
And she put them up,
and looked out under them.
She seldom or never
looked through them
for so small
a thing as a boy."
I just had another visit
with Norma and the baby.
Fatherhood is
a remarkable thing.
I wouldn't know.
What do you mean?
You had Alex.
But I didn't raise him.
He never even knew I was alive
until he was a grown man.
I was never
a father to my son.
Oh, and here's Ruby,
who's not my own,
who I will help to raise.
Still, I'd like some day
to have my own offspring,
From my own loins,
as it were.
Agamemnon, please.
I've just eaten.
I guess it's a fool's goal,
since we're not allowed conjugals.
And by the time I'm out,
Norma will be past
her child-bearing years.
There are alternatives.
Artificial insemination,
for example.
Sure,
I could jerk off,
and then overnight my sperm
to Norma, next-day delivery.
Bob, you-you're brilliant!
The commissioner
says no.
No?
How can he say no?
Well, he doesn't want to start
an avalanche of requests
for prisoners to
artificially inseminate.
He says that it opens up
the State to safety,
security and legal risks.
But I have a right
to procreate.
Well, not necessarily.
The United States Supreme Court
guarantees a prisoner
the right to marry
and not to be sterilized.
Now, the justices have never
expressed an opinion
on prisoners
bearing children.
- What can we do?
- We? Nothing.
You should contact the Society
for Prisoners' Rights,
have them
assign you a lawyer.
I will, goddamn it.
Just because I broke the law
doesn't mean I'm not a man.
True, but, Busmalis,
not every man was
supposed to be a father.
Every man should
have a right to choose.
Whoa.
Go easy with that stuff,
Agamemnon.
You're looking
like an oil slick.
You're right...
I'm nervous.
The judicial panel
is meeting today
to decide if I can artificially
inseminate Norma.
If they say yes,
I could be a father
by Christmas.
Have you talked this
through with Dr. Nathan?
The entire procedure is
costly, time consuming
and most often
unsuccessful.
Why are you always trying
to dampen my spirits?
Because you constantly rush
into things without thinking,
only to get your heart broken.
That's not true.
Okay, maybe
it's a little true.
But, Bob, in Oz,
that's all we have,
hopes and dreams.
Having reviewed
the testimony and evidence,
we have reached
the following conclusion...
Since the state has the right
to eliminate conjugal visits,
we do not see restricting
artificial insemination
as unreasonable.
And though we agree
that to procreate
is a fundamental right,
the very purpose
of punishment
is to take away
fundamental rights.
We, therefore, deny
the plaintiff's petition.
We lost?
I'm afraid so.
Well, we-we'll appeal.
No, I'm sorry,
there's no appeal.
Back to your cage,
Busmalis.
No.
Don't give me any lip.
Wait, you bastard, wait!
This is my life we're
talking about, my life!
- Back off!
- You cocksucker!
- Get this man off me!
- I'll kill you, motherfucker!
But it isn't fair!
It isn't fair!
Morning.
What's wrong with her?
Claire asked me
for a second opinion.
Is she sick?
She's pregnant.
You asked to see me,
Father?
Yes, come in,
sit down.
What's this about?
Your being pregnant.
I'm not trying to insinuate
myself into anything.
I just wanted you to know
that if you want to talk.
What I tell you
remains between us, right?
'Cause I could lose my job.
I promise.
My relationship with men
in general has been disastrous,
yet here I am
surrounded by them.
Which is why...
Father, since coming to Oz,
I have fucked a lot of men.
Yeah!
A lot of prisoners.
- You're shocked.
- In a way, yes.
And, um, in a way, no.
Now, I'm pregnant
by one of them.
You know which one?
Well, my best guess is
the baby will be golden brown
and marinated in salsa...
which means
I can't raise him or her
in my redneck neighborhood.
I can't afford to move.
And if I could,
where would I go?
Little Havana?
I am screwed.
Claire, are you thinking
of having an abortion, because...
Oh, save your breath,
Father.
You Catholics aren't the only ones
who are against abortion.
So, what are you gonna do?
Take a leave of absence...
drop the calf.
And from then on,
keep my fuckin' legs crossed.
I'll never be
a father now.
Yeah, well, we all got
our problems.
Here's a story,
and it's true.
Up in Vermont,
an inmate was caught
breaking into prison.
He'd evidently slipped out
of his work camp,
went to a nearby
convenience store,
bought a case of beer
and a carton of cigs,
and then crawled back
under the fence
where he was arrested
by the C.O.'s.
The man was sentenced
to six more months.
And the poor motherfucker,
he didn't even get
to keep the beer.
You know what I'm saying?
Okay, raise your arms.
Turn around.
Through here.
Jackson Vayhue,
welcome to Oz.
It's not my first visit,
Warden.
I know.
Since being paroled,
I've tried my best to keep other
guys from making my mistake...
you know, lecturing the kids
and gangs and stuff.
I'm happy you're here
to do the same.
Younger prisoners look up
to a big basketballer like you.
Well, I hope they hear
what I have to say.
After you.
So, in conclusion,
I just ask you to use
your time wisely and well.
With any kind of luck,
you can pull your
life back together...
And get the fuck out
of Oz.
Can I get an autograph?
Officer Brass, you still
dancing down these halls?
Yup. Some of us ain't
as lucky as you.
I had nothing to do
with that tendon being sliced.
Oh, I know.
Hey, I bought season tickets
to the Knights,
so I'll be at the arena
every time you play.
Maybe after a game I can
come into the locker room,
hang out,
meet the other players.
No, I don't think so.
Oh, okay.
Let me ask you something,
Jackson.
When you're out
on the court playing,
all those eyes on you,
you ever wonder?
Wonder what?
Who's out there?
There's a lot of crazies
in the world, man.
No, I'm not afraid.
Bro, you got
huge "stundeens."
Nice to see you again.
All right, fellas.
Take care, man.
Dave!
Sean, Sean,
you threw me off my game.
Sometimes I wonder
if I wanted to play pro ball
because I loved the game
so much,
or because I wanted everyone
to see how great I could shoot.
Be adored by millions.
Money, women...
the whole rigmarole, huh?
I don't care about
the fringe benefits.
I want to be famous.
I don't want to die being a gimpy
old guard at a half-ass prison.
I don't want to disappear.
Well, I mean,
what can you do?
You play the hand
life deals you.
Sean, I know you did what you
think is right, about Morales.
I want to tell you,
I admire you.
I always have.
No hard feelings, huh?
Why do I feel like
you're saying goodbye?
I am.
I've decided...
I'm quittin'.
To do what?
Reshuffle the deck,
play a new hand.
This just in...
basketball star Jackson Vayhue
was shot at this afternoon
during practice at the arena.
The assaillant David Brass
had been working
as a guard at the Oswald...
Officer Murphy?
Vayhue served time at Oswald
and says he barely knew Brass,
though they did play opposite
each other in a prison basketball game.
Come on over
to the other side.
Here's a story,
and it's true.
A municipal court judge
in Texas
was indicted on four counts
of sexual misconduct.
Seemed this judge
extorted sexual favors
from the female relatives
of criminal defendants
in exchange for reducing
the defendants' bond,
or ordering their release.
Hey, when you're horny,
you're horny.
Mr. Hoyt, thank you
For coming to see us.
- I'm Father Mukada.
- How do you do?
Oh, and this is
Sister Peter Marie.
Sorry. Hello,
nice To meet you.
How do you do?
This, um...
this is my first trip
to a prison.
Oh, you haven't
visited Jaz before?
No.
I'm not exactly sure what it is
that you want from me.
Well, we feel that in order
for Jaz to fully recover,
he needs to deal with
certain emotional problems.
Yeah.
You can't blame
Evangeline and me
for the way
the boy turned out.
We were good parents.
I mean, we didn't
just give him things.
We-we gave him love,
plenty of love.
But there was always something
not quite right about the boy
from the very first day
that we brought him home
from the orphanage.
Jaz was adopted?
Oh, yes. My wife and I
couldn't have children.
We adopted three.
Have you ever tried
to find out more
about Jaz's birth-parents?
Yes, the father died
in prison.
The mother lived
in Morrisville.
Whether she still
lives there, who knows.
Mr. Hoyt, could I have
the information
- about Jaz's birth-parents?
- Certainly.
Drink your juice.
- No.
- Drink your juice.
- No!
- Drink the goddamn juice.
No, bitch!
Get the fuck
out of my face!
Jessica, one of the hardest
things about working in Oz
is trying to separate
the man from his crime.
If you can't do that,
even with Jaz Hoyt,
you shouldn't be here.
No, I'm sorry.
You're right as usual.
Let me... let me
make it up to you.
Are you... are you free
for lunch?
No, actually.
I'm in the middle of trying to locate
Hoyt's birth mother.
Why?
I want to know
where Hoyt came from.
In order to save him?
Well, yes.
You are
a remarkable man, Ray.
You are a saint.
Hardly.
If you won't have lunch with me,
how about dinner?
You haven't eaten unless
you've tasted my roast chicken.
I won't take no
for an answer.
All right,
I'd be delighted.
Great.
7:30?
He was only one day-old
when I gave him up for adoption.
My boyfriend had just
been sent to prison,
and my parents thought
that I should have a chance at life.
Buster was a real bastard.
You should excuse me,
Father,
but he was a slimeball.
My husband, John...
he's a sweet, sweet man.
I gotta tell you, I'm real nervous
about seeing my son.
I actually thought
to call and cancel.
I'll be with you
every step.
Thank you.
Mrs. Oppenheimer,
Jaz is in an extremely
volatile mental state.
He may say terrible,
terrible things.
I have no expectations,
Father.
I only hope that...
I hope that my visit
can help make my son whole.
Are you ready, Jaz?
Uh-huh.
- Hi.
- Mama.
Hello.
Well, we'll see you
at 12:00 noon tomorrow then.
Excellent.
Thanks again for everything.
Okay, goodbye.
Working late?
Well, yes.
I've been trying to do
what you suggested...
to separate the man
from the crime.
But I don't know, I see Hoyt
every day in the hospital ward,
and the two seem
to be intertwined.
There are many, many places
looking for qualified nurses,
Jessica.
- I could help you...
- Then we'd never see each other.
Look, I'm certainly not your
only reason for working in Oz.
Not my only reason,
no...
but I have
so few close friends.
Here, let me.
Please, stop that.
Stop what?
Stop touching me.
Oh, I'm sorry.
No, I'm sorry that I can't
be more to you.
What do you mean?
I took a vow
of celibacy.
Cel...
Do you...
How dare you!
I am a good
Catholic woman.
I have been
all my life!
- That's not what...
- How dare you have such thoughts!
My son was right
about you,
you are nothing but
a fuckin' slanty-eyed mongrel!
You do something for me.
Kill Timmy Kirk.
Ray, Ray.
- Hey.
- Listen to this.
After his mother left,
Jaz Hoyt really opened up.
He told me it was
the Reverend Cloutier
who ordered him to kill
Timmy Kirk the first time.
Well, how is
that possible?
Cloutier was
in the burn unit.
He was barely able to make
sounds, let alone speak.
Well, he says that Cloutier
appeared to him in his cell
looking completely normal.
An apparition?
Afterward, when he was
sent to solitary,
his biker buddies decided
to take revenge.
They went to the burn unit
and carried Cloutier away.
To where?
Well, Hoyt says
that's the one fact
he will reveal
only to you.
Where did they take
the Reverend Cloutier?
If I tell you,
the other bikers,
they'll kill us both.
Hoyt, I need to know.
Okay.
Here's a story
and it's true.
A male prisoner at the Muskegon
Correctional Facility in Michigan
sexually assaulted
the three-year-old daughter
of a woman
who was visiting him.
As a result, the state D.O.C.
Came up with the harshest,
most restrictive
visiting policies
of anywhere in the country,
which included the banning
of all minors,
even family members.
So you see,
one man's fuck up
fucked up
everybody else's happiness.
Redding, I have
to talk to you.
I feel guilty lying
to my brothers,
telling them
the book binding machinery
was destroyed by accident.
Did you get your check
from the insurance company?
So none of you all
lost any money,
which you sure as shit would
have when the company folded.
The money
is not the issue.
You committed a criminal act,
and I'm benefitting from it.
I have to do something.
Whatever you do
will destroy your reputation
with your brothers
over there.
Can you live with that?
You gonna tell me
what that was all about?
I was coming
to see you next,
to make
a full confession.
I'm all ears,
as they say.
The accident which destroyed
the book-binding machinery
was not an accident.
Burr Redding
is responsible.
Why jabber now?
Because I feel guilty.
I disgraced the memory
of Kareem Said.
Each night when I pray,
the words become more
and more hollow.
My soul is in peril.
I have to punish you.
Officer.
Take him back
to "Em City,"
put him in the cage.
I don't know what you're
talking about, McManus.
I haven't been anywhere near
that book-binding machinery.
Arif says
you sent someone.
Arif is delusional!
What's going on?
I'm afraid you're gonna have
to find a new foreman, Donna.
Redding's taking
an early retirement in solitary.
- You got no proof.
- Arif's word is good enough for me.
Get him out of here.
Uh, Tim...
I just signed
a new contract
with a major magazine
publishing house.
- I need Burr.
- I'm sorry.
- Is there a deal we can work out?
- No, no deals!
This is not a negotiation,
this is Oz!
Here's a story
and it's true.
The Wisconsin D.O.C. Has banned
all sexually explicit materials
received by prisoners
through the mail.
These include the swimsuit issue
of "Sports Illustrated,"
copies of "Vanity Fair,"
"Maxim" and "Rolling Stone,"
as well as various motorcycle
and fitness magazines.
Also banned was
a photograph
of Michelangelo's
Sistine Chapel.
The D.O.C. Felt
the nude paintings
that adorn
the Vatican's ceiling
could, quote,
"impede rehabilitation."
Chucky.
- Hey, hey.
- You make the call?
- Yeah, I made the call.
- And our mutual friend?
He gave the okay.
You know, Angelo and I have done
a lot of business together.
In fact, at every club
I've opened,
your nephew has been
like a silent partner.
I don't intend
to be so silent.
You need to mellow out,
big man.
You ever done "D"?
On me.
Pass it out
to your boys.
You see, Chulo,
it's as easy as
one, two, three,
"dial me a dago."
That's all right.
Where'd you get that?
From Torquemada.
Yo, you ever been
to one of his clubs?
Nope.
Never got past
the velvet ropes.
Huh-uh.
You better slow up
on those things, man.
I got into Dino's once.
The lights...
the sounds...
And the women.
Yo, chico,
settle down, man.
The guard's going
to put your ass
in the restraining chair.
Torquemada says he's going
to start giving destiny
to the fuckin' hacks,
too, man!
Whoo!
What's going on?
What's going on, man?
Where am I?
Oh, shit!
It's okay.
Don't touch me!
Don't, don't!
Don't finger me.
Don't, aah!
Get it off!
Get it off of me!
Yo!
All right, put him
on a pulse, stat.
Shake down!
You seem down.
Yeah.
A guy...
overdosed.
Close friend?
You know, in Oz,
you don't have friends.
You have people that
look the same as you.
Wolfgang had the Aryans...
and me...
well, I've mostly
been a loner.
Me, too.
Funny, I used to dread
coming here to visit Wolfgang,
but I don't anymore.
Merry Christmas,
motherfucker!
You've had your last meeting
with Cathy Jo Cutler.
The girl is being
talked to right now.
If you hurt her...
What? You'll get your drugged-out
Latino pals to come at me?
No, no, no.
Just you and me, carajo.
And ruin your chances
for parole,
all because of a cheap,
stupid cunt
who doesn't
know her place?
I had a little run-in
with the Aryans.
- We worked it out.
- Yeah, I can see that.
Listen, I know you're gonna
want to help, McManus,
but it'd be better for me
and for my parole
if this little incident
just disappeared.
Miguel...
Look, the reason
why we fought
ain't gonna
come back again.
Schillinger's
gonna see to that.
Whatever you do, it's gonna
make matters worse.
Okay.
But the good news is Luis Ruiz
has agreed to see you.
How did you do that?
Like everything else
in life, took persistence.
Ouch.
That looks painful, baby.
It's okay.
I've got a new shipment
of D-tabs coming in today.
- So?
- So, since Guerra went whacky,
hacks are making it
tougher
for me to move the merchandise
through the system.
I need your help.
Why me?
McManus trusts you.
Listen to me.
I don't know how many times
I'm going to have to tell you
until it actually penetrates that little
piata you've got for a brain.
I don't want any part
of your bullshit.
You're so fuckin' sexy.
Get your hands off
of me.
I like
straight boys best.
You know what?
Here's one straight boy
you ain't gonna be bending over.
Leave me alone!
Ugh, that's disgusting.
Now remember, if you
want to get paroled,
you've got to convince Ruiz
that you're sincere.
- Are you ready?
- Yeah.
Hello, Mr. Ruiz.
I don't have a lot
of time, Alvarez.
Say what you've
got to say.
Uh, Luis, we agreed that you two
would have a conversation,
that you would
spend a few minutes
- getting to know each other.
- Alone.
Yeah.
Okay, I'll be
right outside.
Mr. Ruiz...
I'm sorry I hit you
at the last parole hearing.
Why are you sorry?
I was an asshole...
deliberately
provoking you
to see if you could
handle yourself.
You failed.
I know.
- But...
- But what, Alvarez?
Sorry don't cut it.
"I've turned myself around,
I said three hail Marys."
Bullshit!
It's not bullshit.
I am improving.
I know you, Alvarez.
I grew up on
the same streets.
I've seen hot-headed dicks
like you
give every Latino
a bad name.
Well, the final score
is this...
You aren't
getting out of Oz,
not in three years,
not in 30...
not ever.
Oh, we'll still go
through the procedure,
so each time
your number comes up,
I can see how much
you've ripened.
I'm going to watch
you ripen until you rot.
That's right...
hit me again.
Go on.
Miguel?
Guess who's
your new roommate?
I knew you'd
be thrilled.
You want to help me
make my bed, sugar?
Hey.
Let me
tell you something.
You may have
wined and dined,
hired and fired,
bought and sold...
and I may have never done
nothing with my life...
but there is no way.
Hear me?
No way that I'm ever
going to be your bitch.
Miguel...
dumpling...
I don't want you
to be my bitch.
I have
a little confession.
I'm a virgin.
That's right.
I've never had sex
with men, women,
fish or foul.
Now, you're thinking,
"I've heard about the orgies."
At my clubs, yes,
my home, quite a scene...
but I myself never indulge.
I provide
a pleasurable environment...
the necessary ambrosia.
Then I let nature
take its course.
And I watch.
Lights out!
So, I don't want
to fuck you.
That would be
too common.
No, Miguel Alvarez...
I want to be you.
You want
To be me, huh?
You know what?
You're welcome to it.
I'm so tired.
I'm tired of trying.
I'm tired of the walls.
The lies.
The fear.
The death.
I'm so tired.
You got one
of those D-tabs?
Well...
you want
to party, baby?
You want
Keep them
D-tabs running.
Here's a story
and it's true.
The Oregon Legislature
passed a law
authorizing the State D.O.C.
To charge inmates
for costs associated
with their imprisonment.
We're talking such luxury items
as medical care,
administrative expenditures,
room and board,
which they estimate
costs $65.00 a day,
Or $25,000
a year per prisoner.
Given that Oregon pays
those incarcerated
only $10.80 a week
for work,
you could end up
leaving prison in debt,
and then be forced
to commit a crime, you know,
in order to make restitution
which, of course,
could lead you back to prison
where you'd have to pay.
Huh?
I guess you'd call
that a vicious circle.
Give it up, boys.
Sister Pete,
this is Noel Behn
from the Society
For Prisoners' Rights.
- Oh, hello.
- Good to meet you, Sister.
Come on in.
I asked Noel here to talk over
the Lemuel Idzik case.
What's to talk about?
He confessed to the murder
of Omar White,
and was sentenced to death.
The case should be reviewed
by the Appeals Court.
Why?
Idzik's lawyer slept through most of
the trial and the judge said nothing.
Justice by assembly line.
And Idzik made no protest?
The man's indifference
to his own fate suggests
some sort of
mental instability.
We'd like you
to determine the extent.
Well, you know me,
if there's a way to get somebody
out of death row, I will find it.
I wanted Omar White
to exterminate me.
When he refused,
I killed him,
knowing
I'd be sent here,
that the State would
do what Omar wouldn't.
So, all of this is an elaborate way
to commit suicide?
You could say that.
Is that why you
killed Kareem Said?
No.
That was revenge.
Revenge?
What did Kareem Said
do to you?
Lemuel, clearly you have
made a choice to die.
Don't go to your grave without
anyone understanding the reason.
What did Kareem do to you
that was so terrible?
He bought me
a cup of coffee...
at an outdoor cafe
in Istanbul.
That was before
he'd converted to Islam.
He was young,
arrogant, brilliant.
We had
a casual conversation,
during which he told me
about "Star-doom,"
about...
"Nightfall,"
you know, about how
the universe would end.
He was laughing
about it.
But his words...
cut into my heart.
His words...
ravaged my soul!
killed me!
And you killed him.
A little bizarre,
isn't it,
how one man's
chatty conversation,
how one man's laughter
can level someone else?
When he walked away
from that table,
he probably forgot
about what we discussed.
He certainly
forgot who I was.
It was a moment, you know,
one of many for him.
But for me it was the most
significant moment of my life.
And I can't help think
that by shooting Kareem Said,
I kept myself from doing
something far worse.
The death sentence
of Lemuel Idzik,
convicted of killing
a fellow inmate
at the Oswald Correctional Facility,
was overturned today.
What?
Motherfucker!
Come in.
Listen...
I know you want to die.
The irony is, in Em City
you probably will...
shanked, suffocated...
OD'd.
You know,
I was remembering
at Leo Glynn's funeral
why I built this place,
why I wanted to create
a better life for these guys.
It's because most likely
they'll never have
any other kind of life.
I've heard all about
your doomsday scenarios.
The sun will cool,
the planets will darken,
man will become extinct.
Well, I say,
okay, so what?
That won't happen for another
10 billion years or so.
We're alive now.
I mean,
we live in the now.
We have to grab the now
with both hands.
We have to move
through the light,
be warmed by the sun...
while we can.
And what about
the darkness?
Shit, I don't know.
I mean,
someone or something
set this whole thing
spinning.
I've got to believe that there's
a reason that we live...
and a reason
that we leave.
To believe is to live,
Mr. McManus.
Consider yourself lucky.
Some days I do.
Yo.
Dad's coming to visit?
Well, not visit...
exactly.
Hey, yo, Dad,
check it out.
Look at that, huh?
Look at me
and my new best friend.
Don't use me
to taunt your father.
Why not, man?
You hate him as much as I do.
No, I never
knew the man.
I just heard the stories
from your mom.
Well, she's just got
the abridged version.
I've got 35 years
of gory details.
You fuckin' asshole!
What's that word called
for when a son kills his father?
Patricide.
Yeah, patricide.
I like
the sound of that.
You always did
look good in gray.
What do you want,
slut?
I assume you've heard that Cyril's
latest appeal was denied.
Yeah, he fries on Sunday.
Sheamus, I want you
to visit him.
I want you to tell Cyril
how much you loved him.
You mean lie?
That's something you've
always been good at.
What do I get
in return?
The piece of mind
that your son
went to his death
with a little comfort.
I'll leave
the hand-holding to you.
He'll get
no comfort from me.
Forget the beatings.
Forget the verbal abuse
growing up.
Let's just focus on
the electroshock therapy, shall we?
Putting Cyril
through all that torment.
They said it was
the best treatment.
- I'm sure that was your concern!
- Fuck you!
You know, the saddest thing,
Sheamus,
is that you had
two wonderful sons
and you destroyed
them both.
When you die, when you're
looking for a little comfort,
there will be no one
there who gives a shit!
Why don't you go suck off
your nigger boyfriend?
- Hey, "Skillinger."
- Schillinger.
Sorry.
I got a job that
needs to be done,
and I got the cash
to pay for it.
Yeah, what job?
Kill Jahfree Neema.
No thanks.
I said I can pay.
Yeah.
And I said, no.
Why don't you get your boy
Ryan to do the deed?
- Come on, "Skillinger."
- It's Schillinger!
Just move the fuck on!
Seven-card bill.
Hello there,
"brother man."
O'Reily, I got no quarrel
with you.
Oh, yes, you do!
Hey!
Get off, get off!
Fuck, Jesus Christ!
We're almost finished.
There we go.
Okay.
Still, I'm keeping you
in until we take the stitches out.
Guess you're not as quick
as you used to be, huh, Dad?
Get the fuck
away from me.
Hey, pal, I got no interest
in changing your bed pan.
I just thought
you should know
that tomorrow's
Cyril's execution,
and so far the courts
refuse to step in.
Mm-hmm.
You really don't
give a shit, do you?
I don't give a shit about
anything I can't control.
Then you must not
care about anything.
Will you get
the fuck away from me?
- Ryan!
- Yo.
Come here, please.
You tell me you want to be
an orderly to help people?
Not him.
Hey, tomorrow Cyril's
going to die, all right?
You can trace back
all the shit that's come down,
and dear ole fuckin' Dad
is at the center!
Maybe so, but that still doesn't
justify what you're plotting,
Ryan, no more than it did when
you had Cyril kill my husband!
I watch you care
for your brother...
and you're so warm
and so sweet with him.
And then you get this
look in your eye...
this dangerous,
terrifying look.
There are moments
when I forgive you
for what you've done,
and others when I can't.
And I want
to forgive you, Ryan.
Help me to do that.
How?
Promise me that no harm
will come to your father.
Please.
Let's just both put
the past in the past.
Here's a story and...
it's true.
Last year, the United States Supreme Court
Justice Antonin Scalia
criticized the Catholic Church's
opposition to the death penalty.
He believes Catholic judges
who don't support capital
punishment should resign.
A devout Catholic himself,
Scalia has not demanded
judges who support
the Church's stand
on abortion should resign.
Lopresti told me
Dad got stabbed.
Don't worry about Dad.
Is he gonna be okay?
Dr. Nathan's taking
good care of him.
I like Dr. Nathan.
Me, too.
That man's
taking notes again.
I told you, that's because
this time you're gonna...
get that special
E.C.T. Treatment.
Right.
Finally.
Show time!
Any word
from the lawyer?
Oh.
See ya, Ryan.
Yeah, I'll see ya.
"Yea, though I walk
through the valley
of the shadow of death,
I will fear now evil,
for thou art with me.
Thy rod and thy staff,
they comfort me.
Thou preparest
a table before me
in the presence
of mine enemies.
Thou anointest
my head with oil."
"...and I will dwell in the house
of the Lord forever."
Mom?
Mom, what's happening?
Mom, what's...
What are they doing?
Ryan!
Ryan! Ryan!
Ryan.
I want to see Cyril.
You're too late.
I did the best
I could for him...
and you, growing up.
I tried!
But I never caught
a break.
Nothing ever went my way,
not one single time.
And the day that...
your sister...
died...
was the day I found out
that Tessie had cancer.
I was scared.
You were afraid?
Yeah.
I don't want to die.
Don't leave me, Ryan.
Please, son.
I don't want to die alone.
Please.
No worry,
I won't let
that happen.
I'm not going
anywhere, Dad.
Uh, is everybody ready?
James would, uh...
like to address
everybody.
Well...
what I have
to say is goodbye.
As of today, I'll be
transferring to Unit F.
You see,
I'm H.I.V. Positive.
Initially I blamed Cutler...
the guy who raped me.
But the truth is,
this is my fault...
because all the times
I had unprotected sex...
thinking I'd
never be the one
to catch my dick
in the zipper.
And even though I know
I'm going to live a long time...
I also know this didn't
have to happen.
Anyway...
I'm glad I got to spend
some time with you guys...
to see through
the window both ways.
What the fuck
are you doing here?
Believe me, Vern, I wouldn't have
come unless I absolutely had to.
How's the kike?
Irv's fine,
sends his love.
Dad's dying...
lung cancer.
All those Chesterfields
finally caught up with him.
He goes in and out
of consciousness,
but when he's awake,
he asks for you.
Horse shit.
You and I haven't been
in the same room for 20-odd years,
but I felt I should come, see
if you had a message for the old man.
A message?
I've hated him
all my life.
Well...
no reason
to stop now.
I have been corresponding
with Carrie's folks in Montana,
sending money for the baby.
They mailed me pictures
of Jewel's first birthday.
I thought you might like them.
Greta...
what I did,
shutting you out
after your wedding,
I had to.
And I despised you
for decades.
But now all
I can say is shalom.
Shalom, Vern.
Agent Taylor.
Mr. Beecher,
please sit down.
How's it going?
Fine.
How's your daughter
Holly?
You know,
the reason I ask is
one of the few joys
of this job
is reuniting kidnapped children
with their parents.
She's adjusting,
all things considered.
It must be tough on her,
though,
I mean, you out of prison one day,
back inside the next.
How would you like another
chance at being paroled?
I can make it happen.
How?
If you cooperate with us,
we'll see to it
that this latest charge
against you evaporates.
If this is about Keller
murdering Brice Tibbetts...
That's a dead issue!
But Keller did kill
two other men...
Byam Lewis and Mark Carocci.
And Keller's got an ego.
And I'm sure that in some point
in your time together,
he must have mentioned
something.
You mean come out
and admit his guilt?
No, he's too sly
for that.
But he suggested
his complicity.
Yes.
You see,
that could be enough...
if you and I figure out
how to phrase it correctly.
Like you did
with Jerry Heeken?
Heeken's a punk.
But you're a former lawyer
with children.
That Keller
fucked up the ass.
You're back in Oz
because of him.
You testify,
you go free.
He dies.
What is it about Keller,
Agent Taylor,
that obsesses you?
I want justice
for those murdered men.
Look, I may have
been disbarred,
but there's still enough
lawyer in me to know
that justice doesn't
come through deceit
by my rephrasing
what Keller said.
- He's guilty!
- I know.
Freedom, Beecher.
Tucking your little girl
Holly in at night.
- Oh, that's a nice touch.
- What's that?
Making sure he saw us
talking together.
Will you cooperate?
I have to
think about it.
Well, don't
take too long.
Now, that he's seen us
chatting together,
he'll start to sweat,
wondering whether you're
going to give him up or not.
To guarantee your silence,
he might do something nasty.
So, the little stroll wasn't
to scare him, it was to scare me.
Jesus, you cover
every angle, don't you?
I try.
Now, look, tonight's
your big premiere...
and Beecher's big finale.
I've got a little opening night
present for you.
Right before
your fight scene,
instead of handing
you the prop knife...
I'm gonna give you
a real one.
You get to stab
that sucker right there
on the stage in front
of everybody.
And all we say is, like,
"It was an accident."
So, if I tell Taylor
what he wants to hear,
I'll be home
in a matter of weeks,
while Keller heads back
to death row,
marking off the calendar.
And all you have to do
is subvert the truth.
The question is...
can you live the rest
of your life knowing
it was built on a lie?
But it's not
a lie exactly.
I mean,
Keller is guilty.
Yes, but it hasn't
been proven.
Your saying that
he said something
he didn't say
is not proof.
Tobias, we live
in a nation of laws,
some of which are
inspired
and some of which are
just lousy.
But we can't abandon
our moral code
whenever it's convenient.
Then we might as well
just open all the gates
of all the prisons.
I want to be
with my children.
My dear Tobias...
in all my years
sitting across that desk,
I have learned one thing...
Most people who come
to me with a problem
have already made up their minds
how they'll proceed.
They're just here hoping
I'll agree with them,
hoping I'll make them
feel better.
I can't do that
with you.
I gotta go.
Tonight's opening night
of "Macbeth."
I have to get ready.
- Miguel, are you okay?
- Hmm?
Just a little
opening night jitters,
A little
cotton-cotton mouth.
Okay. You set?
- Let's make theatrical history.
- All right!
- You guys ready?
- Yeah.
I'm so excited
I'm gonna bust my buttons.
Don't do that,
it's a rental.
All right, everybody,
we worked hard,
so now's the time
to have fun.
So, if you flub a line,
just keep going.
If you miss a cue,
don't panic.
I'm very proud
of all of you.
Break a leg.
Have a good show,
Beecher.
- Miguel, dim the house lights.
- Hmm?
Good evening, and welcome
to the premiere production
of the Oswald Players.
Before we begin, there are
a few changes in the program.
The second "weird sister"
will be played by Reggie Rawls
instead of Chico Guerra.
Banquo will be played
by Tom Smeeding
instead of
Agamemnon Busmalis.
And Norman Duttweiler
will play King Duncan
instead of Burr Redding.
I would also like to say
that warden Leo Glynn
was a great supporter
of bringing the arts to Oz.
So we dedicate tonight's
performance in his memory
and also to the memory
of Cyril O'Reily.
Thank you.
They spent some money
on this shit.
When shall we three
meet again?
In thunder,
lightning or in rain?
When the hurlyburly's done,
when the battle's lost
and won.
That will be
the set of sun.
- Where the place?
- Upon the heath.
There to meet
with Macbeth.
...everlasting bonfire.
Anon, anon!
I pray you,
remember the porter.
Hie thee hither,
that I may pour
my spirits in thine ear
and chastise with the valor
of my tongue
all that impedes thee
from the golden round
which fate
and metaphysical aid
doth seem to have
thee crowned withal.
What is thy name?
Thou'lt be afraid
to hear it.
No, though thy callest
thyself a hotter name,
than any is in hell.
My name's Macbeth.
Toby, I've got a plan
on a way to get Schillinger
out of your life forever.
I don't want to hear it.
Just give me my prop!
Thou was born of women,
but swords I smile at.
Weapons laugh to scorn,
brandished by man
that's of a woman born.
Turn!
Hell-hound, turn!
Of all men else
I have avoided thee.
But get thee back.
My soul is too much charged
with blood of thine already.
I have no words!
My voice is in my sword,
thou bloodier villain than terms
can give thee out.
Stick him, stick him!
You're a dead man,
sweetpea.
That cocksucker.
- Dr. Nathan!
- That motherfucker's dead!
As you know, we're investigating
what happened on the stage,
trying to determine
whether Schillinger's death
was accidental
or intentional.
Chris Keller says
he handed you the knife
just before your entrance.
How did a real knife
get on the prop table?
I don't know.
Suzanne Fitzgerald says
there were no problems
during the rehearsals.
Schillinger and Keller
seemed very friendly.
They were horsing around
and stuff.
What about Beecher?
He-he seemed fine.
Distant, but not in the least bit
confrontational.
All of which jibes
with the statement you made
immediately after
you stabbed Schillinger.
Do you have anything
to add at this time?
No, sir.
Okay.
We've decided to rule that
Schillinger's death was accidental.
You're coming back
to Em City.
Thank you.
Thank you, all.
What are you
doing here?
I asked Querns
to transfer me back.
I guess he
convinced McManus.
Even made us roomies.
- No.
- Yeah.
Nothing has changed,
Chris.
I know, you've got the top bunk
just like before.
I mean my feelings
haven't changed.
I'm gonna
go to McManus,
ask him to move me
to another pod,
Probably move me
to a jammed pod.
Toby, goddamn it.
Look, will you get it
through your head,
I don't want you
in my life.
After everything
I've done for you.
Yeah, like almost getting me
sent to death row.
If it weren't for me, you'd be in
the morgue, instead of Schillinger.
- Maybe.
- Yeah.
But if you think I got
any satisfaction
out of killing him,
you're wrong.
You don't know me
at all.
I don't know you?
I know you're free
of that Nazi fuck!
No, I'm not.
No more free than
I am of his two sons,
or Metzger...
or Cathy Rockwell.
Chris, after six years
in this place...
I'm not sure about
anything anymore.
Heaven, justice,
truth.
The only thing
I believe in is life.
Every life is precious.
Not just yours or mine,
but every single person
on the planet who's breathing,
their lives are precious.
And the loss
of a single life,
even in Oz,
is my loss, too.
Well, that's bullshit.
The only thing
that matters is you and me.
I don't expect you
to understand.
You kill for sport.
I don't understand?
I'm not the one
who got here by accident, pal.
I kill because I have to.
I kill what stands
in my way...
like the Aryans.
What?
What about the Aryans?
That they're no threat
to us anymore.
I took care of that.
How? How'd you
take care of it?
- Never mind, kiss me.
- Wait.
- Answer me this first, okay?
- Hmm?
I want you
to be honest, okay?
Did you purposely
fuck up my parole?
Toby, I couldn't face
the rest of my life
living in here
without you.
Don't you see?
I did what I did out of love.
If you really love me,
then leave me alone.
I can't.
Listen to me.
I loved alcohol.
I loved heroin.
I had to put them behind me
because they were poison.
Death.
You are death.
Let me live.
I can't.
Motherfucker!
Toby, I love you.
Beecher, don't!
No! No!
No!
God is a funny fellow,
Sister.
See, I decided this morning
to cooperate with the F.B.I.
- To help them convict Keller.
- Oh?
And now,
with Keller dead...
that opportunity
is gone.
And with it
my chance for freedom.
In fact, I may be facing
the death penalty
for Keller's murder.
You didn't push him,
did you?
No.
Well, let's hope this time
the truth works for you.
You know, he said he did
what he did out of love.
Oh, love is used
as an excuse
for so many things.
No.
He really did
love me, Sister.
Yes.
And I loved him.
When God was designing
the universe...
why did he make something
so wonderful
so fucking painful?
I think he thought
we could handle it.
Beecher!
I'm going to move you
back to Unit J.
I'm concerned
about the Aryans
taking revenge on you
for Schillinger.
I said the same thing
to Keller, and he said,
"Don't worry,
I've handled the Aryans."
What did he mean
by that?
Hey, Andenaur.
Check it out.
You've got a package.
Hmm, no name...
no return address.
What the fuck
is this?
I don't know.
- They're all dead?
- Yes, plus two C.O.'s.
- From what?
- I'm not sure.
But it could be any number
of toxins or chemicals.
I cordoned off the area.
I've got to tell you,
- this is way beyond my expertise.
- What do we do?
Call the state
bio-terrorism unit
and clear out
the entire complex fast!
Proceed immediately
to Level One.
Emergency evacuation.
Where are we going
to take them?
Beats the shit
out of me.
All I've been told is
the move is temporary.
We'll be back someday.
Emergency evacuation.
Proceed immediately
to Level One.
Come on, move it!
Come on, ladies,
let's move!
Let's go!
Come on, let's go!
Move to the back
of the bus first.
of the bus.
Count!
A lot of people thought we'd
never re-open "Emerald City."
- I killed a man.
- I know.
- Fuck you.
- Help!
Lights out,
O'Riely.
Settle down!
Officer!
You are to follow routine.
We tell you when to sleep,
when to eat,
when to piss.
So, what have we learned?
What's the lesson for today,
for all the never-ending days
and restless nights in Oz?
That morality is transient?
That virtue cannot exist
without violence?
That to be honest
is to be flawed?
That the giving
and taking of love
both debases
and elevates us?
That God or Allah or Yahweh
has answers to questions
we dare not even ask?
The story is simple.
A man lives in prison
and dies.
How he dies...
that's easy.
The who and the why
is the complex part...
the human part...
the only part
worth knowing.
Peace.