Here are some scary facts
about impotence:
10 to 20 million Americans
suffer from it,
85% due to physical causes
not related to the penis:
10% suffer because
of psychological reasons:
And scariest of all, for 5%
of the men who are impotent,
the cause is unknown.
Hey.
Jesus.
Don't do this
to me, Vern.
You guys are
all I got in here.
It's not my choice,
James.
We've got a charter
we gotta follow.
You know that charter
better than anybody.
I asked the fuckin' dentist.
He said he put white man's
gums in my mouth.
- White.
- Really?
'Cause that bruise Dr. Faraj
planted on your cheek is blue.
That tells me you didn't get
the answer you were looking for.
Tomorrow you're moving
to another cell.
There's Robson.
You were right, lmam.
Allah has punished him
for his sins.
- How's the mouth?
- Arif.
Fuck you.
Robson.
Despite all you done,
my heart goes out to you.
God is trying
to teach you something.
Please be smart
enough to learn.
Yeah.
He's saying my friends
will take me back.
I'll make them
take me back.
Oh, lookie here,
my step-brother.
Feels good talking
with a black man's gums, don't it?
I need a shitload
of tits, now.
You? All that Aryan drug-free bullshit
just bullshit, ain't it?
Will you shut your fucking
corn-trap and hook me?
- Or I can take my cash elsewhere.
- All right, man.
Shit! Guard! Officer!
One of the physical causes
of impotence
is lack of frequent
spontaneous erections.
In other words,
you can't get it up...
because you
don't get it up.
Because you can't
get it up,
because you
don't get it up...
either way,
you're fucked.
I can't get it up.
Miguel Alvarez
is up for parole again.
So what? He'll just get rejected,
same as last time.
Maybe not.
Tim, come on.
With all the shit he's pulled,
the board's not gonna let him go free.
Well, Alvarez
is a changed man.
He's really trying
to stay out of trouble.
Bullshit. Look, I know he did a good job
training the seeing-eye dog,
but one pooch hardly balances
out his criminal record.
Well... I'm writing a letter
to the board recommending parole.
Alicia Hinden, who ran the program,
is gonna do the same thing.
And if Ray Mukada were here,
he would too.
Tim, do you honestly
believe Miguel Alvarez
is ready to rejoin society?
Six months ago
the dink was in solitary
smearing shit
on his cell wall.
I know there's been bad blood
between you and Alvarez
almost since
the day he arrived.
What are you saying,
my judgment is clouded? Fuck you.
- Have you spoken to him since?
- No!
- Don't you think you owe him that?
- Owe him?
Not warden to prisoner,
man to man.
If a person's
trying to change,
- shouldn't we acknowledge that?
- Not in Alvarez's case.
- Leo...
- No, damn it, no, hell, no!
You file your fuckin' letters
of recommendation, okay?
I'll call Steve Dawkins myself
and put an end to this bullshit.
Thanks for setting up
the parole hearing, McManus.
To tell you
the truth, Miguel,
these parole board
hearings...
your chances for release
are a long shot.
No, no, no, no.
I got a good feeling.
I got my "A" game on.
God, it'd be great just to get away
from Oz, you know?
I could see Maritza.
She's been let out of Parker Women's.
She's got a job. You know,
she's got her life on course.
Shit, maybe I can have
another baby, you know?
I just gotta let
the parole board people
understand that I can do that
too, you know?
That I know in my heart
that I'm ready.
It's a pleasure to meet you guys,
you know.
Yeah, my... dad
and my... grandfather
were both
incarcerated in here.
- Excuse me?
- Alvarez, what are you doing?
I'm just practicing my answers
for the parole board hearing.
Count!
- Hey!
- Hey, pretty boy, man!
Hey, Charlie Brown.
Maritza.
Maritza, mi amor.
- Fuck you.
- Ooh, careful, Miguel.
You wouldn't want a smudge
on that record this late in your parole.
Shut the fuck up!
You know what would be
a terrible tragedy?
Just before you got out,
if Maritza...
has some kind
of accident.
You hurt her...
you're dead.
You fuck with my parole,
Oh, you're so fuckin' beautiful
when you're angry.
All right, Mr. Alvarez, that was
a very lovely speech you just made.
But now we'd like
to ask you some questions.
Mr. Dawkins, you can
ask me whatever you want.
You were convicted
of beating a 75-year-old man,
then cutting his face,
all because his car scraped yours.
Yeah, I wasn't
myself that day.
Once you were here in Oswald,
you cut your own face
and later tried to hang yourself
in your cell.
Were you yourself
either of those days?
Last year you masterminded
an escape from Oswald.
I didn't mastermind
an escape.
Busmalis was digging a tunnel
and I was fearing for my life...
You were one of the major
leaders in the riot
and hurt a number of people,
including an officer, Joseph Mineo.
He was making
a move on me...
Later, you poked out the eyes
of another officer, Eugene Rivera.
Then you murdered
two fellow prisoners,
Carlo Ricardo
and a Jorge Vasquez.
So, my question is,
what the fuck
makes you think
we should set you free,
you little prick?
Knock it off!
Let him go, Alvarez!
Fuck!
This is fuckin' bullshit!
I'm fuckin' tellin' them...
I'm trying to tell them
how I got rehabilitated.
Fuckin' bullshit!
He asked me how I think
I changed in all this bullshit.
I'm talking to him and I'm
trying to explain how I changed.
- Are you listening to me?
- I gotta talk to you about my trial.
He fuckin' cuts me off.
He just cuts me off.
- I'm lonely. I'm afraid!
- Are you listening to me?
Montgomery is a cunt
that got what he deserved. Cunt!
Hey, that C.O. Had no right to shove
my face in shit. Get me out of here.
Get me the fuck
out of here!
- I'm afraid.
- Cunt!
Get me the fuck
out of here.
McManus!
It's quittin' time.
You promised
to buy me a drink.
I really need
that fuckin' drink.
- Let's go.
- I'm sorry. I'm gonna have to pass.
- I don't want to leave Pancamo.
- You know...
I've been dumped by a lot
of women for a lot of guys,
- but never one in a coma.
- He could die, Tim.
It's my fault.
A man comes into my E.R.
With a non-life-threatening stab wound,
gets infected
and goes into toxic shock.
I didn't take proper care
of him before
but I sure as hell am not
gonna let him die alone.
- How about a cup of coffee?
- Okay.
There you go.
You ever met
my wife...
my ex-wife,
Eleanor O'Connor?
Our paths
have yet to cross.
We've been divorced
five years.
When I was first offered
the job at Oswald
to build Em City,
to fulfill a lifelong dream,
she didn't want
to trail along.
She had this great job,
she didn't want to leave, so...
I just walked out,
and for five years
I've carried
the guilt of that.
I mean, every time
something goes haywire,
I just think,
you know, "Fuck.
I could be with Ellie
and maybe by now
we'd have
a couple of kids."
Don't talk to me about regret.
I own the patent.
Well, my point is...
today I was
walking in solitary
and I was surrounded
by all my mistakes,
and my head
was gonna explode.
But then I thought
about Omar White,
about how hard it was
to turn him around.
But we did it.
I mean, we can't
save them all, Gloria,
but if we can
save just one,
that's enough.
And I want
to save Pancamo.
Well...
thanks for the coffee.
Now, I'm gonna
get myself a real drink.
Good night.
- I'm gonna snap the faggot's head off!
- Take his head off!
Prisoner #02C773:
Wolfgang Cutler:
Convicted February 20th, 2002:
Murder
in the first degree:
Sentence: Life imprisonment
without the possibility of parole.
I want into
the Brotherhood.
You know the deal,
Wolfgang.
You gotta demonstrate
your fearlessness.
By whacking somebody?
Who?
Killing a nigger's
always nice.
The higher up the better.
Kareem Said.
I like the way
you think.
- Omar, you ready for some hot gossip?
- Hmm?
I overheard the Aryans
in the gym.
That new guy
Wolfgang Cutler,
he was bragging
to the others
about how he was
gonna kill Said.
Yo, you Cutler?
How the fuck
did you get back here?
That don't matter.
Look, I came because I heard
a rumor and shit, all right?
Just stay away
from Said, all right?
No, no, whatever you got brewing,
just stop it, okay?
I don't know what the fuck
you're talking about.
And get the fuck
out of here.
I'm trying to be
diplomatic here, okay?
And I'm telling you,
get the fuck out of here!
Look, I've been
pretty good lately.
You don't want
to see me bad, okay?
- You touch Said...
- And what?
Nigger,
you gonna cry?
Fuck you!
Hey...
- Motherfucker, motherfucker.
- Fuck.
- Motherfucker.
- Fuck you.
Stay away.
You motherfucker,
I'm going to fuck...
I'll kill you,
fuckin' black motherfucker.
I'm telling you,
don't touch Said!
Stay away!
Stay the fuck away
from Said!
Stay the fuck away.
Stay, stay the fuck...
Oh shit, what's that?
What's that, Cutler?
Cutler?
Cutler...
Hey, hey.
Come on, man.
Hey, Cutler.
Cutler!
Come on, man,
don't do this to me.
Don't fuckin' die.
Oh, shit!
Fuck!
Oh, shit, fuck.
Fuck! I almost
killed the motherfucker!
I mean, look, it's not
like I started anything!
The motherfucker was
all up in my shit, man...
taunting me! I don't know
what the fuck happened!
Omar, slow down.
Who are you talking about?
- Cutler's getting ready to jack you!
- Wolfgang Cutler.
The motherfucker's
still alive, okay?
In a second, the hacks
are gonna be up here
punching in my fuckin' ass!
Shit! Fuck, fuck!
Omar, you follow me,
you do not stop, you understand?
Let's go.
But I saved him, both of them,
I mean, Cutler and Said.
What do you want?
Do you want a fucking medal?
You almost
killed a man.
Do you understand that,
God damn it?!
I give you
10 second chances,
this is what
I get in return!
I bend over
backwards for you,
as a result, a man
ends up almost dead.
You want me to be
fuckin' happy about that?
McManus, it is
not that simple. Ms...
Yes, it is that
fuckin' simple, Said.
Don't you be looking
to her for help.
I've made my decision.
The rule book
says solitary.
I'm playing by
the rule book this time.
And if he had done this
to protect you instead of me,
would you be
sending him away?
Shut up, or you're
going with him.
McManus!
McManus! McManus!
That wasn't
for you, Ellie.
No, no, that
was genuine rage.
I remember it well.
Tim...
you think
I divorced you
because you wanted to come
to Oswald and build Emerald City,
but that's not true.
You want to know
what made me leave?
Your relentless,
unflappable,
never-say-never
idealism.
You would have
preferred me cynical?
No!
You want to
save the world
and when you
realize you can't,
you crucify yourself
and everyone around you.
This nonsense,
where it's up to you
to change everything for the better...
your wife,
your prisoners,
whoever else until
we all fit your ideals.
Isn't it time to see that
for the pride that it is?
- Go on.
- No.
I'll just go.
Minister?
Look, whatever it is
that you want...
it can wait.
What I want is for you
not to blame yourself
for what happened
to Omar White.
Well, like I said,
what you want...
can wait.
? Amazing grace?
? How sweet the sound?
? That saved a wretch?
? Like me...?
Will you
shut the fuck up?!
? I once was lost?
? But now I'm found?
? Was blind
but now I see.?
Lmpotence can also be
the result of depression,
marital discord, job stress,
financial worries.
That's right, a little salary
can make a hard man soft.
A drop in the DOW can
diminish rising expectations.
That was my son.
Alex Jr.'s days
away from death.
Gosh, Bob, what are
you gonna do?
What can I do?
I'll wait for the call
that tells me that my
grandson's life is over.
- No, you gotta see him.
- How?
He's in intensive care.
He can't even
leave the hospital,
let alone visit a prison.
- Then you go to him.
- They'd never let me.
Why not? McManus has been
helpful in the past.
Go.
Ask him.
You can cuff me,
shackle me,
gag me if you have to,
just let me see Alex,
make eye contact
so that he knows
that his granddad loves him.
I remember when
you took up that collection
to take him
to Adventure Country.
That trip meant
a lot to him.
It did to me too.
Not only you wanting
to raise the cash,
but then actually rallying
these dinks to help you.
So... may I go?
Yes.
And gagless,
shackleless even.
I'll arrange
the visit today.
- Are you traveling with me?
- No.
Handing you off
at the door.
I was once sentenced
to die, you know?
I remember
something about that.
A power failure shut down
the electric chair.
My death was
commuted to life...
legally.
I only wish there were laws
that could do the same for Alex.
But only God can grant
that kind of reprieve.
- Chug.
Chug-a-chug, work it!
This is the best
"Miss Sally" ever.
Mail call!
What you got
for me, Vern?
Mr. Schillinger.
Stinkin' with
cheap perfume.
It's from Norma.
Hey, Fiona,
would you do me a favor?
This letter is
from my former fiancée.
Would you mind
reading it to me?
Make me kind of feel like
she's here in the room.
Hey, we all
got our trip.
"Dear Agamemnon,
I got very depressed
after 'Miss Sally'
- was canceled and I lost my job."
- Poor thing.
"But the one thing that
hasn't been canceled
is my love for you,
and I'm coming to visit on the 15th
to explain why I never showed up
on our wedding day.
If you can find it
in your heart,
please see me.
Love always, Norma."
- Ah, well, ain't that sweet?
- The 15th.
That's today.
- Norma!
- Hello, Agamemnon. Wait!
Surprise.
Hey, Bob,
how'd the visit
with little Alex go?
Tired.
Guess what happened
while you were gone.
I'll tell you tomorrow.
If you want, we can talk
more about little Alex.
I have nothing
else to say.
I'm on the death watch.
I fold.
Bob, you've gotta
get some rest.
Did you see that?
See what?
He's gone.
Count!
Your grandson
was stable,
but the storm...
Well, the electricity
went out for a minute
and the surge
scrambled
his equipment.
- And?
- I'm sorry.
Alex died.
I need help.
Hey.
I'm real sorry
about little Alex.
You know,
you try to prepare
for a death...
but always secretly
you believe
there's a chance
that the doctors were wrong,
that they'll find a cure,
and that as long as
he's alive, there's time.
So while you think you're steeling
yourself for the sorrow,
all you're really doing
is waiting on the miracle.
Which is why when death comes,
it's so horrible
because you realize...
you weren't
prepared at all.
But you knew last night.
On some level.
30-some years ago
it was a power outage
that saved me from execution,
but last night
the electricity finally came back
on to finish the job.
Except so much
time had passed
that my grandson
was now in the chair.
I never really
liked this hat.
But now that he's passed away,
I understand this hat.
This was my grandson
at his most alive.
So I'm gonna let
Rebadow go to the funeral.
Jesus...
after 35 years he gets out
twice in one week,
and all for
the worst reasons.
Holy shit.
I'm back.
I decided...
to give Rebadow his money.
I decided he should
help his grandkid.
New studies show
that even Viagra,
which is supposed to help
a fella get an erection,
can sometimes cause problems
in young, sexually active men
who use the drug
recreationally.
You see, if an erection
lasts longer than six hours,
the blood supply gets
cut off permanently.
Of course,
after six hours, you know,
maybe you don't
give a shit.
You know
what I mean.
Your father and I went
to Adam Guenzel's funeral.
When I saw Olivia walking down
the center aisle of the church,
so crippled up
with arthritis,
moving so slowly, each step
measured, supported by a cane,
my heart...
my heart broke.
You know, when you
were first arrested,
Olivia Guenzel was one
of the few friends who stood by us,
and there we were,
burying her grandson
who caused her so much...
shame.
I'm sorry.
I... couldn't
protect him.
I know.
I know you
did your best.
Funny, when I
hugged Olivia,
when I saw the grief
in her eyes,
I thought...
"Good.
Now you really do
understand."
God forgive me.
I almost forgot...
Holly sent you this.
Happy Valentine's Day.
- Winthrop...
- Get away from me, Beecher.
- I need to talk to you.
- I gotta get this food to Schillinger
- or he'll kick my ass.
- I've been where you are.
- You don't have to be his bitch.
- Yeah, right.
- I can help you.
- Like you helped Adam?
No fuckin' thanks.
Sister, at our
last interaction,
you were asking
about Adam Guenzel,
about the circumstances
surrounding his rape,
and I kept silent
at the time
because of...
because of
my own involvement.
Now I think, had I spoken
and told what I knew,
- Adam might still be alive...
- Beecher.
Vern, you know
the rules.
No interruptions.
Go on.
Yes, go on.
Though it's too late
to save Adam,
- I think being honest might...
- Might what?
We're all getting along
so well these days.
- Vern!
- No.
He starts making
wrongful accusations,
all the good work
you've done here will unravel.
You don't want that,
Sister, do you?
I want him
to speak his mind.
I'm not gonna sit here
and listen to this horseshit.
- That's your choice. Officers.
- Beecher, tread very carefully.
You tell
the truth, Tobias.
Just tell the truth.
Take Said to his unit.
Beecher stays here.
In accordance with
D.O.C. Regulations,
this committee has
given you a fair hearing.
We have listened to testimony
from witnesses and examined evidence.
We have determined
the following:
One, that you conspired to and engaged
in the rape of Adam Guenzel:
Two, that you conspired to and engaged
in the rape of Franklin Winthrop.
We find you guilty
of these charges
and have decided that you will
be transferred immediately
to solitary confinement
for an undetermined length of time.
Nice color.
Chris?
- How'd the trial go?
- Fantastic.
A jury of my peers found me guilty
of murder in the first degree.
- Oh, God.
- My idiot lawyers are going to appeal,
but he doesn't
hold out much hope.
I go back...
Thursday to the courthouse
for sentencing,
and more than likely...
I'll get the death penalty.
Well, I'll do ev...
I'll do everything
I can to help.
Show me your tits.
Don't do that.
I'm sorry.
I guess I'm
in a bad mood.
It's not every day
you get sentenced to death.
Weird.
All of these years
my penis has
dominated my life,
forced me to go in
whatever direction...
it chose.
Now I want to share
my love with someone and...
I never will.
You know, there are people
out there who are fighting
against the return
of the death penalty.
Tell that
to Shirley Bellinger.
You know
on the ride over here,
I was thinking about
how I wanted to die.
Well, there's only
two choices now:
Lethal injection
and the electric chair.
I want the chair.
I want the juice.
I want to go out
on a charge.
Christopher Keller
was convicted today
in the brutal slaying
of Brice Tibbetts.
Tibbetts was tortured, sodomized,
and murdered in July of 1997.
Keller, who faces
the death penalty,
will be sentenced on Thursday
by Judge Grace Lema.
Keller is suspected of committing
at least two similar murders.
Fuck. I have to
go see him.
May I remind you
of your promise to yourself
- never to speak to Keller again?
- Yeah.
The great thing about breaking
a promise to yourself
is only one person gets hurt,
and I can live with my guilt
a shitload easier than I can live without
ever seeing Keller.
No, this is wrong.
How is love wrong,
Kareem?
In whatever form it takes,
how is love wrong?
Especially here in Oz,
where there's
so little of it.
You and I,
we love each other.
You stabbed Schillinger
and Robson for me.
But the Aryans say that any
sort of love between the races
is a perversion.
Who decides these things?
Who chooses which
love is permissible?
God.
The God I worship...
Ioves everybody, and he
created a universe full of
different kinds of people
sharing different kinds of love.
Allah says
"Man..."
Don't quote scripture
to me, Kareem.
You know
what's gonna happen
when you go
and see Keller again.
I'm not gonna fuck him.
I'm just gonna
let him know I care,
that he's not
totally alone.
I think Allah would
approve of that.
Here you go, Keller,
your brand-new home.
They say the ghost of Shirley Bellinger
still haunts this cell.
- Oh, yeah?
- When the moon is full,
you could still
smell her vagina.
You're a very funny guy
there, Lopresti.
You should think
about doing comedy.
Hey, how you doing?
Chris.
You got mail.
Diabetes,
multiple sclerosis,
Alzheimer's,
Parkinson's,
high blood pressure,
obesity,
aging can all
cause impotence.
So can riding a bicycle.
You put that hard seat
between your legs,
there may be nothing else
hard between your legs
for a long, long time.
- Suck my fucking...
- Quiet down!
Come on, man.
Get up.
- Leave it.
- No.
Leave it.
Fuckin' retard.
Hang in there, Cyril.
- Where is this?
- End of the line.
I'm not supposed
to be here.
Where's Jericho?
- Relax.
- Where's Jericho?!
- Jericho!
- Oh!
- Ryan!
Go, retard boy!
Ryan!
- Ryan!
- Wow, bitch, let it out!
I'm not
supposed to be here!
I'm not supposed
to be here!
No!
- Finally the S.O.R.T. Team had
to subdue your brother. - Christ.
I gave him some Haldol
to calm him down,
but as we learned
from previous episodes,
it's just
a stopgap measure.
It's never gonna be
a long-term solution
to Cyril's
violent episodes.
We don't need
a long-term solution.
The judge has set
his execution for next month.
- What?
- Why are you acting so surprised?
He was found guilty
of the murder of Li Chen.
The punishment is death.
Look... you're gonna
have to discuss with Cyril
the way he wants to die, either
the electric chair or lethal injection.
Lethal injection.
I want Cyril just to doze off
and go to sleep.
There's more
to it than that.
The drugs they inject into
his body first paralyze him.
I don't want
to hear the details, okay?
It's not okay,
Ryan.
Up to this point you've resisted
all our attempts to help your brother.
You should know
what his last moments will be like.
- Can I see him?
- Not yet.
I'll allow a visit
once he's settled down.
Take O'Reily
back to Em City.
The guilt or innocence
of Cyril O'Reily is not at issue here.
The question is whether
the Eighth Amendment
of our Constitution,
which protects us
from cruel
and unusual punishment,
will also protect
Cyril O'Reily,
whose IQ,
by the way, is 51.
That's one
of the lowest IQs
of any condemned
prisoner on record.
As a mother, I appeal,
I plead to all of the other mothers
and fathers out there
to stop the state from committing
this monstrous act.
Governor Devlin refused
to comment on the demonstration
held outside
the capitol building.
You know, Meehan...
you can hold a million
press conferences,
but you're still won't
be able to save my brother.
If I had that attitude,
you'd be right.
But I'm going to prove
you wrong, Mr. O'Reily.
I'm going to show you
the power of prayer,
of hope, and faith
in the Almighty.
Okay, well while you're at it,
why don't you suck my dick?
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
Father Meehan!
Are you here
for a lesson?
No, I was the only seminarian
booted off the choir.
The prefect said,
"Your voice is
an offense to God."
You were magnificent
on your television press conference.
- Oh, thanks.
- A veritable firebrand.
Well, I've had
a lot of practice.
I want to talk
to you about Ryan.
Ever since I came to Oz,
I've been trying to reach him.
Well, I know that he and Cyril
were brutalized by their father,
and that's enough
to dent any boy's psyche.
But my gut feeling is
there's something more,
that your son
is hiding something,
some...
some naked truth,
some deeper pain.
I was wondering
if you knew anything.
My greatest regret, Father,
is abandoning my child.
He was just a little baby
when I left,
and until a few months ago,
I've had no contact with him.
Is there anyone
I could ask?
Well, certainly
not his father,
but maybe Brenda
his aunt.
Thank you very much,
Brenda.
Yes, we're doing
everything we can for Cyril.
Right.
Well, keep praying.
Lockdown, lockdown!
Ryan, tell me
about Carolyn.
What the fuck
are you talking about?
Carolyn,
your little sister.
She's dead,
end of story.
Then don't
tell me the end,
tell me the beginning,
the middle and all...
Who the fuck told you
about Carolyn?
That doesn't matter.
Just tell me your memory of her.
No.
She died.
She was barely six months old,
fell out of her crib,
and broke her neck.
Why you doin' this?
Well, I've seen
how you love your brother,
how you're
protective of him,
yet you're willing
to let him die,
and I was
wondering why.
I thought I told you
this before.
Death is better
than any day in Oz.
Isn't that what you priests
are always preaching,
the upside
of "life everlasting"
and all that fucking
Catholic nonsense?
Did you have any responsibility
for Carolyn's death?
Were you taking care of her
when she fell?
No, I'm not
talking about this.
I haven't spoken
about my little sister
with anyone my entire life,
not even Cyril,
and I'm not about
to start with you!
So, that's what happened,
you think you killed her.
No.
- So, what did happen?
- Shut up!
Ryan,
now is the time
to speak the truth.
You've been carrying this burden
on your back for far too long.
Whatever you say to me
will stay right here between us.
- No, no.
- Like in confession.
Now, you can finally say
what you want to say since Carolyn died.
No, fuck you!
God damn it!
Fuck!
- Don't.
- Come on.
- Please, stop.
It's all right.
God loves you.
I went to a priest,
and I told him the truth
and he didn't
believe me.
And she was so small.
It's my little sister.
I know.
God loves you.
Suddenly I'm famous.
I done six interviews,
newspapers and TV,
ever since that nonsense
with your brother started.
I gotta admit, I'm getting
kind of used to the attention.
The guys at Kelsey's have been
buying me rounds every night.
There's this broad,
sits at the end of the bar,
she's been
flirting with me.
I might
just fuck her.
You gonna see Cyril
while you're in the building?
Yeah, yeah.
I guess I oughta.
I don't know what the fuck
I'm gonna say to that boy.
- Tell him you love him.
- Oh, yeah, right.
You ever told
Cyril that, Dad?
Cyril or anyone? Ma?
Tessie when
you were married?
Have the words "I love you"
ever crossed your lips?
Because I never
heard them, not once.
Don't start
with your whining.
I'm sorry, I forgot
how sensitive you are.
You asked me to come,
I'm here. State your business.
I wanna talk
about Carolyn.
Carolyn?
What about her?
I want to talk about
the day she died.
I remember her crying,
you know,
non-stop for what
seemed like hours.
Tessie couldn't
get her quiet.
You were drunk
and in a foul mood.
- Sit down!
- Fuck you!
You sit...
or I finish
telling my story to a cop.
Carolyn was crying
and you took her
from Tessie's arms
and you put your hands
around her and you shook her
and you shook her and you
shook her until she stopped,
until she went limp
like a ragdoll.
She fell
out of her crib.
No.
I was there, Dad.
I was in the doorway.
I saw what happened.
You were just a kid.
What the fuck did you
know about anything?
Think my old man didn't beat me,
that fuckin' scumbag?
My life has been
nothing but shit
since the day
I was born,
and I didn't have no brother
to lean on like you did.
I've been alone
my whole fuckin' life,
and soon...
you will be too.
I'll never tell
anyone the truth
about what happened
with Carolyn.
That's between you and me.
But, Dad...
you better pray
to Jesus Christ Almighty himself
that I never get out
of this place.
Because when I do...
I will kill you.
And...
I brought you
some company.
- Jericho.
- Yeah.
Hiya, buddy.
Did you miss me?
I missed you.
Hey, Sister.
Look, I want you to know
that I've decided to become
totally selfish, okay?
I'm not gonna lose
Cyril from my life.
I'm gonna help save him,
and whatever you need me to do,
I'm there 100%.
I am so glad
to hear that.
Hey, little brother...
- Who loves you?
- You do.
Fucking-A.
Drugs can
cause impotence.
Marijuana,
heroin, steroids.
So does alcohol
and tobacco.
72% of men who smoke
20 or more packs a year
suffer from
penile artery clot.
Anybody got an ashtray?
Just because I'm sending
you back to Emerald City
doesn't mean
you're completely well
or that you can stop
taking care of yourself again.
- Uh-huh.
- Don't "uh-huh" me, Augustus,
or I'll come and clean your
catheter myself.
You think it's funny.
You know, when I heard that
you was healthy again, man,
and that you was coming back, I kicked
myself with joy. Let me give you a hand.
I don't need
no help, man.
Man, you know I always liked you,
Augustus. I always respected you.
Cut the shit, man,
what you want? What?
You know Burr got all lathered up
when you went down, all right?
Blamed me for
getting you smack.
You did.
You gave me the tits.
Yeah, I know.
Burr ain't got to
know that, though.
He thinks Guerra
gave you the shit,
so our little peace treaty
with the spics,
it kind of fell apart.
You know, Burr and Morales
got into a little fandango,
now they both
in the hole.
If Burr finds out you was
the one that gave it to me,
- he's gonna skin your fat hide.
- Yeah.
Don't worry, son,
I ain't gonna rat you out.
I wanted those drugs.
It don't matter who gave it to me.
- I'm gonna tell Burr that.
- All right.
Thanks, man.
You know, if I was a girl,
you'd get tongue.
If you was a girl, son,
you'd be butt-ass ugly.
Why you gotta
be all like that, man?
So I was sitting in my office
watching the two of you
when the fight broke out.
Now, I'm not naive
enough to think
that you're gonna tell me
what the argument was about.
You're not naive
enough to think that I'll let it go.
So, in order for me to not send
both your asses to Gen Pop,
we're gonna agree,
once again,
no violence
between you.
- I agree.
- Redding?
Sure.
That was a little less than
enthusiastic, but okay.
You can go.
So it was Morales that gave
Augustus the drugs, right?
Morales or one of his stooges,
am I right?
Gospel truth,
I don't know.
I thought it was the spics,
but maybe I was wrong.
Then who?
Well, like I said before,
Augustus will give it
to me straight.
You should've let me talk
to him in the first place.
Isn't that touching?
Look, I know I didn't
do right by you guys,
siding with that nigger,
muscling you
out of the tit trade.
- I'm sorry, okay?
- Sorry?
- You think sorry's gonna be enough?
- Mario, please.
I think you'll find that
we Sicilians are misunderstood,
that at heart...
we can be
very forgiving people.
Oh, yeah?
And what's that
forgiveness gonna cost?
Redding's 50%,
10 of yours.
- That's bullshit.
- Chico.
Okay.
One condition though.
You kill Redding.
My pleasure.
I got angry when I heard
you was using that shit again.
I wanted to lash out
in every kind of direction.
And then I realized that
I was really angry at myself...
for being so blind
that I didn't see
that you had been back
on that shit again,
for getting you strung out
on it in the first place.
- Burr.
- I sat down there at the table,
sitting in your
daddy's chair,
eating your momma's food.
And all along Eugenia never knew
that I was feeding you that shit...
that I had you
slinging for me.
But why'd I do that?
Why'd I tell a lie?
Why'd I hurt
that sweet girl?
Listen, it's like
you said, Burr,
life happens the way
life happens.
No, man,
that's a copout.
We make life happen.
I got you strung out
on that shit
'cause I wanted you
dependent on me.
'Cause I was always afraid
you was gonna leave me.
And yet, I almost lost you
altogether forever.
Burr...
you never need no drugs
to keep me close to you, man.
I always loved you.
Always.
Look at me, acting like
a weepy old woman now.
Burr, no! No!
Get him a doctor,
for Christ's sake!
Redding, let him
the fuck go, let him go!
Jesus Christ.
L-l...
I can feel my legs.