"The road to hell is paved
with good intentions."
Now there's a mind fuck
if I ever heard one.
"The good side of my will
is the road to damnation."
Fuck! Why even try
being good?
And if good intentions
take you to the lake of fire,
where do bad
intentions lead?
Oz.
Nino, please, you don't understand.
I didn't mean it.
- I did the best I could.
- Hey, doc. Dr. Nathan.
Can't you shut him up?
He blabbed all night. I couldn't sleep.
You're well enough to be discharged.
Transfer Shupe back to Em City
and give Pancamo five milligrams
of Haldol twice a day.
- Hey, Gloria.
- Hey.
- Chucky Pancamo's delirious.
- So what else is new?
- That's not funny, Tim.
- The paperwork said Augustus Hill
was being transferred here today.
I don't see him.
He's still in bad shape.
I put him in a private room.
Okay. Thanks.
- How you feeling?
- Like shit.
You came pretty close to killing
yourself. You want to tell me why?
I wasn't trying
to kill myself.
You had massive amounts
of heroin in your system,
which made you get a little sloppy
with your catheter,
which resulted
in renal failure.
You may not have been trying
to consciously kill yourself,
- but the result was the same.
- My moms died,
wife deserted me.
All of a sudden the walls in Oz
got too high and too thick.
Augustus, who gave
you the drugs?
- It don't matter.
- It does to me.
Look, what I did, I did.
Ain't nobody else gonna suffer.
Salvatore Desantos
is brain-dead from a drug overdose.
I suspect Burr Redding
is responsible.
I suspect he thinks
Desanto sold you the drugs.
- He didn't.
- All the more reason to tell me.
- I want to talk to Burr.
- No.
- McManus, please.
You got a message for Burr Redding,
I'm your AT&T.
Salvatore Desanto
didn't sell Augustus the drugs.
What?
Then who did?
- Well, he wouldn't tell me.
- He'll tell me.
Why, so you can feed
that guy LSD?
See, I don't have any proof,
but I got a feeling
you're the one
that fucked Desanto up,
and I won't give you an opportunity
to fuck someone else up.
Officer, escort
this gentleman out.
- Where's Busmalis?
- Why?
What's up?
- You said Desanto sold those drugs.
- Yes.
- You lied.
- No.
- Why'd you lie, Busmalis?
- Well, l...
- Who you protecting? Guerra?
- Guerra.
- Yeah, Guerra made me lie.
- Why?
I don't know.
Maybe he sold the drugs to Augustus.
All right.
Get out of here.
We need to have a
sit-down with Morales.
Morales,
did Guerra give Augustus
those drugs?
No.
- You lying.
- Know what, Redding?
You and me,
since we made peace,
we've had a good
thing going.
Don't blow it
by being an asshole.
Motherfucker.
Who the fuck you think
you're calling an asshole?!
What the fuck you
think you're doing?
John and Jane Doe
decided to go on a diet,
eat better, get healthy, live longer.
What could be wrong with that?
Well, studies now show
that the stress John suffers
from trying to lower his cholesterol
can do as much harm
as cholesterol itself:
That the stress can actually raise
his cholesterol.
And take those low-fat,
no-fat products.
Shit's loaded with sugar
to make it taste better.
So while Jane's
trimming down,
she's jacking up her blood sugar
and risking diabetes.
Bottled water. What the fuck could
be wrong with that?
The bottles, my friend.
1.5 million tons of plastic
are used for them each year,
which means more toxic gases
in the air we breathe.
So by going all natural,
we're actually
killing ourselves,
killing the whole
fuckin' planet.
Look at O'Reily.
He's been there all day.
Yeah, he's waiting for the verdict
on Cyril's murder trial.
The jury's still
deliberating.
- Think he'll get convicted?
- I hope not.
I like Cyril. I'd hate to see him
sent off to death row.
Ryan, what news?
Nothing.
The lawyer says
it could be a couple of days
before the jury
comes back with a verdict.
I just wish I was with Cyril
in solitary, 'cause I know he's scared,
and I don't think he has a clue
as to what's going on.
- Good.
- What's good?
Well, the less aware
he is of things,
the better chance we have
of overturning a guilty verdict.
I don't follow.
I'm not going
to let Cyril die,
not without one
hell of a fight.
What do you care
about my brother for, huh?
What fuckin' business
is it of yours?
Just because I'm a prisoner doesn't mean
I've stopped being a priest.
- Cyril is one of God's kids...
- Hey, Meehan! Yo!
You know what? Stay the fuck away
from me, all right?
The last thing I need
right now is hope, so just beat it.
Get the fuck
out of here.
What are you, deaf?
O'Reily,
come with me.
- Where?
- Jury's in.
Oh, take that.
Ryan.
- Oh, Christ.
- I'm sorry.
- We're going to appeal.
- A lot of fuckin' good that will do.
Hey, you okay?
Sure.
- Kiss Jericho.
- No, Cyril, I don't...
Kiss him!
He misses you.
- When's sentencing?
- It's Thursday.
I'll plead for clemency
because of his mental state.
- Don't.
- Why not? The judge...
I'm responsible for
his decisions, right?
I say no appeals,
no clemency.
Now leave us alone.
Is there
a problem, Ryan?
No, just the opposite.
You're getting
out of here, kid.
You're going
to be free.
Why would you want
your brother to die?
Look at our lives.
We were beaten
as kids, ignored,
in and out of juvie
all the time.
Then Cyril gets
his brain smashed in,
and we're stuck in this shithole
for the next 90 years.
Nothingness is better
than a lifetime in Oz.
Once he's gone,
he's gone forever,
and you will have to live every day
with the part you played in that.
Believe me, I accept everything
I've done to screw up Cyril's life.
- I can carry this.
- No.
- No, you won't be able to.
- And what makes you say that?
- Because I know you, Ryan.
- What?!
You think
you know me?
Because we sit around and jaw,
you got me all figured out?
Is that it, huh?
Well, let me tell you something, Ma.
Even if you'd been in that house
my whole life,
you wouldn't have
a fuckin' clue who I am.
- Ryan.
- Let me out of here!
Ryan?
The only way to win this case on appeal
is in the court of public opinion.
In 1989,
the Supreme Court ruled
that executing the mentally retarded was
not a violation of the Eighth Amendment,
because there's no national
consensus against such punishment.
So we have to demonstrate
in court now
that there is a consensus,
that even Americans who believe
in the death penalty
find these particular executions
to be cruel and unusual punishment.
We need to get
the media aroused.
Sister, can you get
out a press release
to the effect that it's
impossible to determine
the extent of Cyril's
culpability?
I mean, he knew he
did something wrong,
but he has no sense
of the gravity.
A press release isn't enough.
We should hold a press conference.
I want to make it clear
that I was never able
to discuss the specifics
of the case with Cyril,
that he did not actively
participate in his own defense.
Father Meehan, do you really think
we can pull this off?
The law is like
God Almighty Himself...
it moves in strange ways,
so we have to keep nudging it toward
a more merciful outcome.
Hey, everybody, check
it out. Shupe's back.
Let's give him a hand.
You're a regular
Chris Rock there, O'Reily.
- What can I say? It's a talent.
- Speaking of talents,
you made a deal with us. We'd hurt Shupe
if you airholed Jia Kenmin.
Well, I never said
I'd do the deed myself.
I'm gonna find someone to do it
who the C.O. S can't blame.
- Who?
- The C.O. S themselves.
I hear justice
has been served.
Your brother's going to die
for whacking Li Chen.
My only wish is that you'd been
in court the day I testified.
Li Chen, he was a good man
who wouldn't hurt a flea.
I even choked back
a fuckin' tear.
I was brilliant.
Hey, wonton.
Get off him.
Get off him now.
Fuckin' cocksucker.
Son of a bitch!
You're going
to be fine.
- How you feeling?
- Sore.
- How's Jia?
- I didn't get to see him.
The C.O. S threw him directly
into solitary.
It's not nice to hit
the hacks.
Given his previous concussion,
I'm a little worried.
Don't be. It's better for all of us
if Jia goes back into another coma.
I'll get someone
to take you back.
I'll take him.
Appreciate what
you did today, O'Reily.
If you hadn't gotten
there when you did,
that chink would have snapped my
neck. I was just returning the favor.
Yeah, Jia, man, he's got some
set of balls.
He's always talking about what pussies
you hacks are.
Yeah? Well, he's got
a lesson coming.
He'll learn.
Hey, Jia.
How's the head?
Fuck you.
See, I would call that
an act of aggression.
Oh! Jeez!
You happy with
what you did?
What'd I do?
Got your revenge
on Jia Kenmin.
- That motherfucker came at me.
- I saw otherwise.
Hey, keep your
fuckin' mouth shut.
You wear that
cross of gold. Why?
Do you believe in the risen Christ,
or is it just a bauble?
What happened to you
when you were a child?
What made you walk away
from the church?
- I didn't walk away, I ran.
- Why?
When I was a kid...
and all the shit was
going down at our house,
my dad was wailing
on us non-stop,
so I went
to our pastor.
I had a welt on my back
the size of this fist.
So I asked
the good monsignor
if he could please talk to my dad
and ask him to stop beating on us.
He said if my dad hit us,
it was because we were bad
and we deserved
to be punished.
Then he told me to go home
and "honor thy father."
There are bad priests,
but there are lots
of good ones too.
Your priest wasn't there
for you, but I am.
I'm here for you,
and I'm here
for your brother.
No, it's too late,
Father.
It's too fuckin' late.
John and Jane Doe,
both looking slim and sexy,
meet, fall in love,
decide to get married.
John buys a nice fat diamond
for Jane's finger.
Sweet, except for the fact
that people in Africa
are living in shit
because of those precious little stones.
Men are dying every day
in dangerous mines.
in civil wars
fought to control
the diamond trades.
Anyway, John and Jane
get married,
start pumping out
the kids.
Shit, even God told Adam and Eve
to be fruitful and multiply,
but now we've multiplied
to the point of plague...
six billion
and counting.
Suddenly, my cell
don't seem so cramped.
I don't know how I'm going
to give Julie up.
I had a kid once. Died.
It fuckin' nearly
crippled me.
I ain't felt love
since then,
until now.
You know that C.O.
That you blinded?
- Eugene Rivera?
- Yeah. Is he going to get your dog?
No. He shouldn't.
He don't want any part of anything
that had to do with me.
You ever seen these
babies fight for sport?
I've seen roosters.
- I haven't seen dogs, though.
- It's fuckin' brutal, man.
Three rounds
of absolute mayhem.
Dogs just rippin'
each other apart.
- Jesus Christ, fuckin' stop!
- I'm sorry.
Hey, Penders,
Alvarez, what's this?
Beats me.
It's dogshit,
dickhead.
How can you be sure
that a dog did that?
Who else shits on
the floor?
Guerra.
That's funny.
Clean it up.
- No.
- No?
- Clean the fuckin' shit up.
Lopresti, why you always
on my fuckin' ass?
Because I'm tired of you
and your fuckin' pooch.
At least Chester
doesn't have bad breath.
Chester, now!
- Yes, yes, Chester.
- Damn!
It's a shame
what Penders did,
teaching Chester
to attack.
He put a shadow
over the whole program.
He really loved
the dog.
He just fuckin'
hates people.
Let her take you
up the stairs.
- What else?
- Have her sit.
Julie, sit.
Good girl. And?
Now take off
your blindfold.
- I pass?
- Yes. A plus.
Gold star.
Great job.
Thanks.
She did all the work,
you know.
And she'll continue to do so,
thanks to you.
You know what I wish?
I wish I could just see
whoever's going to get her, you know?
Well, Miguel...
you're going
to get your wish,
'cause that person will
be here in just a second.
- Who's that?
- McManus has been working the phones...
Oh, shit.
I thought
he didn't want her.
Tina didn't.
Well, neither did I, at first.
Look...
I love my wife and everything
she's done for me,
but she deserves
her life back.
I mean, I know this dog
would be great for me,
but I think...
over time it would be
great for her too.
That's good.
Cool.
This is Julie,
- and I trained her special for you.
- Special?
What do you normally
speak at home?
Spanish.
Now make believe you're at home
right now and ask for her.
Julie...
- You taught the dog Spanish?
- Yeah.
Yeah. Every command,
she's fuckin' bilingual.
Tell her to sit down.
Julie...
She's all yours.
Come on, Eugene.
Let's go.
Well, congratulations, Tim.
You're two for two.
Both the music program
and the Man's Best Friend
have had tangible
and positive results.
- Hear! Hear!
- Thank you.
I just want
to tell you both
that I appreciate
your support,
as guarded and as
half-assed as it's been.
Ouch. I was wondering what happened
to that backhand of yours.
Oh, I've gotta go.
I'm due over at Lardner.
Leo, Timmy.
Well, there certainly
has been a thaw
in your icy relationship
with the governor's office.
- Huh?
- If I didn't know better,
I'd say you had a liaison
with the state liaison,
if not last night,
then very recently.
Yeah,
I gotta go too.
Okay, "Timmy."
51.
Yeah! Jesus Christ,
I fucking won!
That winning ticket
was mine, damn it!
- Have I got any legal recourse?
- No. No.
I mean, even if
we could find him,
it's Dave Brass'
word against yours.
He's a C.O. Injured
in the line of duty:
You, a prisoner known
to talk to God.
That bastard!
He should be arrested
for killing my grandson.
Alex Jr.'s only chance to beat
the leukemia is to find a donor,
- someone willing to give bone marrow.
- I know.
I thought because of his unique
ethnic mix, a match was difficult.
The difficulty
is that no one is looking.
- There must be someone out there.
- Or here.
I'll bet if you search the computer files of
every prisoner in Oz,
past or present,
you'd get a match.
Well, why don't I?
- What?
- Search the files.
You'd do that
for me?
For you,
for your grandson,
for Dave Brass,
for my own peace of mind.
Martinez.
- They're shipping your ass to solitary.
- Yeah.
Listen, I could
help you out.
A word from me
and you're sitting in Unit B,
- maybe even Emerald City.
- Yeah?
And why would
you help me?
You doused Dave Brass
for no apparent reason.
Only I'm thinking
you had a reason,
and I'm thinking
if you tell me,
that's maybe
when I could step up for you.
I got nothing to say.
You attacked
a C.O., Carlos.
Where you're going,
you've got no friends.
If you don't get smart, you're going to
hurt a lot more than you do now!
Martinez is cracking.
We're so close to him jabbering
all the names of everybody involved,
and my guess is
Enrique Morales tops the list.
Good. None of that'll do much good
for Rebadow, though.
I mean, even if we find Brass
and tell him who cut him,
he's not going to give
that lottery money back.
Yes.
Yes, yes.
- Got it.
- Got what?
Salvation.
Farai Gyrobile is a Rastafarian
from Unit C.
It turns out him and Bob Marley
have more in common
than just reggae.
Both of them have white fathers.
And was his mother half West Indian
and half Guatemalan?
Yeah, so he appears to be
the perfect match for your grandson.
Now all you've got to do is convince
him to be the bone marrow donor.
May I talk
to this man alone,
- prisoner to prisoner?
- Of course.
Good luck.
Farai?
Bob.
Bob Rebadow.
The guy who got aced out
of two million Mightyball dollars?
Yes.
You see...
I needed to win that money
on account of my grandson.
- He's dying of leukemia.
- Pity.
Which is why
I need your help.
Alex has a very
specific racial makeup,
- which you match exactly.
- How the fuck you know?
McManus told me.
And I was hoping
you might be willing to donate
your bone marrow to my grandson.
McManus has no right
sharing that shit with you.
Everyone here thinks
my blood be black, 100%.
I fuckin' donate,
and they all know different.
And if you tell a soul,
you're as dead as your grandboy.
No, wait.
I'm sorry, Alex.
I tried.
God spoke to me
last night.
He told me that
the missing element
in Alex Jr.'s
recovery is faith.
Uh-huh.
Not money,
not science.
I want to find
a faith healer,
someone who will
go to my grandson in the hospital,
lay hands on him, flush out
the leukemia once and for all.
- I see.
- You're wary.
What little I do know
of faith healers gives me pause.
A lot of people expecting
a miracle get deception instead.
Okay.
So you don't choose the bruised fruit.
You look carefully.
For whatever
it's worth,
the kind of people
you're talking about
are not typically
sanctioned by any church.
Sister Pete, I didn't say religious
healer, denominational healer.
I said faith healer...
the faith that alone transcends
all cultural divisions and systems.
Aren't you sick
of the club mentality
surrounded by members
of other clubs?
Who belongs to what,
what and which one
has the upper-hand on God?
I mean no offense,
but I don't want to belong,
- I just want to believe.
- So what happens next?
I wait for instructions.
I wait for the word.
I am an arrow
in God's bow.
How long has he got?
What?
Your grandson,
how long has he got?
Who are you?
A. R. Whitworth.
How long has he got?
I don't know.
Only God does.
Good answer.
- Now we're talking.
- About what?
Faith healing.
Right?
How do you know that?
Would you believe
that last night
I dreamt that your grandson
was restored to perfect health?
Maybe.
Go on.
All right.
I was born a gimp...
spinal shit,
impossible to fix.
When I was in high school, found out
that my neighbor's a faith healer,
born with x-ray vision.
She denied it for years,
said it embarrassed her.
Then she goes and heals
a friend and the word spreads.
All this time,
right next door to me.
I was pissed off at first,
to tell you the truth.
But she's
the real deal.
No showbiz shit.
But you still
limp a little.
Just started
bothering me again.
But still, it's better
than what it used to be.
God may hold the key
to your grandson's health,
to heal him,
but he's holding
a key inside of the boy.
Regina can turn it.
Absolutely not!
- Sarah, listen to me.
- I have listened to you.
There will be
no strange woman
doing some sort of seance
or voodoo over Alex Jr.'s bed.
- I will not have it.
- Put aside your prejudices a moment,
- take Mother and go meet her.
- No.
There is no way I'm going
to dangle that kind of carrot
in front of a terminally-ill
10-year-old.
The boy is
too fragile.
Say it doesn't work,
Robert. What then?
We tell him that God
didn't love him enough?
I don't want
little Alex to die.
We're waiting
and praying
for a bone marrow
transplant.
Waiting and praying,
waiting and praying.
What about doing,
God damn it?
Cool down, Rebadow.
Step back.
This is a family matter.
I want to stand
on a mountaintop
and curse our idiotic,
modern small-mindedness,
our lame, civilized methods
of surviving sickness.
Hospitals are the summit
of human potential?
Bull-fuckin'-shit!
- Are you finished?
- No.
- I'll find someone to visit Regina.
- Who?
The only reason you called me
instead of Alex, Sophie or Mother
is because you knew
they would need convincing.
No. There is no one in our family
who is going
to let that strange woman
into Alex Jr.'s room.
You can't do this.
Yes, I can.
You know what I see?
I see a man trying to redeem himself
in the eyes of his family,
making a last-ditch effort
after decades of absence.
See, sometimes
I have x-ray vision too.
Why?
Why open this door
just to close it in my face?
Be healed...
in the name of God.
Our Lady of Fatima church
and its rectory
burned to the ground
this evening, killing two priests.
Also injured was
Father Raymond Mukada,
who suffered
from smoke inhalation
and is in serious condition
at Benchley Memorial Hospital.
I don't want to hear any more, Seroy.
You're going to solitary.
Warden, wait.
What if I give you some intel?
Will you give me a reprieve?
- What kind of intel?
- About Father Mukada.
What if I tell you
the fire at Mukada's church
was requested
by a prisoner here at Oz?
- Who?
- Huh-uh. Not until we have a deal.
Clarence Seroy is
a lying sack of shit.
That's what you said when Jaz Hoyt
implicated you in Jim Burns' murder.
- I'm innocent.
- No, you're a guilty little prick
who's going to take responsibility
for the shit storms you created.
You've got
no hard-core evidence
that either I set up the arson
or was involved in Hoyt killing Burns.
It's still their word
against mine.
Think you got
the system beat, huh?
Well, I've been around
a lot longer than you, Kirk.
Ray Mukada is
a friend of mine.
He's lying in a hospital
and that's pissing me off...
pissing me off royal.
It's your testimony
versus Kirk's.
He claims to have had nothing to do
with Burns' murder.
- He says you're lying.
- I'm on death row. Why would I lie?
What we need is
another witness.
One of your biker buddies
has got to come forward.
- They do that, they end up here.
- Not necessarily.
If they didn't participate in the crime,
I give them a free pass.
All your buddy's
got to say
is he heard Kirk propose
the murder to you.
Done.
Timothy Kirk,
you are hereby charged
with the murder of James Burns.
- What?
- My friend Max here
just corroborated Jaz Hoyt's
version of the truth.
- In solitary until the trial starts.
- No.
- Murder one... death row.
- I didn't... Warden, please.
- "He who comes in with vanity
- shall go out in darkness..."
- I'm sorry.
"...and his name shall be
covered in darkness.
He shall
never see the sun."
And finally,
I'm happy to announce
that Ray Mukada
will be released
from Benchley Memorial
tomorrow afternoon.
When is he coming
back to work?
Well, the doctors aren't sure yet,
but we hope soon.
Okay, that's all.
Peter Marie...
you haven't
said a word to me
since our little discussion
about Peter Schibetta.
"Little discussion"?
You know, Leo, when you
decided not to resign, I was thrilled.
But since then
you've become intransigent.
Keller can't see Beecher...
Schibetta, Alvarez.
It seems like when you get
an attitude about some guy,
boy, you just don't want to hear
anything else,
and I don't work
that way.
Speaking to Dr. Nathan
really helped me.
Hearing her thoughts
about being raped
- helped me to feel not so alone.
- That's great.
- That's good.
- So what's the next step?
That's up to you.
I would like to schedule
a session with your wife.
I'm not ready
to face her yet.
All right.
And perhaps
you should think
about interacting with the men
who attacked you.
How do you feel
about that?
No.
No way.
I'm no rat. I'm not going
to give up any names.
Why would you want
to protect them?
I didn't say
I'm protecting them.
You're going
to get revenge?
- I didn't say that either.
- Peter.
Just let it go.
Okay, for now.
I want to ask you
one more thing.
What's your relationship
with Warden Glynn?
So there is bad blood
between you.
Maybe we need
to let that go too, Sister.
Yeah, let that go too.
Hey, Petey.
Nice ass.
John and Jane
raise their kiddies
to be decent citizens,
teach them the laws
of political correctness,
teach them to respect other races,
genders, body shapes, beliefs.
But think about it.
Doesn't making our children
too aware of the differences
plant the same seed
of separateness?
Are we blinding
little Jane and John Jr.
So they only see what makes us different
and not what makes us alike?
Hey.
Feeling better?
Those painkillers are
fuckin' with your brain.
You've been sitting there
for two days.
You don't talk,
you don't eat with us.
Not to mention you got me worried
about this gum shit now.
Can't tell if they're
recessive or not.
Take a hike, girls.
Yes, sir.
- Vern.
- Yeah.
I don't know
who the donor was,
where that fuckin' dentist
got the gum tissue from,
whose cadaver.
Could be anyone's.
Get the fuck
out of here.
The shit's anonymous,
stored in some
fuckin' freezer somewhere.
How am I supposed
to know to ask?
Don't look at me
like that.
When exactly did this come up?
While I was whacked on gas
and under the knife.
That scum-sucking
towelhead,
he's fuckin' with me
in the middle of surgery.
Christ Almighty.
Is it normal color
at least, the gum tissue?
I don't know.
- I haven't looked.
- You haven't looked?
You haven't paid a follow-up visit
to Dr. Faraj to find out?
He won't be in again
until Thursday.
Listen, nobody
hears about this,
especially not
in the Brotherhood.
So, Vern,
am I right in deducing
that the reason I drove 80 miles
to hear this pathetic story
is because you don't know
what effect
James Robson's
little dental dilemma
is going to have on his standing
in the Brotherhood?
- Yes, sir.
- And because you care about Robson.
- He's your friend.
- Yes, sir.
Well, let's see if you can answer
some of your own questions here,
and we'll see if my trip
was worth the time.
Define purity for me, Vern.
You see, I'm not concerned
about James Robson.
I never did care
much for the boy.
His type joins us more
out of an identity crisis
than true faith.
Sir, with all due respect,
Robson has proven himself.
With all due respect,
Vern, I don't give a shit.
What does
concern me is you,
that your convictions will falter
in this embarrassing situation,
that you will overlook
Robson's infection
because the two
of you are close.
We don't know
anything for sure yet.
Robson'll find out the truth
as soon as he can.
Just remember,
a little leaven
leavens the whole loaf.
That goes
for you as well.
And next time,
spare me the road trip.
Use the fuckin'
telephone.
Yo, by the way,
I got James Robson over in Unit B.
He was asking me if I can get him
a copy of your schedule this week.
There some sort of nastiness
going on between you two?
- What did he say?
- Nothing.
He was just
all on edge,
in a darker mood
than most days.
You look kind of
freaked out yourself.
Shit.
Shit, shit, shit.
Quitting?
As of when?
- Today.
- Today?
Jesus, Tariq, a little advanced
notice would have been nice.
Leo, I didn't see it
coming, really.
You can't give me
the rest of the week?
Look, I'll finish out my shift,
and then that's all.
Here, these are some contacts
that could probably help you out.
First Kochurn, now you. Why can't I
hold on to a dentist around here?
- I'm sorry, Leo.
- Bullshit!
Yeah, I guess so.
Do me a favor...
Spread that around.
And don't tell anyone
where you heard it, okay?
Faraj should be in by now.
I'm going to corner him after lunch.
You don't want to talk much
until then, is that the deal?
I'm not handling this
any different than the next guy would,
so give me
a fuckin' break.
- Just soup.
- Sure you don't want
no chitlins and gravy
to go with that?
What?
Shall we?
Everyone, listen up.
Robson here went to the dentist
and got a pair of dirty ghetto gums.
- Thanks, Vern.
- I didn't say a fuckin' word.
Shut up, you goddamn nigger.
Give him some soup.
Whoa, you gonna
take that, G...
man calling your brother
a nigger and all?
Hey, don't get stupid.
Don't want me to Sammy Sosa
that jaw with this here spoon.
Keep it moving, girls.
I need to see Dr. Faraj.
- My mouth is killing me.
- You poor baby.
Follow me.
Dr. Faraj, hi.
Now who's the fuckin'
donor, huh?
I have a wife.
I have kids. Please.
- Don't make me fuckin' slip.
- No, no, he was white.
He was like you.
He was just your age.
Prove it. Call the fuckin'
lab or whatever.
I'll prove it. Could you just please
go get me my address book
from other there, okay?
- He wasn't white. I made sure of that.
- Fuck!
What's done is done.
Officer!
He attacked me.
Must be
his gums acting up.
Now...
you all know how highly
I've esteemed James Robson...
but the past,
unfortunately,
is nothing more
than the past.
Satan has scored
a very ugly victory,
and it pains me that
Robson is a casualty.
We must, nevertheless, abide
by principles, not feelings.
As of today, James Robson
is no longer a part of the Brotherhood.
- Hello, Chris.
- Sister.
You have to talk in this ear. This one
doesn't work too good anymore.
Yeah. Dr. Nathan says the hearing loss
may be permanent.
Eh, that'll give me a real excuse
for ignoring people.
She also says you'll be sent back
to protective custody tomorrow.
Just in time
for my trial.
- How do you like your new lawyer?
- I think I'm gonna lose.
- How do you feel about that?
- Angry.
I don't want to end
my days on death row.
I'll pray for you.
- Do you think Jesus was a fag?
- What?
You think Jesus was a fag?
It's a legitimate question.
Are you trying to provoke me,
mock my religion?
No, just looking
for a role model.
Jesus was divine...
and human
simultaneously, right?
Did the divine part
control his sexual appetites?
And if so,
what chance have I got?
I'm not divine,
far from it.
All my life...
anytime
I've gotten the urge,
I've stuck my cock
into any cavity
that was open
and available.
That's what's led me
to this point in time,
this precipice of death.
If I'd have been celibate,
do you think I'd have been happier?
- We fight our natures, Chris.
- Why?
God gives us natures.
What, for us to fight them?
It proves we're
better than animals.
I guess I failed
that test.
- You shouldn't think that way.
- What? I can't hear you.
I see the Aryans
have snatched your friend Adam.
Yeah.
It's my fault.
How so?
L... I don't want to go
into all the gory details.
- I delivered Adam into Schillinger's
hands. - Why?
Because Schillinger could arrange
for me to see Keller.
The irony is I didn't see Keller.
He was sent to Benchley Memorial
before I could get
to protective custody.
So to satisfy
your desires,
sexual or otherwise,
you sacrificed the boy.
I was convinced that Adam
deserved to get raped.
He raped that girl,
he attacked me.
But when I saw him
in the gym, l...
I realized that no matter what Adam
had done, no one deserves that.
My guilt is
devouring me.
So it should.
What can I do to make
peace with myself?
Well, I could tell you,
- but you want to hear it?
- Go on.
This calamity was brought on
by your need to see Keller,
so the only way for
you to punish yourself
- is by you denying yourself Keller.
- You mean don't see him.
That's right.
Ever again?
Christ.
If you are really
truly sorry, Beecher,
that's what
you must do.
I want to transfer
to another work detail.
You transferred to the mailroom
not even a week ago.
Yeah. I'm not enjoying it
as much as I thought I would.
- Is there trouble with Schillinger?
- No, I just realized
that pushing a cart around
isn't the best use of my talents.
- Sister Peter Marie's replaced you.
- I know.
The only opening's
in the women's dress factory.
- Fine.
- So wait a second.
Sewing hems on women's dresses
is a better use of your talent?
Don't fuckin' bullshit me.
What's going on?
Nothing.
All right.
This is a prison,
not an employment agency.
We try to accommodate people,
but we can't always.
Now you asked to
work in the mailroom.
Until you give me
a legitimate reason why you can't,
you stay in the fuckin'
mailroom! Go.
I have a special
delivery for Dr. Nathan.
- Can I help you?
- Where's Sister Pete?
- In a staff meeting.
- You're that sheriff from Unit J?
- Alvin Yood, yeah.
- Yeah.
- I'm Tobias Beecher.
- Hey.
- I used to have this job.
- And you gave it up?
- Yeah.
- Nothing personal, but you're a dolt.
Look, Sister Pete gets back
from her appointment,
can you give her
this note
and tell her to make
a meeting with Adam Guenzel?
He's in Unit B, and I think
he needs somebody to talk to.
- About what?
- She'll knows when she sees him.
Okay, I'll give her
your message.
Thanks.
So long.
Hey, Beecher,
don't take
any wooden nickels.
- How you doing, Adam?
- What do you care?
Look,
I'm sorry I let them
rape you, okay?
But it's this place, you know?
It got my head all fucked up.
Mine too.
We've got to be there
for each other, bro'.
What? You want
to borrow my lipstick?
Guenzel, Sister Peter
Marie has requested your presence.
- What for?
- My guess, to Saran Wrap your brain.
Hey, prag, come here.
You listen up.
You don't jabber one fuckin' word
to her about what we done to you.
- Yes, sir.
- And clean that shit off your face.
So that's it?
- You have nothing else to say?
- No, ma'am.
Tell me about your relationship
with Tobias Beecher.
I don't have a relationship
with Beecher.
We shared a cell
in Em City, that's all.
What about when you
were both outside?
Our families were friendly,
but he's 10 years older than me.
We never hung out
or anything.
What if I told you that he's very
concerned about you?
I'd tell you he's
a lying cocksucker.
I'm sorry
for swearing.
I've heard worse.
- Why is he a liar?
- He knows why.
- You don't want to tell me?
- Ask him.
Normally, my role
in these sessions
is to mediate,
to referee,
but today I'm gonna
be a little more aggressive.
Our subject is
Adam Guenzel.
I had a meeting with Adam Guenzel
when he first came to Oz.
Since then, his behavior patterns
have changed significantly.
Clearly, he has been
abused sexually,
and I suspect that the three of you
know the details.
Tobias?
He was raped...
gang raped about a week ago.
By whom?
I'm not investigating
this as a crime.
I just want
to help the boy.
Vern?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Said...
can you shed
any light on this?
No.
Fine.
But I want you to know
that I am not letting this pass.
I'm going to be seeing
Adam Guenzel every single day
until I can get
him to open up,
until he can tell me
exactly what happened.
This session is closed.
I am sick of sitting
in the same room with you.
Adam Guenzel has
become a liability.
You think he'll
blab to the nun?
Mm-hmm.
Hey, prag,
get in here.
Yes, sir?
I've got good news.
We're gonna
help you escape.
Beecher,
I've got some news.
Adam Guenzel is dead.
What?
They just found
his body.
Evidently,
he was climbing the fence,
he was attempting
to escape.
He got past the barbed wire,
but then the fence...
- He was electrocuted.
- 4,000 volts, straight through him.
Fuck.
I'm sorry.
So, that road to hell
that's paved
with good intentions?
I'm not saying
to make a detour,
only that before you make
your first step,
consider
the consequences,
'cause good
can turn to bad
in the blink
of a fuckin' eye.