People are always looking
to have their fortunes told.
They get their cards read,
their palms read,
even the bumps
on their head.
Well, if that card
ain't credit, why read it?
If that palm ain't holding something,
let it go, and shit,
if you've got bumps on your head
big enough to read,
forget about
your future, yo,
because your problems
are in the here and now.
Ahmad Lalar was murdered
by James Robson.
You keep saying that, but you offer
no proof. Look, I need evidence.
A witness, the murder weapon,
anything.
Robson may not have
sliced Ahmad himself.
He may have assigned another Aryan
to do the job, as he did Salah Udeen.
Then getting a conviction
is gonna be harder.
- So what do you intend to do?
- Continue the investigation.
Yes, you drag out the process,
hoping that everyone's gonna forget?
Let me tell you this,
Warden,
we won't forget.
Lalar's death
must not go unpunished.
It won't. Believe me,
Robson's day of reckoning
- and retribution is coming.
- Mail call!
Yo, you got Minister Said's
mail in there?
You know, Omar,
I discovered that the minister
and I have something in common.
Yeah, okay.
We both
support slavery.
For me, slavery
don't exist anymore,
which is
a damned shame.
But according
to this book in the library,
for those Muslims,
slavery is alive
and well in Africa.
That's right.
I figured Said
must've known that, too,
since he went
and got himself one.
You.
What the fuck
you jabbering about?
I ain't nobody's motherfucking
slave and shit, man.
You tote that barge,
you lift that bale...
you's his house nigger.
You motherfucker!
Omar! Come here!
Look, I know I ain't
supposed to fight, but...
but don't no-motherfucking-body
talk to me like that!
Come here now!
- Oooh!
- You heard that shit, yo?
Fuck, huh?
I am your
fucking nigger, huh?
Fuck!
? I wanna hold your hand,
walk along the sand?
? Laughing in the sun,
always having fun?
? Whoa, whoa.?
You sing like shit.
? I wanna hold your hand,
walk along the sand?
? La la la?
? I wanna hold your hand,
walk along the sand?
? La-la-la-la-la,
la la la.?
What was Reggie Rawls
doing in this room?
Oh, Reggie?
He's a big fan, man.
He's a major drug dealer
in Unit C.
Yo, yo, man, he hear music,
he drawn in and shit.
Omar...
are you selling drugs
from this room?
No.
Are you
selling drugs?
Well, yeah, man.
What the fuck, huh? Shit.
I mean, I ain't doing them
and shit, man, or using them or nothing.
You know,
what you thinking, man?
- That's the deal, ain't it?
- No, it is not.
Selling drugs
is using them.
My piss test
say different.
I don't care
what your drug tests say,
it's what I say
that matters.
Yeah?
Well, I say, "Fuck you."
Watch. Fuck you.
No, fuck you!
Hey, yo, Said...
Fuck you!
- No, no! Help!
- Fuck you! Fuck!
- Fuck! Fuck!
- Help! Help!
I'm waiting.
For what?
An explanation.
Like I said,
for what?
For the beating
you put on White.
A reason makes
a difference, McManus?
I beat him!
I failed him...
- him and myself.
- Everything was going so well.
Why didn't you
come to me?
You don't get it, McManus,
you don't get it.
The only thing I need
to get from you is an explanation.
And until I do,
you can fucking rot!
Why?
I tell you, I don't know why
the motherfucker attacked me, man!
You're beat to shit
for no reason? Bullshit.
All right, I'm gonna
be honest with you.
But look, don't let
what I say blur the fact
that what I'm getting ready
to fucking tell you
is the absolute, straight up, goddamn,
motherfucking truth. You understand?
I was moving drugs,
okay?
You're fucking shitting me.
From your practice room?
No, man, hear me out.
I was threatened.
I mean, I didn't
do nothing, man.
I swear to fucking God,
I didn't touch shit.
Who are you
moving them for?
If I tell you that, man,
I'm dead.
- I'm seriously dead.
- All right, all right,
let's put that aside
for now.
McManus,
I am clean, man!
- I am clean...
- Shut up!
Will you fucking
shut up one second?!
Please, as a favor,
don't put me back
in solitary again, man.
Goddamn it, Omar,
I oughta.
All right,
here's the deal.
From now on,
you rehearse in your pod.
No more fucking
practice room.
And your piss shows even
a hint of aspirin, you're toast.
Okay? Do you
understand me?
I hear you.
Afternoon, gents.
Our lmam is in the hole
'cause of you.
Huh-uh.
That motherfucker's in there
'cause he can't get a grip
on his own
goddamn guidance.
You're toxic, White.
You managed to turn the only person
on your side against you.
The rest of us, we saw
this disaster coming.
Every day Said
is in the hole,
is a day you're
out here alone.
Yeah? Well...
I gotta go practice.
Fuck me.
I hate your voice.
McManus.
Lockdown's in a couple
of minutes.
Why aren't you
in your pod?
Look, where you
headed to?
To the hole?
You know, 'cause maybe
you and me should go on over there,
you know, maybe see how
Said's weathering the storm.
Why, what do you care?
I'm kind of
floundering here.
Floundering?
I mean, old mojo,
you know, I mean,
he ain't treating Omar
so great these days.
Without...
Said here...
see, everything's just...
kind of harder.
I mean, I really
need that fuck.
Who knew?
Come on.
- We're going back to Em City.
- What if I refuse?
You'd be
the first person who did.
I'm not ready to leave,
I don't deserve to.
You know, Omar told me
what happened and why.
Why...
and yet again,
I lost my humanity
in pursuit of what I thought
was the greater good.
You know, Said,
I don't think that you
lost your humanity at all.
I think what scares you
is that your actions
are completely human.
Let's go.
McManus, either I find
my soul in this place,
or I am lost forever.
I need more time.
I need more time, please?
Please?
Man, this is crazy.
All right.
I'll wait
to hear from you.
And then you're
back in Em City
dancing
with Omar White.
What kind of people
become fortune-tellers?
Most times, they're
a bunch of half-literate,
middle-aged women
who only tell you stuff
they wish would
happen to them.
They fabricate
your dreams,
because theirs got
dashed on the rocks.
So, how you
figure dat, huh?
Having your
future told...
by someone
who ain't got one?
Doctor, what the fuck
is wrong with me?
I'm hot, I've got
rashes, diarrhea.
Well, I'm afraid
what you have is...
it's called
a staph infection.
Sometimes when a wound
gets infected,
toxins are released
into the bloodstream,
- and these toxins tunnel into tissue...
- That's why all the drugs?
Well, antibiotics, yes.
But your system seems
to be resistant to them.
And I got this
from being in the hospital?
Yeah.
Am I gonna die?
Look, we're doing
everything we can, all right?
- I'm sure that...
- Oh, Christ, don't let me die.
I don't wanna die.
I don't want to die
lying in my own shit.
Oh, man,
oh, man,
I'm getting hard just
looking at that beauty.
Rack 'em, Prag.
So, I hear Pancamo
caught the flu or something.
- It may be fatal.
- Good.
If it isn't,
when he gets out,
we'll make it fatal.
Schibetta's in the psych unit,
Urbano's in the hole,
and the Sicilians don't run
the cafeteria anymore.
Those wiseguys ain't looking
that wise these days.
Meanwhile...
we got other fish
to fry.
You know, sweet pea,
I like a nice, firm ass.
You need to
go to the gym.
Yes, sir.
And if you see your buddy
Adam Guenzel there,
I need you to give him
some pertinent information.
About what, sir?
About his buddy,
Tobias Beecher.
How was your visit
with your mother and dad?
She cried the whole time.
It was embarrassing.
Well, you should be grateful
somebody's crying about you at all.
Okay,
that's enough.
Stop.
- Come on, stop.
- Oh, cut it out.
- Come on.
- I'm gonna go use the free weights.
I got to get you back to Em City
before I go to work for Sister Pete.
- I can get back to Em City myself.
- Yeah, but...
Look, I gotta start
being my own man.
Ah, okay.
- Hey there, handsome.
- Fuck you.
Hey, what's with
the attitude, man?
Hey, pal, I'm in here
because of you.
- I didn't wanna rape that girl.
- Look at yourself.
- Look at what you've turned into.
- I had to, to survive.
You don't see me
all dolled up.
That's because you got Beecher.
From what I understand,
- you're paying the same price for
protection. - Bullshit!
Everybody knows
Beecher's a fucking fag,
and that you're
sucking his cock.
What?! What'd you say,
you stupid fuck?!
Come on, fuck!
You fucking bitch!
Fucking psycho!
You wanna tell me
what that was all about?
Winthrop came on to me.
I had to set him straight.
- I thought you two were friends.
- Not anymore.
All right, since this
is your first offense,
I'm gonna be lenient, but you only get
one hall pass, you understand?
Yes, sir.
So, he slapped you
on the wrist?
Just like you said
he would.
You don't wanna spend
any time in the hole, Adam.
I already got my lecture
for the day, okay?
Hey, are you
all right?
Don't be fucking
touching me!
I wanna say something
about our last session,
when we were
discussing homosexuality.
At the time,
I implied that I never
harmed you, Beecher.
Well...
my reaction was...
knee-jerk.
You have to understand,
I was worried
about saying anything out loud
that might expose me
to possible disciplinary
or legal action.
I did abuse you
when you arrived.
And for that,
I am sorry.
I ask your
forgiveness.
Tobias...
do you accept
his apology?
I...
I don't know.
So, the FBI has decided
to let the local D.A. Prosecute you.
- Why?
- The eyewitness that came forward
claims to have seen you
dump Brice Tibbetts' body
in a field outside
of Alden township.
But the FBI only has jurisdiction
if they can prove
that you brought Tibbetts
across the state line, which they can't.
Let's say that I did
dump the body.
It doesn't mean
that I killed the guy.
Exactly.
See, now if I'm gonna
keep you off death row,
we'll have to create
that doubt in the jury's mind.
- But you said you didn't kill Tibbetts.
- That's right.
- What were you doing with the body?
- It wasn't me.
Okay, 'cause the eyewitness,
he picked you out of a lineup, so...
Catherine,
it wasn't me.
Now this witness says
that it was nighttime, right?
There's no lights
at nighttime.
All of a sudden, this motherfucker's
got x-ray vision?
Well. Jeez, Keller,
you don't need me,
so you can just plead
your own case.
- You're prettier.
- Not by much.
- The arraignment's tomorrow.
- Mm-hmm.
Ready for a little trip
into town?
What, and leave
this place?
Jeez,
I don't know.
Officer?
Till the a.m.
You gonna see Toby?
Yes.
Tell him I had
a funny dream about him.
He was elected President
of the United States.
I had a dream
about you and me.
Yeah?
We were gladiators.
Your name was Sextus.
Mine was Cunnilinga.
God, it is good
to see you.
Yes, you too.
Oh, I spoke to Holly
this morning,
and she said she had
such a great time
at Adventure Country with you
and your son Brad.
She's a wonderful kid.
How'd your meeting
go with Keller?
Good.
We're well on our way
to building a solid defense.
Toby, he never talked
about these killings, did he?
No.
You wouldn't lie to me
in order to protect him?
No.
Okay.
I'll see you.
Oh, Catherine, Keller...
he didn't give you
a message for me, did he?
No.
So, there's two ways
this could go, precious.
They both end the same:
With my dick up your ass.
Beecher, I need
to talk to you.
- Look...
- I didn't wanna say in our session.
I tried to convince Robson
not to rape your boy, Guenzel.
But you know Robson,
he's headstrong.
Anyway, the Sicilians
stopped him and I'm glad.
You're glad?
Yeah, well,
not glad, exactly.
I'm like you.
I'm all turned around,
you know.
I'm trying to stop
the shit in my life,
but it's Oz,
you know?
I realize I can't
stop most of it,
but I can do
some things.
Now, I heard
what's going on.
The warden won't
let you see Keller.
So, I'm offering
on my next mail run...
to take a letter
to Keller for you.
You'd do that?
You would?
You write it up,
I'll slip it through.
I'm...
What? Amazed?
In shock?
Suspicious.
Well, you have
every right to be.
But I swear to you,
on the graves
of both of my sons,
I'm just trying
to make up for the past.
Trying to clear my conscience
so I can move on.
Hello there,
Keller.
Schillinger,
my old friend.
I got a package
from one of your ex-wives,
subscription renewal notice
from Sports Illustrated...
and this,
from Beecher.
What's the game?
No game.
Tomorrow,
if you want,
I'll take your letter
back to Beecher.
Lights out!
Adam?
Is everything
all right?
You haven't said
a word all evening.
Were you a fag
before you came to Oz,
or did you
start here?
What?
I've been asking around.
I heard some stories, are they true?
It depends
on what you heard.
That when you first arrived,
you were Schillinger's bitch.
- Yes.
- Then some guy named Keller's bitch?
Not... bitch, exactly.
Then what,
his girlfriend?
People like to reduce things
to their most basic form.
You're either a fag
or you're not a fag.
And if you are,
you should have told me
instead of pretending
to act normal,
pretending to care about me
for the right reasons.
Adam, I do care about you
- Stay back!
- Come on, don't be an asshole.
Oh, you'd like that, huh?
To be up my asshole?
Shut the fuck up!
Get the fuck off me,
you fucking faggot!
- Just stop. Just stop.
- Let go of me! Let go of me!
- Break it up!
- I don't need that fucking faggot!
I'm telling you,
this faggot grabbed me.
I don't wanna spend
another night in the same cell as him.
Fine. But since all the cells
in Em City are full,
and since you need a little attitude
adjustment, I'm putting you in the cage.
Me?! I didn't do shit! Get your
fucking hands off me, you fuck!
The boy's got problems.
He raped a girl,
beat her brains in.
I know.
I've known Adam's family
for a long time.
I know, that's why
I made you his sponsor,
but I'm beginning to think I made
a mistake bringing him to Em City.
- Maybe I should transfer him out.
- Don't.
I can turn him around.
- Give me a chance.
- Okay, a chance.
Faggot.
Faggot!
I have a way for you and Keller
to meet face to face.
Yeah, how?
Come work for me
in the post office.
I'll let you deliver the mail
to protective custody.
Quit Sister Pete?
Well, yeah,
you'd have to.
And I'd get
to see Keller?
Every day.
Okay.
There's just one thing
that I'd ask for in trade.
What's that?
The boy.
Give me the boy.
What?
Tell the Sicilians to back off
and let me have him,
to do with
whatever I choose.
This is what this
has all been about?
What do you mean?
The "I'm trying
to change my ways" crap.
You know, it...
I almost believed you.
Oh, it's true.
But really,
it's beside the point.
I have a practical solution
to your problem.
You're asking me to get
the thing I want most
to allow you
to subject Adam
to the same horrors
you put me through? No way.
Hmm. Not even
for Keller?
Not even for Keller.
Well, I have to admit,
I'm stunned.
I admire your strength
of character.
I respect your decision. We'll just
leave the whole matter at that.
Yeah, you never leave
anything at that.
Well, nobody
changes overnight.
Be sure to eat
your vegetables.
Who's to say
that the future
ain't fucking
with the fortune-teller?
Let's say that she tells you
you're gonna fall in love.
But she
doesn't tell you
that your beloved's
gonna die of cancer,
and that she really is
your long-lost sister,
and a serial killer.
Because the fortune-teller
don't know that.
What if God or the spirits
or whatever
is only telling the fortune-teller
half the story...
half the truth?
- Fucking Friday.
- Fucking Friday?
Yeah, you'd think I'd be happy
with the weekend coming, and all.
Working in Oz, I never feel
more fucked than on Friday.
Hmm, payday.
I don't know
if I'd call it pay.
Man makes
a dogshit wage,
money none of those cocksucking
congressmen would work for, huh?
- Hey, you gotta laugh.
- You follow pro basketball?
- Huh, basketball?
- Yeah.
Who do you think
the worst player in the NBA is?
Some white guy.
Actually, maybe two or three
white guys battling for the honor.
Yeah, that's gotta
piss you off.
Seeing some of these jags
play pro ball
- knowing you're better?
- Why would that piss me off?
You know how goddamn good
you've gotta be
in order to be the worst player
in the NBA? You gotta be phenomenal.
No, I realize that,
I was just saying...
My point was that even
the worst player in the NBA
still makes league minimum:
$330,000 a year.
- Wow.
- Take away what the government gets,
your agent's 4%,
worst case scenario,
you've still got 160.
Fuck it, 150,
even 140,
say you wanna jerk off
with 10 of it.
That's $140,000 cash,
in pocket!
Hey Dave, man, I didn't mean
to get you all riled up.
It's not you.
It's fucking Friday.
So, all the blood tests
came back negative.
We should run them again
in three months.
And Martinez,
how are his blood tests?
Oh, he doesn't have AIDS,
if that's what you're asking.
That doesn't
necessarily mean
it was his blood
that got thrown at you.
Why'd you douse me,
you prick?
Because you're the prick,
you prick.
Hey, stop that!
Oh, okay, so it's
okay for you
to hit this cocksucker,
but not me?!
Officer Brass?
- What?
- Did you buy my Mightyball ticket?
What?
Yeah, yeah.
It's almost time, I'm so excited.
Aren't you excited, Bob?
Excited about what?
The Mightyball drawing,
$2 million,
which if you win will go towards
finding a cure for your grandson.
How can you not
be excited?
What if God didn't give me
the right numbers?
What if I don't win?
Then little Alex dies.
Today's numbers
will be randomly selected
from 51 numbered balls
out of our
lotto draw hopper.
So, everybody,
get it out and get it ready,
'cause it's time
to play Mightyball.
If your number
is drawn,
you could be the lucky winner
of $2 million.
The first number is...
seven.
Seven, Bob,
that's a match.
The second number
is...
10.
That's two.
Three.
The fourth number is...
49.
Four for four.
The fifth number is...
30.
And the final number,
and the winner
of $2 million is...
51.
Motherfucker, you gotta be
fucking fucking me.
Yeah! Jesus Christ,
I fucking won! Ah!
- You won?
- Yeah, motherfucker, I won!
God damn it, yes!
Oh, shit!
Fuck!
Oh, yeah!
Shit!
Shit! Fuck!
God damn it!
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
Yeah!
I know, it's wild.
Yeah, all right,
all right.
Okay, okay, bye.
Yeah.
Rebadow's making
a fuss all day.
He claims that Brass
didn't win the lottery, he did.
Oh, yeah?
All right.
All right,
bring him in.
- Bob.
- I need to speak with Officer Brass.
- I've been waiting.
- Slow down, slow down.
7-10-3-49-30-51,
those are my numbers.
I had officer Brass
purchase the ticket for me.
Bob, memorizing
the winning numbers doesn't prove...
You don't believe me?
Ask Officer Brass.
- Are you serious?
- On my dying grandson's life.
Well, Bob,
Dave Brass isn't here.
I mean, when he found out
he won, he just left.
He didn't go to his locker.
He didn't punch out.
Can't you
find him somehow?
Let me see
what I can do.
You walk
by a storefront,
a fortune-teller
beckons you inside.
You know it's a scam,
but you go anyway.
As she flips the cards,
you say to yourself,
"This is bullshit."
And yet, she says the one thing
you really wanna hear.
You lean in
a little closer,
hoping, praying that she
actually knows the truth.
Well, I came
straight from work.
I'm a C.O. At the Oswald
Correctional Facility.
Well, not anymore.
I quit! Woo!
I won! Woo!
Tim, any word
from Brass?
No, nobody's
heard from him.
Not his family,
not his girlfriend.
He left the lottery
claim center
and hopped a plane
to parts unknown.
Damn.
I was with Brass
during the drawing.
He was out of his mind
because he won,
you know, as you would be.
But thinking about it now,
he must have been saying to himself,
"Fuck you, Rebadow."
I'll tell you, if it was one
of the other dinks in this joint
and I was Brass,
I would've ripped them off too.
But to do it
to a guy like Rebadow,
you know, he's got a dying grandson,
not throw him a bone...
I mean, that's
dead-of-winter cold.
Brass was a good guy.
Obviously not
that good of a guy.
When we played basketball
against Vahue,
I got to know him.
He was the most stand-up, do-right-by-you
person I ever met.
Well, guess that's what
two mill can do to a fellow.
No, it wasn't the money,
he felt fucked over.
I mean, he had a big pair
of gigantic NBA tits in his face
and we say to him,
"No, no, no, no, you work in Oz.
You get to get your Achilles' tendon
slashed for no good reason
except McManus can't
keep his mouth shut."
You gonna blame yourself
for what happened forever?
Yeah.
Dave Brass came to Oz
and filled out an application.
Nobody forced him
to do that, right?
He got his leg fucked up,
that sucks.
But this is
a maximum-security prison.
The poor guy got piss and shit
thrown at him, he could get AIDS.
That'd be a lot worse
than being a goddamn gimp.
But you know what?
He filled out
an application.
Tim, every night
I get down on my knees
and pray to God
I don't get shanked
when I come to work.
But what if it happens?
What if one of these fucking animals
ends up butt-fucking me?
Are you gonna blame yourself
because you brought me into Oz?
Because if you did,
you'd be a goddamn idiot.
I filled out
an application.
Cold out there,
ain't it?
Oh, you're telling me.
I wish I had a fur coat like one
of your seeing-eye dogs.
- We prefer to call them guide-dogs.
- Well, what's the difference?
Well, you work
for the governor.
You should know what it's like
being politically correct.
How's the program going?
Well, it's a real testament
to man's best friend.
I have three of the more disparate
inmates that I've ever had,
and each of them are
doing a wonderful job.
I'm impressed.
Most skeptics
usually are.
- Oh.
- Catch you later.
Hey, Layla.
It's hot in here
this morning.
Layla.
Lay...
He's got septicemia, a kidney disease.
He went into septic shock.
We managed to bring
his temperature down from 105.
This is, like what?
A virus? Is it contagious?
No, it's a bacterial infection.
Oftentimes, paraplegics
are prone
to kidney disorders,
especially if they take
poor care of themselves.
Wait, wait. Augustus is nearly
maniacal about his upkeep.
- There's something else.
- What?
He's also got a shitload
of heroin in his bloodstream.
Everybody, back up.
Keep your wrist stiff.
Whoa, what the fuck
is this, man?
Miss Sally's new
TV series, "Sallycise."
- It's a health and exercise show.
- Well, one of my muscles
- is already getting bigger.
- What's the latest on Hill?
Is Augustus
gonna be okay?
Yo, what's up?
Did he O.D., man?
McManus, how's Augustus?
So, how's he doing?
You son of a bitch.
Augustus' blood
is swimming in heroin.
You want to fucking
tell me about that, do you?
I don't know nothing about that!
Just tell me how the fuck he is!
He's dying. He's lying
in a fucking hospital bed, dying.
Well, why are you standing here
trying to talk to me?
I wanna know who
gave him the drugs.
I don't know nothing about that.
I swear to you, you gotta believe me.
- Why the fuck should I believe you?
- I'm getting old!
I should've died
a long time ago.
But there's one thing I won't do,
and that's outlive that boy.
Now you go and do everything
you can for him, and I swear to you,
I'll find out who it was
that gave him that smack!
All right,
and when you do,
you bring him straight to me.
You understand me?
- Yo, Burr, how's our boy doing?
- You been feeding him tits?
Why, he overdosed or something?
I thought it was a kidney thing.
Brought on by some motherfucker
that got him smack.
And you at the top
of my list, Poet!
What, me?
No way, man. No way!
I swear to you,
I will root out the truth.
You keeping digging,
motherfucker,
but I didn't
give him shit.
You know,
you got a lot of enemies, Burr.
Before you start
accusing your friends,
you need to go check out
them Sicilians and them spics.
That's what
you need to do.
Prisoner #97P528:
Greg Penders:
Convicted May 7th, 1997:
Criminally negligent
homicide:
Sentence: 17 years:
Up for parole
in nine.
- You heard the news?
- Yeah, too bad.
Augustus was doing
a great job with Layla.
Well, what are
the steaks for?
They're for
today's training.
We're gonna teach
the dogs to cook?
You're gonna teach
the dogs self-control.
Now, it's of primary importance
that your dog's attention
at all times remains
focused on you,
even when tempted
with those things that,
as a dog,
they love.
Like raw
fucking meat.
Or cats or other dogs,
anything.
So, the two of you
head on over there.
This is fucking
unbelievable.
You know, I haven't seen
a steak in six years,
and now you're gonna
put it on the floor,
so a dog
won't eat it?
Miguel,
you go first.
Have Julie lead you along,
but towards the steak.
Yeah, but what do I do
if she goes for it?
You give her lead
a firm tug and say, "No."
No!
Julie, no!
Good girl,
good girl.
Come on.
Julie, no!
Julie!
No!
Shit!
This is gonna
take awhile.
Cute pooch.
You know, when I was nine,
my parents gave me a dog,
this beautiful
Chesapeake Bay retriever.
One day I decided
to dock the dog's tail.
Dock,
what's that?
- Amputate.
- Why?
I just thought he'd look better.
I grabbed the butcher knife
from the kitchen
and just cut his tail off,
cropped his ears,
kept on going.
By the time
my folks got home,
they were pissed...
dead puppy everywhere.
Get your hands
off the dog.
- I'm kidding.
- I don't care,
get your hands
off my fucking dog.
Do what
he says, Jia.
Someday, Morales.
Someday.
Are you
protecting me now?
No, I just hate
that yellow scum fuck,
and I've got
a question to ask.
You've been tight
with Mukada, right?
Yeah, on and off.
- I was wondering something.
- What?
Where the fuck's
his office?
Open.
Enrique...
- what a surprise.
- Yeah, you're telling me.
Nice digs.
So?
I fried a guy once.
That's why I'm here.
I chucked his useless ass
into a transformer.
Now, he begged me
not to kill him.
I mean, that's what put me
over the edge, the begging.
So, now you're feeling
guilty about this.
Fuck, no.
I'm thinking,
I was the last guy
to hear this jag's voice.
I own his last words.
I'm not following.
I got a feeling you own my sister's,
and I want them.
Oh, well, yes, we did have a chat
shortly before the bus crashed.
She said that
she loved you very much
and that she was very excited
about seeing you.
And I couldn't wait
to see her.
I mean, her smiling face... she was
the spitting image of our mother.
Now you gotta
tell me, Father,
did Annette
at least die happy?
She seemed to be
in very good spirits,
except for the problems
that she was having in her marriage.
- She was having problems?
- Yeah, you didn't know about that?
No, what kind of problems?
Well, I'm not sure
of the specifics.
L-l... maybe you better
ask her husband.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm gonna
do just that.
Damn, you look nicer
in here than you did out.
At least you still
look like shit.
It's been
a tough time,
planning the funeral
and all.
Yeah. Well, how you doing
about Annette?
Okay, I guess.
I mean, me and her,
we was...
Hey, hey, hey, I know.
She was a cunt.
Man, you don't know how happy I am
to hear you say that, Enrique.
I mean, I didn't want to come down
here and lie to you about Annette.
All of a sudden, she wanted
to be this model, right?
She was walking
around South Beach
and she's shoving
her tits in the face
of every agent
and photographer in town.
If she was spreading it around,
you gotta set her straight.
She kept wearing
these skimpy tops
no bigger than
fucking rubber bands.
- You know what I did?
- What?
I cut a fucking chunk
out of her arm.
- The bitch wore sleeves from then on.
- That put her right?
Fuck, no. The girl would spread
her legs for anything that moved,
and sometimes
for things that didn't.
I don't like
to disrespect the dead...
Hey, you know what, Javier?
You never will again.
My sister was a saint,
you motherfucker!
Son of a bitch!
- Fucker!
- Let him go!
- You motherfucker!
You cocksucker!
Father?
Father Mukada?
Come here, please.
I heard that you'd been transferred
back from Benchley Memorial,
that you'll recover
from the stabbing.
Where's Hoyt?
Hoyt confessed
to a series of murders.
Today he's being
transported to death row.
Father, I...
I wanna make
confession as well.
I wanna be
a Roman Catholic again.
No.
What?
What do you...
you can't refuse me.
I sure as hell can.
Welcome to death row,
Hoyt.
In olden times, when you
wanted to know what the future held,
you'd drag your lamb down
to the local witchy woman,
where she'd proceed
to slice him neck to ass,
and read his hot,
steaming entrails.
From this, somehow,
your fortune was revealed,
from some woman
with cataracts and no teeth,
watching your livestock
bleed out.
Seems to me, all you've done
is lost a lamb,
which ain't gonna help
your fortune at all.
No!
Pig! You fucking pig!
No! No!
His violent episodes
are increasing.
Every day now he's getting
into some kind of brawl.
We can't just keep
sedating him.
Well, then get him
out of solitary.
It's making him go crazy.
Send him back to me.
Ryan, I tried.
The warden refuses.
- Why?
- Ryan, your brother killed Li Chen.
In self-defense,
he was gonna rape my ma.
But unfortunately,
you have no proof of that.
And Jia denies ever
having said that to you.
Fucking chink bastard.
Because of that cocksucker,
Cyril's facing
the death penalty now.
If only we could
find someone else
to corroborate
your story.
Oh, fuck,
wait, there is.
I've been so distracted,
I forgot, Glen Shupe.
He overheard Li
threatening my ma.
I'll go tell Leo.
You gotta handle it
so careful.
You know, you gotta treat it
like a piece of fine glass.
It's that fragile.
What is?
Happiness.
Did you or did you not
tell Ryan O'Reily
that Li Chen was gonna
rape O'Reily's mother?
I did not.
Take him back
to Emerald City.
I think I need to go
into protective custody.
Okay.
Leo, it's obvious
he's lying.
He did tell Ryan
about Li Chen.
Listen, it's not for me
to decide, Peter Marie.
That's the jury's job.
But you better explain
to Cyril O'Reily
that what he needs now
is a good lawyer.
Yeah, this is gonna
be a tough one.
The history of Cyril's
violent behavior,
the death
of Hamid Khan,
putting Jia Kenmin in a coma,
various other altercations.
That'll all play right
into the prosecution's hands.
And, Sister,
according to your analysis,
- he knows right from wrong.
- Yes.
Right, like I said...
this is gonna be tough.
- I'll take the case.
- You will?
But Mr. O'Reily,
if I were in your shoes,
I'd go with
a name brand.
Wait, what do you mean
a name brand?
A lawyer who can
razzle-dazzle,
someone who will turn
Cyril's mental state into a cause,
headlines, op-ed pieces,
segments on the nightly news.
- You can't do that?
- Not as well as others.
You need Barnum
and F. Lee Bailey,
Johnnie Cochran,
Ken Starr.
- Get real, those guys are expensive.
- Yes.
So, I guess the question
for you and your family is...
how much is your
brother's life worth?
- So, I'm the cause of all of this?
- No, you're not.
You tried to warn me something
could happen, and I didn't listen.
Don't blame yourself. Having you around
has been great for me and Cyril.
Now we gotta figure out
some way to get him off of death row.
Let's do what that woman said.
Let's hire a big-time attorney.
- You got money?
- Well, I've got some savings.
Well, whatever you have
is not gonna be enough.
Have you talked to your father,
to your Aunt Brenda?
- Why, what good would that do?
- Well, I'm not sure,
but they deserve
to know what's going on.
We need a family meeting.
You and Dad?
In the same room?
- Yes.
- Have you seen him lately?
No, I haven't seen
Seamus O'Reily for over 30 years,
but I can't think
of a better reason
to stare
the old bastard down.
I don't know.
Hey, Dad.
Aunt Brenda, hi.
How are you?
I brought
chocolate peanut clusters,
Cyril's favorite kind.
Oh, I'll make sure
he gets 'em, thanks.
Have a seat.
Suzanne.
Brenda.
For God's sake, Seamus,
we came all this way.
Take another
two steps.
I won't bite.
I promise.
Like you ever
kept a promise?
Let's get down
to business.
Okay, so I explained
the particulars
to the both of you
over the phone
and I just...
I need to know.
Can we afford to hire
the best lawyer to defend Cyril?
- Well, how much are we talking here?
- Upwards of 20,000.
Oh, sweet Jesus.
Neither one of us
have that kind of money,
not even if we stacked together
our nickels and dimes.
Aunt Brenda, I remember
when you got hurt on the job,
and the company, they cut you
a big, fat compensation check.
That's the money
I live on, Ryan.
I mean, that's all
I have for my old age.
Don't you be asking Brenda
to risk her future because of Cyril.
She says
she loves him.
- I do.
- But not enough.
Wait a minute. How come your mother
hasn't asked her family to step up?
You know as well as I
that my family disowned me.
Oh, that's right,
they disowned you.
But not for walking away
from your husband, your children, no.
For blowing up that cop.
For bringing shame
on your father,
the lace-curtain fuck!
I have accepted responsibility
for my actions, Seamus.
Maybe it's time
you did the same.
Hey, I took fucking responsibility
32 years ago!
By putting food
in their mouth,
paying the rent,
wiping their dirty asses!
And where were you,
where the fuck were you?!
Let me ask you
something, Seamus,
and tell me the truth
for the first time in your life.
You and Tessie got together
real quick after I left,
and you had Cyril
a year after we had Ryan.
- So?
- Were you fucking her behind my back?
Yeah.
In fact, I fucked her
the day Ryan was born.
Okay, enough!
Please.
We're talking
about Cyril here, okay?
You know...
I mean, shit,
we're talking
about saving his life.
I mean,
this shit don't matter.
- I mean...
- You're wrong, Ryan.
The shit
is all there is.
You say we have
to save him, for what?
A lifetime in Oz,
you know, with his mind
all a-smuddle?
Maybe the only
generous thing
we can all do
for the boy
is to let him die.
What?
Come on, Seamus,
give me a ride home.
No, no, Brenda,
please don't go.
Please?
There's more.
There has to be more
to a family than just blood, Ryan,
more than Christmas dinners
and the birthday cakes,
more than old hurts
and unsettled scores.
We're not a family.
We never have been.
You knocked on
the wrong door, honey.
See you in another
three decades, you cunt.
I'm so sorry
for that, l...
No, it's okay.
Actually, it went
better than I expected.
Oh, Jesus.
Oh, Ryan.
You know, she is wrong.
She's wrong,
because you and me and Cyril,
we are a family.
I mean, they were
tattered and torn,
but we're gonna
get through this.
Yeah, Aunt Brenda's right
about one thing, though.
The best thing we can do
for Cyril is to let him die.
Oh, shit.
Hiya, Ryan.
Hey, kid.
Whoa, whoa,
wait. Shh.
- Hey, hey, it's okay.
- What happened?
Was I bad again?
Yeah.
- Sorry.
- It's okay.
Can we go back
to Em City now?
No, Cyril, I'm afraid you have
to go back to solitary.
- I don't like solitary.
- I know.
- It's scary.
It's lonely.
Believe me, if I could trade places
with you, I'd do it in a fucking second.
Ryan?
Are you crying?
No.
Boys don't cry.
That's right.
Daddy always said,
"Boys don't cry."
And Daddy knows best.
Out of the way,
O'Reily.
Are you gonna
behave yourself, hmm?
Yes, sir.
Listen...
for all the gypsies,
seers, tea leaves,
tarot cards,
and ouija boards,
your life is
your fucking life.
No, check that.
There is one person
who tells the future for a living,
and he's right
100% of the time.
Who's this magical
motherfucker?
He's called the judge.
And all of us in Oz,
we got our
fortunes told.
And let me tell you,
the future...
it ain't bright.