So there used to be this tribe,
the Aztecs,
who believed that the universe
was created by violence.
Every year,
at what was their version of Christmas,
they would cut out someone's heart
and offer it up to the gods.
These people were convinced
that without this sacrifice,
the sun would fall from the sky
and the world would come to an end.
Then the Spaniards landed and wiped
the Aztecs off the face of the earth.
Turns out they was right.
The world did come to an end.
For them.
Welcome to Oz.
Ten months after the world ended.
All right.
A lot of people thought
we'd never reopen Emerald City,
but after almost a year,
a lot of politicking, ball-busting
and some backup from the warden,
here we are.
- lt's a new deal, gentlemen.
- lt's a better deal.
lt's a fair deal.
Now, l have identified ten groups.
The Muslims, the Gangsters,
the Latinos, the ltalians, the lrish,
the Aryans, the Bikers, the Christians,
the Gays, and one called the Others.
Each group will have four prisoners
living at Em City, no more, no less.
Each group will be equal.
- Each individual, equal.
- Bullshit.
No, it is not bullshit.
And to make sure that it's not,
l'm also establishing a council
to air grievances, to advise me.
Each group will have one member
serve on said council.
- Any questions?
- Yes.
Given all that's happened,
why did you come back?
Why do you still believe
Emerald City will work?
Well, the truth is this:
We either learn to change
or we repeat our mistakes.
We either become a part
of our community,
or we remain isolated from it.
ln either case, the success
of our lives depends on us.
l am not solely responsible
to make Em City work.
lt's you too.
Any other questions?
Kareem, you should be
our representative on the council.
- That's assuming that we participate.
- Are you saying we shouldn't?
No, l'm saying that we wait.
Our absence may speak louder
than our presence.
First thing, we start to sell tits again.
- Yeah, but what about O'Reily?
- l'll handle O'Reily.
l'll handle Adebisi.
What worries me
is the Sicilians coming in.
- l don't see Nino Schibetta anywhere.
- Schibetta's dead.
lt's his son who's the hair
across our ass now.
We're gonna take back
the drug trade,
find out who hurt my father,
and then...
Shit. The rest of these
cock motherfuckers,
they gonna learn, bro.
They can't shit on us no more.
How the fuck
did l get to be an Other?
On the streets, l was selling dope.
l was as bad
as any of those Homeboys.
l fucking killed a cop!
- l'm thrown in here with you guys.
- You're disabled.
And the rest of you
are fucking certifiable.
Who are you?
Agamemnon Busmalis,
a.k.a. The Mole.
- The Mole?
- l dig.
l can dig anywhere.
l'm gonna dig my way out of Oz.
l tell you, l don't belong
with those three clowns, man.
They're crazy. Especially Beecher.
l mean, forget all that shit
he did to Schillinger.
Beecher bit off
some fucker's dick, yo.
That was ten months ago.
Oh, yeah, well, then that's okay.
l gotta share a pod, McManus.
l gotta sleep with one eye open.
Sister Peter Marie says
he's responding to therapy.
Well, then let her bunk with him.
All right, l call this first meeting
of the Emerald City Council to order.
We're gonna need
a recording secretary.
- Anyone know how to write?
- l'll do it.
- l'm famous for my penmanship.
- Here you go, watch out.
Now, a lot of you men
have had raw deals growing up.
Abusive parents,
shitty housing, no jobs.
Now, my goal is to make clear
that each of you
has an equal opportunity
to turn your lives around.
Oh, yeah?
And how you gonna do that?
lnitially, with education.
Over half the inmates in Oz
never finished high school.
The Federal prison system
has mandatory education programs
in place since 1 982.
We're gonna have the same
requirements in Emerald City.
- There's already a program.
- lt's not mandatory.
Yo, who cares, man?
What's important is
we start bringing back them conjugals.
How about
some fucking cigarettes, huh?
One thing at a time, guys.
One thing at a time.
Education first.
Since it's mandatory,
we're gonna have more students.
Therefore,
we're gonna need more teachers.
And since our budget for this thing
is so small, l'm asking for volunteers.
- O'Reily.
- Yeah.
Coushaine, l saw in your files
- you used to teach high school briefly.
- Yeah.
- How about helping us out here?
- Okay.
- Nice one, buddy boy.
- What a trouper.
Okay, okay.
Said, the Muslims weren't represented
at the council meeting.
lf this council has real power,
- then we will participate.
- Well, how do you mean?
Do we get to make policy
or do we simply rubber-stamp yours?
- This is a prison, not a democracy.
- Oh, l know that only too well.
You know, l meant what l said
about a second chance.
l wanna do it right this time.
lf you don't wanna participate,
that's fine. Just don't get in my way.
McManus, you want us to be allies,
but that will never happen.
Better for you to transfer me back
to Gen Pop and be done with me.
No.
You know, when l was laying
in that hospital bed
and l was afraid l was gonna die,
l started praying.
l'm not saying l had
any great spiritual awakening, Said,
but l did come to realize that my God
and yours aren't so different.
They both expect the best from us,
and for us to find the best
in each other.
l've written another book, McManus.
Comes out next month,
it's about the riot.
And when l was writing,
l looked for the best in you.
You wanna know what l found?
A confused, frightened little man.
Well, l was frightened
and l was confused.
But you take a bullet in the chest,
you see things differently.
People can change, Said.
Even me.
Even you.
Kenny.
McManus, you're fucking up my floor,
McManus.
- That's all right.
- My dick.
You don't have to mop it up again.
You went to class
when you first got to Oz,
but then you dropped out.
- l hated that shit.
- So you prefer mopping floors?
l prefer to be chilling with some chicks
and some Henny, but l can't, can l?
What about when you get out?
How you gonna get a job
without an education?
- l got a job when l get out.
- Yeah, what?
l made some connections in here.
People are gonna take care of me.
l see.
You're gonna be selling drugs?
- What do you want, McManus?
- A trade.
- lnstead of this, you get your GED.
- What?
You finish high school.
lt's a simple offer.
Class instead of work, your choice.
And l won't have to mop no more?
All right, l'll look into it.
- Hey.
What you working on there?
l'm working on a poem.
- That's a poem?
- Yeah, it ain't finished yet, though.
- Got any words for it?
- Up here.
- You never write them down?
- lt's easier like this.
Why don't you read it to me?
l gotta keep away from these motels.
These cockroach motels.
But l ain't going out like that.
You see, us cockroaches,
We been around
Since the beginning of time.
Now l'm letting loose
On a little bit of crime.
Look, these motherfucking
Motel makers
They shook.
But l ain't getting caught.
l ain't from the silly sort
Who venture too far from the nest.
You can't touch some sand.
l gotta play the deep dog,
Lower level funk for a sec, though.
LEL shit
Get that mental in check.
Prisoner number 96J332,
Arnold Jackson, a.k.a. Poet.
Convicted February 1 5th, '96.
Armed robbery, attempted murder,
possession of a deadly weapon.
Sentence: 1 6 years.
Up for parole in nine.
Listen, l want you
to start coming to class.
l ain't with that, man. That's not me.
l want you to get your education,
l want you to get a diploma.
Fuck that.
- Man.
- Wait, wait, wait. Just wait.
- l'll tell you what.
- What?
You start going to class,
l'll arrange for you
to have a conjugal visit.
- l ain't even married, man.
- Got a girlfriend?
- Yeah.
- Well, like l said,
you start going to class, you keep
going to class, you get your GED,
l'll arrange for you to see her once.
Ain't there rules about this, man?
Fuck the rules.
Deal?
All right.
Today, we're gonna concentrate
on reading and grammar
so l can get a sense
of everyone's skill level.
Let's start with having somebody
read out loud.
Anybody?
Kenny, right? Yes.
Open to page one
and read the first paragraph.
- What do l need to read this shit for?
- We're all gonna listen,
and if there's a word
we don't understand,
- we're gonna make a vocabulary list.
- A what?
See, there's our first one:
vocabulary.
How many people here know
what the word ''vocabulary'' means?
- Ain't that a disease?
- Okay, vocabulary.
- Vocab--
- Hey, you got that, don't you?
A limp vocabulary?
Fuck you. You ain't even got one.
--bulary.
Now, a vocabulary
is any list of words.
And now, the word ''vocabulary''
can be added to our vocabulary list.
Let's get started. Kenny?
- Let this mick fuck right here read it.
- He'll get a chance. You go first.
l said no, man.
Just open the page. Read page one.
- No big deal.
- You fucking deaf?
l said l ain't reading.
- l'm just asking you to open--
- You fuck--!
Yeah!
Lockdown! Lockdown!
What happened?
- He tried to strangle me.
- Kenny?
- That bitch got in my face!
- l wasn't in your face!
- Do you need a doctor?
- l'm okay.
- How did this happen?
- l asked him to read out loud,
- next thing, he's trying to kill me.
- Fuck you!
- Shut up, Kenny!
- That's what happened.
Take him to my office.
- Why did you do it?
- Look, l told you.
- He got in my face, all right?
- That's bullshit!
We made a deal, and part of the deal
was you do what the teacher tells you.
Look, l'm nobody's prag, McManus.
- Nobody's.
- Fine.
- Read.
- No.
Read. Read it.
What does that say?
Look at it.
What does it say?
McDonald's.
Officer.
Take him back to his cell, please.
- l want Wangler in the hole.
- lt's not that Wangler wouldn't read,
he couldn't read.
Leo, the kid can't fucking read at all.
So that excuses his behaviour?
No, it gives us insight
how to help him.
- And you're gonna teach him to read?
- Yeah.
A hundred and fifty years ago,
it was against the law
to teach a slave to read.
But some did
because they had a thirst for it.
Well, now, the reverse is also true.
You cannot force someone to learn.
l can try.
Them Aztecs, they had this king,
Montezuma ll.
That's the Halls of Montezuma guy.
One night, Montezuma
saw this flaming ear of corn
shoot across the sky.
A comet.
Montezuma saw this comet
as an omen,
a sign of his own downfall.
And so he surrendered his empire
to the Spanish conquistadors
without a fight.
Have a seat.
Stupid fuck.
You gotta fight,
even if you know you're gonna lose.
You know what this is called?
''Learning to Read.''
Oh, man.
Lesson one.
A.
- That is definitely rat shit.
- One big fucking rat. Smell it.
Get that away from me.
Well, we gotta kill this motherfucker.
- With some traps or something.
- You can't kill rats.
Rats and cockroaches,
they'll inherit the whole fucking planet.
Whoa, what's the fucking hold-up?
Easy, easy, we're coming.
Which one of you moolies
is the cook back there?
Hey, l ain't no moolie, pal.
What's your fucking problem?
- Problem is, the food sucks.
- Don't eat it.
Things are gonna
start to change around here.
Oh, yeah, who says?
- Peter Schibetta.
- Who Schibetta?
- l'm talking to the mick.
- Mick?
- Peter wants the kitchen back.
- Tell him okay if he sucks my dick.
You ain't careful,
you might not have a dick to suck.
You think they know about Nino?
- That we killed him?
- Who gives a fuck?
l took care of Nino,
l'll take care of them.
Come on, come on.
- Where you going?
- l need to talk to you about your father.
What do you know about my father?
l know how he died.
l know who killed him.
- Who?
- Adebisi.
- Adebisi, the moolie in the kitchen.
He was putting ground glass
in Nino's food every day.
That's how he died.
- How do you know that?
- l saw him grinding up the glass.
And when he wasn't looking,
l put the same glass in his food.
- Hold him.
- No.
Fuck off!
- Did you kill my father?
- No!
- That's what you're telling me!
- Adebisi killed him.
l was trying to kill Adebisi.
- Why?
- He's totally out of control.
He stores up most of the tits
that we bring into this place.
l helped your father
when he was alive.
l figured you and me
could do the same.
Let him go.
lf that fucking mulignane
killed my father, l'll take care of him.
Now excuse me,
l'm in the middle of a workout.
Well, just so you know,
l'm here for you.
Yeah, l heard you the first time.
You believe him?
All rats know
when to desert a sinking ship.
He's a smart one,
but a rat just the same.
Keep an eye on him.
Prisoner number 98S 1 1 2,
Peter Schibetta.
Convicted May 19th, '98.
Five counts of extortion,
money laundering.
Sentence: 35 years.
Up for parole in 20.
lt's open.
- Thank you, officer.
- You want me in or out?
Out, please.
Sit there.
You're a tough man to reach
all of a sudden.
- What does that mean?
- l'm here three weeks,
and this is the first time
you'd see me.
- What do you want?
- A return favour.
- What kind of favour?
- l want the kitchen.
Me and my guys
will run it from now on.
- Why?
- Because l'm asking.
- That's how it works between us now.
- No.
The way it works
is you're in my prison.
l don't take orders from you.
You take them from me.
This doesn't have to be complicated.
All l have to do is make one phone call.
l know.
Your father,
he was a respectable man.
We got along, and he never
would have pulled this shit with me.
My father lived by a code
that doesn't exist anymore.
A code that got him killed.
l do things my way
and l'm asking for a favour
in return for a favour you owe me.
So, what's it gonna be?
All right.
You can have the kitchen.
- Thank you, Leo.
- Warden Glynn.
We're done here.
Officer Armstrong.
Where do l find a knife?
Adebisi.
Hey, Adebisi.
Peter Schibetta will be running
the kitchen from now on.
Schibetta?
Why are you giving that guinea
my job?
- Because l can.
- All right.
Well, you tell that guinea fuck
something from me, then.
We got rats.
l'm gonna start unwrapping
the bandages now.
Dr. Richards thinks
that the surgery was successful.
You'll have a scar, but your sight
should be nearly fully restored.
Okay.
Tell me if l hurt you.
Okay, open your eye.
- Can you see?
- Yes.
Good.
- Let's go get a martini.
- What?
You know, when l was a lawyer,
after a long day
of trials and tribulations,
we'd all head over
to McSwaggins' for a vodka martini.
Dry, one olive.
Man, that would taste
so good right now.
Too many martinis is what
landed you here in the first place.
Hi. Do you have Schillinger's
psych profile ready yet?
Tim and l have to review it
before parole hearing.
l'm not finished yet.
- Another day okay?
- Sure.
Tobias, pull up Schillinger's file.
l'm going to the ladies' room.
She leaves you in here alone?
Why?
What do you think l'm gonna do?
Start a riot? Take hostages?
Listen, you're not making
any fucking sense.
- What the hell is going on?
- l threw them both out.
Those fucking boys of yours
are fucking out of control.
Drugs all the time and they're stealing
from me to pay for them.
- Where are they?
- Who knows and who the fuck cares?
You listen to me,
you stupid old bastard, you find them.
- You find my sons.
- And then what?
Bring them to Oz
for a little heart-to-heart?
Hey, don't you walk away,
you cocksucker!
Come on, Dad.
- Get the fuck back here, Dad!
- Party's over. Knock it off.
- God! Goddamn it, Dad!
- l said, knock it off!
You find my boys!
Well, Vern, baby.
Oh, l knew
that was gonna leave a fucking mark.
What you reading? Mein Kampf?
Let me tell you how it ends.
The Aryans get their ass kicked.
l've been doing some reading myself.
Your psychiatric profile.
According to Sister Peter Marie,
you have demonstrated
a genuine personality adjustment.
Bullshit. You're faking it
so you can make parole.
l'm gonna see to it
that you never leave Oz.
You hear me, sweet pea?
Never, ever.
Fill her up.
- l need an ask.
- What kind of ask?
Kill Beecher.
The motherfucker's crazy.
Wasting him, that's a pretty big favour.
All right, forget favour.
Job, l'll pay.
No way.
- Mark, how about you?
- No way, man.
Anybody?
- Pussies.
- Fuck you.
Yeah, you kill him.
l wish to Christ l could.
Hey. You guys doing business?
- Depends on what kind of business.
- l need somebody to kill Beecher.
Plenty of mooks around here
who will whack that nut.
- You?
- l'm no mook, pal.
Why don't you try the Latinos?
l thought you had no use
for us Latinos?
Will you whack Beecher or not?
Depends on what we get in return.
All right, l work the mailroom, right.
l can push whatever you need,
in or out, through the system.
- Tits?
- Sure.
l thought you were anti-drugs.
l don't care if you smuggle in
fucking tacos.
l want Beecher dead. Today.
What else? What else you got?
What the fuck do you mean,
what else?
No, mailbox shit is nice,
but l want more.
- More?
- Everything. Everything you got, man.
Goddamn it,
you fucking spic cocksucker.
See? That's the Schillinger
l know and love, baby.
Fuck you.
Get the fuck away from me.
You know the wonderful thing
about computers?
They don't know right from wrong.
You push a button,
they do what you tell them to do.
- People aren't like that.
- Get away from me.
Believe it or not,
l think you're gonna wanna hear this.
Working in the psych office,
l have access to all the files
from the whole prison.
l can change those files
to read any which way.
l can take away infractions,
or add them.
Like in your file,
the one the parole board's gonna see.
- Get the fuck away from me!
- What's the problem?
Him! He's the goddamn problem!
Then why are you the one yelling?
Take a walk.
- He's a bug, Wittlesey.
- You're all fucking bugs.
- Yeah, what about you?
- What are you talking about?
Like l said, l saw everything.
l saw you shoot Scott Ross.
Keep moving.
l know about your kid too,
and your mom being sick.
You could use
some extra cash, right?
Keep fucking moving.
You do Beecher like you did Ross,
l'll pay you.
- You'll pay me to kill Beecher?
- Two thousand dollars.
My parole hearing's tomorrow.
lf l get out, what l know goes with me.
l would need the money up front.
l can make a call
and wire it to your account.
Okay, soon as l get verification,
Beecher's dead.
When the Aztecs first saw
the Spaniards on horseback,
they thought the man and the horse
were one creature,
and the Aztecs knelt down
and worshipped this creature as God.
Sometimes, what you see
is not what is.
Hey, did you see that shit last night
between Wittlesey and Beecher?
- They're probably fucking.
- She didn't look too romantic to me.
Wittlesey was helping
Beecher escape.
He paid her to get him get out of Oz.
- They're fucking.
- No, l just heard they been fucking.
But Beecher was gonna tell someone,
so Wittlesey tried to kill his ass.
Say what to who?
That they'd been fucking.
He was gonna tell everyone.
- So, what?
- So?
So she banging
half the COs in this place.
Beecher opens his mouth,
that piss off the COs,
so she grabs Beecher, pop, pop.
l ain't seen him this morning.
That's for sure.
- That's because he escaped.
- l'll tell you, he's dead.
Who gives a fuck?
Come on, let's go.
So last night?
- You wanted Beecher dead, right?
- Yeah, l wanted him dead.
You paid me, right? Two grand?
Yeah.
You wanna see the body?
Shit. Sure.
All right.
lt's in here.
What the fuck?
- Nice try, Vern baby.
- Beecher.
You got anything to say?
About what?
l don't know what you're talking about.
- You wanted Beecher dead, right?
- Yeah, l wanted him dead.
You can forget about
your parole hearing.
lnstead, get yourself a good lawyer.
We're charging you
with conspiracy to commit murder.
This is bullshit. l'm being set up.
Take him to the hole.
And a merry sing-song
Happy let us be
Merry was myself
And merry l could sing
With a merry ding-dong
Happy, gay and free
And a merry sing-song
Happy let us be
- What are you so cheerful about?
- Hill, you think l'm insane, right?
- Shit, yeah.
- Well, maybe l am.
But every once in a while,
the lawyer in me still pops out.
- Yeah?
- l wanted Schillinger away from me.
Out of Em City, but not free.
l had to figure out a way
to get his parole hearing cancelled.
l couldn't start a fight with him,
or l'd get in trouble.
So l manipulated him.
l got him so psycho
that he tried to have me killed.
So now, not only
is Schillinger's parole chances dead,
but he's facing ten more years.
That's good, moyel.
And bad.
With no hope of leaving Oz,
now he's got even more reason
to fuck you up.
Yeah, well, thank God l'm crazy
because l don't give a shit.
Merry are the bells
And merry would they ring
And merry was my cell
And merry l would sing
With a merry ding-dong
l became free
And a merry sing-song
Happy let us be
- Hi.
- ls he in?
- With Father Mukada.
- For long?
- l don't think so.
Okay, l'll wait.
- So how do you like your new job?
- lt's fine.
- The warden's a very nice man.
- Yeah, he is.
l have to admit, the idea
of working in a prison terrified me,
but l've really gotten used to it.
Good.
Warden's office.
Sure. Hold on a moment.
Warden, your wife's on line three.
- Tell her l'll call her back.
- She says it's urgent.
- All right.
- Okay.
You know, l know what
you were saying about being afraid
because the first couple of weeks here
l was a nervous wreck.
- l think you're just being nice.
- No.
lt's very hard to imagine
you nervous about anything.
Believe me.
- Oh, Leo, good.
- l gotta go.
- l just wanna ask you one ques--
- l don't know when l'll be back.
Something's happened.
Something's wrong.
Diane.
- Are you avoiding me?
- No.
Look, l want you to come back
and work at Em City.
- l'm happy where l am.
- Yeah, but l need you.
Oh, sure.
Diane.
The way that you handled
this thing on Schillinger...
Schillinger says
that you murdered Scott Ross.
You read the commission's report.
Ross was shot by the SORT team.
Yeah, but he says he's gonna tell
everybody that you shot Ross.
So? No one's gonna listen
to Schillinger, Tim.
Especially since
l turned him in on Beecher.
- Did you kill Ross?
- No.
What, are you gonna believe
that Nazi's word over mine?
Excuse me.
Warden Glynn just called.
He's not gonna make it back in time
and he'd like Sister Peter Marie
to run the meeting.
- Okay.
- Here's the agenda.
Sarah, did he say what happened?
Only that his daughter
is in the hospital.
Oh, well, what do you think
we should do?
Do what Leo wants. Let's get
the meeting started. Good morning.
- Excuse me.
- ltem one...
- Yeah.
- Warden, it's time for you
to address the prisoners.
Okay.
All right, starting next month,
the librarian
will be available in the library
from 1 to 5 pm
Monday to Friday only.
Yeah, that's because the rest
of the time, she gonna be with me.
- What did you say?
- Nothing.
Bring him to my office.
- Yeah?
- Miguel Alvarez.
Send him in.
Thank you, officer.
Yo.
Get up!
- Man, what the fuck is going on?
- You've been reassigned
- to work here in my office.
- Yeah, so, what you need me to do?
Go over to the door.
And?
Stand there.
What, you just want me
to stand here?
Until l need you to do something.
Yo, l got visiting hours at 4.
My mom and my sisters
are coming. So...
Yeah, l know.
Yeah, okay.
Really?
Warden?
- Yeah?
- lt's ten to 4, man.
- Yeah.
- Well, l haven't done dick all day, man.
l've been standing here.
My mother and my sisters
are coming in ten minutes.
You're right.
You haven't done dick all day.
- Clean my bathroom.
- What?
Clean the bathroom.
The floor, the sink, scrub the toilet.
And when you're done,
when it's spotless,
go meet your family.
- Are you fucking with me?
- You're right, l'm fucking with you.
The mop and the bucket are in there.
Shit! Shit!
Fuck!
Caught you.
He said he was leaving it
right here, but l don't see it.
- What's your name?
- Sarah.
Hey, Miguel.
l know.
You and me, it's weird, huh?
l mean,
how we don't have much contact.
l'm always on one side of the door,
you're always on the other side.
But l see you.
l see you looking at me
when you open the door.
l'm not looking at you.
Come on, l see you looking at me
looking at you.
l gotta tell you something,
and l know you know,
you're beautiful.
And you are flirting with me.
What, you gonna have me arrested?
- Sarah, where the hell is that file?
- l can't find it.
- She's been looking hard, man.
- Shut up!
You don't talk unless l speak to you.
And don't you ever, ever talk to her.
- Do you understand?
- What, talk to her?
l already fucked her.
The fuck up her!
Fuck you! Get the fuck off me!
Get the fuck off me!
You're fucking choking me!
You're choking me!
Get the fuck off!
Fuck you, fuck you!
- We got him, we got him.
- Wanna fuck with me?
- Take him to the hole!
You're a fucking pussy!
Don't fucking hit me!
Fuck, come with me. Fucking bitch.
Fuck you. Get the fuck off!
You're bleeding.
Ah, gymnasium.
The smell of testosterone,
the smell of sweat.
You have something
to say to me, just say it.
Well, Sarah's thinking about quitting
because of what happened today
between you and Alvarez.
Then she should quit.
Well, maybe so, maybe not,
but that's not the point.
You know, Leo,
when somebody asks me
what's the real Leo Glynn like,
the first word that comes to mind:
Balanced.
The most balanced person l know.
And the second word:
Honest.
Listen.
l don't want you
to tell anybody about this.
You have my word.
My oldest daughter, Ardith,
she was walking to class.
She's a student, you know,
at the university.
They raped her.
Oh, my God.
She's in the hospital.
She's lying there
with her eyes open.
Some kind of shock.
She is just the sweetest person
on the planet, you know.
l mean, never a bad word
to say about anybody.
l know, l know.
So do they have any idea
who did this?
Witnesses say
they saw a gang of kids.
Latino kids.
So some unknown
Latino kid hurts Ardith
and you lash out
at the first Latino you see?
- No, no.
- Leo.
Leo, Miguel Alvarez
did not rape your daughter.
And whatever else he's done before,
you are too fine a man to punish him
for something he didn't do.
You're going back to Em City.
- Does Glynn know about this?
- Yep.
What?
Did you convince him to let me out?
Nope.
You know,
l haven't seen you since...
- Look, what happened with the riot--
- l don't wanna talk about it, Miguel.
Miguel. Miguel!
No! Miguel!
l've already forgiven you, all right?
l expect you'll do the same
for Warden Glynn.
Besides horses, the Aztecs
had never seen a cannon.
They had never seen such raw,
boom power thundering at them.
They was afraid.
Between the cannons and the horses,
the fucking comet,
shit, that whirlwind turned
pretty fucking fast, son.
l don't know.
Come on, come on, come on.
- Hey, O'Reily.
- Yo.
- Did you spill coffee on yourself?
- What are you talking about?
Fuck.
Does that hurt?
Well?
Do it again.
This is a medical examination,
O'Reily, not foreplay.
Yeah, says you.
ls there any pain
when l touch your nipple?
No.
Has it swelled up or been sore?
A little, but l just figured it's because
l've been exercising a lot lately, yeah.
ln general,
your health has been good?
l'm alive, right?
All right. Well,
we'll have to run some blood tests.
- Take some x-rays.
- What do you think it is?
Beats me. l'm gonna have to
crack open my medical books.
l think we'll keep you
in the ward overnight.
No problem, just so long
as you come and tuck me in.
Suck out his blood.
Hi.
What's your name?
Blackjack. Read them and weep.
Ryan.
Hold those.
Ryan?
You're calling me Ryan?
Can l call you Gloria?
l got your test results from the lab.
Oh, shit. Does that mean
l'm going back to Em City, huh?
- l was just starting to get comfortable.
- You're not leaving quite yet.
This lump under your left nipple,
it's a tumour.
l need to do
what we call an aspiration.
We draw a small amount of fluid
out of the nipple
and examine it under a microscope.
- To look for what?
- A carcinoma.
Ryan,
you may have breast cancer.
That's funny.
l'm not kidding.
Breast cancer?
- Girls get breast cancer.
- Men do too.
lt's rare, especially at your age,
but it does happen.
- l'm not a fag, you know that?
- Ryan--
No, l've been in this shit hole
for over a year,
and l ain't ever taken it up the ass.
No one is saying that you have.
Bullshit! You're telling me
l've got a chick's disease!
- Men have breasts, same as women.
- What the fuck are you talking about?
l don't got any breasts.
l got a chest. See it, huh?
- See it?
- Dr. Nathan?
lt's okay, it's okay.
You listen to me.
You go back inside
your medical books.
You suck out more of my blood.
You do what you gotta do,
but you get me another verdict.
You understand me?
Because l ain't got
any fucking breast cancer.
Fuck.
Well, you can't really blame him
for overreacting.
l mean, men with breast cancer?
Who's ever heard of it?
Gloria, are you absolutely positive
about the diagnosis?
Look, l'm a GP.
lt's not the kind of thing
l come across every day,
but l called a friend of mine
who's an oncologist,
ran the specifics down.
He said he'd be hard pressed
to figure out what else it indicates.
- So do the needle aspiration.
- O'Reily says no.
He's in denial.
Now, if he does have it,
he's gonna need all our help
to accept the reality
of what's happening to him.
To fight the disease.
l have a pretty good relationship
with him. l'll talk to him.
l think, you know, maybe l should.
Maybe he'll feel more comfortable
talking about it with a guy.
- Maybe he'll be embarrassed.
- Well, see him together.
No, then he'll think
that we're ganging up on him.
- Got the perfect solution here.
- What?
- Sister Pete, heads or tails?
- Heads.
Ryan.
All of a sudden everyone's
on a first-name basis with me?
Look, Dr. Nathan told me
about the cancer.
Hey. For chrissakes, would you?
l don't need every asshole in here
knowing about my business.
We can go into my office
if you want.
For what?
We got nothing to say to each other.
Nathan's got this whole thing
screwed up.
Maybe.
But the only way
we're gonna know for sure
is if we do the biopsy.
Let's just say, for the sake
of argument, that she's right.
Then what, huh?
l go back into Em City,
those fucks find out.
You know as well as l do,
any weakness,
any weakness at all, and l'm dead.
Look, if you do have...
lf you're sick
and you don't do anything about it,
you're dead anyway.
Don't you see that?
lf this shit
spreads through your body,
then everybody's
gonna know the truth.
And by then
it will be too late to save your life.
l'm sorry.
Yeah.
So here's the funny part.
The Spaniards actually exterminated
the Aztecs by accident.
Yeah, they had the horses
and the cannons,
but they also brought over
smallpox.
lt was a disease
that finally finished the job.
A disease the Spanish gave the Aztecs
without even knowing.
ln Oz, we do
what we can to survive.
But ultimately, it doesn't matter.
Life always gets in the way.