Oz
In the beginning
was the word.
And the word was with God,
and the word was God.
So, from the starting gun,
it's all about the word.
All about communication.
Couple million millennia
go by, along comes man.
God wants somebody
to chat with.
Turns out man wants
more than that.
Man wants the gossip page
and phone sex,
reruns of "Seinfeld"
and auctions in cyberspace.
Man's got his own plan
as far as communication goes
and the inventions to see it through.
And poor God...
He's still got
no one to talk to.
Thanks for getting here
so quick.
So tell me,
what happened?
About an hour ago
a man posing as
a newspaper reporter...
...entered the visiting
room to see Kareem Said.
- He pulled out a gun...
...shot Said dead.
Oh my God.
Get the fuck
out of here, man!
Your press pass
says that your name
is Lemuel Idzik.
Is that in fact
your real name?
Who'd make up
a name like that?
Yes.
Idzik.
I'm Detective McGorry,
Homicide.
I need to ask you
some questions.
I did it.
I killed Kareem Said.
What more is there?
You'd be willing
to sign a confession.
Yes.
You write out the words,
and I'll sign it
in my best penmanship.
After I've read you your rights,
I'll want you to tell me
what happened.
Here's all I'll say.
I had to kill him
before nightfall.
Leo, we just got an inquiry
from a local TV station
wanting verification
of Said's death.
Shit!
How'd the word get out so fast?
I guess the Muslims
must have contacted them.
Well, don't call
the station back just yet.
They said they're
sending over a news truck.
Well, don't let them
on the grounds.
Have them park in that empty
lot across Monroe Boulevard.
Well, that was
relatively easy.
- Did Idzik say why he killed Said?
- No.
No, he just kept
talking about nightfall,
whatever the hell
that means.
I'm gonna
take him downtown.
And I'm gonna find out
how the fuck a man with a gun
could get into Oz.
According to the logbook,
you signed Lemuel Idzik in.
Seems so, sir.
And you checked him
thoroughly for weapons?
He went through
the metal detector
same as everyone else.
And the machine
didn't go off?
No, sir.
Would've noticed it.
Breese, I've had
to discipline you twice
for drinking on duty.
I can smell the alcohol
on your breath.
- My wife's got cancer.
- Look, I don't care!
You have a job, man,
a responsibility.
And you failed.
As a result
a man is dead.
A prisoner.
Here's what
I want you to do.
Change out
of your uniform,
and then get the fuck
out of my prison!
The way things are going,
it won't be yours much longer.
Jesus Christ,
what the fuck's going on?
Mayor Loewen, Harrison Beecher,
Schibetta, Kirk,
now Kareem Said,
all murdered in a matter of weeks.
There doesn't seem to be a link
between any of these deaths.
Is that supposed
to make me feel better?
Do you have any suspects
for the Wilson Loewen case?
There were 11 men
on the ward that night.
All of them
are suspects.
The difficulty is
narrowing the list.
Look, just pick someone,
any of these scumbags.
Governor, you're not actually
suggesting that I do that?
I'm suggesting that you do
your job, McGorry, and fast,
before I tell
the police commissioner
to put another
Sherlock in charge.
So, Detective,
now what?
Beats me.
Easy answer is that a black man
murdered Loewen,
only my gut tells me
that's not what happened.
This isn't about prejudice.
This... this is personal.
Somebody hired somebody
to kill Loewen.
Yeah, but who
and why?
The printing press
changed the world forever,
and for the better.
Bibles got printed in vernacular
rather than Latin,
bringing God out
of the Dark Ages,
out of dark corners,
to ordinary folks
like you and me.
But imagine old Gutenberg
at a newsstand today.
Think he'd be proud
of paving the way for "Jugs,"
"High Times"
and "Soldier of Fortune"?
Well, look who's back.
What's with
the news trucks outside?
Oh, you know.
Same old nonsense.
Metal objects.
Step through.
Who are you
here to see?
My client
Chris Keller.
Client. Is that what
they're calling it now?
Are you carrying any alcohol,
drugs, weapons or explosives?
- No.
- Very good, sign here.
Social security number there,
favorite color there.
A little humor
breaks up the day.
You going in
or not, Beecher?
- Tobias...
- Hey.
Tobias, I have...
I have terrible news.
Kareem Said
is dead.
What?
Brice Tibbets' murder case.
A witness has come forward.
Imagine that.
So, we're going
to file a motion today
to have your
death sentence overturned.
Toby, do you really think
there's a chance?
I mean,
with this eyewitness?
Well, you see,
he's the key.
I kept wondering why
Jerry Heekin waited
four years to contact
the authorities.
And then the law firm
did some digging.
Heekin was caught dealing
crack, your dad told me.
Last year.
And he was arrested for the third time.
Three strikes, right?
So, hoping for a deal
he goes to the FBI,
says he saw you
dump Brice Tibbets' body.
Whether he did or not
is immaterial,
because I think your pal
Agent Taylor
helped him fill in
most of the details.
In Heekin's initial conversation
with the FBI,
he doesn't say anything
about the flashlight.
Only afterwards, to the D.A.
Does he add the flashlight
to the story.
Which is bullshit,
right?
Because you would've noticed
somebody shining a flashlight on you.
Especially if you're
dumping a dead body.
Oh, Christ Almighty, this is
what I kept saying to McClain.
Well,
the bottom line is,
he can cut a deal with the D.A.
Pending your conviction.
Because of that, we can imply
Heekin made up the whole story
or was given the account
by Agent Taylor.
Unreliable witness testimony
plus prosecutorial misconduct
equals an overturned verdict.
That's beautiful.
Can you girls keep
the giggling down?
Yeah, I'd better
get over to the courthouse.
Hey, all we've been doing
is talking about legal shit.
How you doing...
with your father gone
and now Said?
Hey, it's okay.
I'm sorry.
Toby, what's it like...
being free?
It's, uh...
the zoo,
the soccer field.
We're outdoors constantly,
you know?
Spending time
with my kids, real time.
It's little things, like helping them
with their homework.
Going to P.T.S.A. Meetings.
Holly's teacher is this
really funny, smart woman.
You'd love her.
She's...
she makes me laugh out loud.
I'm happy for you, Toby.
- I'm happy for you.
- Hey, what'd I tell you two?
No smooching!
Time to go.
Get me out of here.
Get me the fuck away
from Lopresti.
Thank you, Officer.
Good morning.
- Hello, gorgeous.
- We're in that kind of mood, huh?
All right,
under a new state law
every six months
I have to review
the mental health
of every resident
of death row
and it's your turn.
So, how's your
mental health?
Beecher seems to think my days
on death row are numbered.
Yeah, I know.
I saw him earlier.
How'd he seem to you?
Well, he's obviously
grieving for the loss
of his father and Said.
Yeah, I mean
other than that.
What are you
asking me exactly?
Beecher's in love.
Really?
Did he say so?
I can tell.
And how does
that make you feel?
I don't know.
Come on, Chris,
don't bull me.
How does that
make you feel?
Happy!
- For him?
- Yes.
And for you?
Jealous.
And what are you going
to do with that jealousy?
Chew on it? Suck on it?
Devour it whole?
Yeah, okay?
Beecher has what I want!
I want a life!
I get executed
and he lives a long old life
surrounded by
his grandchildren.
I want a life!
You can't expect me
not to be a little envious.
Sure I can.
If you truly love him,
I expect that and more.
I'll write in my review
that you're behaving normally.
Mail call.
Hey, Vern, I heard
about your pal Loewen.
A tragedy.
A fuckin' tragedy.
Well well well,
look at this.
The three of us
together again. I'm all misty.
Hey, Vern,
wait a minute.
I want you to hear something.
You too, Lopresti.
"Upon considering the body
of relevant precedence
in general and in holdings
of the court blah blah blah,
I am compelled
to conclude that
the petitioner's claim
is meritorious."
- Meaning?
- You're out of here.
- No shit?
- No shit.
Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
Toby.
I owe you my life.
Winthrop.
You're Keller, right?
Mm-hmm.
- I heard plenty of stories about you.
- Yeah?
I've heard a couple
about you myself.
There's one in particular
that interests me.
I interest you?
Fascinate
is a better word.
Meet me later,
storage closet, unit B.
Okay.
Nice.
I thought you only
had eyes for Beecher.
Beecher's the one who
brought you and me together.
- What do you mean?
- That story I heard,
the one that fascinates me.
Yeah?
That's the one where you
killed Beecher's father.
No no! No no!
Hey, Keller.
How's it feel to be
back in the gen pop?
Sweet.
One day in 1876,
Alexander Graham Bell
uttered through a wire,
"Watson, come here.
I want you."
130 years later we're talking
through satellites.
Strange, huh,
that before hanging up
we say,
"Keep in touch,"
when there's never
any touch involved,
no contact.
Just cables
and frequencies.
Still...
to get
an l-love-you call
in the middle
of a shitty day,
that makes a cell phone
seem miraculous.
By and large, things are
off to a good start.
A few glitches, but nothing
I didn't factor in.
I confess, I'm the type
who hangs up as soon
as I smell
a solicitation.
What percentage of these
calls actually get people
to donate to Senator
Laken's campaign?
Believe it or not, you only need
a 1-2% success rate
for telemarketing
to be effective.
2%?
I like to do better. My numbers
are hovering in the 5-6% range.
Your men are proving
to be very effective.
- Mrs. Howard?
- Yes.
Good afternoon. I'm calling
on behalf of the campaign
to re-elect Archibald Laken into
the United States Senate.
May I have a moment
of your time?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
Mr. Erickson, good afternoon,
I'm calling on behalf of...
Mrs. Sharif,
good afternoon.
Persevere,
Kenaniah, persevere.
Senator Laken's record
has been outstanding,
especially in regard
to education,
national security
and anti-crime measures.
How are the others
holding up?
We're sad...
demoralized, you know.
Kareem had made plans for us
to start a bookbinding business,
and the preparations
are in motion.
And the first book
was supposed to be
Augustus Hill's memoir?
Well, you have
to keep going, Zahir.
In order to honor
them both,
you have to galvanize your
men to complete the task
Said set for you.
I tried to lead
once before.
I failed.
You know,
Said and I
didn't always agree,
but I know one thing,
this is the moment
he would've trusted in Allah.
I've spoken to the publisher
of Hill's book.
He wants to go forward.
So, it's up to us
to fulfill the promise,
to achieve the vision
of Minister Said.
But first, we must
choose someone to lead.
I nominate Zahir Arif.
All in favor?
Yo, what'd you call me?
Yo, fuck you,
you greasy old bitch.
- Hey, Poet.
- Oh, what you think?
I don't know where 122 Wayne Street is?
Think again, bitch.
What the fuck's wrong
with you, son?
Nah, she said
she wasn't about to give
her credit card number
to some strange spook.
How the fuck
she even know I was black?
That's irrelevant.
You hang up and calmly
move on to the next call.
No, man, fuck that.
I ain't putting my pride on the line,
so some bullshit senator
can get re-elected.
Well, in that case,
you're fired.
- What?
- You heard me.
Carry your lazy ass
and that bad attitude
off the premises!
- Move it.
- Fuck you, Burr.
Fuck you!
Well, what the fuck
you looking at?
Get back to work.
All of you!
It's a good thing
we got out now, yo.
I'll tell you.
Man, that telemarketing,
man,
- that shit short the brain.
- Yo, no shit.
I'll tell you,
I got a plan, though.
Yo, we're going
to work for Arif.
McManus
and the Sicilians
will think we're
done dealing, right?
We lay low for a minute,
then we come back
double-time
up underneath
the radar without Burr.
- Know what I mean?
- Yeah, son.
Sounds like quite
a crowd out there.
Yeah, I know.
So, I spoke with Augustus'
wife and the Hudack family.
And everyone's willing to make
a deal on the royalties,
so, we can move forward.
It's exciting.
Yeah, and terrifying.
Should we open
the doors?
Nacim, close the door.
Hold up for just
another minute.
- What you doing?
- Hold up.
We need to pray.
Miss Coffo,
I finished the book.
- That was fast.
- It was good, funny.
Sit down and tell me what you liked
about it and what you didn't.
I can't right now. I got
some business to attend to.
- Business?
- I'll come back tomorrow.
In the meantime, can you
find me another book?
On baseball?
Whatever, as long
as it's funny and good.
Bob, I'm a perfect mess.
Hello, Stella.
Today's the day I'm supposed
to see Norma and I'm wavering.
Don't waver,
Agamemnon.
Put on a tie,
some aftershave,
slick your hair back
like you always do.
It's time Norma and I see each other
for who we really are,
liver spots and all.
Why am I putting myself
through this?
Because a part of you
is in love,
and that's the part
that matters.
You've been reading
too much poetry, Bob.
Love sucks, remember?
Hello.
Nice to see you.
Please, let's skip the pleasantries.
We know why we're here.
I should just dive
right into an explanation.
After stranding me at the altar
and then getting pregnant,
- yeah, I think that you should.
- Okay.
Basically, I got stuck
in that snowstorm
on the way
to our wedding.
As I sat there trapped,
I had time to think.
All along,
I had told myself
I could handle a marriage
to a man in prison.
But sitting there,
I had clarity for the first time
about how hard
it would really be.
I used my cell phone
to call Elliot.
Elliot?
Who's Elliot?
The man I was with
when I met you.
You had a boyfriend
when we met
and you
dumped him for me?
- Yes.
- Oh, wow.
Anyway, Elliot comes and digs me out
and we go to dinner.
He tells me his mom died
and I guess we both drowned our
sorrows in a bottle of cheap wine.
One thing led
to another and well...
He had you
for dessert.
But during the sex
I thought of you.
It's not a delusion,
what you and I feel.
It's love.
"Think not,
thou canst weep a tear
and thy Maker
is not near.
Oh, He gives us His joy
that our grief
He may destroy
till our grief
is fled and gone,
He doth sit by us
and moan."
I love the timbre
of your voice, Robert.
Wrap it up,
Rebadow.
Five minutes
to count.
Fine, I'll be there
in four.
Don't be late,
lover boy.
Did you know that Blake
and his wife used to sit
in their garden and read
to each other naked?
With no concern
for the passerby.
This may sound crazy,
Stella,
but I want to do that
with you, just once.
Oz has a garden?
I could pay a C.O.
For privacy,
and you could bring
a plant.
We'll lock the door,
kill the lights,
sit by a candle to read
"The Marriage
of Heaven and Hell,"
naked as the day
we were born.
It's a lovely thought,
but I don't know
if I can even finish
what I've started here.
Robert, I'm sick.
I've been diagnosed
with breast cancer.
Oh, don't start
imagining the worst.
I'm gonna be okay.
I can't be late
for count.
You okay?
Fine.
The most noncommittal word
in the English language, fine.
So, I've been
thinking...
I might let Norma
bring her baby in.
- Oh.
- I'm not sure.
But she did dump the jerk
for me in the first place.
I guess the bottom line
is the ego doesn't need
- that much to rebound.
- Uh-huh.
Besides,
his name's Elliot.
Who can be jealous
of a guy named Elliot?
Bob, what's with you today?
You do remember telling me
I should see her, don't you?
I forgot to say
to be careful.
We're full of false
fantasies, Agamemnon.
See her, yes,
but cover your ass.
You said yourself
love sucks.
There's nothing to be
gained from your pains,
except more pain.
Midway through
the 20th century,
man wants communication
without communication!
He wants to sit
in his living room
and watch people
in a box
fall in love,
work, sing, golf,
cry, fuck
and fuck up.
Television!
A one-way conversation
between you and the world,
where the world
does the talking!
Like God,
man can finally create man
in his own image
and then kick back and watch
all sorts of shit hit the fan.
Okay, Cyril,
time for another
fabulous E.C.T. Treatment.
What's E.C. T?
Jesus, why is
it every time,
I got to tell you
what E.C.T. Means?
That's because electroshock
causes memory loss.
Oh.
Jaz?
Jaz, it's very important
that we talk.
Your execution is
set for next week.
16 devils.
Today, there were 16.
I appreciate your stopping
by to see me, Miss Lang.
I'm thrilled when anyone shows
an interest in Jaz Hoyt.
Arnie Zelman seems to be
getting all the death row publicity
for his client,
Cyril O'Reilly.
God, Zelman
is a P.R. Genius.
How's Hoyt's appeal going?
Well, through the testimony
of various psychiatrists,
some of whom have been treating
Hoyt since he was 6 years old,
I think I've been able
to build a fairly solid case.
And your contention is that
he's always been crazy?
Yes.
As a child
he tortured animals,
sodomized a playmate.
And where were his parents
during all of this? In a bar, drunk?
Actually, in Captiva.
Hoyt comes from money,
Father Mukada,
lots of money.
He went to Exeter.
He dropped out of Harvard.
This whole Jaz-bad- biker thing
is part of his delusion.
Holy shit, he's rich?
Well, who do you think's
paying for my fees?
Pater and mater.
Hearing the music
and I saw
another buffalo.
And I saw a dog,
and I saw one...
I saw two wolves...
I saw two...
two wolves...
And on a more
controversial note,
in a stunning defeat
for state prosecutors,
convicted murderer Jaz Hoyt's
death sentence was overturned.
Instead of being
executed as scheduled,
Hoyt will be moved to the Oswald
Correctional Facility's psychiatric unit
and then later to the Connelly
Institute, a hospital in Morrisville,
which specializes in treating
the criminally insane.
This is bullshit! How come
fuckin' Hoyt gets off and Cyril doesn't?
From a purely legal
standpoint, the circumstances
of each case
are very different.
You're telling me that in the eyes
of the law, Jaz Hoyt's life
is worth preserving
and my brother's isn't?
- Afraid so, Ryan.
- God damn it!
Unless our latest appeal
is accepted by the court,
Cyril dies
two weeks from Thursday.
Fuck.
Prisoner #03N679:
Jahfree Neema;
Convicted January 10th,
2003;
Kidnapping, assault;
Sentence: Seven years;
Up for parole in three.
In other news,
'60s radical Jahfree Neema
was convicted today
of kidnapping his daughter
from the Pinkel
Day Care Center.
Mr. Neema, a prominent community
leader on the city's east side,
was at one time involved
in the Black Panthers.
This castle hath
a pleasant seat.
The air nimbly
and sweetly
recommends itself
unto our gentle senses.
This quest of summer,
the temple-haunting marlet.
All right, that's it.
Rehearsal's over.
- But I didn't even...
- Tomorrow at 3:00.
It's okay. We'll get to it.
Thank you.
- Things humming, Ma?
- Oh, Ryan,
well, not exactly.
We haven't found anybody
to replace Schibetta
in the lead and...
Ryan, I need to talk to you,
- but I don't know where to start.
- Just start.
Right.
- Jahfree Neema is coming to Oz.
- Hey, Ma, seriously.
I know the man.
At least, I knew him.
He... he was the one
that convinced me
to join the peace movement.
He was the one that...
He's the one that got you
to leave Dad and abandon me, right?
That's one way
of putting it.
You have to understand, he was
very passionate about his beliefs.
- He's a very charismatic man...
- Did you fuck him?
You did.
Ryan. Look, we're
both adults here.
You know what it was like
living with your father.
It was very repressive, and Jahfree
helped me to free myself
and I'm telling you this
because I want you to know
that he changed my life
for the better.
Uh-huh.
I'm just asking you to be
open to him, that's all.
Yeah, can't wait
to meet him.
Maybe I'll call him
Uncle Jahfree.
Later, man.
Hey.
How they hanging
there, bud?
Do I know you?
Indirectly. Suzanne Fitzgerald,
she's my mom.
So?
Get out of my cell.
She just asked me to come down
here and try to, you know...
Get out of my cell,
white boy.
Asshole.
Hey.
Back in the '60s,
the Department of Defense
created the Internet.
Little did they know
they were mixing concrete
to build
the global village.
There's nothing concrete
about it, though.
People get digital mail
from electronic boxes,
they congregate
in chat rooms
that have no walls
and no doors.
Millions around the world
have instant access
to each other and stores
and food and entertainment.
But if it's such a revolution
in communications,
why do studies show
the more time
one spends online,
the more isolation
one suffers?
We've been contacted by
a lawyer for one Greg Penders,
a resident of solitary
confinement.
He's suing the state.
Because of the methylene
chloride poisoning?
Yes, he says the death
of Carlos Martinez
is proof the prison put his own life
in unnecessary danger.
Penders is trying to get
the Martinez family and Omar White
- to join in the lawsuit.
- Christ.
I warned you not to go
public too soon,
- not to have that press conference.
- Ellie, please!
The last thing I need to hear
right now is "I told you so."
This is gonna work,
Omar, I guarantee it.
I guarantee it.
The word's out that
the air in here is toxic,
that it's lethal as shit.
You've got to join
my class-action suit.
You've got to do it.
I understand you want
to speak with me.
Omar, who's out there?
What's going on?
Okay, you let me
out of solitary, right,
back to Em City?
And I won't sue
with Penders.
That's all I get
in the deal?
Well, what more
do you want, man?
Look around, I ain't got...
I ain't got much to offer.
Here's an idea,
I put you back
in Em City
and you don't mention a word
of this conversation to anyone.
Not a fucking syllable.
Oh, no, fuck syllable, I mean,
not even a fucking letter, okay?
But if you do talk,
I will build a cell so small
you won't have
room to stand.
There'll just be room
enough for you
and that yappity mouth
of yours, got it?
We never spoke.
Omar.
White back in Em City?
No fucking way, Leo.
I've had enough of his bullshit.
Tim, do you really expect me
to put your headaches
with one inmate
above the larger burdens
of this prison?
I didn't think so.
Allahu Akbar.
Arif, where's
my man Said?
Allahu Akbar.
- Seriously, where is he?
- Said's dead, White.
- What?
- Somebody shot him. Come on.
Come on, let's go.
McManus.
- McManus.
- Today, White!
The autopsy report
on Carlos Martinez.
You'll be glad to know
that he didn't die
of methylene chloride poisoning.
He suffocated.
Or I should say he was
suffocated by someone else.
What?
I guess that's one less plaintiff
for you to worry about, right?
You still pissed off at me
for not sending Martinez
to Benchley Memorial?
Yes.
But not half as much
as I am at myself.
You know what's really
disgusting about this?
I'm relieved that a prisoner
was killed in his sleep
instead of dying of what might
have been a preventable death.
Now, I'm not guilty.
Now, l...
I'm just horrified
to find myself thinking this way.
Do you know what?
That is the last time
I take care of Oz
over a person.
Great.
I've got another murder
investigation on my hands.
So, what are you accusing
me of, killing Martinez?
Look, normally I could sweep
this thing under the rug,
but since we've had
this rash of murders
and I went public with
the methylene chloride
promising to release
the autopsy,
the media is not
gonna let this go.
They're going to scream
for an investigation.
And I need to learn
every detail I can.
Okay, sorry.
You told Officer Murphy you visited
Martinez just before he died.
Yeah.
Martinez sent word
that he wanted to see me
'cause he was desperate
to confess that Morales
was the one who ordered him
to cut my tendon.
Did you see
anything suspicious?
Any threat from
the other patients?
No.
Well, you ask me, one of the Latinos
did the deed, sir.
They work as orderlies
in the ward.
They had opportunity
and motive.
You mean to keep Martinez
from jabbering on Morales?
Yes.
Look, Dave,
I'm gonna bring in
the homicide unit,
same as I did on
the Loewen murder.
They may want you to take
a lie detector test.
So, I am a suspect.
Unfortunately, for now,
you're the prime.
I'm so innocent it hurts.
Then what are you
worried about?
Take the fucking
lie detector test.
- I can't.
- Why?
Because I did lie.
I don't understand.
I lied about Martinez
blaming Morales.
What?
I didn't even see Martinez
the night he died.
Oh, Jesus, Dave.
You and I both know
that Morales is guilty.
I simply took Martinez's
death as an opportunity
to nail that motherfucker.
What we did, getting Morales
in solitary, cutting him up...
Was totally justified.
No, because
we had no proof.
Don't get all righteous
with me, you bastard.
It was my leg that got cut,
my life that got fucked.
Man, you got to go tell
Glynn the truth, all right?
Because we've got to get
Morales out of solitary.
No.
All right,
if you don't, I will.
Fuck that!
For Jesus' sake,
stop it.
Stop it.
Go go.
- Dr. Nathan?
- Oh, hi.
Come in.
Thanks for coming.
Look, I want to apologize
for getting so upset
the night Martinez died
and for firing you.
The chemical poisoning
thing in solitary
has put me under
a lot of stress,
and I know what it's like
to get blamed for things
that really aren't
under your control.
And if you still want
your job, it's yours.
Oh, Dr. Nathan,
thank you.
I'll do my best, I swear,
to make you proud.
Well, let's get to work.
Enrique, I heard
about what happened.
Get away from me,
you Judas.
- Hey, I'm no Judas.
- Did you kill Martinez?
Did anybody in El Norte
kill Martinez?
No.
Then move the fuck away
from me. Muvate.
Everything okay,
here?
Can I have some juice?
Too bad about
your friend Martinez.
But he was a nasty man.
He deserved to die.
Yo.
I'm glad you came.
It's good
to see you too.
You look a shitload better than you did
the last time I was here.
You know, I hit a couple
of potholes, you know.
I'm cruising now, man,
70 miles an hour
with the fucking
top down, you know?
Speaking of which,
how's my car?
I don't know, bro.
What you mean you don't know?
When I got convicted
I gave you the keys,
told you to treat her like a lady.
I did, man. I fine-tuned her,
I polished her up, but...
Maritza gets out of Parker's,
bro, and she sells it.
What?
She said that car was
the cause of all her grief.
She didn't tell me nothing
about selling the car.
You seen her lately?
Oh, yeah.
I mean, all the time.
I mean, we live right across the street
from each other, remember?
Right.
I gotta ask you something.
I need you to tell me
the truth, okay?
- Is she fucking anyone?
- Oh, Miguel, man, l...
Yo, bro, bro,
I can feel it, man.
Okay?
I know she is.
Now, we've been like
brothers, man, a long time.
We ain't ever lied
about nothing.
You know,
I need to know.
Tell me, okay?
Who's the guy?
I don't...
I don't think you...
Bro,
- tell me, who's the guy?
- Me.
It's me.
Look, I'm sorry, Miguel.
Man, I got
no excuses, bro.
What happened,
it just happened.
You cocksucker.
You gonna hit me?
Go ahead, hit me, come on.
Okay, Alvarez,
time's up. Let's go.
Now that I know
the truth about Maritza,
in a fucked-up way,
I feel better,
you know?
I mean,
just the not knowing
was totally
eating me alive.
I'm surprised
about two things.
I haven't cried,
and I didn't pound
the shit out of Reynaldo.
That's a good thing,
right?
I mean, everything happens
for the best.
Right?
I wanted to kill him.
But I didn't.
So, I don't know,
I'm making progress.
So, what's next,
microchips in the brain?
The ability to read
each other's minds?
Too late.
A primitive tribe
in the other Oz...
Australia...
already beat us to it.
They talk by not talking.
Yeah, they're way
way ahead of us
in the realm
of communications
and they didn't have to
invent squat to get there.
They stayed connected
in the original sense,
in the aboriginal sense.
I'm done.
Which means
you're done too.
Now go get me a towel.
Hey, Robson.
- How's that bitch thing coming?
- Get away from me.
Listen, the only people
who hate Cutler more than you
is us.
So, why not do
everybody a favor?
Ace him?
Ain't no downside.
It proves to the brotherhood
you're still a man.
And it'll make you a lot
of friends in the kitchen.
Win-win.
"I'll go no more.
I am afraid to think
what I have done.
Look on't again
I dare not."
"Infirm of purpose.
Give me the daggers.
- The sleeping and the dead..."
- Hang on, stop stop.
I don't fucking get this.
What's confusing you,
Wolfgang?
- Well, I just killed the king, right?
- Right.
I come downstairs
with these bloody daggers
and now I'm like
a complete pussy.
Hmm, well, see...
Macbeth is conflicted
about the implications
of his act.
And I'm supposed to let this bitch
take care of things for me?
- You can't seem to do it yourself.
- Watch it, buttercup.
Uh, um...
could you just take a look
at the last line of the scene?
"To know my deed, 'twere best not
know myself."
And what does
that mean to you?
Why don't you just tell me?
That you would hate yourself
if you ever thought about
the things you've done.
Like I said,
Macbeth's a pussy.
Dont fuckin' move!
Take that shit off
your fucking head.
So you like that,
Prag?
You know what
we should try?
"We should try"?
When did I start giving a shit
about your input around here?
- B.C.P.
- What the fuck is that?
Breath control play.
First you make
a noose, see?
- Keep talking.
- Then you put it around your neck.
My neck?
Are you fucking
kidding me?
No, hear me out.
You put the noose
around your neck
and you hang
yourself lightly.
And all the blood
from your head
rushes straight
to your dick,
and then I blow you.
When you get off,
it's like God himself
is swallowing.
So, where's the noose?
Who would have thought those
things would have so many uses?
I was telling you
that shit about my dad.
Well, in many ways
I've become him.
I mean, I've done shit to guys
that I'm not proud of.
But in other ways,
I'm still that little boy
getting fucked in the shed.
Is someone
sodomizing you, James?
Wolfgang Cutler.
Here I am again,
shacked up with a psychopath.
But I'm older now,
seeing it
with different eyes.
What are you seeing?
In Cutler?
A guy who deep down
is really depressed,
really hates himself.
It's how his gaze
goes totally blank
while he's...
well, I think
he'd be happier dead.
And the thing is
sometimes his mood
goes so dark,
I think
he may do himself.
- Has he talked about suicide?
- No.
But with all
this "Macbeth" shit,
it's really fucked him up.
Sister,
maybe you could
talk to him, huh?
Before he does something
terrible to himself.
Wolfgang, I requested
a session with you,
but since it was supposed
to have started 40 minutes ago,
I guess you're not
showing up.
You and me got nothing
to talk about, Sis.
I'm not crazy.
Crazy is not the only reason
folks come to see me.
Shrinks are for fags.
Wolfgang,
you don't have to...
- Listen, bitch.
- Problem, Sister?
No.
Never mind.
Oh, morning, Wolfie.
Jeez, I guess I forgot
to untie you last night.
Holy shit.
Officer.
Officer!
Base one,
we got an 823 in B.
Well,
ain't that a kick?
One of you actually went
and lynched yourselves.
When man goes
collectively mad
from downloading all
the mental messages in the air,
when there's no trees left
'cause we needed all that paper
for the printing press
and therefore are left
with no oxygen to breathe,
then satellites will fry
from overuse
and drop from the sky.
And we'll make desperate
cell phone calls
to our loved ones
while watching Mother Earth's
last days on reality TV.
Communications
will be once again
what it was
in the beginning.
The word moving over
the face of the deep,
over the face of God,
Who now, instead
of wanting to talk,
is tired of listening.