Six percent
of the total prison population
is 55 and older.
That's double 1 0 years ago.
And we say 55 is old
because criminal life adds about
ten years' worth of wrinkles.
Still, in Oz, you get decent food,
exercise, regular checkups.
And if you don't get whacked,
you'll live longer than you would
in your own hood.
Yeah, the prison system.
lt can keep you alive,
but it can't take care of you.
l'm telling you,
we're ignoring the problem.
We have to deal differently
with aging inmates.
That's right. Oz was designed
to punish the young,
to keep them in line,
to keep them down,
but with a guy like Rebadow,
we don't need to keep him down.
So, what are you proposing?
We turn Unit 2 into a cellblock
exclusively for seniors.
They sleep together there,
eat all their meals together there,
they can play cards, they can watch
the TV shows they wanna watch.
Saturday night Bingo?
Well, why not?
We need to keep them active.
And less stress will help
slow down the aging process,
which will help save
on medical costs.
Plus, the older guys aren't
a security problem,
so you can save money
on the officers.
McManus,
you've been awfully quiet today.
Never thought l'd ask,
but do you have an opinion on this?
Sure. Sounds like a good idea.
- That's it?
- Yeah.
Fine, l'll run it by the commissioner.
Meeting adjourned.
Finally.
Hey, Tim, you okay?
You don't look so good.
- Are you feeling all right?
- l said yeah, okay?
Okay.
Free for dinner tonight?
Dinner? You think l'm an asshole.
- l do not think--
- Well, l appreciate the offer,
but the last thing l need from you
is a mercy dinner.
Bob Rebadow's in the hospital, Kenny.
- So?
- So l'm pissed off about that.
- So l hear you're responsible.
Where'd you hear that from?
l got ears everywhere, Kenny.
l know it's true.
You don't hit old men, Kenny.
- You don't hit old men.
- What do you want, McManus?
You see those guys out there?
lf l tell them to,
they will gladly kick your ass.
l'm not afraid of them.
l'm not afraid of you.
- You're not?
- No.
- What are you afraid of?
- Nothing.
- Nothing?
You afraid of this, huh?
You afraid of dying?
You little fucking punkass!
Get him the fuck out of here.
Leo, what are you doing here?
Same thing you are, l guess.
l like to work out
when no one else is around.
l'll ignore you if you ignore me.
McManus, you okay?
Why does everybody
keep asking me that?
l don't know.
Past few weeks, you seem different.
l'm fine.
Commissioner rejected our proposal
for a senior-citizens unit.
Big surprise.
Commissioner didn't reject it.
Governor Fuckwad did.
Well, Devlin's almost out of office.
l mean, he's on trial
for taking those kickbacks,
for lying, fraud, extortion.
l'll miss him.
You know,
l've been hearing rumours
that you're living in Emerald City,
that you never leave the grounds,
- never go home anymore.
- Since when do you listen to gossip?
You know, l've been dancing
down these hallways a long time.
l've seen this place
change people completely,
not just the prisoners.
lf you're not careful, Tim,
Oz will nick away at your soul.
That's the first time
you ever called me Tim.
You know, you don't even
have to be 55 to be old.
- Take a break.
- Okay, Mr. McManus.
How you feeling?
l can't stay here anymore.
- ln the hospital?
- ln Oz.
Why?
l'm afraid.
Of what?
Them. The young.
When l first came to Oz,
we treated our elders with dignity.
But these kids, it's all different now.
l've decided to leave.
Leave?
Escape.
How you gonna do that?
God will show me the way.
The human body.
lt's amazing.
Made up of all these cells
and neutrons and veins
and shit like that.
So many little pieces, so many things
that could break down.
And add on to that the wear
and tear we give our bodies,
what with the drugs and drinking
and chicken-fried steak.
Man, that any of us
are still standing,
still breathing, it's a miracle.
Breakfast time, boys!
Let's go, Alvarez.
- l think maybe we got a problem.
- What?
Look at Alvarez.
- Hey, Alvarez.
- You think he's faking?
Alvarez.
Call for the doctor.
Prisoner number 43A5 1 5,
Ricardo Alvarez.
Convicted March 3, '43.
Armed robbery.
Sentence: 20 years.
Convicted June 6, '6 1.
Murder in the first degree.
Sentence: Life imprisonment,
solitary confinement.
Ricardo, we're gonna start
with a series of tests.
You have to go home?
Your mother--
Ricardo, where are you?
Do you know what city you're in?
Havana. Havana.
So we're agreed? The medication's
controlling Cragen's paranoia.
- Yeah, we should keep him on it.
- Definitely.
Thank you. Next is Miguel Alvarez.
Oh, yeah. l'm scheduled to do a
psychiatric re-evaluation on Thursday.
Good luck, Pete.
His baby died right after birth.
He's pretty depressed.
He's about to become
even more depressed.
His grandfather, Ricardo Alvarez,
has Alzheimer's.
- Christ.
- Does his family know?
No, not yet.
Ricardo's son Eduardo
is an orderly in my ward.
l'll tell him when he comes in
for his shift.
Eduardo.
That's the one with no tongue, right?
l'll talk to Miguel.
Listen, Tim, can l do that?
lf you don't mind.
Hey, l'm always willing
to give up an opportunity
to deliver bad news. Next?
Miguel, l need you to come with me.
- l didn't do shit.
- Miguel, please.
Come on.
How come no one knew till now
that Ricardo's mind was going?
He was in solitary, Miguel.
He hardly says three words a day
to anyone.
And there's nothing we could've done
to stop the disease anyway.
So, what happens now?
Well, that's the tricky part.
Unfortunately, Oz is just not equipped
for long-term custodial care
and there isn't anywhere else
to send him.
The state doesn't have a place
to take care of its old prisoners?
The state. The state's attitude
toward the elderly,
any elderly, in or out of prison...
...is hurry up and die.
l wanna see my grandfather.
- Hey.
lt's me, Miguel, and Eduardo.
Hey.
Eduardo, your son.
- Miguel, grandson.
- Hey.
Hey.
Hey, hey, hey.
You know what we should do
with Ricardo Alvarez?
What's that?
Let him go free.
Let him go free?
The man is a convicted killer.
He stabbed the inmate
who cut his son's tongue out.
- And he's old.
- He's old, Leo.
Old doesn't necessarily mean nice.
lf there's any doubts about that,
spend ten minutes
with my mother-in-law.
Leo, a 31 -year-old inmate
costs $21 ,000 a year to maintain.
A senior costs
three times that amount.
Since when did you get so interested
in the budget?
Since l figured out
that the money we're gonna waste
taking care of Ricardo Alvarez
could be put to much better use.
Besides, Ricardo doesn't know
where he is or even why he's here.
There is such a thing
as criminal menopause, right?
Look, he cannot commit
the crime again.
The man is no longer
a threat to anybody.
lt doesn't change what he did,
and it doesn't change his sentence.
Life imprisonment means just that.
Besides, if he really doesn't know
he's in prison,
then he's already free, isn't he?
When l was growing up,
both my father and my grandfather
came to Oz.
You know, when l was little,
l always wondered
what was so great about prison that
they'd wanna leave us and come here.
But you're a kid, you know.
What do you know?
Yeah.
So the word ''grandfather.''
What does the word
mean to you, emotionally?
Nothing.
Don't mean nothing at all to me.
''Pizza'' means more.
''Doorknob.''
Would you like ''grandfather''
to mean something to you?
Yeah.
Dr. Nathan's not sure how long
your grandfather has to live.
Look, since your father's an orderly
in the prison hospital
and is gonna spend time
with your grandfather,
there's no reason
you can't do the same thing.
Maybe if you take care of him,
you'll learn to care for him.
You know, in my family,
Ricardo was like a god.
You know, he was a legend.
My grandmother used to show me
these pictures,
you know,
telling me stories all about him.
And l wanted to be like him,
you know.
Yeah.
Now l see he's just a man.
You know, he's just an old man
and he's rotting away.
l don't wanna end up
like my grandfather.
You don't have to, Miguel.
Oh, really?
Well, l don't see it going down
any other way.
Rebadow.
Hey, l'm sorry you didn't make it out.
lt's okay. lt was worth it.
The adrenaline rush.
l felt 25 again for a moment.
- Here's your dinner.
- l don't want it.
Okay.
What do you want?
l'd like a few years at the end of my life
to be free.
Do we care for people
when they're sick
because we actually
care about them?
Or do we care for them
because when our time comes,
we want someone to care for us?
Or does it matter?
At least you got your health.
Don't you hate it
when people say that?
l mean, you lose your job,
you lose your wife, you're in prison,
and some punkass dude gonna say,
''At least you got your health.''
Like that's supposed to
make you feel better.
So what if l'm broke, or if some
drug dealer wants to cap my ass?
At least l ain't got a tumour.
l swear, the next person
that says ALYG YH to me,
l'm gonna make sure they ain't got
their health much longer.
You say you were having nightmares.
Can you remember any of them?
No.
What's the matter?
My tooth hurts.
lt's been hurting for a week.
- Then go see a dentist.
- No.
- Why?
- l hate the dentist.
All dentists,
or just Dr. Kochurn in particular?
The concept of dentists.
Then what?
You prefer the concept of pain?
Make an appointment, Groves, okay?
Okay?
- Oh, God.
- What?
Oh, sweet Jesus,
Donald Groves is coming in to see me.
- So?
- Gloria, he ate his parents.
l'm not sticking my fingers
in his mouth.
My fingers are my livelihood.
He's been working in the ward
as an orderly.
He seems harmless.
So you'd stick your fingers
in his mouth?
lf l had to.
lf he's in pain, you have to.
- No, l don't.
- What about the Hippocratic Oath?
Dentists don't take
the Hippocratic Oath.
We don't make any promises
to anybody.
How's that gas working?
You feel happy?
Calm?
Good.
Okay, let's have a look.
Open your mouth.
Wider. Wider. Wider.
- l can't get any wider.
- Alrighty then.
They look fine.
- lt hurts.
- lt's probably nothing.
- Don't be a baby.
- Who you calling a baby?
- Nobody.
Forget it. Forget l said anything.
There is a tooth that's rotted out.
So we're going to have to pull it.
That means l have to take a needle,
inject some Novocaine in your mouth.
- l hate needles.
- Everybody does.
- Then l have to drill.
- l hate drills.
Right now, so do l.
Right now, l wish there were
holistic dentistry.
l'm in pain.
Well, you're going to be in a lot more
before we're finished.
But after that,
you won't have any pain, see.
lf l cause you pain, it's not my fault,
so don't bite my head off.
l mean...
- l know what you mean.
- Okay.
Let's get started.
First, the Novocaine.
Open wide.
Carol,
could you
give me a hand here, please?
This is my tooth. lt was in my head.
This tooth and l have been together
since we were kids.
This tooth chewed on my mom.
You should sell it.
- Sell it?
- Sell it.
Tooth from the mouth
of Donald Groves?
Know how much that's worth
on the market?
- How much?
- Plenty.
- Who'd wanna buy my tooth?
- Collectors.
- Collectors?
People collect everything.
Stamps, salt and pepper shakers,
World's Fair tchotchkes.
Some people collect crime stuff.
Lindbergh ladder,
Ted Bundy's toenail clippings,
and this.
We'd have to get a fence, right?
We're in prison.
How hard's that gonna be?
Ross, if we get a good price...
...l still got 30 more.
The mind is just like the body.
lt's under constant assault
from fear and hate
and a whole pile of loneliness.
These things are as deadly
as any cancer cell.
The mind is just like the body.
The fact that the mind can survive
is a miracle.
Okay. All right. Yo. All right.
Our next contestant
is the lovely and talented
Tobias Beecher.
He never treats me sweet and gentle
The way he should
l've got it bad
And that ain't good
When the weekend's over
And Monday rolls around
l end up like l start out
Crying my heart out
He don't love me
Like l love him
Nobody could
l've got it bad
And that ain't good
And that ain't
Good
Yo, chill, y'all rowdy-ass
motherfuckers. Shut up.
Yo, next up on the stage...
All right, all right. Next on stage,
our very own George Bailey
doing a drum solo.
Well, we knew Beecher
was doing drugs.
Yeah, but now l'm beginning
to figure it out.
He thinks of himself as a victim,
so he's not gonna get better
unless he feels
he can control his life.
He's in prison, Pete Marie.
His life is totally out of his control.
Well, now we have to get him
back to when he was in charge.
We have to remind him that
there's another victim involved here,
the little girl he killed.
Hello.
My husband wouldn't come.
He said he was afraid
he might kill you.
This is Kathy.
l'm sorry, l didn't mean to...
l'm not sure why l came.
At the trial,
l was sitting behind you.
l could barely see your face.
Guess l just wanted to finally...
...see you.
See your eyes, and to tell you...
...that l miss her.
Every single moment
of every single day.
You fucking bastard!
l hope you die in here,
you motherfucking--!
l hope you rot in hell!
You killed my baby!
l don't know.
Maybe l let Schillinger
treat me like dirt
because l deserve to be punished.
Because l--
l killed Kathy Rockwell.
Because l destroyed her family.
And my own.
And you hate yourself for that?
Yes.
l guess l hated myself
back before, too, you know.
l hated myself, so l drank too much.
Then l hated myself
for drinking too much
so to punish myself,
l drank more.
Sister...
...l don't wanna hate me anymore.
Hey, don't think you're fooling me.
l know the only way you got through
that variety show was by using drugs.
- Look, l--
- Hey,
l told you,
l don't want you doing that shit.
l'm sorry, sir.
No, l'm sorry.
Here. Put it on.
Perfect fit.
No, no, no. Leave it on.
Come on.
lf l go out there with this on,
a black guy is gonna kill me.
Yeah, l know.
What is this?
There's a new kid in town.
Okay, that's great.
l'm happy for you.
l'll move to another pod.
No.
Why not?
l don't want some nigger
to have your ass.
Goodbye, prag.
- O'Reily, l need your help.
- Well, l'm here.
Schillinger wants me dead.
He just gave me this to wear.
What am l gonna do, man?
Well, if you gotta go,
you gotta go high.
Ever tried PCP?
The trial of James Devlin
opened today at the state courthouse,
not far from the capital building,
where the governor has ruled
with an iron fist for the past year.
Devlin, who says he will not resign
even if convicted,
faces 25 years in prison
for fraud, extortion, racketeering,
and obstruction of justice.
Yeah, motherfucker! How's that?
l'm sorry, sir.
l'm getting out of here!
- Beecher, get down.
- Here l go!
No way out of here, you fucking
cocksucking, motherfucking--
Someone get a fucking doctor!
How does that feel, you cunt?
Beecher! Beecher! Beecher!
You better get a fucking doctor!
Help me! Help!
- Keep your hands out of your face.
- Oh, shit.
l need a couple of 4-by-4's
and some tape.
The glass in his eye is pretty bad.
l'm not sure l can save it.
We need to get him
to Benchley Memorial
for surgery as soon as possible.
Fuck, l'm gonna kill that motherfucker.
Beecher, you're a dead man!
You have to go back
to drug counselling.
- Fuck off.
- lf you don't,
- l'll transfer you out of Emerald City.
- Fuck off.
- Tobias, we're trying to help you.
- Fuck off!
Look, if you're afraid
Schillinger's gonna kill you,
l'll place you
under protective custody.
Fuck off, fuck off, fuck off,
fuck off, fuck off, you fucks.
People say, ''She broke my heart.''
That's bullshit, man.
The heart can't break, it's a muscle.
Muscles tear, muscles cramp.
Yeah, the heart's a muscle.
So's the brain. So's the dick.
O'Reily, give this guy the mop.
You're through
with the bucket brigade.
Good.
Dino Ortolani ran the kitchen
like a Swiss watch. The best.
Joey was good. Markstrom too.
But this Adebisi character,
he's not really focused on the job,
you know.
And he abuses the privilege.
Everybody steals,
but he steals too much.
Now, you're a smart guy.
And you've been very efficient
doing the jobs l've asked you to do.
So l'm putting you in charge
of the whole cafeteria.
What are you talking?
l run this kitchen.
And you're doing a half-assed job.
l got rotten fruit. l got cold entrees.
l got Glynn complaining
about cost overages.
- l'm not working with him.
- Fine.
How about l have you transferred
to the sweatshop?
- l don't like the sweatshop.
- Then shut the fuck up.
Okay?
lt's all yours.
All right, ladies, back to work.
What?
- We had a deal. We were partners.
- We still are.
When it comes to running tits,
that part of the operation,
l got no complaints with.
But the kitchen,
l can't afford you fucking up.
O'Reily will do a good job.
Fuck that pretty little mick.
Hey, Adebisi, you make your peace
with this any way you can.
l say O'Reily's gonna run the kitchen
as good as Dino ever did.
You wanna bet on that?
What the fuck is going on here,
Wangler?
- Nothing.
- Exactly. Pick up the goddamn pace.
We're going as fast as we can, man.
All right, everybody quiet down.
- You're not fooling me.
- What are you talking about, boss?
Yeah, right. Adebisi, listen to me,
l know why Schibetta
put me in charge over you.
He's doing the old divide
and conquer.
As long as he keeps the two of us
at each other's throats,
- he's got all the power.
- Cocksucker.
- What are you doing?
- Let's face it,
the both of us
only got one goal in mind,
and that's to take over
Schibetta's drug trade.
- Together, we can do it.
- Together?
We gotta make him think
that we're enemies.
Keep him off guard till we kill him.
- We kill them, the mob kills us.
- They won't know.
Not if we put this in his food.
Glass.
As long as we make it fine,
he won't be able to taste it.
Over time,
the glass will cut his insides up.
- And he'll die slowly.
- Painfully.
You are a sick motherfucker, O'Reily.
Coming from you,
that's a compliment.
Wangler.
What's up?
- Bring me Schibetta's food.
- Yes, sir.
And tell everyone
to start working full speed.
Okay.
Everyone, move your asses now.
So, Ryan, if you were released
from Oz today, what would you do?
- Travel.
- Where?
Around.
You know, since l got here, l've been
reading brochures and vacation guides.
They're great for when
you're taking a shit
or wanking before you go to sleep.
While l'm sleeping, l actually dream
about going to these places.
Like?
Morogoro.
Morogoro? That's a jungle, isn't it?
- Yeah. You knew that?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, it's in Africa.
- You wanna go with me?
- Me?
Yeah, you and me, you know.
l'm twice your age and l'm a nun.
Yeah, well,
growing up and going to St. Pat's,
l never had a nun like you.
St. Pat's, huh?
- Tough neighbourhood.
- Yeah, yeah.
l learned the alphabet the hard way.
DEA, HlV, lOU.
l see.
You know, Sister,
l got 1 2 years to my parole.
l wanna be alive to make that parole.
l'm gonna walk out of here.
l'm gonna survive.
Nine of spades.
Trump.
- You okay, Nino?
- Yeah. Yeah, just a little agita.
l told you, you're making the red sauce
too spicy.
l don't know what the fuck you're
putting in it, but it's too fucking spicy.
- Trump.
- Shit.
l was addicted to crack.
Then l had my accident.
Lying in the hospital bed,
l went through detox.
But that was easy.
The doctors had me on morphine,
Demerol, Percodan.
l didn't know l was in pain.
l didn't know l was in the hospital,
paralyzed.
Then l came here
and went into counselling.
l take it one day at a time, you know?
But every day, l think about drugs.
About not doing drugs.
Every single day, every single hour,
every single minute.
Staying straight has become
my obsession. My new addiction.
Twelve years for his conviction
in the attempted rape and assault...
Oh, shit.
Jackson Vahue got 1 2 years.
Yeah, and l hear he's coming to Oz.
Judge Anthony Pepitone
levied the maximum sentence
saying that Vahue's conviction
should send a signal that no one,
especially a famous sports figure,
is above the...
Hey, McManus,
l been waiting to see you, man.
You ought to get wheelchair access
to your office.
Put it in the suggestion box.
Hey, l wanna be
Jackson Vahue's sponsor.
How come?
The man is one of the greatest
B-ball players of all time.
l'm one of his biggest fans.
What makes you think
l'm bringing him to Emerald City?
Like everybody else,
you're a starfucker.
Oh, right. Nobody could ever
accuse you of being an asskisser.
All right,
you're Jackson Vahue's sponsor.
- When does he arrive?
- Tomorrow.
- Great.
- You think you can get
the marching band ready by then?
Where the fuck do you think
you're going?
No!
Prisoner number 9 7 V588,
Jackson Vahue.
Convicted August 1 7, '97.
Attempted rape, assault.
Sentence: 1 2 years.
Up for parole in five.
Vahue, you wait here
for transport to Em City.
The rest of you scumfucks,
now that you've had your shower and
you're all sweet and squeaky clean,
are gonna follow Officer Smith
to your new accommodations.
Let's go. This way.
Right through there.
Come on, come on, come on.
Hey, Jackson,
can l get your autograph?
lt's for my kid.
- Yo, what's up, Jackson?
- Jackson.
Hey, Jackson, what's up, baby?
- He's a ball-handler, too, man.
- He can handle these balls.
Nice shot, yo.
Thought l'd find you here.
You go ahead
and leave me the fuck alone.
l'm just here
to help you get adjusted.
What, adjusted to this shit?
Where you from?
You from the projects?
- Yeah.
- Oh, well, me too.
Spent all your time adjusting, right?
Figuring out
how to fucking stay alive, right?
why you don't have nothing.
What, you got about three ways
you can get out?
You can sell some drugs, or sing,
or this shit right here.
They all take some talent, man.
l just happened to be lucky.
Fucking jump. l could hang,
l could put this ball in the hoop.
Oh, l got adjusted.
l got famous, l got rich.
l got used to the touring,
the endorsements, the women.
Maybe not the women.
l fucking blew that, boy. l blew that.
The one thing l'm good at
don't mean dick in here.
So how the fuck
am l supposed to adjust to that?
Fuck you. l ain't doing this.
- Oh, yes, you are.
- What's the story here?
Mr. NBA won't do
his work assignment.
lt was explained to you, right?
Everybody in Em City
has a job to do.
Give me another job, then,
because l'm not doing this one.
You don't get to choose.
Look, pal, l don't do windows, okay?
l don't do windows.
Well, now you get to clean that up.
George Washington Carver.
He was born to slave parents
but he worked his way up
and through lowa State College,
becoming a botanist
and an agricultural chemist.
Now, he discovered
hundreds of uses for the peanut,
the sweet potato, and the soybean.
Now, Mr. Vahue,
are you listening to me?
Sure. Soybean.
All right,
we'll pick up here next week.
Vahue.
Now, l know you're a big
hotshot basketball star.
lf you don't start paying attention
in the class,
you're going on report.
- Go ahead, nigger.
- Oh, no, my friend, you're the nigger.
- You got any drugs?
- No.
Then what the fuck good are you?
Hey, Jackson,
we made this special for you.
- Thanks, man.
- No, thank you.
l won 1 0 grand on that Bulls game.
What, you're looking
for an autograph?
Oh, no, my brother,
your fame means nothing to me.
Except that you are important
to many children
and you are a role model.
l didn't ask to be nobody's
fucking role model.
Nonetheless, you are.
And that carries
an enormous responsibility.
Look, man, fuck you, all right?
Go preach that shit to somebody else.
All right, my brother, all right.
But we will talk again.
Don't bet on that.
Eat me, nigger.
Who do you have to fuck
to get high?
Come on, son. Come on, son.
Let me squeeze them titties,
man, what?
Come on, yo.
l been fiending for this freedom
l been begging for the beat
l been jonesing
For the jump over the wall
But all l keep coming back to
ls them titties
Round and firm
For the vein burn
l keep bugging over the reasons
For this shit, l yearn
Years in this piece got me wanting
The shit that l unlearned
Got me wanting to block it out
Forget about
Erase it from my think
Come here, brother.
No.
Boy, you don't wanna get titillated.
Come here, boy, don't be a pussy.
Man, l been clean almost two years.
Man, this one little hit
ain't gonna kill you. Come on.
See, we talking
about the '95 Bulls game.
Right. You scored 58 points.
That's right. That ain't all l scored.
A little three-way
with two cheerleaders.
Yeah, you'll always be my hero, man.
That's me. Fucking role model.
- Fucking role model.
- Yeah, boy. Come on.
Well, maybe just one.
Yeah. Doesn't get harder, right?
You know that's been
up Kenny's ass, right?
Next is Kareem Said.
Dr. Prestopnick diagnosed him
for hypertension
prescribed Calan,
but his vital signs have yet to stabilise.
He's not taking his medication.
That doesn't make sense. A guy
like Said has everything to live for.
Well, my guess is that
he's concerned about the effect
the drug's gonna have on his mind.
He doesn't want his judgment clouded.
Well, l can understand that.
Oz is the last place
you want to let your guard down.
Can't you switch his prescription?
Yeah, but they all have side effects.
lf we don't get him
to take something, and soon,
it's only a matter of time
before his blood pressure explodes.
Don't think of me as a psychologist.
Don't think of me as a nun.
Think of me as your mother.
Kareem, take your medicine.
Now, Sister, l thought l was in here
for psychiatric evaluation.
You are. Because when you play
fast and loose
with high blood pressure,
you are crazy.
Oh, Sister, l'm far from crazy.
You see, God endowed me
with a mind, a free will
and gave me the ability to choose.
l choose to be drug-free.
And you make the choice how?
By considering the facts.
The fact is, you will die.
My physical condition
is a small part of a greater reality.
Now, it's been hard.
But l am now
at peace with this, Sister.
Now, why can't you be?
You...
Asalaam alaikum, Sister.
You're a good woman.
Yeah.
Okay, Huseni Mershah,
this is Kareem Said.
Kareem's gonna help you get used to
the routine in Emerald City.
Asalaam alaikum, brother.
Here, your cuffs.
Asalaam alaikum, huh?
Yeah. Have a nice day.
Prisoner number 9 7 M688,
Huseni Mershah.
Also known as
James Monroe Madison.
Convicted August 1 1, '9 7.
Attempted murder,
assault in the first degree.
Stop.
Sentence: 20 years.
Up for parole in three.
The Jew shot Omar Selim
because he figured Selim
was gonna rip off his little store. Selim
didn't even have a weapon on him.
- And the Jew got off.
- Oh, you know it.
So we had to teach the Jew
a little lesson on respect.
Thank you, Brother Huseni.
But now we pray.
lmam Said, listen,
l think we gotta do
a little more than pray.
We will, brother. Believe me, we will.
''Believers are like a single man.
lf his eye is affected,
then all of him is affected.
lf the head is affected,
- then all of him is affected.''
- Hey, wanna shut the fuck up? Yo.
- Got a problem?
- Your bullshit's making me sick.
Don't insult the holy word.
Suck my dick, asshole.
- What's the problem here, guys?
- There ain't no problem, officer.
Sit down.
l'm sorry if we disturbed you.
- Fuck you.
- Make nice, Ross.
lf you can't handle that, take a walk.
- Fuck you too.
- Okay.
Everybody sit down.
He was making fun
of the word of God, Minister.
God does not need you
to defend him from a moron.
What God needs you to do
is to rein in your basic instincts.
is just to be a little patient, brother.
The more little skirmishes
you get us involved in...
...is the more you weaken
the holy war we about to fight.
- So where you from, Minister?
- From?
Yeah, where you from?
You're not from the ghetto, right?
l was born in the ghetto.
But unlike most, l got out.
l have travelled the world, Huseni,
studied the great religions.
And l have sat at the knee
of mystics, shaman and madmen.
l know the world, Huseni.
Maybe you been on the mountaintop
so long, you forgot where you're from.
l have not forgotten who l am.
Well, maybe Allah sent me
to remind you.
Hey, lmam Said's moving slow, man.
lt worries me.
He knows best, brother.
Yeah, well,
he's blessed by Allah and all that,
but that don't mean
he can't be wrong.
So?
So l'm thinking, you know,
he might be more valuable to us
as a symbol rather than as a leader.
A symbol? What do you mean?
Nothing, man, nothing.
l'm just talking smack.
l'm just wasting time.
Huseni.
What, what, what? What, what?
lmam, what?
- My heart.
- You're having a heart attack.
Call the doctor.
lt is the hand of God.
lt is the will of Allah.
Help me, help-- Help me.
You must go ahead and die.
All those little aches and pains,
eventually, they add up to something.
Body, mind. Body, mind.
They gotta work together
or they don't work at all.
You gotta take care of your body.
You gotta take care of your mind.
You gotta love your body.
Most people don't.
Most people hate their bodies.
You gotta get your mind
to love your body.
Even if you're fat around the neck,
or even if things don't work
like they're supposed to,
you gotta love your body.
Because it's all you got to hold on to.
lt's all you got.
l'll make a deal with you.
l'll love your body if you love mine.