There are three kinds of laws
which govern us all.
First and foremost
are the laws of God,
followed closely by the
laws of nature
and, running a distant third,
the laws created by man.
You see, in order
for man to create a law,
a group of people have
to get together and decide
that they have come up
with the ultimate truth,
a basic inherent truth
by which every citizen
must conduct
himself or be punished.
The only problem is the group of people
who decides on the ultimate truth
is a bunch of politicians.
Given the choice, would you rather
be judged by a whim of the Almighty,
or a vote by Congress
Here comes the dead man.
Make you move, bro'.
Later, but I'm keeping
an eye on you.
Truer words have
never been spoke, man.
What the hell
does that mean?
Being only that you got
one good eye,
you droopy-eyed
motherfucker.
- You cocksucker!
- Get him! Kill him!
Kill that
motherfucker!
Kill that fucking brown-ass
motherfucker! Kill him!
Fascinating,
you in the cafeteria.
What do you mean?
Throwing caution
to the wind.
Think it'll work?
- Will I survive?
- I don't know.
But you gotta know.
You been in Oz,
like, 36 years.
Been through the same shit
that I've been through, and more.
And I know
you know all the tricks.
No, no tricks.
Well, then what?
I've just been myself.
Like I said, it's fascinating
the difference in generations.
You young people have grown up
with so much choice and possibility.
On the one hand,
that's a marvelous thing. On the other,
so many of you
battle with who you are.
For us, it was simpler.
There was none of this
finding yourself jazz.
You just concentrated
on what you had to do.
You were 18, 19 years old
going off to war.
So that's who you were.
That's who we all were.
So you guys are heroes?
That's what
you're telling me?
You guys are he-men?
Lord, no.
We were scared to death.
But when the landing boats
carried you to shore
and the metal doors
came down
you charged the beach,
took the blow.
That's just how it was.
It had to be done.
I've faced many hurdles
and moments of great fear
in my life.
But coming from an age
when men took the blow,
I've always felt comfortable
in my own skin.
Sounds good.
That's good.
Oh, Raider baby. Whoo.
Mmm!
Man, this baby...
Oh, shit.
Oh, hootchie mama.
Mmm.
I want you to stab me.
What?
I want you to shank me.
I won't retaliate.
Yeah? Are you going
to let me kill you?
Not kill.
Stab in the shoulder.
The proposition's this:
I'll give you
a free shot at me,
and in return,
I don't die.
What the fuck are
you talking about?
I'm willing
to take the blow.
Wouldn't it be satisfying
just to stick me?
Lt'd be immensely fucking
satisfying.
Okay. Make sure you hold up
your part of the bargain.
I want witnesses.
I want a lot of them.
I get this.
You let me
take a swipe at you
and the hacks throw me
in solitary for the next 10 years.
No.
We do it when the guards
aren't around.
You'll control that.
I just want
the inmates to see
so in case you do
decide to kill me,
one of the inmates
will go to Glynn,
give you up,
you end up on death row.
Deal.
What that loco motherfucker
don't know
is that I am gonna
kill him.
After he's down, I slip
a shank in his hand
and it's self-defense.
Fuck.
What's the matter?
My sister's dead,
and ever since I heard the news
I've felt nothing.
And now you tell me
you're going to kill Alvarez
and I feel
this little charge in my belly.
Jesus, what the hell
is that?
It's nothing.
My little sister
worshipped me.
You can't kill Alvarez.
- What?!
- I haven't shed a tear for a sister
who thought
that much of me.
And at the same time,
this Alvarez thing is revving me up.
It's not right.
There's something wrong.
And out of respect for Annette,
I gotta take a look at that.
We both do.
What's happening is you're
on a delayed reaction.
You're in shock.
In a week, you'll be crying
like a baby over your sister.
Thing is,
we don't got a week.
Our best chance to kill
Alvarez is here, right now.
Chico.
You ready?
Ready.
Yo! Yo, my man!
Look over here!
Over here!
Guys, over here! Watch this!
Right.
Right here.
Central, this is 14.
We got a 29 in the gym.
Repeat, we got a 29
in the gym. Get down here.
Hey, hang on, hang on.
Repeat, I have a 29 in the gym.
This is 14.
There you are.
You look right smart.
I wish they'd let you
come with me to the funeral.
Me too, but I wasn't
really a relative or nothing.
I still can't
believe this, man.
How can my moms be dead?
I remember
when I first met your mother.
We were none of us
no more than 14.
I was with your dad,
doing some kind
of nonsense
when all of a sudden,
I saw her coming across
Friedmont Street.
Mmm! She had the
sweetest pair of eyes.
Your dad didn't
even notice her
until I tapped him
on his shoulder.
He looked at her,
she looked at him and that was that.
They got married,
they had you.
Burr...
you always loved
my moms, didn't you?
Of course.
No. No.
No, I mean
you loved her.
I loved your father too.
But life works out
the way life works out.
I want you to put that
on her grave for me.
- What is this?
- My high school graduation ring.
Yo, Busmalis, any word from your fiancée
since she left you at the altar?
Ha. Yeah, sure.
Like, "Don't try and track me down.
I done skipped town."
No, I watched this show yesterday.
Norma's still working
on "Miss Sally."
Her name's still in the credits.
Those are repeats.
In fact, I read in the newspaper
they may even cancel
"Miss Sally's Schoolyard."
What?
Jeez, you are a sad fuck.
No wonder she ditched you.
What the hell
do you know about it?
Know about what,
motherfucker, what?
Loss, being left. You have
no damn idea, you stupid fool.
Ooh!
Hey, I appreciate
your sticking up for me,
but you're gonna
get your butt whooped.
Okay, whatever you say.
- What's eating you?
- My son came to see me today.
Alex Jr.'s condition
has gotten worse.
He's developed
nonlymphocytic leukemia.
Oh, Bob.
That's terrible.
He's in desperate need
of a bone marrow transplant.
- They need you to be the donor?
- No, I'm no good to him.
Nobody in our family is.
Alex Jr.'s mother is
of West Indian
and Guatemalan descent.
My grandson's unique
mixed-race heritage
makes...
for the most beautiful skin
you'll ever lay eyes on.
It also makes finding
a suitable donor extremely difficult.
- There's gotta be a match somewhere.
- Oh, sure, somewhere.
But there's
a great shortage of donors,
and an even greater shortage
of minority donors.
Then doctors should get the word out,
sign more people up.
I wish it were that easy.
But like with so many
other diseases,
there's never enough
money to go around.
Where you going?
To see Dr. Nathan.
I don't feel so hot.
The umbilical cord,
like bone marrow,
contains cells capable
of fighting leukemia.
Unfortunately, that procedure's still very
much in the experimental stages.
Oh, thanks.
Here you go.
Take these.
You'll be fine.
I know how helpless
you feel, Bob.
I hear a story like your grandson's
and it frustrates me too.
My Latina heritage kicks in
and starts kicking me
for being so American.
- I don't follow.
- In Central America,
South America, there's wide belief
that certain herbal medicines
hold great promise in regards
to treating cancer and other diseases.
But you think that's
a bunch of baloney?
Like I said, the AMA
got the best of me.
Pamphlets, magazines,
medical journals,
anything to do
with herbal medicine,
particularly material dealing
with research and treatment of leukemia.
Lights out!
I've found
the cure for cancer.
- You what?
- Lapacho.
- Lapa-who?
- An herb,
from the rainforests
of Paraguay.
Some doctors claim they've
effectively used the herb
to treat cancer,
leukemia in particular.
- Wow. This is great news.
- No, no, no, it's not.
- It's maddening.
- Maddening?
Lapacho is an evergreen.
There are more than 100 species
of lapacho trees.
Identifying which ones
yield the necessary
medicinal material
is very expensive.
Oh, here we go again.
Always money, money, money.
The only way for a man
to get ahead in the world
is to be some kind
of goddamn millionaire.
- I'll raise the cash!
- In Oz? How?
I don't know,
but I'll find a way.
Good luck.
Here are some laws,
real laws currently on the books.
Laws that if you broke,
you'd end up in jail.
The state of Rhode Island
says it's illegal to throw
pickle juice on a trolley.
In the state of Washington,
all lollipops are banned.
Down in Indiana,
baths may not be taken between
the months of October and March.
Over in San Francisco, you cannot
pick up and throw used confetti.
And in North Carolina,
the law forbids dogs and cats to fight.
But you see, that goes
against the laws of nature.
Dogs and cats
are born enemies.
Okay, all done.
Wheel him into the ward.
- We've got trauma to the head.
- What happened?
I was releasing this joker from the hole
and he took a swing at me.
- I ain't no pussy.
- Yeah. So I gave him one of these.
- Faggot!
- Prep him. It doesn't look too bad.
You'll need a couple of stitches.
What's your name?
Stanton, Henry Stanton.
And I don't love you.
- What?
- Glynn sent me to the hole
'cause he said I was obsessed
with your tits, but I'm not.
You gotta tell the warden
I'm an innocent man.
- Okay.
- You gotta... get the fuck...
- tell the warden I'm an innocent man!
- Get off me!
- Hey, hey, hey, Stanton!
- Oh, Jeez! Ow!
- You all right?
- I was handling this, Ryan.
- It didn't look like it.
- Well, l... I don't need you in my life.
- Okay.
- Just get the fuck away from me!
- Okay!
- Keep moving, O'Reily!
I need those sutures!
Where the fuck are they?
I need another pair
of gloves, and prep him for sutures.
Can you hold him,
please?
There you go, Enrique.
Yo, Ryan, save
some extra beets.
All of a sudden you got
quite an appetite there, Marty.
Oh, yeah, I never seem
to get enough.
- Which is why we gotta talk.
- About what?
- My compensation for lying to Glynn.
- Shut the fuck up.
That's what I'm talking about.
For me to keep my lips zipped,
- you gotta come up with more moolah.
- Come on, Marty, man.
- We had a deal, right?
- Well, I'm renegotiating.
All right.
I'll tell you what,
what do you say we meet
in the library, 4:00?
Bring your checkbook.
I had Montgomery lie
to the warden and say
that Henry Stanton
killed Patrick Keenan.
And Montgomery says if I don't
pay more he's gonna rat me out.
If he does, Glynn will know
for sure that you killed Keenan.
He'll fry your ass.
Which is why I'm not gonna make
my 4:00 appointment with Montgomery.
No?
No, I'll have Stanton
show up instead.
Yo, Stanton.
O'Reily, I ain't
bothering your brother
or Nathan or nobody.
So just leave me alone.
Look, I know that, man.
I think you and me,
I think we got off
on the wrong foot.
But I just want to let you know
that I got no beef with you.
- That's good.
- In fact, actually, you and me,
we got something
in common.
We're both suspects in
the murder of Patrick Keenan.
I know.
You know, we both got eyewitnesses
who say they saw us do the deed.
And I don't know
who's accusing me,
but as luck would have it,
I found out who's lying about you.
- Who?
- I'm hesitant to tell you there, Henry,
for fear you're gonna
do something crazy.
Motherfucker lies about me,
that does make me crazy.
- See then, I'm not gonna tell you.
- Tell me, God damn it.
- No, I don't think I should.
- Tell me!
- Please tell me.
- I'm not going to tell you.
- Tell me!
- I'm not going to fucking tell you!
- God damn it, please, tell me.
- Martin Montgomery.
Martin Montgomery?
I'm gonna kill
that fucking cunt!
I guess you won't be talking no more,
will you, motherfucker?
- Get off him!
- Oh, shit!
I got him.
We got a neck wound!
I got this guy...
Stanton!
Stanton's in solitary.
Montgomery's at Benchley Memorial
in critical condition.
People at the gym
say they overheard
you telling Stanton that Montgomery
squealed on him.
Oh, no. Stanton asked me if I'd...
if I knew anything about it,
and I told him I just heard
a rumor. That's all.
We found this
in Montgomery's foot locker.
What's that?
Keenan's shamrock.
Oh, yeah, right.
I recognize that now.
What the fuck was
Montgomery doing with it?
I was hoping maybe
you could tell me.
Oh no. Jeez, warden,
I don't know.
Suzanne Fitzgerald, the '60s radical
who turned herself in
to federal authorities after 32 years
on the run, was released today
from the Parker Correctional
Facility for Women.
No fucking way.
Governor James Devlin
has commuted Fitzgerald's sentence
- to two years of community service.
- Yes!
The governor's decision,
while widely expected,
- remains controversial.
- Yes! Come on, Cyril.
We're so glad you decided
to do your community service in Oz.
And the idea of starting
a performing arts program is great.
Oh, thank you. L... I taught music
for 20 years in St. Albans.
And when I heard that you didn't have
any kind of arts education program here,
it seemed like a good fit.
But you know the hardest part is gonna
be convincing these guys to sign up.
I don't know about that. I think
they'll sign up out of the novelty.
But the tough thing will be
getting them to stick with it.
Well, if I could motivate 10-year-olds,
I think I can handle your prisoners.
So what do you need
to get started?
Well, l... I would love to see
where I'm going to work.
The stage is in the cafeteria.
I'll take you right over.
- And then I'd like to see my son.
- Oh, sure.
Psst.
Ryan!
- Hey.
- Ryan.
Oh, Christ, I thought
I'd lost you forever.
Oh, no, baby.
You're stuck with me.
I know he's not your son,
and he's only my half-brother,
but I kind of want
you to meet Cyril.
- Oh, yeah, I'd love to.
- Yeah? Okay? Hey, Cyril? Cyril?
- Hello.
- I made this for you.
- Oh. Thank you.
That's so sweet.
It's beautiful.
Can I give you a hug and kiss?
- Sure.
- Okay.
So, are you two going
to be my first pupils?
Oh, jeez, you know, Mom,
l... I can't sing.
- Me neither.
- You can't?
Oh. Guess you take
after your father.
That man had the voice
of a warthog.
- She's funny, right?
- She's funny.
I'm glad you
think so.
Will you have some
of your friends sign up?
- Our friends?
- Uh-Huh.
Oh, yeah.
Of course.
All right, all right,
I'll do it.
In fact, I've been told I have
a pretty good voice.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
In high school, I had the lead
in "The Pirates of Penzance."
? I am the very model
of a modern major general?
- ? I have information...?
- As far as my mother's concerned,
you've never sang a note,
you got it?
- Okay, not a problem.
- Okay.
Hey, O'Reily,
your mama's looking fine.
Does she
fuck younger guys?
What was that, Hoyt?
What the fuck you say?
- Fuck you, bitch!
- I'm gonna kill you!
- Shut the fuck up!
- Get the fuck away, you cocksucker!
- Bring it, Hoyt! Bring it!
- Get the fuck off!
Slowly, slowly roll up.
Roll up.
Wait. Slowly, slowly, slowly.
Wait... wait, Matt.
Hold on.
Okay.
Relax your jaw.
Relax your shoulders.
Relax your arms.
- We gotta talk.
- I'm in the middle of a class.
Oh, that's okay.
I've got work to do.
Well, l... I'll
see you Thursday?
Um...
definitely.
- Come here, come here, come here.
- What?
- I want you to quit.
- Quit?
- Yeah, look...
- On my first day?
I've ticked off a lot of the assholes
in this place, okay?
- I don't want to put you in jeopardy.
- Jeopardy?
- Yeah.
- There's a C.O. Standing nearby.
- Trust me, the hacks aren't reliable.
- I'm not worried.
- Yeah, but I am.
- Well, that's sweet.
Look, I'm not
being sweet, okay?
Christ, you could get hurt.
Ryan, I'm a big girl
and I've made my choice.
Look, this is where I'm needed.
This is where I belong.
Nothing you can say
is gonna make me change my mind.
Hey, O'Reily,
you working today?
- Go.
- Yeah, but, Mom...
- Yo, move your fucking ass, O'Reily.
We working alone
on this, motherfucker?
Shit!
Dave, you're back.
- Yeah.
- How are you?
All right.
Look, I meant to get over
to the hospital, but...
That's okay.
How are you?
Oh, I already asked that, didn't I?
But you're...
you're good though, huh?
I'm working.
So you're staying at Oz?
I'm not sure.
Warden's got me
stationed here,
and I'm going to have
to think about my next move.
I feel fucking terrible
that this happened.
So, you never did find out
who cut me, did you?
No.
Truthfully... I think
that's why I'm here.
I want to know.
I fucking want to know.
I'd fucking hurt the guy, Tim,
I'm serious. I'd hurt him for keeps.
Your injury was
the result
of someone not wanting you to play
in that final basketball game.
- But how?
- Well, after we decided not to play...
I told Morales that you
were going to play.
Oh.
I'm so goddamned sorry.
I'll buzz you in.
Goddamn
motherfucking thing!
Tim, the warden
wanted me to tell you,
special staff meeting
at 11:00.
- Is there an emergency?
- Governor Devlin's coming.
- Got some kind of announcement.
- Can't wait.
- 11:00 on the dot. Don't be late!
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And even though I think
Commissioner Douglas
does an outstanding job,
we've had an ongoing
lack of communication
between my office
and you people here
in the trenches.
We want to open
the lines of dialogue...
- Don't interrupt me.
- Yes, sir.
And so I've decided
to create a liaison
between you
and the governor's mansion.
Someone you can go to...
Sorry I'm late.
...someone experienced
in the field
who you can talk to about
any problems that arise,
who can clear up
any changes
in my administration's
prison policies.
And so,
I'd like to present
Eleanor O'Connor.
Thank you, Governor,
Commissioner.
Well, I'm the new kid
in town,
fresh off the boat
from New York City,
where I worked in a similar
capacity for the mayor.
I won't pretend to grasp
all the needs of Oswald,
all of your needs.
But I can promise you that my door
will always be unlocked.
I intend to help cut through
the bureaucracy, the bullshit.
Thank you.
Okay, get yourselves some
cookies and some lemonade.
- Ms. O'Connor...
- Ellie.
Ellie will be hanging around
to meet and greet.
- I have to go.
- Me too.
Ellie, welcome.
I love what you said.
This is the first smart thing
the governor's done in years.
I get the impression
Devlin's not well liked.
Really?
Some of us love him.
- Hello.
- Best of luck.
- Thank you.
Tim, wait up.
I'll head back to Em City with you.
- She seems nice, genuine.
- Yeah.
- Do me a favor. Don't try to fuck her.
- What?
Every skirt that crosses
the threshold here, you jump on.
Oh, that is simply
not true.
Wittlesey, Nathan, Howell,
that broad from the State Department.
I'm not gonna be fucking
Eleanor O'Connor.
- Oh no?
- No, 'cause I already did.
- What?
- She's my ex-wife.
You got...
Jeez, man.
In Arkansas, a man
can legally beat
his wife once a month.
In Los Angeles...
pay attention now...
a man can legally beat his wife
with a strap as long as the strap
is less than two inches wide.
Or if the woman gives
her husband permission,
he can use any size
strap he wants.
I don't care.
This is not right.
- Leo free?
- No.
- God damn it!
- Who's that?
- Officer Brass.
- This is bullshit!
- Brass!
- If I could get another fucking job
somewhere else,
I'd quit in a second.
But I'm a gimp.
Nobody's hiring gimps these days.
- Dave, what's wrong?
- Wall-to-wall bullshit.
Leo?
He's pissed
I assigned to him to reception
and I won't let him deal
with prisoners... put him back in Unit B.
Well, why won't you?
Tim, if there's trouble,
I need my C.O. S to be agile,
to be able to move, not...
hobble.
All the same,
he was cut on the job.
Hey, and I feel badly for him,
but I'm not running a funhouse.
Brass' desires fall on the far side
of the overall good.
What do you want
to see me about?
Lt'll keep.
Dave, I think
you should sue.
Sue? Sue who?
Oz. The whole prison
system,
the fucking state,
if need be.
- How can I sue?
- Look, I checked this out for you.
In 1990, Congress passed
the Americans with Disabilities Act,
which protects the disabled from being
discriminated against in the workplace.
Yeah, but that's like
for wheelchair access and stuff.
No, no, no, not only.
It covers people like you
who, because of their
injuries, are demoted.
Well, I'd have to get
a lawyer.
Well, yeah, but maybe
you should try talking
to this state
liaison person.
This Eleanor O'Connor.
Tell O'Connor how you feel.
Okay, I will.
All right.
And...
don't take
any shit from her.
Still work late, huh?
Yeah, well, you know.
I stopped by earlier,
but you weren't around.
Took a tour
of Emerald City.
It is quite something
you've built here.
Guess it was worth
walking out on me after all.
- Ellie...
- No recriminations, Tim.
You made your choices,
I made mine.
Good to see you.
Want to grab some dinner?
No, thanks. I'm still up to my chest
in cardboard boxes.
Oh, well...
another time then.
I had a chat with your friend
Dave Brass.
Sad tale, his.
Promising basketball career
nipped in the Achilles.
Had a chat with the warden too.
He's reassigning him to the cafeteria.
Good.
It'll free up his hours
for physical therapy too.
See, I knew you could
turn the situation around.
- You told him to sue the state?
- Well...
Were you serious
or were you just testing me?
- Both.
- You son of a bitch.
You know what? That's the nicest
thing you ever said to me.
Wait. I'm sure the name calling
will get much worse.
- Looking forward to it.
- Likewise, I'm sure.
Nice try.
Hey, you want
to play some pool?
Still torn up about
that bus accident?
Yeah.
I just talked
to Carrie's parents.
They're in town
for the funeral.
They said they're taking Jewel
back to Montana with them.
I might never see
my granddaughter again.
Hey, that sucks, Vern,
but what can you do?
You never had kids,
did you?
Nah.
My wife didn't want
to mess with her figure.
Well, then you don't have
a fucking clue what I'm talking about.
Come here, you bitch.
Come over here.
Bye, baby.
Prisoner #97P468:
Charles Pancamo,
a.k.a. Chucky the Enforcer:
Convicted June 4th,
1997:
Sentence: 35 years:
Up for parole in 15.
Get your feet off my desk!
All right, I wanted to see all of you
because I've got some news.
Peter Schibetta is
returning to Em City today.
Schibetta? I thought
he was in the loony bin.
Well, not anymore.
He's undergone long-term therapy,
and I'm happy to say
he's recovered.
You mean, he got over
being raped by Adebisi?
I don't want
to minimize his trauma,
or pretend that he's exactly
the way he was before.
But he's learned to accept
and deal with the situation.
Be good to see Petey.
He and me, we came up together.
- And his father...
- Yeah, his father was a legend here.
Yeah. Well...
it's gonna be rough
on him for a few days.
So all I ask is
that you tread lightly.
Don't worry about it, McManus.
We know how to take care of our own.
It's all different, huh?
Yeah, the gas explosion
pretty much obliterated the place.
Good.
There you go.
- Come with me.
- Where?
- The FBI wants to talk to you.
- FBI?
- They fucking want talk to me?
- Just move it, Pancamo.
Do you know a man
named Gaetano Cincetta?
- Not that I recall.
- You don't know him?
- You never met him?
- Not that I recall.
- That's odd.
Mr. Cincetta,
who just blabbed his way
into the witness
protection program,
says you hired him
to kill someone.
Hank Schillinger.
Do you know Hank Schillinger?
- Not that I recall.
- He's the son of Vernon Schillinger.
- Do you know Vernon Schillinger?
- Not that I recall.
He's a fellow resident here at Oswald.
Do you remember him now?
- To the best of my "reciglection"...
- Recollection.
I don't know
the fucking guy.
Chris Keller confessed to hiring
a hit man to kill Hank Schillinger,
only he never identified who.
Mr. Cincetta says
he's never heard of Keller.
We gave Keller
a lie detector test.
Turns out he lied about
his part in the murder.
Now why do you think
Keller would do that?
Nice tie.
Okay.
Officer, take this weasel
back to whatever hole
he crawled out of.
I guess my next conversation's
with Vern Schillinger.
I wonder if he'll
remember you.
He's gonna tell Schillinger
that I ordered the hit.
Then Schillinger's going
to come searching for details.
Fuck!
You know, when I asked you to hire
somebody to kill Hank Schillinger,
you said nobody would find the body,
not in a million years.
You guaranteed it. Well, it only took
six fucking months.
Seems like you did
a really half-assed job.
Hey, you be careful.
To be honest,
Gaetano Cincetta
was a big disappointment.
Schillinger's gonna
cut off my balls
- if he finds out the truth.
- He won't.
Look, it was my screw-up,
so I'm gonna cover for you.
I'll sleep well tonight.
That's the thing about Oz,
you know,
you try to put
the shit behind you,
you make a real effort.
And just when you're thinking,
"maybe I have,"
more shit comes flying.
You sure it was Pancamo
put the mark on Hank?
Absolutely sure.
Hey, you, you fucking dago!
You killed my son.
I'm fine, I'm fine,
I'm fine.
Just give me
a fucking band-aid.
Let's see. Okay.
Whoop.
Jimmy?
What's going on?
The Aryans attacked
the Sicilians.
Pancamo hired the hit man
to kill Hank Schillinger.
Oh, I see.
Keller wasn't involved
in Hank's death,
so Massachusetts has
no reason to hold him.
- Wait. That means...
- Chris Keller is coming back to Oz.
McManus, hold up, hold up.
- Can... can I have a word with you?
- Sorry, I'm on the run.
Oh, please don't
do me like this, man.
Heartless motherfucker.
What the fuck
did you say to me?
I got a big heart
a few days ago.
- Now I'm fucking heartless?
- I didn't mean it, okay?
Well, I'm here.
What do you want?
I know that you done everything
that you can to help me.
But sitting here,
I've come up
with a whole new solution.
If I could just, you know,
hang with you a bit, you know.
No, no, no, no,
not like before.
Just if I could chill in your office,
you know, just from time to time.
No!
Jesus Christ!
What the fuck
am I supposed to do?
I mean, yo,
you're the only friend I got here.
I mean, just anything.
Just to have somebody to talk to.
All right, vacation's over.
Come on, White. Out.
- Help me, please.
- I'll try to think of something, okay?
What am I supposed to do
while you think?
If it takes staying
in your cell 24/7
to steer clear
of trouble...
That... that's worse
than the cage.
That'd be like
being back in solitary.
Damn.
Take that bread
out of your mouth.
- Sorry, Minister.
- Oh, you're sorry?
- Yes, Minister, forgive me.
- Get up,
- walk away.
- What?
You can't quell your desire
for even a moment
in order to give thanks
and praise to Allah?
Grab your tray.
Take off your keffiye.
Imam, you're being
too severe.
Are you
contesting me, Arif?
Brother Lalar is new
to the fold. Scold him,
take away his food,
but don't cast him out.
You're sitting down?
You'll sit down?
Did I tell you to sit down!
You cannot sit down!
Hey! Hey!
Did I tell you
you can sit down! Did I?
So what was
all that about?
Why'd you attack
Ahmad Lalar?
You keep me
from going to the hole,
- so in return I answer questions?
- Yeah.
Although part of me thinks I'm not gonna
get any answers from you.
I mean, a man who used
to fight with words
is now not only using his fists,
he's choking Muslims.
I'll give you 10-to-one odds
you don't have the slightest clue
why you're doing
the things you're doing.
And you would lose the bet.
The day Adebisi died,
I changed
and I took his life
to save my own.
That was the Adebisi side of me
coming to the surface.
Only now I realize it hasn't
just come to the surface.
It's at the very center
of who I am.
Bullshit.
Everybody's got demons.
But you've given all
the weight of who you are
over to this horrible shit
you're discovering about yourself.
Yet you're more equipped
than any other prisoner in Oz
to straighten yourself out,
and you know it.
And knowing that and having failed
to do so has fucked you up even more.
- Just put me in the hole.
- I'm not putting you in the hole.
- Please.
- I'm giving you a job instead.
- A job?
- You want to save yourself, Kareem?
Yes.
Well, I want you
to save somebody else.
What you looking at?
What's he doing here?
What the fuck is he
looking at me like that for?
I'm the one
who's gonna help you.
I don't need no motherfucking help,
especially from him.
- What he gonna do for me?
- Kareem's gonna be your new sponsor.
- Sponsor?
- Starting today, you and I
will share the same pod.
We will exercise together,
we will eat together,
we will work alongside of each other.
You still need to meet
with Sister Pete for counseling,
and your attendance is mandatory
at all drug rehab sessions.
Plus the warden wants you tested
for drugs once a week.
Now, Omar,
this is your last play,
and it's fourth and long.
You miss one meeting, you get in
one fight, you piss Said off one time,
it's back to solitary permanently.
You understand me?
All right.
Hey, yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah, boy.
My boy is something else,
ain't he?
McManus, jack. That motherfucker's
like a straight up brainiac, you know?
A genius motherfucker
and shit, boy. Shit.
He be coming up with all kind
of little ways, you know, and shit,
you know, to help
me try to lick my...
what's it called?
Shortcomings.
Yeah, and I done fucked with him
a couple of times too, and shit.
But you know what? Having me,
you know, all up in your draft and shit,
picking up all the, you know,
Saidian vibrations...
First of all,
don't hustle me.
Whoa,
hold up, baby.
Yo, you got to chill, baby.
Second of all,
I am not your baby.
My name is Minister Said,
and you will address me as such.
No, no, no, fuck that shit.
I told you, man, about that shit.
You're not coming up here,
converting my ass.
Man, that shit is out.
Forget it.
I am not converting you.
Also, I am not going
to argue with you.
So this thing is over.
- Get out.
- What?
- Out.
- Whoa...
Look, shut the door,
all right?
I'm sorry.
Shut it, please.
Make your bed.
Make... your bed.
I will not fight.
- You talking to me?
- Say it,
"I will not fight."
I will not fight.
Again.
From now on, that
will be your mantra.
Every time another inmate
gets in your face,
you will say,
"I will not fight."
You will say it
over and over,
out loud
if you have to.
- I will not fight.
- Yeah.
I will not fight.
If I could just
conquer not fighting...
Shit, I'm home free, boy.
I mean, there's nothing in the world
I hate more than
motherfucking solitary.
If I go back in there,
the fucking worms.
Worms? What are you
talking about, worms?
In my head, man.
Every time I go back, it's the worms.
Fat ones, big ones,
old ones.
I can't survive
the fucking worms!
I think about spending
the rest of my life
in this Em City...
for eight... 18,000 days,
23,000 days.
That's a lot of days.
A lot of days not to fight,
not to get high.
Think about it like that...
the chances
don't look too good.
In Nogales, Arizona,
it's illegal to wear
suspenders.
You gotta wonder
what happened.
What cataclysmic event occurred
which caused the city fathers
to decree that in our town
no one, under any circumstances,
can wear suspenders?
And are there radical
fringe groups in Nogales
who meet at night in secret,
who slip off their belts
and in defiance of the law
put these suckers on? Huh?
- How's Cloutier?
- Oh, his vital signs are stable,
but he still can't
move very much.
- Is he talking yet?
- Um...
No, only
guttural sounds.
- Could I see him?
- Ray, he's pretty disfigured.
I was assistant chaplain
at Benchley Memorial
when I was a seminarian.
I've seen burn victims.
Oh, sweet Jesus.
Jeremiah?
If you don't mind,
I'd like to say a prayer.
Our Father,
who art in heaven,
hallowed be Thy name.
- Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done...
on earth
as it is in heaven.
Give us this day
our daily bread
and forgive us
our trespasses...
It's open.
- Mukada?
- Come in.
Leave the door open.
What did you need
to see me about?
I heard that you're planning
a memorial service
to honor the victims for the families
who were killed in the bus crash.
Yes. I've asked Arif
and Rabbi Gold
and Reverend Taylor
from the First Baptist to participate.
- But not me.
- You?
Ever since Jeremiah Cloutier's
unfortunate accident...
I would hardly call being
bricked up into a wall accidental.
I meant the third-degree burns
he suffered from the gas explosion.
- Oh.
- Since then, I've been ministering
to many of the Christians
in Oz.
Getting up on stage
and reading from a Bible
doesn't constitute
a ministry.
You're still holding a grudge
because I rejected Romanism.
No, I'm glad you're no longer
part of my congregation.
I demand to be included
in the ecumenical service.
- You're not qualified.
- I'm an ordained priest.
Since when?
I signed up by mail.
50 bucks. See?
Get out of my office.
I'll go over your head,
to the warden.
Yeah, and he'll ignore you.
Then I'll go over
his head to God.
Listen, you little punk,
we know that you were
involved in Cloutier's accident.
And as soon as he's able
to talk, to testify,
you're going to solitary
for the rest of your goddamn life!
We have to kill
Cloutier right now.
His throat's still sore from the burns,
but when he's well,
he's going to sing
and we'll all be up shit's creek.
Look, I'm already up
the creek, pal. Okay?
Look, Jaz, I know that
because you were the one
in charge
of the work detail that day,
you've taken the heat
for the rest of us.
But that's no reason
that Cloutier should live.
Look, he dies,
the hacks blame me.
Right, so the person
who kills him
has to be
above reproach.
Jim?
No, I can't.
Cloutier brought me
to Jesus.
Jim, if you're not part of the solution,
you're Satan's tool.
Yeah. Do the deed, or die.
Jim?
Jim Burns?
Those men want you
to kill me, Jim,
but you know that
what they ask is wrong.
- Yes.
- So I say unto you,
kill them.
Kill Hoyt and Kirk.
The Reverend Cloutier was
in my cell last night.
- For what, a blowjob?
- This ain't funny.
- You had a dream.
- It was no dream.
- Chickenshit.
- You're trying to get out of the job.
Go kill the cocksucker.
- No!
- No?
He told me to kill you!
It's self-defense.
It's... it's motherfucking
self-defense.
I got witnesses.
You got nothing on me.
There was fucking
10 guys there.
Put him in the hole.
Self-defense!
Will we be having
a service for Jim?
Yes, of course.
We must pray
for his immortal soul.
Lights out!
Manmade laws are arbitrary,
transitory.
What was perfectly
legal yesterday
suddenly becomes a felony today
with the stroke of some president's pen.
The laws of god, however,
are carved in stone.
They do not change.
And when you break
God's law,
you don't go to prison,
you go to hell.
And you burn.
Hoyt!
Don't be afraid.