l don't wanna fight nobody!
ln America we all have certain
inalienable rights,
like the right to bear arms
and the right to remain silent.
But the state has the ultimate right.
lt can kill us.
Due to popular demand,
Governor James Devlin revived
capital punishment.
And he decided
that Jefferson Keane,
a man he doesn't know,
a man he will never even meet,
should be put to death.
Should be put down
like a rabid dog.
The mood in this country
has changed.
People are sick of crime,
sick of being afraid.
They need a sign
that something is being done.
Even, governor, if it's been proven
that executions have no effect
on the increase or decrease
in crime whatsoever?
Especially if it has no effect. These
days murders are random, senseless.
Maybe the punishment
should be too.
Jefferson Keane will be the first person
executed by this state in 34 years.
He's the first because he snapped
the neck of another inmate.
He's the first because
he deserves to die.
Jefferson Keane is the first
because he's black and he's young.
The public is not gonna feel safe
if we execute a 70-year-old white guy.
- You gonna turn this into a racial thing?
- Oh, please.
Anybody thought about all the protestors
we're gonna have outside,
marching around, yelling slogans?
And the counter-protestors
yelling at them?
Yeah, and we'll have
even less parking spaces.
The protestors aren't
gonna be a problem.
l want you to know
that when those protestors come,
l'm standing with them.
l can't have an employee of mine
out there at a vigil,
- holding a candle in front of a camera.
- The last time l looked,
we had freedom of speech and
freedom of assembly in this country.
- Or did you eliminate those rights too?
- The governor's been biting my ass,
saying he's gonna make
more budget cuts.
And he means it,
up to, and including, your job.
ls this a threat?
l've got a job, Leo.
l've got a permanent vocation.
l can go teach fifth-grade kids
at Cathedral School.
l can go be a missionary
in Pago Pago.
- Don't join the protestors.
- And if l do?
You're fired.
Well, that's fine.
l'll send you a postcard
from Pago Pago.
Hey, Markstrom, man,
what if Keane didn't kill Martinez, huh?
Look, what if they got
the wrong man?
- He did it, Kenny.
- Look, l know he did it.
l'm saying what if he didn't do it?
- l don't understand.
- All l'm saying, Nino, is,
makes you wonder
what the guy's doing,
what the guy's thinking, sitting
on death row knowing he's gonna die.
The only difference between
you and him, Joey,
is he knows the exact date he'll die.
So the state's gonna let Keane choose
which way he wants to go out.
Me, l'd take hanging.
- What about lethal injection?
- That's for pussies.
They say lethal injection
causes no pain.
How do they know?
Did someone come back from the dead
and say they didn't feel anything?
Did you hear?
Sister Peter Marie got fired.
Yeah, l know. l was her assistant.
She got fired because
she's against the death penalty.
- So am l.
- Me too.
Were you around when the last
person in the state was executed?
l was the last person
in this state executed.
So you're saying your life was saved
by the '65 blackout?
All the electricity in five states gone.
To this day they don't know
whether the shortage kept me alive
or if l caused the power to go:
- And you had no after-effects?
- Sure.
That's when l first met God.
He shook my hand, smiled
and said, ''Bob, play the oboe.''
- The oboe?
- The oboe.
- And do you?
- What?
- Play the oboe.
- No.
l don't have the lips for it.
Gonna share?
Hey, lawboy.
l thought Schillinger said
you couldn't get high anymore.
Yeah. Fuck him.
You go over my appeal?
Ryan, l told you,
l was in litigation, not criminal law.
l got no chance, huh?
Considering the number
of eyewitnesses?
- No.
- Yeah. Fuck it.
Least l'm not getting the juice
like that scumfuck Keane.
He should've just let
the Latinos take him out.
That's the reason
why they were there.
What do you mean?
The Latinos were in the gym
to kill Keane?
- Never mind.
- Are you saying he was set up?
- Never mind, Beecher.
- No, no, no, if it was self-defence,
- he shouldn't be executed.
- Fuck that.
Don't make trouble or you'll be next.
Excuse me.
l'd like to get a fax copy of the transcript
from the Jefferson Keane trial.
Beecher.
Get your ass over here.
- Yes, sir?
- My laundry's not gonna wash itself.
Sir, have you heard anything
about Jefferson Keane being set up?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, the hacks
made him a gladiator.
Even got the whole thing
on videotape.
- Wouldn't you love to see that?
- Yeah.
lf we can get ahold of that videotape,
he wouldn't be executed.
What are you talking about?
Another nigger's going down.
l'm glad.
- But--
- But, but what?
Nothing, sir.
Don't forget, a little starch.
So l'll go to McManus, tell him
what might have happened in the gym,
- get him to investigate.
- You can't.
- Why not?
- You say anything, they'll kill you.
- They who?
- Exactly.
Hey, Beecher.
Sorry l got a little testy before.
That's okay.
You wanna get high?
No, thanks, man. Not right now.
Kind of trying to keep my head clean.
Later.
What l should do is represent Keane
and appeal his murder conviction.
You?
- l'm a lawyer.
- The state disbarred you.
The state can't take away what l do,
who l am. l can help the man.
He killed Martinez in self-defence.
He shouldn't die.
You need to talk to Keane himself,
find out what really went on that day.
Yeah, l know,
but getting into death row isn't easy.
l have a way.
- l'm in fear for my life.
- From who?
l can't say.
You know l can't say. l need you
to put me in protective custody.
You can't be going in and out of
protective custody whenever you want.
lt's to be used
only in extreme cases.
- Well, this is.
- Next time you ask for protection,
- l may say no.
- l'll take that risk.
Keane?
Keane.
- Who wants me?
- Beecher.
Tobias Beecher.
l need to talk to you about your trial.
l read your transcript.
You weren't cooperative
with your attorneys.
l killed Martinez.
Why didn't you tell the lawyers
that you were set up?
Look,
Johnny Post killed Dino Ortolani
because l told him to.
Now, the Wiseguys know that.
Now they want me dead.
lf they kill me,
one of my Homeboys gonna kill them.
And then they gonna kill
another one of my boys.
And on and on and on.
- My death can put an end to that.
- Not necessarily.
Look, if l die,
l feel like l might go to heaven now.
lf l go back to Em City,
l might go back to my old ways.
l may lose my faith, my soul.
l'm at peace right now, Beecher.
Please don't take that from me.
Look, l'm not responsible
for your soul,
but as a lawyer,
l am responsible for justice.
l don't need your cooperation
to file an appeal on your behalf.
Beecher, please, don't.
lt's something l have to do.
We gotta get ahold of that tape.
lt's got the fight
between Keane and the Latinos.
What are the chances
of one of the hacks giving it up?
The video would implicate them
in the murder.
Yeah, well,
- do what you can, Bob.
- Sure.
There you are.
Oh, yeah, hey.
Why did you go into PC?
You know, l just needed
some time alone.
- What are you doing here?
- Working on Ryan O'Reily's appeal.
Really?
- Thought you said that was useless.
- Well...
Yeah, you know, but he asked me
to take another stab at it,
so l figured l would.
You wouldn't be bullshitting me,
would you?
You wanna take a break?
- You wouldn't be up to something else?
- No, sir.
''Argent v. the state of Texas--''
This is about a stay of execution.
Since when is O'Reily
being executed?
- Eat it.
- What?
- Eat the page.
- No.
Do not fuck with me, prag. Eat it.
Another one?
- Rebadow?
- Yes?
l understand you've been asking
questions about a certain videotape.
- Well...?
- Said videotape does not exist.
- Oh, really?
- You don't believe me?
No. Why should l?
Maybe a couple of days in the hole
will help clarify reality for you.
Heard you talked to Keane
even though l said don't.
Yeah.
That took some balls.
Starting to grow some balls,
Beecher?
l had balls...
...a long, long time ago.
And l thought l could get them
back again by saving Jefferson Keane.
But the lawyer in me...
...got stretched out on the rack
and hung by the neck until dead.
You got any dope?
What you need, pal, is an upgrade.
What you need is some heroin.
Go ahead.
You swat a fly, step on an ant,
squash a cockroach,
you don't think much of it.
ln fact, killing the bug gives you
a sense of accomplishment.
Fucking ant was ruining your picnic.
Cockroach was crawling
through your kitchen cabinet.
You put an end to their disgusting,
miserable little lives
and make a better world
for everyone.
Only for every one you kill,
more appear.
Bigger, uglier, meaner than before.
As a man of colour,
l am outraged by that verdict.
As a Muslim, l have to be concerned
with Tizi Ouzou's soul.
- Tizi Ouzou?
- Since the conversion,
that's the name that Jefferson Keane
chose for himself.
And so you wanna serve
as his minister?
As his imam, yes.
- You have any objection?
- No.
Okay, then. Here's the deal.
You can go see Keane in death row
and talk to him,
but only about spiritual matters.
lf l get wind of him or you,
or any of the brothers stirring up shit,
l will give him a rabbi.
As the day of execution draws near,
tension grows
both outside the walls at the Oswald
Maximum Security Penitentiary,
and inside, where the debate
on the death penalty is no less fierce.
l don't believe in murder. First degree,
abortion, or by jury decree.
- lt's all murder.
- Lethal injection?
What's wrong with
the good old electric chair?
Jefferson Keane will die tomorrow
in this prison.
ln light of the historic, moral
and political nature of the event,
we might lose sight
of the human factors involved.
We spoke today with
Cornelius Keane, the inmate's father,
and Helen Martinez,
mother of the murder victim.
You teach a boy right from wrong
and then you just hope,
you just hope for the best.
l want him dead.
l want him in the ground,
dead.
Dead. Dead.
Jefferson Keane's sister's
in kidney failure.
- They think she'll die.
- Oh, this is just great.
Well, life just keeps getting
better and better.
l fucked this up from the get-ready.
Ortolani's dead because of me,
and now
Keane's gonna join him.
You think you're responsible
for that bad boy being on death row?
Timmy, and l mean this
in the nicest way possible,
you are one fucked-up guy.
Well...
...does that mean
we're not going to the play tonight?
Doctor. We need you.
We should run some tests.
Hey, some say
there are five stages of death.
Denial, anger, bargaining,
depression, and finally, acceptance.
The moment
when you say to yourself:
''l'm gonna die
and there ain't shit l can do about it.''
Oh, yeah,
in Oz we know all about that.
We know all about acceptance.
Look at your hair.
Come on, let me braid it for you.
Nah. lt's all right.
Come on, l'll make your hair
look so nice they won't wanna kill you.
- Come on, come on.
- You're crazy.
lf you really want to, chief.
- l saw Pop on TV yesterday.
- Yeah?
Talking about you,
talking about our family.
Sorry l ain't who you want me to be.
l like being queer.
l love you, Billie.
Allah loves you.
But Dad don't.
Jefferson. l'm sorry, Tizi.
l've got some bad news.
Your sister Grace is in the hospital.
Kidney failure.
The doctors think
that she'll probably die soon
unless she gets a transplant.
- But organs are scarce.
- Well, just take one of mine.
Not like l'm gonna use them
much longer.
- Make that happen, McManus.
- l'll try.
No, you do more than try.
Make it happen.
Make it happen!
You are sick people!
The governor says no.
He won't grant a stay.
Even that little prick Devlin
can't be that heartless.
Says Keane is too dangerous
to be released to a hospital.
He's changed.
This conversion of his
could be bullshit.
Talk to him, Leo. lt's real.
- We gotta fight for this one.
- How?
We go public, we stoke the protestors
and piss Devlin off even more.
- Devlin thinks he's God.
- Yeah.
Maybe it's time we got some help
from the real one.
You want me to call the cardinal
to intercede?
- Yes.
- Tim,
Cardinal Abgott
is more conservative
than Jesse Helms and Bill Buckley
all rolled into one.
He once gave a speech
where he justified the torture
of the Holy lnquisition.
That's fucked up.
Even so, you gotta make the call.
- You make the call.
- What, Ray? Are you afraid?
- No, of course l'm not.
- Then?
Why do you think
that l work here, huh, Tim?
l went to the Pontifical Gregorian
University in the Vatican.
l was in the top of my class.
l was the cardinal's
great yellow hope,
until l started working in his office and
l just asked a few too many questions.
l had a few too many opinions.
l defied him, instead of deifying him.
So His Excellency decided
to punish me by sending me to Oz,
to extinguish my career.
So Jefferson Keane's sister dies
because you
and the cardinal had a tiff?
l didn't say l wouldn't make the call.
l'll make the call.
l'm just warning you,
it probably won't...
...do any good.
Sorry to disturb you.
You've come about the transplant.
Governor James Devlin,
under pressure from religious leaders
including Sheik Zahir Farar
and Francis Cardinal Abgott,
has granted a 30-day stay
of execution to Jefferson Keane,
the man convicted
of killing another inmate
at Oswald Maximum Security
Penitentiary.
Keane will donate a kidney
to an ailing sister.
He is expected to go into surgery
sometime today.
The governor was quick to point out
that all medical costs
are being covered
by the family's own insurance.
Clemency.
That's a fancy word for mercy.
You see, the governor can
commute a death sentence.
He has the power to just
pick up the phone and say no.
But to me, the only time
the governor shows clemency,
is when he don't make that call.
Because life in prison without parole
is a shitload worse than death.
Death is parole.
Death is the real mercy.
- King me.
- Oh, fuck.
- O'Reily.
- Yeah?
- Come here.
- Why?
- Because l say.
- So?
- We got business.
- Don't move any pieces.
- l got them memorized.
- Would l do that?
What do you think of me?
Hey, Joey. l'm here.
- You bet Detroit in the game?
- Yeah.
- You lost.
- Fucking Thomas.
- You owe.
- l know. l'm good for it.
- Says you.
- Haven't l paid before?
- l want it now.
- Why?
- Because you owe.
- Why you busting my balls?
- l don't like your face.
- Hey, take a look in the mirror.
- You wanna die?
- Wanna try?
Problem, guys?
Yeah, the joint smells
of too much...garlic.
- What you want?
- D'Angelo, count to ten and walk away.
Fucking dago jizzbag.
- You lose, white boy.
- No, l never lose when it counts.
l'm telling you, Jefferson was set up.
- By who?
- Come on,
you don't have to be John Thompson
to figure out the game plan.
You know it was the Wiseguys
that did it.
Schibetta sent Jefferson
to the gladiator ring?
No, not Schibetta.
l been asking around.
Looks like Joey D'Angelo
was roguing.
Ever since Ortolani croaked,
D'Angelo's been wanting to move up,
but the old man has been slow.
So D'Angelo took it on himself
to off Jefferson
just to impress the old man.
That fucking mook, D'Angelo?
lf D'Angelo got Jefferson
the death penalty,
we gotta execute that mother--
Look, you fellas do
what you gotta do,
but with all this shit
that's been going on around here,
if you whack D'Angelo,
Glynn's gonna lock us down for good.
- So, what are we supposed to do?
- You two work in the kitchen, right?
D'Angelo works in the kitchen.
- Maybe he has a little accident.
- Yeah.
- l like that.
- Yeah, yeah.
Now, why are you so hot on
justice for Jefferson, huh, white boy?
Because Jefferson took care
of Ortolani for me. l owe him.
Good morning.
- l'm Colin Auerbach,
- Who?
and, as you know,
Sister Peter Marie is not around,
so the warden asked me to pitch in.
- We want Sister Pete.
- She's not here.
- Today, we're gonna be--
- Shut the fuck up!
Thank you.
Today we're gonna talk about
anger management.
Controlling the savage beast
inside you.
You fuck.
Mr. Schibetta?
Can l come in?
l heard what happened to Joey.
Steam pipe bursts, knocks him
backward, hits him in the head.
- ls he okay?
- He's unconscious.
He'll be laid up for a while.
l don't mean to be reaching,
but if you ever need an extra hand...
l mean, come on, l took care
of Jefferson Keane for you.
He's gonna die
and both our hands are clean.
One of my best buddies
in the Army was Donnie O'Reily.
lrish guy.
From Howard Beach.
Tough little fucker,
didn't take any bullshit from anybody,
including the sergeant.
He loved women. He loved boats.
He loved women on boats.
He loved vodka.
He loved women
who drank vodka on boats.
Who knows,
maybe we can do some business.
Great.
Poor son of a bitch.
- Yo, Padre.
- How you doing?
How's my baby?
He's not doing so good, Miguel.
- He's not getting any better.
- Shit.
The doctors, they're thinking
of taking him off the life support.
What you mean? Pull the plug?
- No. No. No. No.
- Maritza thinks it's the best thing too.
No, Maritza's sweet, she gonna listen
to anything anybody tells her to.
- l don't want them to kill my baby.
- They're not killing the baby, Miguel.
The machines are keeping
the baby alive. lf they turn them off,
the baby can have a natural death.
l wanna speak to Maritza.
l wanna see my baby right now.
You can't see Maritza,
you can't see the baby.
They're not even gonna
let you make a phone call.
They're gonna start
a psychiatric evaluation of you.
- What, they don't think l'm a bug?
- You cut yourself all up.
So? l did it for the baby.
What do you mean
you did it for the baby?
You tell me l gave the baby life,
right, that he's my responsibility.
Well, the baby being sick,
you know, l don't know what to do.
l ain't a fucking doctor.
And slashing your face
did what, huh?
That's between me and God.
Oh, Miguel, you tell the shrink that
and you're gonna be in here
till you're 90 years old.
You gotta help me.
You gotta get me out of here.
You gotta help me see my baby.
You gotta tell them not to kill it.
You gotta-- You gotta let me
see my baby.
You gotta tell them not to kill it.
l wanna see my baby!
You see, l got Alvarez
on the road to redemption.
l got him to start caring.
And l guess
that's tearing him up inside.
The doctor at the neonatal unit,
he says that keeping the baby alive
- is actually cruel at this point.
- l'm trying to catch up here.
l've had one meeting with Alvarez,
he sort of just whined about his kid.
See, all l want is l just want a release
so l can take him to the hospital
because l think that when he sees
the condition the baby is in,
he will understand why they're
gonna take the life support away.
- l need more time.
- We don't have time.
They wanna turn
the machines off tomorrow.
Tomorrow? Forget it.
Okay. l don't need
his permission, you know.
You're gonna take
this responsibility on yourself?
Absolutely.
l appreciate everything
you've done for me,
especially, like, you know,
with the baby and all.
l mean, l guess sometimes that's
the way things go, you know.
Things just work out like that.
You're right.
l feel better about myself.
l mean, l never thought
that l'd love a baby with all my heart.
And, you know, l never loved
anything before in my life.
lt's like it opened up
a whole new me.
That's important, right?
Figuring out who you are,
you know, and about yourself?
So, you know, l know now.
Well, l'm real glad.
Well, l owe it all to you.
Well, l gotta go.
Hey, Father.
Where was God
when my son died?
Same place he was
when his own son died.
- Well, it's looking pretty good.
- l feel good.
Well, the remaining kidney's
functioning fine.
The rest of you is pretty healthy.
So this afternoon
l'll have you transferred back to--
Death row. You can say it, doctor.
Keane, you have a visitor.
Hey, Pop.
How's Grace?
Doctor says she recuperating
faster than expected.
That's some rocking kidney
you gave her.
So how you doing?
l'm still a little turned around
by all this publicity, you know.
Having a microphone
shoved in my face
every time l leave the house.
We've been getting lots
of letters and cards, mostly nice.
One guy from lowa,
he sent $1 00 cash.
Your Aunt Tillie said
that l had to send it back.
- Did you?
- No fucking way.
Dad...
...l need you
to do something for me.
Anything, son.
Come on, now, you know that.
l need for you to talk to Billie.
- He's turned into a fag.
- You don't know what it's like in here.
You don't know the things
they do to you, the loneliness.
Talk to him.
l raised you three all alone.
And your sister, she's gonna
make something with her life,
especially with
what you've done for her.
But when he leaves,
what's Billie ever gonna be?
Your son. My brother. Forever.
Okay, time's up.
lt's rare when you say
goodbye to someone
that you know it's the last time.
You can try to say whatever it is
you should have said before
or you can just hold on tight.
Just hold on, hoping the moment
will last you a lifetime.
You all right?
Jefferson was my oldest.
So he always had a special place.
A man...
...shouldn't live
to see his own son die.
Hey, l brought you some tea.
You brought me some tea? Why?
Well, it's herbal.
- Maybe you don't want it.
- Hey,
just so happens l'm out. Thanks.
- So.
Why you here, McManus?
l mean, what do you want?
l don't know.
l just...
l just wanted to tell you...
...that l'm sorry you're gonna die.
And...
You'd like my forgiveness?
Well,
whatever you think you've done,
l forgive you.
Did you get
Kareem Said's test results?
That feels so good.
So far, everything's fine.
l'm just waiting for the MRl results.
Well, good. You want to go
to dinner tonight?
- l can't.
- Why not?
l'm witnessing Keane's execution.
- What?
- Yeah, l told you.
- What? You didn't tell me. Oh, man...
- Yes, l did.
You didn't tell me. Gloria, this is not
something l would forget, believe me.
- Christ!
- Look, what is the big deal?
l'm only prescribing the drugs,
declaring the death.
- lt's not like l'm sticking the lV in.
- Gloria. Gloria.
Gloria, doctors are
supposed to be healers.
You're supposed
to keep people alive.
- You're not supposed to kill them.
- You really see this as a killing?
l don't want you doing this.
- You what?
- l don't want you doing this.
Look, we've only been going out
a couple of weeks.
Where do you get off telling me
what l can and can't do?
- Wait, wait, wait.
- Hey.
Don't grab me.
You better take some time off, Tim.
You been around this prison so much,
you're starting to act like them.
Thanks.
ls the governor here yet?
No, l haven't seen him.
But a pro-death-penalty marcher
just took a swing at Sister Pete.
ls she okay?
Good aim.
She just kicked him in the balls.
l take it you're not gonna
watch the execution?
How about you?
No.
Can't stand watching flowers die,
let alone another human being.
Closest l ever came was Bambi.
- Bambi?
- Yeah.
My ex was a big hunter.
He was always going off
with his buddies,
so l said to him one time,
''Take me.''
After some complaining, he did.
So l got out there
in the forest with this
big hunky shotgun
and l fired at a deer.
Hit it dead-on.
So l went over to this thing
and l leaned down,
and this deer looked up at me
with these eyes...
...these eyes like flashlights.
l knelt beside it and l held its head
and l whispered, ''l'm sorry.''
Then, like batteries going bad,
the light in his eyes
flickered a little bit and went out.
For the next two years
we were married,
every time l walked into the den
l had to stare at that deer's dead eyes.
l had to dust them.
When we got divorced,
that's all l asked for, the deer's head.
Then l buried it.
That's how l feel tonight.
What do you mean?
Like my head's hanging on
somebody's wall.
- Wanna have dinner?
- Sure.
Hey.
Yeah?
- How you doing?
- Okay. You?
Not bad, for a man about to die.
Yeah, you go tonight, huh?
Yeah. You?
Next Thursday.
But l'm on appeal.
Did you ever see that old movie
with that old actress,
what's-her-name... Susan Hayward?
Which movie?
l don't know what it's called.
She's Gotta Live or something like that.
She's on death row,
waiting to be fried or gassed
or whatever they used to do
back in the day.
The only thing, her attorney
has applied for some reprieve,
so she just waits.
The clock keeps ticking.
Waiting for that call from the governor.
Yeah, and at the last
possible minute he calls, huh?
Well, you know, now that
l think about it, l think she fries.
l need to ask some questions.
What do you want done
with your property?
Give it to my dad.
And the money in your
trust account?
To my brother and sister.
Will your family
be claiming your body?
Yeah.
Who are your witnesses?
My dad and the Minister Said.
You sure you should see this?
Yeah.
Tizi and l have come
on a long journey together.
l'm not gonna turn
my back on him now.
Okay. Let's do it. Officer?
Death is the supreme moment
of truth, my brother,
so sayeth the prophet.
- Praise be unto him.
- And peace be unto you.
Minister, they took my kufi.
l don't wanna die without my kufi.
You take mine.
Over 3,000 men and women
are sitting on death row right now.
Congress has denied state inmates
access to federal courts.
Congress has also eliminated
financing to law officers
for death row appeals.
The states themselves
are shortening the appeals process.
ln this country, there's now
one execution every single week.
There were more executions this year
than any time since the '50s.
And we all know how righteous
the '50s were.
You can make
any statements you'd like.
l want my family to know
that l love them.
And l believe that this punishes them
more than it punishes me.
l'm so sorry
for the three murders that l did...
...and l wish by killing me today,
you could bring them back.
My time on this Earth...
...has been far too short.
Maybe too short
to get it all done right.
So...
...l'm ready to move on.
All praise to Allah.
All praise.
- Governor!
- Justice has been served.
L'ltalien, the Supreme Court
refused to hear your appeal.
Rehnquist is a fag.
Be that as it may, your execution
is scheduled for tomorrow.
Prisoner number 9 7L64 1,
Richard L'ltalien.
Convicted April 3, '9 7.
Murder in the first degree.
Sentence: Death.
Tomorrow?
Well, my schedule's clear. Okay.
Hey, warden,
there's something l wanna tell you.
Something l never told anybody.
l suffocated Jennifer Miller.
Yeah, l know.
That's why you're gonna die.
l also suffocated Dorothy Paine.
- Who?
- Dorothy Paine.
She was a waitress
up in Council Bluffs, lowa.
You confessing another murder?
l'll notify the proper authorities.
Wait!
l also suffocated Ethel Peterson
and Gertrude Victor.
And Mary Rapp.
And Christina Trudell
and Eleanor Hughes,
Linda Lomaz, Lisa Masters,
and Lorraine McCarthy
and Betty Case and lrene Martin
and Amelia Nugent,
Elizabeth Phelps and Lucille Upton
and Esther Vaughan.
Well, l did.
Richard L'ltalien confessed
to 39 murders, all young women.
He suffocated them all.
lf the governor had his way,
he would execute L'ltalien 39 times.
l have to get over there.
Ray, listen.
How can you go along with this?
You're as much against
the death penalty as l am.
Of course l am, Pete. l don't know.
Maybe if anyone deserves to die,
Richard L'ltalien deserves to die.
Maybe the world will breathe
a little easier once he's gone.
My job is not to make judgments.
My job is to be by his side.
My place is with him...
...if he needs me.
Pray for him, Mary.
That's for him.
That's for all of them.
Have you ever had
bull's balls, Father?
No, sir, l can't say that l have.
Well, they serve them every year
at the Bohemian Grove.
What's that? That's a restaurant?
Oh, man, you never heard
of the Bohemian Grove?
lt's a retreat in San Francisco,
you know.
For investment brokers,
bankers, politicians, intellectuals.
l'm amazed you're not hip to it.
Of course, l grew up in the Bay Area,
so we knew when it was happening.
Even as a kid l always
wanted to go, you know.
Wouldn't that be something?
Swim in the Russian River
with some secretary of state,
piss on a redwood
next to Donald Trump.
l mean, these guys are the elite,
men of power.
Men.
Women were excluded,
but the Supreme fucking Court
forced the Bohemian
to let the coozes in.
Can you believe that shit?
Once they were in,
l wanted nothing to do with it.
l was done.
But who knows the women
you would have met?
Not the kind l'm gonna wanna fuck.
There's a big difference between
wanting to fuck a woman
and wanting to kill her.
ls there?
Have you ever been laid, Father?
No.
Then what would you know
about pussy?
And what would you know
about anything?
All l know is that,
once upon a time,
you wanted to walk in the woods
with important people,
and now, instead...
...you're here.
l'm here because l love women.
l love every woman l see.
Tall ones, thin ones, fatties.
lt's true.
You know, l once worked
at a circus one summer,
and l fucked the dwarf
while the fat lady watched us.
l fucked trailer-park trash
in West Virginia,
l fucked rich girls up the ass
in Aspen,
l fucked Ph.D.s, retards...
You know, once l fucked an amputee
with both legs missing.
Fucking them isn't
the same as loving them.
You sound just like a shrink
l had once in juvie.
She tried to tell me
that l hated women.
l showed her.
You fucked her?
And her daughter.
Then l snuffed them both.
lf you love women so much,
why do you kill them?
Because when you love someone,
they own you, they possess you.
l will not be possessed.
l'm here to give you
absolution for your sins.
- Do you wish to be absolved?
- Fuck, yes.
Shit.
You know, they told me l could order
anything l wanted as my last meal.
l should have ordered bull's balls.
l'm really not ready for this.
Oh, man.
First, the inmate's given
sodium pentothal,
the same anaesthetic used
in hospitals for major surgery.
Then, a massive dose
of pancuronium bromide
that paralyzes the diaphragm.
Then potassium chloride
to stop the heart.
Don't try this at home, kids.
He's finished.
Hello.
Christ was executed, you know.
And if he hadn't been,
the world would be
a very different place.
A better place?
l didn't say that.
l want my job back.
- Okay.
- l don't have to beg?
lf it'll make you feel better, beg.
l want you to know l still
disagree with you on the death penalty.
Even for a cyst like L'ltalien?
Leo, thou shalt not kill.
The Bible makes that pretty clear.
You cannot take a human life
for any reason.
Yeah, but the Bible also says,
''an eye for an eye.''
Which says to me
that if you kill, you die.
Seems to me God's talking
out of both sides of his mouth.
Maybe he's just as confused about
the death penalty as the rest of us.
All l know for sure is,
no one's gonna claim L'ltalien's body,
so we're gonna stick him
in a cheap pine box,
stamp an lD number on the lid,
and throw him in a hole
at Potter's Field.
There he'll be...
...with no one to grieve for him.
l grieve for him.
Yeah, l know. That's why l love you.
That's why l'm glad you're back.
There's this brother
on death row somewheres,
he checked in when he was 1 6.
He sat there another 1 6 years
while the courts and lawyers argued
about this and that.
While he waited,
he painted a mural on his wall.
For all those years he painted,
not letting a soul see what he was up to.
Finally, when he was 32
and had spent more life on death row
than in his mama's house,
all his appeals were exhausted.
He was about to die.
As he was about to be let out
for the final time,
he finally unveiled his masterpiece.
All there was were six words.
''Death is certain, life is not.''
The next day the hacks
painted over it.
Peace out.