The power of music.
Whether a concerto
or ballad or rap,
music stimulates us.
Yeah, it stimulates us.
Willy Shakespeare said, "If music
be the food of love, play on."
Hey!
You're supposed to be having
a farewell conversation.
Use your lips for talking.
- Asshole.
- You girls got one minute.
- Hey, asshole.
- Chris, come on.
Forget about him.
There's a lot I want
to say before I go.
Look, I gotta tell ya,
I'm having a tough time
wrapping my head around
the reality of you being paroled.
Trust me, I won't
fully comprehend it
until I'm sipping
my first martini.
Toby, I'm...
I'm, uh...
What?
I'm glad.
You're finally going to get some
time to spend with your kids.
Come on.
- What's really on your mind?
- Don't forget me.
Never.
And now that I'm out,
I'll be doubling my efforts
to overturn your death sentence.
I'm going to see you
more than before.
Even so, if I die,
don't forget me.
You are not gonna die.
When you say it,
I almost believe it's true.
It is true.
Time.
Time!
Asshole.
Chris, don't!
Fucker!
Hey, you got
anything for me?
Nope.
I love my Rosie.
Maricon!
Thanks.
Mayor Loewen?
Vernie, I wondered
when you'd pop up.
It's great
to see you, sir.
Is that mail
for me?
Oh, yes.
So are you comfortable?
Got everything you need?
Yeah, mm-hm.
You gave me
quite a scare.
When I heard you
almost choked to death.
When's the doctor
releasing you?
I get back to
Unit J tomorrow.
Christ.
- Sir?
- Another hate letter.
Some nigger says
I got off too easy.
Says he's got a cousin
here in Oswald
who's gonna airhole me.
- What does airhole mean?
- Kill.
Black bastard.
Don't worry, Your Honor,
I'm not gonna let
anything happen to you.
Oh, yeah,
is that right, huh?
From what I hear, the Aryans
in Oswald are a sorry bunch.
That guy who saved me
from choking, Beecher.
I hear you've been
trying
to airhole him
for about six fucking years,
and all you have
to show for it
is that little scar
above your eye there.
I did have his son killed,
and his father.
What are you an idiot?
Saying shit
like that out loud?
You know, Vernie, I've got
to tell you, I never thought
you were the brightest bulb
in the chandelier.
You always had this huge ego
with nothing to back it up.
You always had these big plans
with no balls behind them.
Shit, if it weren't
for your daddy
I wouldn't have given you
the time of fucking day.
You're an embarrassment
to the Brotherhood.
I have balls.
Speak up, boy,
I can't hear you.
Nothing, sir.
How'd your meeting
with the mayor go?
Fuck him.
Well, it's been
nice knowing you.
You too, Yood.
You too, Yood?
Well, you're in
such a cheery mood
I'm not sure if
I should burden you
with the little info
I just learned.
I know who killed
your father.
Who?
Franklin Winthrop.
On orders from
Vern Schillinger.
I knew it.
Fuck.
I thought you might
want the facts now,
in case you decide to do
something before you leave.
Like what?
Schillinger murdered
your father.
Wilson Loewen's like
a father to Schillinger.
Tooth-for-tooth time.
So I said, "Ronnie,
you tell Nancy to keep
her panties on."
- And did he?
- No, when it came to that woman
the great communicator
had no voice at all.
This has been
enjoyable, Mayor,
but I have a meeting
over at Lardner.
Yeah, I have
to run as well.
Jimmy, could you stay
just two more minutes?
- Uh, yeah.
- I'll see you again.
Oh, I hope so,
darlin'.
You fucking cocksucker.
You swore to me that you would
never let me serve a day.
Wilson, they were
burning down the city.
Correction, they were
burning down their city,
their neighborhood,
their businesses.
The violence was
escalating, spreading...
So you send in the National Guard,
tear gas, rubber bullets.
What you don't do is
betray a lifelong friend.
What you don't do
is humiliate a man,
especially when that man knows
where the bodies are buried.
I want my pardon, Jimmy,
and I want it fucking today.
I'm not going to spend another
night in this cesspool, understand?
I don't care what kind of
political typhoon it causes.
If you don't
give me my pardon,
I will call a press conference
and I will tell tales, Jimmy.
Tales of corruption, tales
of graft, tales of voter fraud.
By the time I'm finished you'll
be sitting right next to me
in Unit J playing
par-fucking-cheesi.
All right.
I'll figure out a way.
Yeah, you always do, Jimmy.
That's why you're my boy.
Perry.
There's something
I want you to do.
Something that requires
enormous discretion.
So, here we are.
Yes.
But I'm not saying goodbye
because this is not goodbye.
My dad's law partners,
in his memory,
have decided to do pro bono
work for the prisoners.
Even though
I've been disbarred,
- I'm going to coordinate the office.
- That's great.
I'm glad, Tobias.
I'm glad some good will come out
of all the sadness you suffered.
I want to thank you both
for always being there.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
I'll see you
tomorrow.
Tobias, do not
come back tomorrow.
Be with your family. Take the time
to play with your children.
And comfort my mother.
I promise you, Beecher,
I will find
who killed your father.
Yeah, uh-huh.
Hey, Beecher,
sign here.
Okay, you're free to go.
Free to go.
Free.
Be well.
"One good thing about music,
when it hits, you feel no pain.
So hit me with music."
Bob Marley.
Wilson Loewen
is dead.
Oh... well.
Oh, well.
It amazes me some of the books
the prisoners read.
I mean,
Henry James?
They had to force-feed me
James in college.
I too thought it odd
that Pablo Rosa would want
to borrow "The Ambassadors."
He's 18,
in for murdering
a classmate.
Nice to know he's
expanding his horizons.
Turn the book over.
Is that blood?
He clubbed
his cellmate with it.
Pablo Rosa, huh?
What cell block's he in?
Why?
I know you want
to help people,
but you can't
reach a kid like that.
Which is exactly
why I should try.
Doesn't your boyfriend worry,
you coming in here every day?
Is that your not-so-subtle way
of asking if I'm involved?
Yes.
Well, Robert,
to me...
men are like books.
Sometimes I want
a romance,
sometimes a thriller,
sometimes maybe a trashy novel
to take to the beach.
And sometimes...
I want a classic.
But when I finish, it's back
on the shelves and on to the next.
You've never
been married?
Oh, no.
Then maybe...
you're reading too fast.
I'm voracious.
Prisoner #02R104...
Pablo Rosa;
convicted December 22nd,
2002;
involuntary manslaughter;
sentence... 18 years;
up for parole in 10.
Pablo?
Come on in.
What do you want?
I've been reading
through your records.
You're 18 with 18 years
left on your sentence?
I get parole in 10.
Okay, so...
how do you want
to spend that time?
Fast as fucking possible.
The thing is, Pablo,
that's not an answer
any more than
this is a weapon.
Did the job pretty good
if you ask me.
Not the job
it was meant to.
Tell me,
can you read?
- Sure.
- Do you enjoy it?
No.
Books are just
shit teachers give you.
- So you did go to school?
- Sometimes.
But not always because
you hated the shit
your teachers gave you,
right?
Well, can't expect everyone
to enjoy the same thing.
So what I'd like us to do is find
a book that's right for you.
- Why?
- Because when we do,
it'll make the time fly,
and that's what you want.
Tell me some of the things
that interest you.
Like what?
Like pussy and baseball?
Now we're cooking.
Hey, Rebadow, heard
you were in the library
checking out more
than just books.
I don't really care to dignify that
with a response.
Chill, man. I'm just a little
jealous, you know?
You got your old lady
on payroll, right?
I call mine twice, she won't even
so much as fart my way.
You and Busmalis
should switch places.
His girl keeps showing up,
but he won't see her.
Well shit, let me know
the next time she comes by.
Shit, I'll visit anything
in a skirt, man.
Norma's here today.
For some reason,
she asked for me.
Well shit, share the love.
Share the love.
Damn!
You think I can convince
Busmalis to visit with you,
but I can't.
He's impenetrable.
Oh, come on.
We both know Agamemnon.
What looks like a wall
is only an inch thick
over that tender
little heart of his.
Well, I'm no
cardiac surgeon.
I'm not sure how to cut
through the wall.
Say you saw me,
that I was crying.
- But you're not.
- But I do.
Every day.
And tell him this,
I'll show up one last time.
If he doesn't come,
even just to say farewell,
then I swear he'll never
hear from Norma Clark again.
Okay.
But I can't
promise success.
Please, Bob!
Do your best.
See?
Tears.
Where have you been?
You know I hate
playing solitaire alone.
Black four
on that five.
And this is why.
I just saw Norma.
What, my Norma?
- Agamemnon, calm down.
- Went behind my back.
Is there a reason
everyone's taking her side?
I'm of the mind you're both
on the same side.
Oh, and what are you,
Dr. Love?
And what's led you
to such a learned diagnosis?
For one, you called her
"my Norma."
You've got 12 years
left in Oz.
Do you really want to spend
that time angry and desolate?
Oh, what do you know?
You're busy mooning
over that librarian.
Yes.
Stella's conjured up
all sorts of feelings in me.
Reminding me of what
I was like when I was young,
passionate about architecture,
about Betty.
I was on the verge
of an extraordinary career,
an extraordinary life.
But I've been
alone 38 years,
and I'm just beginning
to make up for lost time.
You, you're choosing
to lose the time
you and Norma
have together.
Red queen on that king.
Yeah yeah,
I see it.
Little man, what was
that bullshit?
You didn't like
"Of Human Bondage"?
I thought it was
an instruction manual.
It was about
some crippled kid.
There's no pictures,
even.
Sorry.
Uh...
how about "Macbeth"?
The story of a brutal
Scottish warlord
who kills mercilessly
to gain power.
They're doing
a production here.
Yeah, sounds all right.
Well, Lady Macbeth,
what are you waiting for?
Get me my fucking book, man.
Hey, don't forget
my cookie.
Hey, Robson.
Hey, what shade of
lipstick is that, huh?
Dick-suck red?
Yeah, we heard you're working
receiving and discharge.
Uh-oh.
Fuck you, Pancamo.
I'll tell you what, prag,
this time, I'll use
my bad hand to beat you.
- Even it up a little.
- Bitch.
I was only talking.
- Since when's it against the rules?
- Since right now.
- "Since right now."
- Hey, what did I just say?
This is the problem, you got
zero listening ability.
So focus and either nod
or shake your head, got it?
That's a start.
Since Redding plans to move
over to telemarketing,
I'm giving you
back the kitchen.
Keep it efficient,
keep it clean,
keep it honest.
And in return
for my generosity
I want you to stay
the fuck away from the Aryans.
Got me?
Now, this is the part
where you say thanks.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
So, what'd you give
those Nazi fucks?
And now
you shut up again.
Psst, White.
White!
What, man, what?
How you feeling?
Better, thank God.
How about you?
Good, not great.
They tell you what we got?
No, man, only dribs
and drabs of shit.
Yeah, me too, but it can't
be that terrible
if Nathan sent us out
of the hospital that quick.
I wanna hear quiet!
- When's Martinez coming back?
- I don't know.
They tell you
what's ailing us yet?
I don't know!
Ah, see?
Quiet.
Let's give Gannon
10 milligrams.
Carlos Martinez...
He's one nasty man.
His liver is
deteriorating rapidly.
Let's up his
Aldactone 25 milligrams.
Martinez, you look
like fucking hell.
Brass giving you grief?
Always, man, always.
Listen up.
Morales is worried you're
going to tell Brass the truth
about how his ankle got cut.
No, I would never tell.
I swear on my life.
That's what Morales
had in mind.
He wants me to shank you.
I'm too weak
to fight, Chico.
Que estés fuerte.
Gracias, hermano.
Stay strong.
Is it done?
No.
I talked to Martinez.
He's not gonna jabber on you.
I told you to kill him.
That was an order.
He's a compadre.
You want him whacked?
Do the deed yourself.
I will.
And I won't
fuckin' forget this.
- Grace!
- He's dead.
What the hell happened?
Well, I was in the office
filling out report sheets.
- I never heard him code.
- How do you not hear the code?
Well I was busy.
Well now you're not.
You're fired.
Carlos Martinez is dead.
God damn it.
He died because we,
you and me,
didn't send him to a real
hospital for proper care
- and now he's dead.
- Gloria.
I have to do an autopsy,
and this time I am not lying.
I'm not covering anything up.
Full disclosure.
Did you hear me?
Full fucking disclosure!
Aw, shit.
I'm still not sure this is the best solution to
the problem.
Once the state medical board
reviews Nathan's findings
the truth will
come out anyway.
But shouldn't you just wait
until the autopsy's done?
He who creates the news
has the best chance
of controlling it.
Here's to full disclosure.
Thank you for coming.
We have discovered
that toxic chemical elements
residing in the air ducts
throughout solitary confinement
have infected three inmates.
And sadly, yesterday it lead
to the death of one of them,
Carlos Martinez.
I take full responsibility
for Martinez's death.
Good morning,
my beloveds.
Got a newsflash for you...
Your pal Martinez
bought the farm.
Farm?
What farm?
He died, stupid.
- What'd he die from?
- I don't know.
But whatever he had,
you clucks have it too.
- Are you sure?
- That's the scuttlebutt.
Shit.
If I were you, I'd pay up
my insurance premiums.
Wait wait wait
wait wait, look.
But buying a farm is
a good thing, right?
I mean, why does
that have to mean dying?
Shut up, Omar.
No, look, now that
don't make no sense.
Sold the farm, lost the farm,
the farm burned down, but...
Shut up, Omar!
That don't make no
goddamn sense.
Hey, Sean.
Sean, I've been
looking for you.
Here I am. Want to get a beer
after work?
Yeah, and I'm buying
to celebrate the death
of that spic Martinez.
Yeah, I'm not
shedding any tears.
It's too bad he 10-7'd
before he ratted on Morales.
That's the beauty part,
pal, he did.
You know I've been
visiting Martinez regular,
always at him to tell
me the truth?
Well he must have known
he was going to croak
and he wanted to make his peace
'cause last night he spilled.
- A deathbed confession?
- Yeah.
Martinez pinned the tail
on Morales' donkey ass.
You've known since last night,
didn't say anything till now?
That's why
I'm looking for you.
I want Morales
in solitary ASAP.
All right, come on.
Take the cuffs off.
What the fuck
do you want?
- What is this?
- Halftime entertainment.
Yo, Penders.
You think Morales is gonna
get his farm foreclosed?
Martinez cut me
right here.
Ruined my chances of
ever playing pro ball,
and I have this limp.
So you see, Enrique,
if I only cut the one
you'll limp like I do.
But if I cut them both,
you'll walk fine.
I see the devil.
I see the devil everywhere.
And you say this started when?
The moment Kirk died.
It's as if whatever
possessed him came into me.
I'm going to ask Sister Peter Marie
to schedule a session with you.
I'm not crazy, Father.
I see the devil...
right over your shoulder.
It sounds like he's going for an insanity
defense in his appeal.
No, he keeps saying,
"I'm not crazy. I'm not crazy."
Don't get me wrong, I think
he's crazy, but he doesn't.
I'm not sure that he
hasn't always been crazy.
Therefore, I'm not sure
that he should be executed.
Would you
talk to Hoyt?
Certainly.
But I have to ask,
what are you hoping
to get out of this?
- Me personally? Nothing.
- Yeah.
Wait a minute.
Are you trying to assuage
your guilt by helping Hoyt?
You told me yourself that you
prayed for Timmy Kirk to die.
Yes, but I know God doesn't
answer those kinds of prayers,
that Hoyt acted
on his own volition
and that I had nothing
to do with Kirk's demise.
And yet down deep you're
happy that the boy is dead.
Like I said, you're trying
to burn off excess guilt
by making Hoyt into a cause.
Just be sure he is
the proper recipient.
What do you mean?
Jaz Hoyt is not
the victim here.
You can walk away,
but I'm not like
the Reverend Cloutier.
I won't just disappear.
- Mrs. Kirk?
- Yes.
I'm Father Mukada.
I have Timothy's
belongings.
I just need you
to sign this form.
Did you know
my son?
Uh, yes.
Such a sweet
sweet face.
Who knew there was
so much bad inside?
He left his own baby
to die in a dumpster.
Then he came here.
He said such
terrible things,
shocking things...
about the church,
about Jesus.
He called me
Satan's whore.
Father, would you
hear my confession?
What could you possibly
have to confess?
I stopped loving
my son that day.
My heart went cold,
and I stopped loving him.
I need God to forgive
me for that.
"Music expresses that which
cannot be put into words,
and that which cannot
remain silent."
Victor Hugo.
Hello, Cyril.
There's something I want
to talk to you about.
I've been wondering...
Wait, Sister, don't you want
to say hello to me?
Oh, yeah, sure.
Hello, Jericho.
Cyril,
how are you
feeling lately?
He's fine.
Okay, that's enough.
Let's put Jericho
away, okay?
No.
Yes.
Give me the puppet.
Fuck... you...
you... cunt.
Cyril,
I gave you Jericho,
and now I want
him back.
Okay, now let go.
Let go.
Ow ow ow ow!
Officer!
- I need help.
- Let her go!
Jericho made me do it!
Get off me!
- Give me that thing!
- Take this goddamn thing!
Get up.
Jericho.
Jericho!
O'Reily, shut the fuck up.
Jericho.
Sobbing like a chick
over a stupid puppet?
Jericho.
Knock it off right now,
or else.
Jericho Jericho.
Okay, I warned you.
- Matt!
- Jericho.
- What the fuck?
Jericho.
Douse the little prick.
Stop stop!
Stop!
You want some of this too?
Lights out!
If the appeals court
plays ball,
Cyril O'Reily
will die next month.
The first person executed
under the state's new definition
of mentally retarded.
We have to be prepared
for a backlash.
Yes, Reimondo and her
happy band of do-gooders
have been stirring up
the press and the public.
The question is,
how do we fight back?
There wouldn't be all
this breast-beating
if folks thought
the 'tard was normal.
So, we have
to make him normal,
or appear normal.
According to Sister
Peter Marie's files,
Cyril has been given a series
of stabilizing drugs,
none of which
has been successful.
Which is why
I propose using E.C.T.
What's E.C. T?
Basically the PC way
of saying electroshock.
Governor...
There's a nasty misconception
about E.C.T.
It's not the horrible mind
torture you see in the movies.
It's really quite benign.
Look, I'm not gonna sit here
debating the pros and cons
of electroshock therapy.
Cyril is Sister
Peter Marie's patient.
A decision can't be made
without consulting her.
Dr. Donald Rofe, Director of
the State Office of Mental Health
will meet with her tomorrow.
You'll also need permission
from the O'Reily family.
Signed by the father,
Seamus O'Reily.
You agree with all of this?
It was my idea.
Peter Marie,
you okay?
Uh...
No.
I just had a meeting
with Don Rofe
who told me that they're going
to give Cyril O'Reily E.C.T.
And...
that I'd better shut up
and like it.
Will you?
Well...
that's what I'm
trying to decide.
You know, normally
in situations like this,
I just raise high
the battlements
and charge.
But as uh...
Rofe so eloquently
pointed out,
in Cyril's case...
I have failed completely.
Nothing I tried
has worked.
So, I have to weigh my ego
against what's best
for my patient.
I don't want to say no
just to keep somebody
else from...
succeeding where I
have failed.
And you think a spin around
McManus' maze will do the trick?
Can't hurt.
Hey, you wanted
to see me?
Yeah, Ryan, sit down.
That's good, because
I wanted to see you too.
I just saw Cyril,
and he's so goddamn sad.
If his puppet
means so much to him,
why don't you just
give it back to him?
I can't, Ryan.
Jericho was my idea,
remember?
A way for Cyril to deal with
the confusion surrounding the trial,
but unfortunately the puppet
has come to mean
more than that to him.
It's become a whole
other personality.
I don't care about that.
I just want Cyril
to be happy.
It's not that simple.
Cyril is suffering from severe
depression and schizophrenia.
All right, so what's next?
I mean, what can
we do to cure him?
Your father has already agreed
to electroshock therapy.
My father?
What the fuck does that old
bastard have to do with anything?
I know, it's unbelievable,
but in the eyes of the law
he is Cyril's guardian.
All right, so this
electroshock therapy,
does it do any good?
I have no experience
with it.
The treatment was in vogue
for years and fell out of favor.
However, some mental health
professionals swear by it.
Clinical evidence indicates
that E.C.T.
Produces a substantial
improvement in 80% of patients.
Are there any dangers?
There's headaches,
there's soreness,
nausea, memory loss.
Look...
we're talking
120 volts...
an ordinary
household current
applied to the brain
for half a second,
10 to 15 times within a period
of two to three weeks.
And no one knows if there's
permanent damage.
No.
Jesus Christ,
can't we stop them?
The truth is that they have
conspired to make this happen.
We are taken out of
this decision-making.
I spoke to Zelman to see
if we could go to court,
if we could fight it,
and he says we wouldn't win.
That's genius.
Devlin wants
to electroshock Cyril
to make him normal enough
to electrocute him.
"Music is the brandy
of the damned."
George Bernard Shaw.
Hello, Cyril.
Why don't you hop
right up here?
Trust me, this one's going
to be a piece of cake.
We're going to give you
two different drugs,
one that puts you to sleep,
the other relaxes your muscles.
This is gonna prick a bit.
These are electrodes,
and once you're asleep
they'll measure the current
that's stimulating your brain.
We're going to do
a little procedure today.
Now, this is going
to prick just a bit.
Relax.
This will put you to sleep.
- Does it hurt?
- Not if you're asleep.
He's out.
- Ready?
- Fire away.
How are you feeling?
I have a terrible
headache.
Did you tell your doctors?
Who?
Never mind.
Sometimes if somebody
holds you
the pain goes away.
Do you want me
to hold you?
Okay.
Come on, sweetie.
- Hello, Ryan.
- Hi.
I, uh, just...
had a call
from Arnold Zelman.
They've denied
Cyril's appeal.
Shit.
Okay.
Okay, now
what do we do?
Well, Zelman will probably
try to figure out
another approach,
another appeal,
but in the meantime
the judge has set the date
for Cyril's execution.
What?
- When?
- Three weeks from Thursday.
That's not much time.
I feel deep down
we'll stop the execution,
but just in case, Ryan,
- you ought to accept the fact...
- No.
No way.
You know, if I even
entertain the thought,
if I let myself believe for a second that my
brother's gonna die,
then my brother's gonna die.
This was Father Meehan's.
I don't know,
I have faith, Sister.
For the first time
in a really long time
I have faith.
I still don't understand
why we gave up
running the cafeteria.
We got us some new jobs.
Man, kitchen best
detail there is.
I got the belly
to prove it.
Yeah, well I found us
something better,
something that will get us
out of the muck and mire.
Man, we ain't down
in no shit.
Wrong, Kenaniah.
We in so much shit,
you can't even smell it
no more.
- So what's your brainstorm?
- Gonna be telemarketers.
- Tele who?
- I'm serious.
Gonna learn you boys
some skills,
something that'll make you
more cash
than you're making
in the kitchen.
- Not more than slinging.
- Ain't gonna be no more slinging.
- Are you crazy, nigger?
- Yeah, no motherfuckin' way...
Hold up, hold up.
So what's your angle, Burr?
There ain't no angle.
This is the dawn
of a new day, gentlemen.
Our charge is to rise up
and face it.
And rise up we shall.
And this is the nerve center
of our operation.
It's very nice.
Very nice.
And it runs like any other
telemarketing firm?
Better. I hire these guys
cheap, you get me cheaper,
which in turn lowers
your overhead,
increases call volume and fills
those campaign coffers.
And the day-to-day,
no difference?
S.O.P. You provide us with contact
numbers and prepared text,
we get right to work.
And nobody knows
they're talking to convicts?
Not unless you want us
to tell them.
Trust me, that would be
the last thing that Senator Laken
would want
his constituents to know.
Laken? The right-wing,
Bible-toting motherfucker?
His legislation
is the main reason
why half the men in here
are doing twice as much time.
Let me assure you,
Mr. D'Arta,
that my company
is non-partisan
and will be committed to
whatever it is you want us to do.
Can the editorials!
I'm sorry, sir, I didn't
mean any offense.
That's all right.
Everyone is entitled
to their own point of view.
This is America,
after all.
And this program is working
in other prisons?
It's thriving.
A situation like this benefits everybody.
Nobody loses.
I'm a campaign manager,
Ms. Degenhart.
Somebody always loses.
But I will take your proposal
back to my people.
Great.
Don't let me go real-a,
gorilla, bad nigger driller;
Double live, cross-eyed,
see-you-from-the-side schemer;
Type of nigger bang
his chest when he fight,
for he's in too much truth,
so, we see the blessings of
night, blessings of calm.
Nothing lays waiting. Imagine
what he's holdin' in his palm;
Holding in his dream,
500 years of hate
just building like steam;
Mounting like Kilimanjaro.
So just wait until tomorrow
when things get right with me.
I'm gonna smite the wicked,
step off easy.
Burr, Burr, what's up,
what's up?
We're in business,
gentlemen.
Contract got signed today.
Why that put you in such
a fine fuckin' mood?
They ain't turning us
into working stiffs, man.
Poet, that attitude is the first
thing you gonna get rid of.
I ain't doin' it.
Funny how you think
you got a choice.
So we giving up the tit
trade just like that?
If I am, you are too.
You don't have to worry about
getting on board right away.
Just be ready by 9:00
tomorrow morning.
C'mon Burr.
God damn, man.
And you don't have to believe
that I'm right,
because I'm going to show you
how right I am.
So, when do you expect to
publish Augustus Hill's book?
We were hoping
to have it out this month,
but that's why
we needed to see you.
There's been a bump over
who owns the rights.
Augustus had a will, clearly stating
all monies from the book
went to groups that help prisoners,
like The Fortune Society.
Yes, but his wife,
Anabella...
Ex-wife.
She divorced him.
She is claiming the divorce was not final at
the time of Hill's death
and that she is the rightful heir
to his royalties.
Plus we've been served
an injunction
by the family
of Lawrence Hudack.
The officer
that Augustus killed?
This state has a Son of Sam Law.
All the money from the book
is supposed to go
into a victim's trust.
Kareem, we are looking
at months,
maybe years of legal battles.
What are you saying to me?
You're not gonna publish
this book?
The publishing industry's
shaky right now.
And this memoir,
although well written,
it's not a bestseller.
What if I could make it
worth your while,
cut your printing costs?
How are you gonna do that?
I had an inspiration.
Now just wait a minute,
wait a minute, back up.
You want to start
your own company?
Yes, bookbinding.
I've done the research.
Perfect size business
to run from Oz.
I presume you're not looking
to the state
for money to start
this little venture.
No, we Muslims will pool
our bank accounts.
It's a small risk.
My publishers have agreed
to let me produce
Augustus' book for them.
They've introduced me
to potential clients.
I thought you were against
the concept of prison labor.
Not the concept,
the way it's practiced.
I'm not gonna drive some local
competitor out of business,
in that I do not have
any local competitors.
And more importantly,
McManus,
I will pay
the decent wage,
minimum wage.
You're going to fork $5.25 an hour
out of your own pocket?!
In the beginning, yes.
But with projected earnings
I expect we'll be making it
back within six weeks.
Well, I can't think of
a good reason to say no.
You?
You know, we keep developing
our own industries,
Oz is gonna end up on
the cover of "Fortune 500."
Look at this,
my brothers.
It's an ordinary book
to some.
And yet I believe what
I hold in my hand
is the past...
what has been written;
The present...
what can be read now;
And the future...
the glorious work
before us.
And we Muslims, we're going
to lead the way
for the world to see
how workers
can be treated fairly,
can be treated respectfully.
We will demonstrate
true pride in our craft
and we will demonstrate,
once and forever,
how human beings pulling
together can become a force
for good
and celebrated
in the spirit of Allah.
Now, I'm asking
for your help.
I'm asking
for your dedication.
I am asking for your
absolute commitment.
- Are you with me?
- Yes!
I can't hear you,
are you with me?
- Yes!
- Allahu akbar.
- Allahu akbar!
Allahu akbar!
All praise is due
to Allah.
The course you've set
will be difficult, Minister.
Yes, but worth
the struggle.
Being a part of publishing
Augustus' book,
the entire population of Oz
will be rejuvenated.
Now, I've contacted
Anabella Hill
and the Hudack family.
I'm trying to settle
their legal claims.
Who's that?
He's a reporter.
He's gonna do a story
on our new venture.
- Wait here.
- All right.
Kareem Said.
Mr. Idzik.
Arif...
don't harm him.
It's okay.
You're gonna be all right.
Come on, come on.
Breathe breathe.
Breathe, please.
Please...
William Congreve said,
"Music has charms to soothe
the savage breast,
to soften rocks or bend
a knotted oak."
But what happens
when the music is gone?
When there is no melody?
When all you hear...
is silence?
The bittersweet
deafening sound of nothing.
Nothing at all.