Vikings... the word alone
conjures up images
of drunken hordes attacking
and pillaging defenseless villages
from the shores of Britain
to the steppes of Russia.
We got a lot of misconceptions
about the Vikings.
Example: They never actually
wore these stupid helmets,
and because they had a limited amount
of land on which to farm,
they only pillaged
to survive.
I wanna follow you.
You're the next wave
- and I wanna be your lieutenant.
- Kill Guerra.
What the fuck
are you doing, Jaime?
Sorry, bro', you gotta die.
That's just how it is.
Wait, at least do me in the front.
Let me die like a man.
That's how it is,
right, bro'?
Hey, Father.
I need to make a confession.
Saturday, 3:00.
I need
to make one now.
Close the door, Officer.
What's up?
You know, ever since
I've been let out of solitary,
I've just been going
right and left, you know,
up and down. Just trying to prove
to everyone that I'm no pussy.
I know what you mean.
I should have died
in that bus crash.
And now,
the Reverend Cloutier has...
disappeared,
which I think is
supposed to mean something,
but I can't figure out
what that something is.
- So what do you do?
- Pray.
Yeah, well,
you know...
toss in
a couple extra for me.
I always do, Miguel.
Yeah, well, I need just a little bit more than
my usual amount.
Someone died
because of me.
- Jaime Velez?
- Yeah.
This kid was innocent,
you know?
You and I have had a long
and battered relationship...
but I continue to believe
that you have a good soul,
and that you'll find a way to right
whatever wrong you committed.
And if I don't?
Then you really
are a pussy.
The problem is in our state
there are more visually-impaired people
than there are guide-dogs,
but there are more dogs
than there are people to train them.
That's why I created
this program, Man's Best Friend,
where prisoners
do the training.
- And it's worked elsewhere, huh?
- Oh, better than we'd hoped.
Sorry, am I late?
Well, she got here early,
so we just kind of dove in.
Sure, why wait
for little ol' me?
Alicia Hinden,
Eleanor O'Connor,
- the Governor's liaison.
- Nice to meet you.
Please, continue.
Having inmates care for
and train these pups
has been a perfect match.
60% of the dogs
qualify for placement,
90% of the prisoners
demonstrate
a better attitude after
their participation in the program.
Aren't there certain skills
necessary to train a guide-dog?
Of course,
but the skills are teachable.
And the prisoners
don't harm the animals?
Well, we were worried at first,
but what's happened here
is the dogs bring out
the best in their trainers.
Inmates go from having nothing
to nurturing a life.
It means more to them
than you can know.
You'll pardon me,
Miss Hinden,
if I'm skeptical.
I think we should start small.
Sure, the less people,
the less chance of success.
I'm not saying
the program will fail.
No, you're trying
to guarantee it won't last.
- I'm trying to save time and money.
- Yeah, right.
- Fuck you, Tim.
- Actually, I prefer to start small.
Oh, so...
I'll just need
three good volunteers.
If you're interested,
let me know, but remember
this isn't a few weeks
of playing fetch.
You gotta be strongly
motivated to participate.
Now the woman running the program
will interview each potential candidate,
review your files, and then
make her final decision.
That's all.
Shit, I don't want
no dogs in here, man.
You know, where I grew up, man,
there was this rott-pit bull mix,
mean motherfucker. I'm sure
he had some Schillinger in him.
He fucking took
a chunk out of my leg, man.
Something tells me
you deserved to get bit.
Yo, maybe a dog would take
my mind off my problems.
I'm signing up.
I think I'm gonna apply.
I bet these mutts
are drug sniffers.
- Undercover dogs?
- You never know, man.
Fuck it. You know what?
I'm in, man.
Me too.
- Ryan?
- Yo.
- Can we get a doggie?
- Not a chance.
Come on in
and sit down.
Hey, girl, yeah.
Yeah.
What did you do to get in here
with us bastards, huh?
Miguel, I've looked
through your file,
and I gotta be
honest with you.
You're not really
suited for this program.
- Why is that?
- You've got a history of violence.
Did you read in there about the C.O.
I blinded, Eugene Rivera?
Yeah, that kinda
jumped out at me.
Well, that's why
you gotta let me do this.
It's what I owe.
Just a good thing to even out
all the bad, you know what I'm saying?
Check this out.
She already picked me.
Yeah, yeah, girl.
Oh, that's
my bitch right there.
Step back a second,
Penders.
You don't get
your bitch just yet.
This isn't the city pound,
so I'll be assigning you your dog,
- which is how you'll refer to them.
- You the bitch.
First let me run down what
we're going to accomplish here.
The goal is to teach them,
and you, basic obedience.
So, we step out of line
and you hit us on the nose
with a rolled-up newspaper?
If I have to.
Now, you'll teach the dogs:
Come, sit, stay...
the basics.
But more importantly,
you'll show them love and trust.
For these dogs to be useful
to the visually impaired,
they have to be comfortable,
not just with their owners,
but with all people.
If we don't accomplish that,
then all you've raised is a pet,
just like any other shmoe.
- Yes?
- These dogs, they stay with us?
- Yes, in your pods.
- How do you keep them safe?
Like I said,
love and trust.
Shit, that's like
conjugals and cigarettes.
- Meaning?
- Those two things don't exist in Oz.
Check it out, the boys
brought their dates home.
So has your little mongrel
learned about pain yet?
Stay the fuck away
from her.
You're afraid I'm gonna hurt
your little poochie-woochie?
No, I'm afraid
she might hurt you, bro'.
Come on, girl.
Come on. Inside.
This is your new home.
This is your daddy's home.
Yeah, come over here.
All Vikings were
not stupid brutes.
They had moments
of brilliance.
They were such great
shipbuilders and sailors
that Leif Eriksson and his crew
landed in America first,
some say traveling
as far south as New York harbor.
Here's where
the true brilliance comes in.
They took a look,
turned around and went home.
You sent 200 letters
to the station
protesting the cancelation
of "Miss Sally's Schoolyard."
I wanted the programmers
to see there's a groundswell of support,
a grassroots demand
for the show to continue.
All from the same address?
I just got this letter
from the station manager today.
"Thank you for writing," blah blah. "Your
exceptional education," blah blah.
Unfortunately, 'Miss Sally's Schoolyard'
has ceased production."
- Ah. I'm gonna miss Miss Sally.
- Wait.
"I'm happy to announce
Whitney Allen will be appearing
in a new exercise series
called 'Sallycise.'
We hope you enjoy it.
Sincerely," blah.
I wonder if my Norma
will have a job on the new show.
You still haven't heard
from her, huh?
No, but I live
in expectation.
- Did you get ahold of your son?
- Yes.
- And?
- And there is no "and."
But did you tell him
you plan to win the lottery?
That you'll use the money
to save Alex Jr. From the leukemia?
- No.
- Isn't that why you phoned him?
Midway I decided I shouldn't
get the family's hopes up.
You're starting to doubt you picked
the winning numbers.
Of course not. My concern
is I don't know whether Officer Brass
actually bought
the ticket for me.
Officer Brass?
- Officer Brass?
- What? What is it, Rebadow?
Did you buy
my Mightyball ticket?
What? Yeah, yeah.
- Hey.
- Hey, what are you doing here?
I thought the warden had you
assigned to the cafeteria.
He does. I'm on a break.
I wanted to see how you guys are doing.
I got PMS.
I'm doing like shit.
Officer Brass,
good to see you.
Yeah, why's that?
Glynn's bringing more and more
nigger C.O. S every day.
In my book, any pale face
is a good pale face.
Let me ask you something.
Were you around
the day I got cut?
No, me and Robson
were on work detail.
If I'd have been here, I would have
pulled that monkey off you.
- So you know which monkey it was?
- Who exactly? No.
I guarantee you this, though,
it wasn't a white man.
- Hey, Brass.
- Yeah?
- You drink?
- Why, you wanna grab a couple of beers?
How about a blood-piss-shit-
puke cocktail, motherfucker?
God, that son of a bitch!
- How you feeling, Dave?
- I'm fine.
- Can I go?
- Sure.
Just come back in a week or so
and we'll do all your blood work.
It's important
that we check for everything...
hepatitis, TB, HIV...
just to be safe.
Dave.
I always feel
it's not my place to say this,
but when I think of what
can happen if I didn't,
- I know I'd hate myself.
- Say what?
Do you have a girlfriend
or sexual partner?
- Kate.
- You should mention what happened.
Just so she knows.
You're right.
It's not your place.
- Hola, Dr. Nathan.
- Hola.
Stop that.
Officer?
- Problem?
- He really should be in the hospital.
- No can do.
- I know he attacked one of your own,
but I can't treat him
properly here.
- I have to check with the warden.
- Then go check.
Hurry.
Gracias.
I said stop it.
I said stop it!
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it! I said stop it!
Don't touch me!
What's the matter with you?!
Martinez kept touching me,
I-I had these
flashes back to the rape
then I just lost control.
Or maybe at the moment,
you were actually
in control.
Peter Marie,
I beat an injured man.
Yes, I know,
but by beating him,
you were finally
in charge of the situation.
Look, you've told me
on any number of occasions
that since the rape
you feel adrift.
Well, maybe
this incident today
was an attempt to regain
control of your life.
All I keep having
are incidents like these.
Are you saying I antagonize
these men on purpose?
No, no, no,
but I do think
you have to answer a question I asked
when you first returned to work.
Why?
Why after being
beaten and violated
did you choose to return
to a place filled with brutal men?
I still don't know.
Well, I think
if we work on it,
and if we figure it out,
you'll finally
start to heal.
According to Norse
mythology,
man was made from an ash tree
and woman from an adder.
The great god Odin
gave them both life and souls
and a place
to live called Midgard,
which Odin created from the eyebrows
of a giant he slew.
Sounds almost true,
don't it?
All of us living
on the edge of an eyebrow.
Homosexuality...
is a perversion
against God's will.
I agree.
And yet you practice
sodomy yourself.
- I'm no faggot.
- You raped Beecher,
and Cyril O'Reily
and God knows how many others.
I never touched anybody.
You lying
cock-sucking fuck!
- Tobias.
- How can you deny what you did?
- Tobias! Officer!
- Get your fucking hands off me!
- Stop it!
- Come on! Fuck you!
You fucking lying bitch!
You lying fucking sack of shit!
Hey there, Petey.
Getting some shrink time?
That's good.
After a trauma
like you went through,
getting gang-raped and all...
No!
...it's healthy
to talk about the experience.
You probably shouldn't get
too specific in the details, though.
That might not be
so healthy after all.
Leave me alone.
Sure. For now.
Keep your sunny side up.
Hello, Chris.
How are you?
Well, I tell you,
being alone
gives you an awful lot
of time to think.
I'm sitting here
thinking about irony,
the irony of my life.
I'm sorry I can't convince the warden
to let you see Beecher.
He's not even allowing
an exchange of letters.
Let me tell you, it was easier
being apart when I was in Massachusetts.
Knowing he's
in this building...
knowing that maybe
he's behind that wall.
You said you were
gonna talk to a lawyer,
that you'd get
a defense lawyer for me.
The only way I'm seeing Beecher
is if I beat this murder rap.
I'll know
something shortly.
Meanwhile, keep the faith.
Keep it where?
- Hey.
What a nice surprise.
My cell phone never seems to work
in here, so I asked Sister Peter Marie
- if I could use her phone.
- Mm-hmm.
I was talking to Freddy Rudolph
about his hearing
and then Sister asked
if I could speak with another prisoner.
Chris Keller.
What?
- Don't.
- Why?
- Just don't.
- I've heard legends about Keller.
I'm curious.
Catherine...
- I love you.
- And you love Keller, right?
I mean, you still
love Keller, don't you?
Lf-if you meet him...
He's very seductive.
He...
You're gonna fall
in love with him too.
I'm willing
to take that chance.
Besides, I can't pass up
the opportunity
to meet my boyfriend's
boyfriend.
Here you go, Keller.
Bag of Atomic Fireballs
per your request.
Thanks, Claire.
You know I was needing
a little something to suck on.
Warden finds out I smuggled them
in for you, he'll have my ass.
Hmm, what a great ass it is.
- You're bad.
- So spank me.
You got a visitor, Keller.
Hello.
I'm Catherine McClain
from the Alliance for Prisoner Rights.
Sister Peter Marie
asked me to stop by.
- Can we be alone?
- We'll be right outside.
Did you kill
those three men?
You get right
to the point, don't you?
I don't have
a lot of time.
I got nothing but time.
Maybe not.
You're facing
the death penalty.
I'm not afraid to die.
I just wanna die
for the right reason.
- And the right reason would be...
- Love.
We have a mutual friend.
- Yeah, who?
- Tobias Beecher.
Oh, wait...
I know who you are.
You're the one that tried
to help Toby with his parole.
- Yes.
- And he wrote me about you.
Yeah, what did he say?
- He loves you.
- You'll understand my dilemma now.
You see, if you fry,
you're a memory.
If I get you off,
you and Toby will be reunited.
So now I know you'll do everything
in your power to get me off.
- And why's that?
- If you love Toby as much as I do,
then you want him
to be happy.
Reuniting us
will make him happy.
Yeah.
Counselor.
- Did you kill those three men?
- No.
- Fuck you!
- Shut the fuck up!
You fucking cunt!
Prisoner #02G561
and #02W562:
Adam Guenzel
and Franklin Winthrop:
Convicted January 14, 2002:
Rape, attempted murder
in the first degree:
Sentence: 28 years:
Up for parole in seven.
Okay, let's go.
Come on.
Come on over here, boy!
That one's yours.
This'll be the first time
I ever had to make my own bed.
Adam, take my word,
nothing you experienced growing up
in Broun Park has prepared you for Oz.
I know it's hard,
but I'll be here
for you, I promise.
Your dad was my scoutmaster,
for God's sake.
You have to
understand something.
That girl Franklin
and I raped...
we were drunk,
all three of us partying.
I blacked out.
I'd never meant
to hurt her.
Yeah, but you did.
That's why you're standing
where you're standing.
Don't forget that, ever.
The guilt may
keep you sane.
Yeah.
Get settled,
and I'll introduce
you around.
Yo, you need a helping hand
there, pretty boy?
You ever suck cock before?
Back off, Clarence.
All right, Vern.
No need to get testy.
You okay?
He was gonna rape me.
Fucking nigger.
We'll protect you from now on.
You'll be safe.
Jesus, thanks.
But, like everything else
in life...
it's gonna cost.
You've got
an alcohol problem,
so you should join
Sister Pete's therapy.
Ooh, he's hot!
- Fucking Christ.
- What?
Remember that friend Franklin Winthrop
I was telling you about?
- Yeah.
- That's him.
Franklin.
Your boy is next.
Fuck!
I need your help. I need you
to protect Adam from the Aryans.
I can't.
What do you mean,
you can't?
Beecher...
when I stabbed Schillinger
and Robson defending you,
I put a lot of my Muslim
brothers in jeopardy.
So I can't
do that again.
Certainly not
over some boy
who rapes and beats women.
I know.
Adam's no angel,
but I've known him
since he was a child.
I know his family. I-I can't justify
what he did, but...
Beecher, stop.
My answer is no.
- Well?
- It's not gonna work.
Shit!
Okay here's what
we're gonna do.
As a temporary stopgap,
you're gonna go to McManus
- and request protective custody.
- Until when?
Until I can figure
something else out.
Fuck.
He's mine.
Clean him up.
Prisoner #02U672:
Francis Urbano,
a.k.a. Frank the Fixer:
Convicted January 7th, 2002:
Murder in the first degree:
Sentence: Life:
Up for parole
in 25 years.
Sister Peter Marie wanted me
to drop this off for Dr. Nathan.
Pancamo,
you look like shit.
I got a fever
or something.
Can you hand me
some water?
Yeah, sure.
You know, l... I know you hate
the Aryans as much as I do, right?
More.
Those Nazi fucks shanked me
and raped Peter Schibetta.
Well, I got a friend who
they've threatened to rape, too.
I was wondering if you could
do something to protect him.
- Beecher, what are you doing?
- Nothing.
- Do it somewhere else.
- Yes, sir.
- What do you say?
- Done.
Thank you.
Oh, I like
a man who sweats.
- Leave him alone.
- Stay out of this, prag.
So there's two ways
this could go, precious:
Kick or kiss.
They both end up the same:
With my dick up your ass.
Not necessarily.
Oh, who the fuck
are you?
Who the fuck am I?
- Hey, you piece of shit.
- Fuck you!
How's the wound,
you fucking guinea? Huh?
Lockdown!
- Man, I was so fucking terrified.
- I know.
I mean, there were arms and legs
and knives everywhere!
Yeah, well,
it's over now.
Damn! Jesus, I didn't know
which way to turn!
I mean,
I was so pumped!
Part of me wanted to jump right in
and kick some ass.
- Adam.
- I could've, you know.
I could've kicked
some royal ass.
Fuck!
The Vikings had a code of behavior
which they followed religiously:
Honor and valor
on the battlefield
were the values that
a warrior strived for.
But much like the men in Oz,
they had no concept of good and evil.
They couldn't
tell the difference.
They didn't know
there should be one.
Hey, Gloria. I heard
what happened. Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
- That's good.
Come in.
I met your mother.
Yeah, I know.
She told me.
She seems nice.
She's so
completely different
than the woman I grew up
thinking was my real mom,
my other mom,
Cyril's mom, Tessie...
That was
her first name, Tessie.
Growing up,
Tessie was always sobbing.
She had good reason.
You know, Cyril and I,
we never gave her
any cause to smile.
- It's crazy, though.
- What?
Now that my mom is here,
you know, doing this
community service,
well, she and me
and Cyril,
it's like we're a family,
you know? It's fucking great.
Ryan, have you
told her anything
about what went on
between you and me,
Cyril, my husband Keenan?
No, huh-uh. Huh-uh.
I mean, she's been asking but...
- Don't you think you should?
- Why?
What good would
it do her knowing that shit?
You can't just present
the good son side of yourself to her.
Look, Gloria,
I'm in Oz.
I don't think my mom thinks
I'm up for any sainthood.
If you want to have
a real relationship with her,
you have to tell her
the whole truth.
Huh-uh, I can't tell her
- Why not?
- Because then she'll stop loving me.
I don't think so.
In my experience,
you don't love
Ryan O'Reily by choice.
? Old McDonald
had a farm?
? E-l-E-l-O...?
Relax, relax.
? And on that farm,
he had some cars...?
- Cars?
- ? E-l-E-l-O...?
- With a...
- ? With a vroom-vroom here.?
Not bad, kid.
Don't laugh.
At least I'm trying.
Yeah, he's right.
I don't see you
making any effort.
I got a little
something-something
- I might bust out at the variety show.
- Really?
What's that?
You'll see.
Hey, Ma, I wanna
ask you something.
Do you think families need to be
100% honest with each other?
Yeah.
What... I mean, if your father
and I had been honest,
if we'd been open and we'd
worked through our problems
and all our fears,
maybe I wouldn't have left.
I think about how different my life
would've gone if you'd stayed married.
Yeah, well,
don't romanticize it.
It still would've
been really difficult.
I know that,
but we would've been,
you know, together.
Yeah.
After we're done
fucking around here,
I want to tell you about
some of the things
that I've done, you know,
since I've been in Oz.
And I just...
I want to warn you, Mom,
it's not pretty.
Well, I wouldn't
expect it to be.
But that's good, because maybe
if you tell me about it,
it'll start to make
some sense to you.
Yeah.
So... what do you got?
- It's little something-something.
- Let's see it.
? This is a low card,
what you call a jack move?
? I'm takin' your flow card
to replicate rat's move?
? I'm callin' your bluff,
I've seen enough, what, what?
? Don't you say nothin' until I finish,
your mouth shut?
? Now answer them, yeah, yeah,
your heart is excited?
? So what's
all the fightin'??
- That's great!
- ? If I show you what I did?
? I'm not gonna ever lose,
I'm steppin', so what up, kid??
? You wanna play hard...?
- Today's the day.
- Yeah.
Kill them both,
but if you can
only get one, get Ryan.
We can always whack the 'tard
once the older brother's dead.
Shupe.
- Hey, O'Reily.
- Not now, Shupe.
- It's important.
- Okay, you got 10 seconds. What is it?
I overheard Li talking to Jia.
They were arguing about your mom.
- What?
- Li was saying he's gonna rape her.
Fuck.
- You got any tits, man?
- Yeah.
Ryan, is that man
gonna hurt Ma?
No fucking chance, Cyril.
Whoa, so your boys are
gonna hurt my mom, huh?
He's out of control,
O'Reily.
- I don't know what to do.
- Yeah, well, I do.
Hey.
I'm telling you,
he was gonna rape my mother.
- Do you have proof of that?
- Ask Jia.
- He knows all about it.
- I will.
- Meanwhile, I want Cyril in solitary.
- No!
Li's just the latest in a long line
of people Cyril's hurt.
I want him somewhere
he's not gonna hurt anybody else.
- Hey, he's all yours.
- Ryan?
It's gonna be okay,
Cyril. It's gonna be okay.
- Be gentle with him, man.
- I don't wanna go!
- Come on, let's go!
- I'm sorry.
- You cocksucker!
- Save your anger, O'Reily.
This time we're
gonna go the distance.
Cyril either ends up
in the insane asylum or death row.
And you're going
to the cage, come on.
Come on. Come on, O'Reily.
Let's go.
Sister, you've
gotta believe me!
You know, it's just possible
he's telling the truth.
O'Reily? The truth?
I doubt it.
Please! Please!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
Please, I don't want
to go in there.
No! No!
Please, I'm so so sorry!
Please! No!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Hey, Jia, Jia, Jia,
Come here. Hey, come here.
You gotta go to McManus and tell him
that Li was gonna rape my ma, okay?
- I got nothing to say to that.
- Whoa, Jia, come on!
You gotta
do that for me, man!
You gotta tell him.
Your brother's
gonna die.
They're gonna fry
his white ass,
and I'll be
sitting in the front row
laughing my balls off,
you fucking mick.
What? You fucking
chink motherfucker!
Are you fucking kidding me?
You're fucking dead, Jia!
You're fucking dead,
you rice-eating little fucking bitch!
You're fucking dead! You're dead,
you fucking shit motherfucker!
- You wanted to see me?
- Yeah, Warden.
Nice place you got here.
What do you want, Redding?
Control of the cafeteria.
The Sicilians
run the cafeteria.
Yeah, but Chucky Pancamo's
still in the hospital.
Pete Schibetta, psycho ward.
The place is
out of control.
Hmm, you think you can pull
the operation back together?
Most of those guys
are friends of mine.
Most of them are black
and they don't take too kindly
to kowtowing
to the dagos.
I let Adebisi call
the shots in the cafeteria.
- It was a disaster.
- I ain't Adebisi, am I?
Truth is, there have
been a lot of fuck-ups
all the way back
to the gas explosion.
All right, Redding,
I'll give you a chance.
- Officer.
- One other thing,
I'd appreciate it if you got them
Sicilians out of there.
Sure.
Much obliged.
Augustus, Augustus...
Augustus,
where's your dog?
She's in my pod. I don't feel
like playing with her right now.
- Thinking about your mother?
- Yeah.
It'll take more than a few weeks
for me to get over her death.
That's not
what I meant.
I just keep picturing her
trying to figure out
which way is up
as the fucking bus rolls.
She hated closed spaces,
being trapped.
Freaked her out.
Now she's trapped forever
in some cheap-ass coffin.
- You gotta move beyond that.
- Fuck you, Beecher.
I know what you're feeling.
I buried my son.
You know,
this may sound strange,
but you gotta
work those images.
Your mind's already taken
your mother from the bus to the grave.
Now keep going. You gotta picture
her body under the ground rotting away.
- Get the fuck out of my...
- Listen to me.
You have to imagine
your mother decaying,
the maggots eating away her flesh,
leaving nothing but the bone.
You gotta hear
that coffin splinter,
smell the dirt falling
through the cracks.
And why the fuck would I
want to do that?
To let your mother go.
Right now she's
defined by her death.
This is the only way to lose
the horror of what happened
and to move on to everything
good about her.
I can't, you fuck! All I can see
is the fucking bus!
- Just take a walk, Beecher!
- Augustus.
Take a fucking walk!
Jesus!
Give me
that shit, man. Yeah.
Yeah, let him in.
Give me something.
- Some of this?
- Yeah.
Why? Why the change
of vein?
I need
a consolation prize.
Yeah, welcome back.
Yo, dude,
this motherfucker ain't
done tits in like years.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, there you go.
Go get it. Yeah.
? Swing low?
? Sweet chariot?
? Coming for
to carry me home...?
? Swing low?
? Sweet chariot?
? Coming for?
? To carry me home...?
- Now you expect me to sing like that?
- No, no, Omar.
I just... I want you to enjoy it
as much as I do.
I never thought
I'd say this, but I do.
- I think I really do.
- Good, good.
I mean, you know, the last couple
of lessons, they were slammin'!
I mean, they...
they rocked!
Oh.
Well, it looks
like time's up.
- I'll catch you later, teacher.
- Okay.
Practice.
How's it hangin', boss?
? Swing low?
? Sweet Harriet?
? Bustin' my nut
to the bone?
? Swing low?
? Swing low,
sweet chariot...?
Omar, Omar, Omar,
your lesson's over.
Hey, I got a song
in my heart.
You ain't gonna begrudge me
of that, is you?
All I'm asking you, Omar,
is to keep the song in your heart.
- ? From sea...?
- Yo, White, you take requests?
Sure, motherfucker,
what you want to hear?
Shut the fuck up.
I will not fight.
See if you can sing now,
motherfucker.
- Leave him alone, Guerra.
- Or what?
Break up the square dance.
Come on, as of right fuckin' now.
Tell Mr. Bojangles
to keep his fuckin' trap shut.
Get the fuck
out of here now! Move it!
That's pretty good
looking out, man.
Stay out of trouble,
Omar.
Yo, wait, let me tell you
something, though.
For the first time, me and trouble
ain't even on speaking terms.
- What was up with Guerra?
- He stepped to me.
- You saw that.
- Stop the finger-pointing.
All blame lies with you...
and therefore on me,
and I am not gonna have it.
Said, I gotta practice.
Practice... practice is gonna
make me perfect.
Then when trouble comes,
run away.
That ain't gonna help
my reputation up here at Oz.
The only person your
reputation matters with is me.
The moment you forget that
you go straight back to solitary.
Now you understand me?
Do you understand me?
? Swing low?
? Sweet chariot?
? Comin' for
to carry me home.?
- What's up?
- Omar White.
He's following instructions
without too much whining.
I have managed
to keep him clean.
The singing... seems
to have focused him.
- It's just...
- He's driving you crazy?
No, the problem is he's catching
a lot of flack from the other inmates.
They're harassing him,
and he may get hurt, McManus.
There's only
so much that I can do.
He doesn't have anywhere else
to practice except in my pod.
- Which is when he drives you crazy?
- Yes.
I don't know if there
are any other options.
I will support him
as much as I can,
- but I need to pray in silence.
- Okay, okay.
Let me do some math, okay?
Thank you.
? Comin' for to carry me...?
? Comin' for... comin' for
to carry me home?
- ? Swing low...?
- Omar.
Let's take a walk.
- Did I fuck up?
- No, nothing like that.
So, I hear you're
singing up a storm.
Yeah, no, I mean,
who'd have thunk it, right?
I'm the motherfuckin'
Omar "Barry" White.
- Yo, you wanna hear a few bars?
- Not right now.
As a matter of fact, Omar,
neither does anybody else.
Wait, wait, wait, wait,
hold it, hold it.
First you encourage me
to do this shit, right?
- Now you want me to stop?
- Follow me.
Where you going, man?
You ain't sticking me
in Gen Pop and shit.
Calm down,
we're almost there.
What the fuck is this, man?
Shit. Hey, yo, McManus,
I ain't with this shit
at all, all right?
Oh, no, man, you ain't going
to make me mop and shit again?
Omar, Omar, if you would just
shut up a fuckin' second,
I think that
you'll be pleased.
Oh shit.
Damn, boy.
You'll practice
in here for an hour each day.
Damn, you all right,
McManus.
You a straight up
motherfuckin' humdinger, boy.
Yeah, yeah,
that's me, humdinger.
I heard you got your own
little private practice shack.
You ready to do
a little slinging for me?
Slinging? Sling what?
What you mean, like selling drugs?
No, no, I can't...
I can't...
I can't risk that now.
Now, see...
that's not the answer
I was looking to hear from you.
Now here's how
it's gonna work.
I'm going to give you
the stash,
you move it on over
to my man Reggie,
and he moves it
on over to Unit C.
And if you got
a problem with that,
then you gonna have
a bigger problem with me.
So I'm going to ask you
one more time,
are you ready to do
some slinging with me?
Fuck it, fuck it.
Fine, fine.
Take it.
Omar,
if I find out you been
using some of that shit,
there ain't going to be nothing left
of you to sweep up off the floor.
Believe me, Redding,
this time I actually
want to stay clean.
Yeah, well,
miracles do happen.
? Swing low?
? Sweet chariot?
? Comin' for to carry me...?
? Home...?
? Comin' for
to carry me home.?
- You Reggie?
- Who else you think gonna be knockin'?
- Destiny's child?
- That was rhetorical shit, all right?
If rhetorical means dumb as fuck,
you got that right.
You ain't too big on the small talk,
is you, brother?
- Business is business.
- Yeah, well...
pleasure's better.
Later, fuckin'
rhetorical nigger.
Yo, Red.
Good work.
Never let it be said that I ain't
a patron of the arts.
Whoo, boy!
Tough day
at the office, Jack.
How was yours?
What... what you doing?
Omar. Please.
What?
Be quiet.
Yeah, I'm just trying
to wind down and shit,
- you know what I'm saying?
- Then wind down in silence.
What the fuck?
What's eating you?
Something I did
or something? What?
Omar, now you may be
my biggest concern,
but you are
certainly not my only one.
So please, please, please!
Leave me in peace.
All right.
Good morning, lmam.
Preparing for
tomorrow's lecture?
No.
Music appreciation
and theory?
That's right.
What about us, Minister?
I understand our faith
does not discourage
against the improvement
of others,
but it also mandates
that our leader lead.
We're concerned that Omar White
is becoming too much of a distraction.
We?
Lalar, you concur?
- Look...
- Ahmad, do you feel spiritually adrift
now that I've taken somebody
else under my wing?
- Imam, l...
- Oh...
Lookie here.
Huey, Dewey and Jigabooey
are having a little lesson.
Lalar, step back!
Now.
Arif, let's go.
I hope it was
something I said.
Out on the Serengeti,
where these nigs are from,
you know how you send
a message to the leader of the pack?
You kill the youngest
and the weakest of the herd.
I seen that
on those wildlife shows.
Well, I think it's time
we do a little big game hunting.
The Vikings eventually
got civilized, became Christians.
They're now the Danes,
the Norwegians, the Swedes.
What's ironic is despite all them
war-loving genes in their system,
Norway now gives
out the Nobel Peace Prize.
I guess
a people can change
if they put
their collective minds to it.
Pretty cushy gig
for a jig,
trusting you around
all of this merchandise.
How are we to know that
you're not stealing shit?
I guess we better
open you up and check.
Nope, nothing there.
Maybe in his arm.
Maybe.
Oh, strike fuckin' two.
Well, Lalar,
I recommend you
get comfortable.
This could take
a little while.