A wise man once said,
"Life is an adventure
in forgiveness."
You might rank bungee jumps
off a bridge in New Zealand
or bachelor parties in Vegas
a few notches higher
on the adventure ladder.
But think about
the risks involved.
You could climb
to the mountaintop of attrition
only to get shot down by a victim
who refuses to forgive.
Think about the rewards...
A chance to heal
those nasty wounds,
reconcile
with someone you love.
Huh, now that
I think about it,
forgiveness
might knock bungee jumps
and bachelor parties
off the charts.
It's okay.
Take a break.
Cutler's a suicide, huh?
That's what
Reimondo's saying,
- and I ain't disagreeing.
- I didn't imagine you would.
So now what,
Vern?
Someone else
needs to commit suicide
- before I get some respect?
- Jesus Christ, Robson,
you made your point.
Shut the fuck up and spot me.
And... one.
Come on! Come on!
Miguel, sit down.
What did I do?
Well, that's
what I'm wondering.
Tell me about your relationship
with Wolfgang Cutler.
Cutler, the Nazi guy? We didn't
have a relationship.
Dome-head was an equal
opportunity racist.
Would it surprise you if he
left you something in his will?
He left me
something?
- Like what?
- Everything he owned.
What?
You are the sole beneficiary
of all his worldly goods,
both in Oz
and on the outside.
His house, his car...
hell, his 1942
Indian motorcycle.
- Get the fuck out of here.
- The will is signed, notarized.
Are you shittin' me?
I barely even spoke
to the fucking guy,
a couple of times
at rehearsal. That's it.
The guy had
any wife, kids,
- family, anything?
- Wife, no kids.
- This is fucking crazy.
- We packed up his cell,
put all his belongings
into a box.
You'll have to decide
what you want to keep.
I'm not gonna look
through a dead guy's things.
Jesus.
I guess we'll have to wait
till the afterlife to find out
why Cutler would give his
belongings to a fucking wetback.
Yo, I'm as bugged
out as you.
I know you guys spent
a lot of time with Cutler.
Did he ever mention
anything about me?
Yeah, in his sleep
at night.
He'd whisper your name.
- Fuck off!
- I'll suggest this now,
or I'll find a way
to make it happen later,
you sign all his stuff
over to his wife.
- I already thought about that.
- Don't think, spic, do.
You know? Maybe I should
give all his assets to you, Roby,
being that you already
gave him your ass.
Cunt.
Did you miss me?
I've been missing you.
What happened to you
the last few months?
Well, things got
a little hectic.
But now I'm back
on track.
Goddamn, Leez,
you look good.
Beat me off, baby.
Will you relax? What the fuck
is your problem?
- Let go of me!
- Sit down now!
Let go of me,
you cocksucker!
- What did you just call me?
- Cocksucker!
Don't you ever call me
that again, ever!
- What's your problem?!
- I'm not a cocksucker!
Fuck!
I'm at a Chinese
restaurant.
My fortune cookie says,
"Whoever opts for revenge
- should dig two graves."
- I hate Chinese food.
- Shut the fuck up, Hank.
- "Shut the fuck up, Hank."
My brother is an annoying
little prick, but I forgive him.
Why? 'Cause we only get
two choices...
Forgive,
or die a slow death.
One of them studies
doctors do shows that
carrying around the baggage
of anger and bitterness,
can put you at risk
for mental illness,
for depression
and anxiety,
as well as strokes,
heart disease and heart attacks.
Who knew? Forgiveness
is good for your health.
Everybody's attention,
please.
Can I have your attention,
please?
When Augustus Hill died,
we thought we lost him
forever, but we didn't.
He wrote a book
about his life here...
about your lives,
and Kareem Said's
last great act
was to get Augustus'
book published.
Now when Kareem died,
the book could've
died with him,
but it didn't
because of the hard work
and dedication of these men.
I want you all to share
in their triumph.
Here you go.
Fuck, man.
All right, already.
- Quit fuckin' with me!
- Whoa, Rawls, take it easy.
You have any idea how much
this machine costs?
No. I'm doing
something wrong.
Don't touch it,
I'll get Arif.
We got big trouble. One of the guys
are having problems
with something
I couldn't help him with.
You might want to go take
a few minutes and check it out.
I don't have a few minutes, Jamal.
You can see that, can't you?
Would it help to hire someone
from outside to do the accounting?
And pay them
with what?
See that figure on the bottom right, right
there?
That's our gross so far,
1/5 of what it should be.
With all due respect
to Kareem Said,
taking on Hill's book pro bono
wasn't a sound business plan.
Us paying minimum wage
is the problem.
A small cut, which would
still be far above
what prisoners usually make,
might be the best solution.
And defeat the whole purpose
of this operation? No.
What is the purpose exactly?
To run a successful company
or humiliate
Burr Redding?
Prisoner
number 0-1-R-9-3-4,
Reginald Rawls...
convicted January 10th, 2001...
aggravated assault.
Sentence... 12 years,
up for parole in four.
First, telemarketing,
now bookbinding?
Not exactly the kind of prison
life you hear about on the street.
All right, game's over.
I want you two back with me
in Degenhart's company.
Poet put you up to this,
following him to work
for the Muslims.
Well, in case you forgot,
you answer to me.
We do?
Kenaniah, we still answer
to Mr. Redding here?
You two begged like bitches
to get a place in my clan.
I gave you shelter.
I showed you the ropes.
And this is
the thanks I get.
Please. We were
your foot soldiers,
day and night
running tits and shit.
Now you turn around
and want us to do work
that's just plain
fuckin' work?
Kiss my ass, old man.
- Preach that shit, Reggie.
- You know it, nigga.
Give me that,
give me that.
So Redding,
you wanted to see me.
About what?
Well, when I told you fellas
I was giving up the tit trade,
- you didn't believe me.
- No, we didn't.
Well, now you can see
that my words are righteous.
I got involved in this
telemarketing business
to keep my boys
from slinging...
but it's not working,
and I need your help.
If you see Poet, Rawls
or any of the others
dealing, I want
you to squash 'em...
squash 'em hard.
You want us to kill
your own men?
Not kill, demobilize.
Weaken 'em until they have
to come back to me.
Looks like you got
yourself a deal.
Yo, I am done toting
and lifting heavy machinery.
We need to get back
to slinging drugs.
I hear ya, Reggie,
but the timing
ain't right.
Man, I would love to take
that dago down.
You will, yo, you will.
But not yet, though.
We got to play this real smooth,
real smooth.
Hey, guys.
- Y'all want ball?
- Drop dead, Omar.
Prisoner number
0-3-l-4-6-2,
Lemuel Idzik...
convicted
February 2nd, 2003...
murder
in the second degree.
Sentence...
life imprisonment
without the possibility
of parole.
You'll be staying here in "J,"
at least temporarily,
until we see how the rest of the population
adjusts to you around.
There's your nest.
Good to see you
there, Warden.
I'm Alvin Yood.
Friendly type, huh?
Arif,
I just heard the motherfucker
that killed Said is coming to Oz.
- He's already here.
- Here?
Well, what we gonna do?
- Do?
- Yeah, what are we gonna do?
- We gotta whack his white ass.
- No!
What's the matter, Arif,
ain't you got the balls?
I promised the warden
no harm would come to Idzik,
and no Muslim
would seek revenge.
Like I said, no balls.
Listen to me,
I saw Kareem Said
get shot.
I held him
in my arms as he died.
The last words
he said were,
"Don't harm him."
Now, as hard as it is
not to do something,
I will respect and obey
the minister's wishes,
and you will do the same.
Don't you be ordering me
around, motherfucker.
You don't own me,
you understand?
Not one little bit of me.
Mail call.
- How's the new guy?
- Marathon talker.
The brotherhood is grateful
for what you did to Said.
Them Muslim bastards
start to hassle you,
you just let me know,
we'll take care of them.
- I am a Jew.
- A Jew?
Well, I've always said there's
some good use for you people.
So explain,
why the fuck did you kill him?
Some Israeli-Palestine thing?
Water. Cold water.
Huh?
You put cold water in a...
let's say a teapot,
turn the stove on,
the water
gets hot, right?
At some point it gets
as hot as it will ever be,
blistering. Meanwhile,
the stove is off,
the water
starts to cool,
until eventually
it's cold.
That's the way things
work in the universe,
cold, hot, cold.
You should've
pleaded insanity.
Omar, you wanted
to see me?
Yes, sir.
I am hereby
and officially requesting
a face-to-face meeting
with Lemuel Idzik.
Ah, that would be a no.
- Wait, wait, wait, hear me out.
- He killed Said.
I'm not gonna give you
a chance to return the favor.
- I'm not gonna hurt him.
- That's what you say now,
but what will you say
when you stand over his dead body
with a shank in your hand?
Not gonna happen.
Fuck!
So if forgiveness
is so good for us,
- why don't we do it more?
- Same reason I don't eat tofu.
- It tastes like shit.
- There are two reasons
we hold back.
First, accountability...
as long as we're still in pain,
we need someone to blame.
What can you do
with all that pain
if you've let the bastard
off the hook?
Second, identity...
without this rage
consuming me,
without this resentment,
this bitterness,
who am I?
And finally, the Correctional
Officers Association
is holding their annual awards dinner and
banquet here later this month.
How come we always have
to host these fuckin' things?
That attitude,
Claire, is why
you probably won't be taking
home a trophy again this year.
Don't forget,
it's black tie and evening gown.
Okay, let's make
a good showing.
All right, that's
all for today.
I can't wear an evening gown.
I don't even own one.
- Warden, can I have a minute?
- Sure.
I've been a C.O.
A lot of years,
and in that time I've done
some things I regret.
We all have, Sean.
Occupational hazard.
Yeah, well, what I mean is
that we spend a lot of time
trying to get the prisoners
to rat each other out,
yet when it comes to us,
there's this...
- code of silence.
- Which you're about to break.
Yeah.
I don't envy you
right now.
- Who?
- Dave Brass.
- He killed Carlos Martinez?
- No, no, no,
but Dave lied about talking
to Martinez the night he died.
There was no
death bed confession.
Martinez never implicated
Morales
in the cutting
of Dave's tendons.
That's the real reason you asked me
to move Morales to the hospital.
- I still think the dink is guilty.
- But there's no proof.
We dumped him
in solitary unjustly.
Worse...
Dave, Claire Howell
and myself, we...
we're the ones who cut up
Morales' ankles.
I suspected
that Brass was involved
and that Howell
allowed it to happen.
- But you, Sean...
- Dave was my pal, you know?
Morales fucked up
his life forever.
Okay.
Thank you.
That's it, "Thanks"?
I'll discipline
the three of you, but...
how exactly,
I don't know yet.
- Sean?
- Yeah?
It takes balls,
what you just did.
Well, I didn't
become a zoo keeper
just to behave
like one of the animals.
Put it into your mouth.
Morales.
I'm releasing you
from solitary, permanently,
putting you
back in Emerald City.
- Why?
- I don't need to give a reason.
That might make me
think twice.
All right,
forget the why.
Hey, Warden,
what do you know
about nurse Grace?
Know about her?
Nothing,
except she's worked
here for years.
If I were you,
I'd check her background.
What? She's medically
incompetent?
I'm afraid.
Afraid? You?
- Of her?
- Yeah.
Must be the medication
you're on.
Hey, Rebadow.
What do you want?
Didn't I give you
all the money
that was left
from that lottery?
Too late
to save my grandson.
You blame me,
but you shouldn't.
- Who then?
- Morales.
He had Martinez cut me,
which screwed with my head,
which made me take off
with your winnings.
He's the bastard
you should hate.
There's room in my heart
for both of you.
Yeah?
Well, Morales is on his way
back to Em City,
and I got fined
and suspended...
a solid month...
and no pay, no benefits.
You think
I can afford that?
I just got married,
for Christ's sake!
I'll repeat my question.
What do you want?
For me to feel sorry for you?
No chance.
Fuck you, Murphy.
So, you happy?
Brass gets his ass
handed to him,
we lose
a week's vacation.
All for what?
Enrique-fucking-Morales?
For the truth, Howell,
for justice.
Justice?!
Justice, my pink ass!
Oh, call the blood banks.
Here comes another
bleeding heart.
- Leo told me all the gory details.
- I'm sorry, Tim.
- You're sorry?
- I bring you into Oz
because we've known each other
since sixth grade,
because you're the one person
in my entire life
that I can trust
with my life,
if necessary.
But then, see, I find out
I can't trust you,
that you're just
another thick-headed,
red-neck slug who uses
his badge as a weapon.
You're right,
you're absolutely right.
Don't you fuckin'
agree with me!
I'm telling you
to fuck off!
Listen, I've betrayed
your trust.
If you don't see me
getting it back,
maybe I should just
transfer out of Em City.
- What?!
- Maybe I should just quit.
No. Jesus!
Jesus!
Stop being
so fuckin' remorseful!
- You don't want me to be remorseful?
- No... yes!
We're going to dinner tonight.
You're paying.
Okay.
Sean, I'm proud of you,
that you stepped forward.
It means...
I can still trust you.
Morales?
Morales,
I'm sorry to disturb you.
That sedative I gave you
was pretty strong, huh?
Yeah.
It's a precaution.
You're a big fella.
I didn't want to struggle.
Struggle?
Martinez was so weak.
He couldn't fight me,
but you...
Say your prayers,
Enrique.
- No, don't.
- You're just like Martinez,
a nasty man
who deserves to die.
- Knock, knock.
- Hi.
Can you say,
"Who's there?"
Might be a while before she can
say "Agamemnon Busmalis."
Oh, God,
she's gorgeous.
Thank you.
Oh, that fresh smell
of baby skin...
in Oz of all places.
- Can I touch her?
- Of course.
- Can I keep her?
- How about we share?
Ruby needs a father,
Agamemnon,
and I need you back.
will you marry me?
What?
You're proposing
to me now?
- Is that a yes?
- I think so.
Yeah.
- Oh, my God, yes!
- Yeah.
Yes!
Oh, you little doll.
Little doll.
I can't work
in the library anymore.
What?
Why not?
I'd rather not get
into the specifics.
Given that I run this place,
I need specifics.
Something happen
I should know about?
- No.
- Trouble with other inmates?
- Is it Stella?
Are you two
having problems?
- No.
- Well, what is it then?
Did you forget
the fuckin' alphabet?
I don't wanna get
Robert in trouble,
but I thought
you should know.
It's not like Rebadow
to just stop showing up,
but he did come to me asking
to be switched to another job.
You have
any idea why?
No.
He's probably still
depressed about Alex Jr.
Who?
His grandson.
He died last year
of leukemia.
His grandson?
Of leukemia?
I didn't say anything
when I initially came to you.
I thought that the library
would be a good place
to distract his mind
from his misery.
Anyway, he'll be
there tomorrow.
So I did good by you
with "ball four"?
- I hit a homerun?
- I like the beaver shooting,
where the players drilled holes
in the doors of the hotel room
and watched
the stewardess fuckin'.
Yeah, well,
it's fun for the guys,
but how would you like
to have been on the other side?
What they did was
an invasion of privacy.
- Yeah, whatever.
- Whatever.
Now, this is a very
good book about women.
And I thought something
wilderness-based,
"Into Thin Air," might be
a nice antidote to Oz.
- I look like a fuckin' boy scout?
- Scout, no.
Boy, yes.
I'll just be a minute.
I'd like
to talk to you.
When I told you
about my breast cancer,
I wasn't asking you to watch me
waste away and die, Robert.
I don't need you for that,
if that's what you're afraid of.
I know about Alex Jr.
This isn't that.
I know you're thinking...
you can't go through
the grief again, but...
what if you're missing the chance
to go through the joy,
the joy of being there for someone
who is going to make it?
According to Blake,
they go hand in hand,
joy and grief..."piping down
the valleys wild." Remember?
Stop being an asshole.
If she's talking to you, old man,
show some respect, talk back.
That's enough, Pablo. Take
your book, we're done for today.
70 times 77. Jesus said
that's how many times
you're supposed
to forgive your brother.
Hank and I are still
working on seven.
Meanwhile, an innocent man
nailed to a cross
with iron spikes
says while dying,
"Forgive them, Father.
They know not what
they do."
Hind of raises the stakes
for the rest of us, huh?
Officer Schwartzmyer says
on the night of the murder
you started screaming.
I had a bad reaction
to the medicine.
As he came over
to check you out,
someone snuck in the private room
and stabbed Mayor Loewen.
The medicine was
giving me hives.
Mr. Kelsch,
Dr. Nathan tells us
you weren't having a negative
reaction to the medicine.
I couldn't stop itching.
You wanna know
what I think? I think
You were paid to distract Officer
Schwartzmyer from his post.
The scratching was
driving me crazy.
That makes
you guilty of murder.
That means you go
to death row.
Huh?
Death row?
For hives?
Okay, Brandt,
here's the deal.
We now know you're guilty
of killing Wilson Loewen.
That's a lie.
We have statements
from two of the other inmates
who were in the ward
that night.
They say they saw you
get out of bed
- and go into Loewen's room.
- They're lying.
We also have a confession
from Lionel Kelsch who says
you offered him $1,000
to distract the officer on duty.
He's a liar.
Okay, we'll play it
your way.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Aryans are gonna be pissed
when they hear
you're guilty
of killing their hero.
Anything you say may be used
against you in a court of law.
Without my protection,
you'll be dead within the hour.
You have the right to a lawyer
before speaking to me.
All right.
All right, all right.
L...
I'll tell you
who hired me.
It was that C.O.,
what was his name?
Johnson.
Johnson,
how's it going?
Not bad, sir,
and you?
The usual brouhaha.
Hey, I hear you just
bought a car,
uh... Jaguar.
- Yep.
- A beautiful automobile.
Pretty pricey
on a C.O.'s salary.
My wife's
maiden aunt kicked.
She left us
a little dough.
Nice.
Willy Brandt...
- What, sir?
- Willy Brandt confessed
to the murder
of Wilson Loewen.
Congratulations.
How did you manage to get
that thing to spill?
The truth?
We lied.
We told Brandt that
we had two witnesses,
which we don't, and that
his partner confessed,
which he didn't.
- Brilliant.
- Oh, here's the good part.
Brandt claims
that you offered
to pay him $5,000
to waste Wilson Loewen.
Not that I believe him
or anything.
No, sir.
He's a lying
piece of shit.
Right.
Well,
good night.
Enjoy that car.
Hey, it's me.
We got a problem.
Glynn knows
I set up the murder.
What do you
want me to do?
Okay.
He brought the devil
in here, your son.
Do you hear me?
Your baby boy got
butt-fucked by Satan,
and now
we're all gonna burn,
you fuckin' bitch!
I'm an idiot.
I thought by talking
to the man who killed Timmy,
I would get to know
more about my boy,
that I'd understand how
he became the man he became.
Well, like I said,
Jaz Hoyt isn't very coherent
these days.
He's been ruled mentally insane
by the court of appeals.
Tomorrow they're moving him
up to the psych unit.
So what do I do now?
How do I calm this guilt
inside of me?
And don't
tell me to pray.
I've prayed so hard
my knees hurt.
Well, when praying stalls,
I usually try to imagine
what my dad would've done
in the situation.
That's an excellent idea.
Do you drink, father?
- Ah, sure.
- Good.
I'll go into town, I'll get us
a quart of Jameson's
and sit in the dark
and drink until dawn,
'cause that's how my dad would've
handled the situation.
- Uh, Mrs. Kirk, I-I...
- I'm joking, Father.
Call me Jessica.
- Call me Ray.
- Ray...
like a ray of sunshine.
I think what
I should do is...
what I should've done
when Timmy was alive,
and that's volunteer
to work at Oswald,
help men like my son
- become better people.
- Volunteer?
- What would you do?
- I'm a nurse.
I bet they could use some help
in the hospital ward.
Yes.
- You'll set that up for me?
- Of course.
Thank you.
I consider you
my really good friend.
Morning, kiddies.
Do I have to go
get more ECT?
Later.
Come on, Hoyt, time
to move you up to Psych.
Hoyt!
What the fuck?!
I'm bleeding.
He'll sleep.
I sedated him.
He's got no cuts
on his forehead.
What's causing the bleeding?
A rare condition
called hematidrosis.
Underneath the skin there are
these tiny blood vessels,
capillaries.
When people are stressed,
they sweat, right?
Well, sometimes
under extreme stress
the capillaries
hemorrhage,
releasing small amounts
of blood into the sweat glands.
Hoyt is literally
sweating blood.
"And being in fear,
he prayed more earnestly,
and his sweat became
like great drops of blood,
which fell
upon the ground."
Luke 22:44, the agony
of Christ in Gethsemane.
Jesus and Jaz,
I didn't know they had
so much in common.
What's the matter
with him?
Side effects
of the electric shock.
I threw up on myself.
Oh, poor Cyril.
Clean him up
and then admit him.
I was gonna give him
some Emetrol
and send him
back to death row.
He spent enough time
up there.
He could use a change
of scenery.
All right, but I'm putting
him in restraints.
Hey, Gloria.
Hey, thanks a lot
for letting my brother, chill out
in the hospital ward.
- It means a lot to me.
- Well, that's okay.
Yeah.
Hey, we...
we just
heard that...
yeah, his latest appeal
has been denied
and... the lawyer...
is gonna plead his case
to the State Supreme Court
but, you know, unless
a fuckin' miracle happens...
I think Cyril's going
to be executed next week.
I have to go.
Hey, Gloria...
I never stopped
loving you,
not for a second.
Excuse me.
Don't you fuckin'
ignore me.
You think because I'm slow
I don't know what's going on.
I have to go
to the bathroom.
Listen to me,
you fuckin' asshole,
I'm gonna shit
in my pants.
Help me.
Too late.
Hey, you're gonna
leave me lying here
in my own shit?
Hey!
- What's the matter?
- I had an accident.
Not again.
Machelo.
Can you give me a hand
over here, please?
Okay, I'm here.
What's so urgent?
Mr. Neema,
your reputation
on the street is...
well, it's massive.
Back in the day with
the Black Panthers thing,
and since then with
the community development...
I know my own resume.
Get to the point.
Well, you see, sir,
we've been a little
leaderless lately.
Burr Redding's off on some
telemarketing ego trip.
Yeah, and you want me
to take over.
Shit, yeah.
You fellas know
why I'm in Oz?
For kidnapping
or some such.
I picked up my daughter
from day care.
My ex-wife was intending
to leave this country,
thereby depriving me
of my rights to see my child,
and I love my children,
gentlemen,
every single one,
and I got 16.
Maybe it's your turn
to get to the point.
None of my children
do drugs,
sell drugs
or hang in gangs.
Each lives a life
of their own choosing,
contributing
as best they can
to make a better world.
My children are my pride
because they make
me proud.
So rather than use
this classroom
as a place
to plot your plans,
use it for
a real purpose...
to learn.
End of sermon.
End of discussion.
Hey, stranger, haven't seen
much of you lately.
- You've been busy with the play...
- Yes.
- Your boyfriend.
- Boyfriend?
Jahfree Neema. I see you here,
I see you there,
laughing
and whispering.
- It's very sweet, very intimate.
- Ryan, come on.
What? You gonna tell me
I'm imagining it,
- that my eyes deceive me?
- No.
You asked me
to be nice to the guy,
I tried, he blew me off.
I know you think he's some sort
of hotshot savior and all,
but to me he's just
another fuckin' wanker.
You two enjoy
yourselves.
Meanwhile, my little
brother's gonna die.
- Ryan.
- What?!
Promise me you won't do
anything to harm Jahfree.
Oh, gee, Ma,
you really think I'm capable
of something like that?
Neema,
we haven't had much of a chance
to talk since you arrived...
that's probably because we have
nothing to say to each other.
Well, look, I know
on the outside you and me,
- were never that friendly, but...
- Friendly?
Redding, you are
anathema to me.
See, there you go
using them big words,
think you're going
to curl me, but it don't.
For the past
30-something years,
you've been supplying
the children of our community
with lethal drugs
while I have fought
to keep those
same children safe.
And now, because we both find
ourselves in this clapshack,
you want to believe
that we have a bond.
- We don't.
- We do!
I've seen
the error of my ways,
and I'm trying
to correct them.
I don't believe you.
You know, Burr,
that Neema,
he's a pompous
piece of shit, man.
I say it's time he learns
who's the boss around here.
You want him dead,
O'Reily?
I wouldn't weep
if he was.
If you really want
to do Neema some harm,
tie him to your
mother's crime.
What do you mean?
You're a clever boy,
you figure that one out.
Who's the hardest person
of all to forgive?
Oneself.
The demons inside,
they laugh at the thought.
When you forgive
some other guy,
he's not likely to turn you down,
say, "fuck that."
Tryin' to forgive
yourself, though,
it's "fuck that"
all the time.
10 years go by, you still can't
let yourself off the hook.
15 years, 20, 40.
You gonna take that grudge
against yourself
to the grave?
You gonna carry it
for eternity?
Well, well, well,
Agent Taylor,
- are you here to visit me?
- Fuck you, Keller.
Aww, G-man,
don't get grumpy.
You're the one who made
the deal with Heekin.
You're the one
who got him to fib.
He saw you
dump the body.
Wasn't it J. Edgar Hoover who said,
"Cheaters never prosper"?
Careful there, sir.
You killed
two other men, Keller,
and I'm gonna get
you for one of them.
Henry Stanton?
I'm Tobias Beecher.
Sister Peter Marie
suggested I come see you.
- You're doing pro bono work?
- Yeah, that's right.
Helping the prisoners
with legal shit and such.
I hurt my back doing sanitation
duty a few months ago.
Dr. Nathan told me not to do
anything too strenuous.
I told my C.O.'s
and they put me right back
to work again 'cause they think
I'm faking, but I'm not.
In fact, they give me
harder work.
I complain to my unit manager,
nothing changes.
And the other day
I screwed up my back again.
Well, off the top
of my head,
it appears the C.O.'s
violated your rights
under the Eighth Amendment...
deliberate indifference.
Let me talk to Dr. Nathan,
the officers involved,
and Warden Glynn.
Let me see what I can do.
Meanwhile, take it easy.
Back injuries suck.
Thanks a lot, man.
Stanton is not lying, Leo.
I gave him the proper medical
documentation three times.
Okay, the C.O.'s screwed up.
They will be reprimanded.
That's not good enough.
I've got a rock-solid case
here, Warden.
- If we go to court, I'll win.
- What do you want?
Full physical rehab for Stanton
at the prison's expense,
and a guarantee that he'll be
assigned light duty tasks.
- Okay.
- And those two C.O.'s fired.
- Beecher.
- Gone, today.
- The union will fight this.
- Let the union take the heat.
All right, they're fired.
I'm busy.
- You're good at this, Tobias.
- You ain't seen nothing yet.
So how are you adjusting
to life after death row?
I'm bored.
Bored of the everyday,
bored with shaving,
brushing my teeth,
taking a shit,
wiping my ass.
You know what?
I don't think
you're bored.
I think
you miss Tobias.
Well, he's turned
into a real firebrand.
No sooner does he get
my sentence overturned
than he's out taking on the case
of some other jamoke.
He's found a lot of joy
in helping others.
You might want to try
the same thing.
And how would I do that,
sister? I'm not a lawyer.
Well...
who besides Beecher
do you care about?
My ex-wives,
I guess.
Start there.
You know something, sister,
you just gave me a great idea.
Thanks.
- Socks.
- Yeah, I know how you are.
You wear them
until they fall off your feet.
Exactly.
So what's the latest
from the outside world?
Kids are great,
Harry...
actually hugged me
yesterday.
Sweet.
I'd like
to meet your kids.
- Yeah, right.
- I'm serious.
Yeah, okay.
Yeah, definitely.
You know, you know,
just not right away though.
Been drinking?
Not a drop.
Went to a cocktail party
the other night
and passed
with flying colors.
Good boy. And Holly's
teacher, how's she?
Why do you ask that?
I don't know,
you're the one who's
mentioned her a couple times.
You know, actually,
- to be honest, Chris...
- Yes!
Let's be honest.
Marian and I
have been dating.
You fuck her yet?
- Chris.
- Be honest.
Yes.
Good for you,
you sexy motherfucker.
You're pissed.
I'm not.
Be honest.
You want a slice
of truth?
- I killed Franklin Winthrop.
- What?
Bitch kills your dad,
bitch gotta die.
Are you trying to get
sent back to death row?
I covered my tracks.
- Shit.
- Toby, look,
I'm telling you this...
I'm not bragging.
I'm not trying to upset you.
I'm telling you this 'cause
I need you to do me a favor.
My ex-wife, Bonnie,
she's been diagnosed
with ovarian cancer.
She's dying, Toby.
And the only hope
that she's got is this drug,
it's called oxaliplatin.
And the problem is that
it's illegal in this country,
so I contacted
this guy I know who...
he just... he peddles
in these kind of illegal drugs.
All I need you to do
is just meet him,
take the oxaliplatin
to Bonnie.
- I can't.
- Why the fuck not?
I'd be violating
my parole.
Bullshit, I'm asking
you to take a small package
in your pocket
from point "A" to point "B."
I can't.
Bonnie is dying.
- Chris...
- I love you.
- Don't...
- I know that you love me.
I'm begging you,
please.
Toby, I'm begging you.
All right.
Give me the address.
I gotta go.
Toby, you'll see,
this is all for the best.
It's all
for the best, Toby.
Yes, is Detective Weber
there?
I got a tip for him.
The sale of illegal
pharmaceuticals.
A man stands in the cemetery
reading a letter he wrote,
finally forgiving
his long-dead father.
The mother of a girl
killed by a drunk driver
is wracked with fantasies
of retaliation.
Your boyfriend begs you
for one more chance.
You say to a mirror
you're done hating yourself.
But you know you're not.
Maybe instead
of forgive and forget,
it should be
forgive and remember.
Remember that you might
wake up tomorrow
and have to forgive
all over again
and again and again,
the way the heart keeps
beating like a drum.
Forgive.
I can't.
You can.
Forgive.
Forgive. I can't.
You can.
Forgive.
Same old story...
I got fucked in the ass.
Sit down.
Sit the fuck down.
All right, guys,
welcome to Oz.
Here's
the procedure.