''Fuck'' is a four-letter word.
''Rape'' is a four-letter word.
''Wife'' is a four-letter word.
So is ''love.''
''Fuck'' is a curse.
And l don't just mean
boys and girls.
l'm talking friends, l'm talking family.
Somebody wanna tell me what
the fuck happened to Dino Ortolani?
Well, he suffocated an AlDS patient,
Emilio Sanchez,
and l put him in the hole.
- l heard you had him sedated.
- You what?
Dr. Nathan put him on 4 milligrams
of lorazepam. He was violent.
Since when is it prison policy
to drug inmates?
What the fuck difference
does it make?
Your boys had already
beaten him senseless.
The question is,
who set him on fire?
Maybe the Latinos did it,
to get Dino for killing Sanchez.
Everybody had a reason
to hate Ortolani.
The Homies,
the Muslims, the Aryans.
- Everybody wanted to smoke him.
- Yeah, including you.
Me? Me personally?
You or some other officer.
Somebody let
whoever lit the match into the hole.
- Fuck you, McManus.
- Yeah, fuck me.
Hey, guys, the enemy's out there.
Lenny, l want you
to head up the investigation.
Question everyone.
Find out who killed Ortolani
before Nino Schibetta does,
before the governor sends
in the Feds.
Before we have a full-scale riot
on our hands.
Niggers did Ortolani.
You got any evidence to prove that?
Yeah, right,
like you guys ever need evidence.
You hear one of them
admit to killing him?
No, but think about it.
Who else is there?
- Latinos?
- No.
Burning isn't the spics' style.
Niggers burn things.
- You could've done Ortolani.
- Yeah, sure.
There's no valentines
between me and Dino.
But when l kill a man,
it's because he's standing in the way
of my constitutional rights.
l kill to protect what's mine.
What God has given me.
The Sicilians understand that.
The rest of these fucks
would cut a man for a pair of sneakers
or a fucking cigarette.
They are animals.
Get up. l said, break it up.
Break it up.
- Get the fuck out of here.
- Break it up!
- This is my--
- Get the fuck out of here.
You stupid or what?
Want some of this?
He hasn't come out in days?
Not for dinner,
not for lunch, not for a shower.
Beecher.
What's up? ls he sick?
- Get lost for a minute, okay?
- Sure.
Hope you feel better, buddy.
Your ass belongs to me.
So you've been keeping
pretty much to yourself lately.
Prison is a rough adjustment
for anyone, but a man like you--
- They burned Ortolani.
- Yeah.
He was tough, strong.
lf a guy like that isn't safe--
Beecher, l could tell you you're safe,
but that would be a lie.
You gotta be careful,
respectful.
You gotta try to focus on the day
you're getting released.
You're married, right? You got kids?
Your family been to visit you lately?
l haven't seen Genevieve since
sentencing. lt was about a month ago.
The kids, it's even longer.
Call your wife, ask her to come.
The first time alone,
let her get a sense of the place.
Make a romantic evening of it,
just the two of you.
Romantic? Here? How?
Go see Sister Pete.
Here we are.
Tobias Beecher.
Oh, good, you're married.
A lot of fellas in here try to bring
their girlfriends in as wives.
lt's no dice.
Once in a while, one of these guys,
who is married,
tries to pull off a fast one on me
and pass off a hooker as his mate.
They do that once.
They don't do it again.
You know, the whole point
of a conjugal is not just sex.
But it's, your wife comes in,
she brings food,
she can cook for you,
you talk to each other.
You're together again, you know?
Okay,
fill in this form
and l'll handle the rest.
Where you been, sweet pea?
To see Sister Peter Marie.
Went to the shrink?
What, about those nightmares
you been having?
- To arrange a visit with my wife.
- Oh, a conjugal.
You didn't ask my permission.
When are you gonna learn, prag?
You belong to me.
l make all your decisions, right?
So ask me.
Come over here and ask me
if you can fuck your wife.
- l--
- Come on, ask me. Now.
Can l be with my wife?
''Fuck my wife.''
- Fuck my wife.
- Louder, and say ''please'' and ''sir''.
Please, sir,
may l fuck my wife?
Louder.
Please, sir, may l fuck my wife?!
See, when you ask me like that,
l can't deny you anything.
l am here to see my--
Tobias Beecher.
- B-E-A--
- B-E-E-C-H-E-R.
Okay. Let me see the basket
and your purse.
They said that l could bring food.
Yeah. Step right through here,
please.
Are you transporting any drugs,
weapons, explosives, alcohol?
No.
Sign this.
Right here.
lf l was carrying explosives,
why would l say yes?
Lady, l don't know.
The state says l have to ask, l ask.
Purse goes in the locker.
When you're finished there,
go to room one right here.
Hi.
l've missed you so much.
Holly made a painting for you
but l left it in my purse.
The guard asked me
about explosives
and l completely forgot
about the painting.
lt's of our house.
Holly and Gary are standing out front
and l'm holding the baby.
She drew the dog
about twice as big as anybody else.
You're not in it.
You're not in the painting.
l thought l'd make spaghetti.
Please,
honey, just hold me.
Please.
Let's go! Move it, Beecher!
Lorenzo, move it.
Stay right there.
Let's go, Beecher, come on.
Double time.
Hello there.
- What's this?
- Fuck is this shit, man?
Hey, young lady.
- Me?
- No. You. Come with me.
We're gonna detain you
a couple of minutes.
Put your hands palms down
on the counter.
What's your name?
That's some goddamn nerve...
How was it?
Good.
''Good''?
You come from a night of wild sex
with the only woman you love
and you tell me it was good?
You got a lovely family.
l'm amazed you haven't shown me
these pictures before.
Amazed and a little hurt.
l hope you don't mind me finding these
hidden underneath your mattress.
Beautiful.
My wife is dead.
l got two sons.
Seventeen and 1 6.
Handsome fucking kids too.
Good Aryan stock, you know?
My sons are devoted to me.
l'm an icon to them because
l went to prison for my beliefs.
They would do anything
l ask them to.
Steal, maim,
kill.
Maybe l should have them
go visit your family, huh?
Just a little friendly call,
what do you think?
My sons and your wife.
My sons and your daughter.
Bitch, herm, Maytag, shim.
Here in Oz we call them ''prags. ''
l don't know where it comes from,
but you make a man your prag,
he's your prag for life.
lt's like the old days
when people didn't get divorced,
the only way out of
marriage is death.
Till death do us part.
Donald Groves.
You killed your parents
and ate them, right?
l only ate my mom.
l was saving my dad
for Thanksgiving.
That's festive.
So, what can you tell me
about Dino Ortolani's murder?
l got in trouble for sneaking
into the morgue.
What were you doing
in the morgue?
l was just looking.
- And they put you in the hole.
- Yeah.
And you were in the cell
next to Ortolani's when he got burned.
Yeah.
You hear anything?
No. Not a sound.
He didn't scream.
He gets set on fire
but he doesn't scream.
That's balls.
Anything else?
l saw them carry him out.
Looked like a roasted,
broiled chicken.
His flesh was all brown and crispy.
He looked good enough to eat.
- What's he saying?
- He's talking about how taxpayers
shouldn't have to foot the bill
for prisoner frills.
Thank you, Governor Cocksucker.
Therefore, l am introducing
to the legislature
a measure which would
save this state
an estimated $3 million a year.
This law would eliminate
all conjugal visits
between inmates and their wives.
- Get the fuck out of here.
- l'm gonna see McManus.
The son of a bitch.
This is bullshit, man.
Okay, guys, listen.
Hey, stop talking.
lf you don't stop talking fast,
l'm gonna hang up
my ''out to lunch'' sign, all right?
Get-- Get in line.
All right, now, thank you.
Pass this on to the fella
in back of you,
take the pencil
and start filling out the forms.
l have counted all the pencils
and l want them back.
So if you use any of them as a weapon
or if any one of them is missing,
none of you will get a visit.
ls that understood?
Am l making myself clear?
Because if not, l will repeat myself.
Yes.
That's right.
Freeze!
- Freeze!
- l got him.
Shit. Fuck.
- He's dead.
- You got it, man.
No! No!
- Don't--
- Jump.
Prisoner number 95H522,
Augustus Hill.
Convicted November 6th, '95.
Possession of illegal substances,
murder in the second degree.
Sentence: life imprisonment.
Up for parole in 20 years.
l don't believe this shit.
Word. Fiending to see my wife.
- Least you get to see yours, huh?
- What you mean?
Funky back.
What, you think because
l can't walk l can't fuck?
- So you can fuck?
- Yeah.
Wait. Are we talking getting hard
or licky-licky?
Nigga, we talking in and out,
up and down.
l never thought a nigga
could get hard in a wheelchair.
Yeah, well, it's easier
for some of us than others.
Some people gotta use a pump,
some niggas gotta use drugs,
get a needle stuck in their dick.
Yo, the worst one is implants.
They slice your dick open
and they lay in this kind of like
a steel rod to keep the shit stiff.
Oh, please.
Yeah, but l get hard
the old-fashioned way.
Only problem is l don't know it.
You don't know what?
l don't know when l'm hard.
You don't know when you're hard?
l got no sensation down there
so l don't know when l'm hard,
l don't know when l come.
My wife gotta tell me.
You don't know when you're hard?
You don't know if you've come?
You don't get
any pleasure at all, huh?
- What the fuck are you doing it for?
- For her.
You can take a lot of things
away from a man.
Cigarettes, the gym.
You can take his freedom, his legs,
but not his feelings.
Not his feelings.
That's it. There you go.
Pull, pull. Like that.
A man loves a woman.
No matter what kind of man he is,
if he loves her, he wants her.
He wants her body.
He wants her to want his.
So you say to him,
''You can never make love again.
You will never touch her
in that way again.
This is the last time.
The last time.
Forever. ''
lf that's not cruel
and unusual punishment...
...l don't know what is.
l'm investigating
the murder of Dino Ortolani.
Lucky me, right?
He used to supervise you
in the kitchen?
Yeah.
- You have any run-ins with him?
- No.
No? He's ordering you around
all day:
''Boy, do this. Boy, do that.''
lt never pissed you off?
He never called me ''boy''.
He put your little brother
Billie in the hospital.
He beat him nearly to death.
Ortolani was a scumfuck, man.
You married, Jefferson?
- What's that got to do with anything?
- Answer the question.
No, l ain't married.
You got a girl waiting for you
on the outside?
Yeah.
She know
you're a lying sack of shit?
lf l find out
you had anything to do with this,
l'm gonna bury you
so deep in Gen Pop,
she'll never see
your black ass again.
So, what do l say
when they call me in?
You say nothing, Johnny. Nothing.
Listen up.
l'll be running the kitchen
from now on, okay?
Everything's gonna be the same.
Until we find out who whacked Dino,
we ain't selling any contraband
to anyone for any reason. Okay?
l'll set that wop motherfucker
on fire next.
- Shut the fuck up.
- l ain't afraid of no fucking greaseball.
Shut the fuck up.
Jefferson.
Cops wanna see me about Ortolani.
What's up?
l'm having a visit with Mavis.
- What?
- My girl, Mavis.
l called her, told her
l been missing her.
She said she wants
to stand outside.
Holy fuck.
Told her l'd been missing her body.
Oh, shit. Jefferson, you the shit.
Prisoner number 97K1 86,
Jefferson Keane.
Convicted May 1 4th, '97.
Two counts murder
in the first degree.
Sentence: life imprisonment
without the possibility of parole.
l wanna get married.
To anyone in particular?
Yeah, my girl Mavis.
Mavis wants to marry you
in spite of the fact
that you're gonna be in here for life?
Yeah.
Sounds like a remarkable woman.
She is.
All right.
l'll make the arrangements.
- No, absolutely not.
- Why?
This is a prison, McManus,
not the Elvis Chapel.
Besides, we've got enough shit
going on right now as it is.
A wedding might help
ease some of the tension.
lt might also be perceived as a reward
for Jefferson Keane
who, as far as l can tell,
has done nothing to deserve a reward.
He's not a model prisoner, no,
but this could help turn him around.
The guy killed a couple
on their wedding day,
shot them both down in cold blood.
He says the two of them
ripped off his package.
- And that justifies it?
- No, it explains it.
You'd be okay with this if he'd waited
to kill them till after their honeymoon?
- Yeah.
- Leo--
Hey, l believe
in the sanctity of marriage.
lt's a holy ritual, a sacred bond
between a man, a woman and God.
Marriage is when a husband
and wife live together,
in the same house,
sleep in the same bed.
Jefferson Keane
and whatever her name is--
- Mavis.
- They can't do that.
The marriage would be a fraud,
l'm not gonna be a party to it.
Well, Keane lives in Em City.
lt's my decision.
That's true.
But the lobby
is under my jurisdiction
and you try and bring in
that bride-to-be through the front door.
They don't have a clue
what went down with Ortolani,
so just chill the fuck out.
But what about the Wiseguys?
They stopped everything.
No more drugs, no more bets,
no more contraband.
Ain't nothing moving in any direction
until Nino Schibetta gets satisfaction.
Jefferson.
- l spoke to the warden.
- Yeah?
l'm sorry. He's not gonna give you
permission to get married.
This is not to say
that he's not gonna change his mind,
but l think for now, we have to
put this thing on the backburner.
- We can't.
- Why?
Because l'm gonna lose her.
Well, if she loves you
as much as you say--
You promised me, McManus.
Now you're going back
on your fucking word.
A man who can't keep his word
ain't shit with me.
He ain't shit.
You know, l really appreciate
that you've come to me.
- lt's just that l love her so much.
- l'm sure you do.
But, you know,
your desire to marry her,
that can't come out of your ego.
lt can't come out of a jealousy,
it can't come out of a fear
that because you are in here
and you can't have her,
no man should.
lf you love her, you must be careful
that you do not deprive her
of the fullness of life.
No, man, l wouldn't do that to her.
Okay.
Now, you've told me
why you love Mavis, right?
Now you explain to me
how you know she loves you.
lt's the little things.
lt's like at my trial,
she was there every day.
l mean, just seeing her made
everything so much easier for me.
And her face,
l mean, her smile, it's like--
Hell, l ain't got the words like you.
That's why l want you
to plead my case for me.
l'll get you anything
you want up in here.
- You have nothing l need.
- So what's that, a no?
l believe that you love each other.
But you've gotta take that love, brother,
and you gotta trust in the will of Allah.
Yo, my girl is pregnant.
l screwed her,
now Allah's screwing me.
- Well?
- lt's about Keane.
There's a piece of information
l don't think you have.
l decided to let Jefferson Keane
get married.
- Because?
- Kareem Said came to see me.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
l come to you on Keane's behalf,
you blow me off
in a cloud of platitudes.
Now, Kareem Said says
God knows what to you,
the clouds have parted,
the sun is shining.
Do you realize how this damages
my credibility with the inmates?
So then what? l shouldn't let him get
married for the sake of your credibility?
- That's right.
- McManus,
how often does a guy like Said
come to see us to ask for a favour?
- Oh, l get it. So now he owes you.
- Yeah.
He's gonna help contain
the Ortolani situation,
he's gonna help
slow down the drugs.
Which means nothing.
Why didn't you tell me
that Jefferson Keane's girlfriend
was pregnant?
Because l didn't know.
He didn't tell me that.
So much for your credibility.
Man, this is some bullshit.
Jefferson, the warden
was very specific
about how this is going to work.
So what's this proxy shit?
While you'll be here,
and your fiancee
will be at your local Baptist church,
you'll both be exchanging vows
at the same time
and each of you will have
someone standing in
for the other person.
Come on, Father,
don't this seem fucked up to you?
Do you, Jefferson Keane,
take Mavis Woodson to be your wife?
l do.
Do you, Mavis Woodson, take
Jefferson Keane to be your husband?
Yes. Fuck off.
With the power vested in me,
l pronounce you husband and wife.
You not gonna kiss the bride?
Kiss my ass.
Congratulations, man.
For better, for worse.
Shit, it don't get much worse
than this.
Yo, man,
got a letter from Mavis.
lt's the will of Allah, brother.
What are you doing tonight?
Well, l was thinking maybe you'd
come over to my house for dinner.
So you sleep here
at the prison sometimes?
Believe me, l don't wanna.
l've been doing double shifts
and l live two hours away,
so by the time l get home
l gotta turn around and come back.
So move closer.
lf l could afford to,
l wouldn't do double shifts.
Appreciate it, Leo. l can't.
Too much work to do, right?
You can take a break
from saving the world.
Even Jesus had supper.
Yeah, and right afterwards
he was betrayed and crucified.
l'll try not to take that personally.
You got a daughter, if l remember.
How does she feel
about you being gone for days on end?
Please.
We live with my mother.
Between the two of them
l get the crap beat out of me
every time l walk through the door.
- Come on, get your coat.
- l can't. l have a date.
- A date?
- Yep. ls that so hard to believe?
Frankly, yes.
l got a dick like every other guy.
You need to find a job
closer to home.
What, l haven't looked?
There are no jobs.
You think if the Chevy plant was hiring
l would choose to come here
and babysit these pisspots?
l have no choice.
Just like these inmates. Trapped.
- McManus, get a wife.
- l had a wife.
From what l hear,
you had a nightmare.
You been checking up on me?
- Dinner, tomorrow.
- Yeah, you bet.
Have a nice date.
God made sunsets full of colour
and God made racehorses
that run in a flash.
God made the orange,
the apple and strawberries.
But God's greatest creation
is pussy.
l don't mean to be crude or nothing,
but you can have all the sunsets,
horses, and fruit there is,
just give me
all the pussy in the world.
Fuck, l don't need all the pussy.
Just one a day, every day.
Go! Go!
Miguel Alvarez.
l'm Father Ray Mukada.
l'm one of the prison chaplains.
No shit.
According to this file,
you're about to be a father.
You've got a girlfriend, Maritza,
she's an inmate at Parker Women's.
Yeah, we got arrested together.
Ain't that sweet?
l can arrange for you
to be there for the birth.
l don't give a shit about shit like that.
Miguel, you'll probably be paroled
in two years.
When you get out,
you'll wanna be a father to your kid.
ls that right?
Man, that's my father.
You know, and up in some cellblock
somewhere is my grandfather, man,
so don't be giving me
none of this shit.
l get it.
You had a miserable childhood.
Tough.
But let me tell you something.
You're still responsible
for bringing a new life into this world.
You are responsible.
The same way that l'm responsible
for you, for your soul.
So get ready, Miguel Alvarez, because
l'm gonna be over your shoulder.
Hey, Ray, you wanted to know,
l just signed the papers
transferring Miguel Alvarez to Em City.
Miguel Alvarez.
Another shining example
of how well the penal system works.
A guy walks in the front door
and he gets stabbed in the chest,
not to mention the fact that his father
and grandfather are both inmates here.
Yeah, l know.
You know, maybe l should
talk to them both about Miguel.
The kid's about to become a father
and he refuses to accept
responsibility for it.
Well, the granddad,
Ricardo Alvarez, is in solitary.
And having a conversation
with the father, Eduardo,
- it's gonna be tough.
- Why?
He's belligerent?
He has no tongue.
Senor Alvarez?
l'm Ray Mukada, l'm the--
l know who you are.
l'd like to speak with you
about your grandson, Miguel.
What about him?
He's an inmate here now.
l heard.
Well, then, maybe you also heard
that he's about to become a father.
His girlfriend, who he was arrested
with, is at Parker Women's.
- And?
- l'm trying to get Miguel
to accept the responsibility
for raising the child.
Maybe you can help me?
Because l'm his grandfather?
Padre,
l never even seen him.
You were a shitty father,
your son was a shitty father.
Don't you think it's time
we break the pattern?
l was 1 8 when l was convicted.
Eduardo was a baby.
Next time l saw him, he was 1 8
and wearing
the same prison uniform l was.
Then my son started
mouthing off everybody here,
making fun of people,
making threats.
And he started poking around
with a Haitian.
And one night-- One night,
while Eduardo was sleeping,
the Haitian cut his tongue out.
Yes, sir, l know. l read the report.
So you found the Haitian
and you cut his heart out.
Yeah.
So, what you're telling me
is that you were being a good father
to Eduardo
when you carved up the Haitian.
Well, if somebody hurts
your grandson
you won't be able to do anything
about it, will you?
At least not that way.
All l'm asking you is to talk to the boy,
not for you, not for him,
but for the baby
that's about to be born.
Your great-grandchild.
What the fuck?
Come here.
Who the fuck are you?
Come here!
Okay,
l'm here.
Now what?
You know who l am, don't you?
Yeah.
Sex is a mindfuck.
A wad of jizz hits an egg and...
you're connected to all these people.
These strangers, who maybe
got the same eyes as you
the same sort of nose.
Or maybe they passed you some cell
that makes you drink or do drugs,
even if you don't wanna.
Even if it's killing you.
These gene things are like
the shackles they put on us here,
the chains to keep us
from moving freely.
You gotta be Houdini
to get out of them.
You gotta be fucking Houdini.
Ortolani committed suicide.
Suicide?
How can he be tied down
with restraints and set himself on fire?
- That's impossible.
- Even so, he committed suicide.
- What makes you say that?
- God told me.
God told you?
God comes to visit me
every once in a while.
Actually, he comes more often
than l'd like, but he's God.
What can l say? That l'm busy,
that l'm in the shower? He knows.
We talking about
a burning bush here?
No. lt's more like a strobe.
A little too flashy,
a little cheesy for my taste.
And God told you
Ortolani committed suicide?
Well, that the kid wanted to die,
and consciously or un,
he set up the circumstances
where he'd be killed.
God happen to tell you who did it?
- No.
- l didn't think so.
But he told me to tell you to tell
Nino Schibetta not to seek revenge.
Why didn't you tell Schibetta?
Just because l talk to God
doesn't mean l'm crazy.
How's your mother?
Not good, Papa, not good at all.
Doctor says she ain't got long.
Who is this doctor?
This specialist. The best.
- ls he Jewish?
- l don't know.
His name's Dr. Bidner.
Dr. Russo recommended him.
Get a Jew.
Don't.
Okay.
What else?
Dino's funeral's tomorrow,
you know.
How are his parents taking it?
How do you think?
Paolo is philosophical
and Maria wants revenge.
- Yeah.
- Tell her she's got it.
Okay.
Come on, Nino. You know the drill.
--three females and one male.
Prisoner number 95S604,
Nino Schibetta.
Convicted December 1 2th, '95.
Two counts conspiracy
to commit murder.
Sentence: 1 20 years.
Up for parole in 70.
l'm gonna arrange for you
to visit your wife in the hospital.
That's very considerate of you.
But forgive me,
l'm cynical by nature.
Why are you being
so considerate to me?
lt's hard enough her being this ill
without you being able to--
Say goodbye?
What do you want from me?
Your continued patience.
You're gonna find out
who killed Dino?
- Yes.
- And you're gonna bring him to justice.
- Now you're laughing at me.
- As l said, l'm a cynical bastard.
- No one wants a riot.
- True.
l would like to see my wife.
Then we have a deal.
No.
Look, l know you're supposed
to be my sponsor and all that shit,
show me the ropes,
but l don't need any help. All right?
- O'Reily. That's lrish, right?
- Yeah, you got a problem with that?
- l run the Aryan Brotherhood.
- Yeah, you're doing a hell of a job.
When we heard somebody
was transferring in from the Gen Pop,
we all got kind of curious
because it doesn't happen that often.
Saw you being all palsy
with that hack.
Yeah, l'm much loved.
Yeah, you got friends.
You got another friend if you want.
See you.
Hey, by the way,
whose cell was this beforehand?
Dino Ortolani's.
Mr. Schibetta
requests your company.
Thank you for coming.
Sit.
Dino Ortolani's death
has upset me very deeply.
l am obviously hoping
to learn who killed him,
especially in such
a hideous fashion.
Does he gotta be in here?
Joey.
l know there was bad blood
between you and Dino.
- l didn't burn him.
- l'm not accusing.
l'm extending my hand.
Dino is dead.
Nothing can change that.
But if you could see a way
to help us find his murderer,
l would show you my appreciation,
my forgiveness
for your past indiscretions.
Honestly, l don't know
who offed Dino.
And with no disrespect,
l can't say l'm unhappy about it.
But your friendship
would mean a lot to me.
So if l hear anything,
l'll come to you first.
That's all l ask.
He knows.
Schibetta ain't gonna rest
till he knows who done it.
You wanna be around when
he finds out you were involved?
- We gotta give him Johnny Post.
- Fuck that.
We give him Post, it all goes away.
Maybe you micks work like that,
but l would never rat on a brother.
- What do you say we do, huh?
- Chill. Till it fades.
Sicilians don't forget.
Sicilians don't let things fade.
O'Reily's awfully chummy
with the melanzane.
- Could mean nothing.
- You wanna talk to Keane?
Not yet.
Get word to Burrano.
He should bring O'Reily in
for a little fishing trip.
- She's a hooker.
- You're full of shit.
She's a hooker.
l tell you, l been there.
You're shitting me about this.
The St. Pauli sector of Hamburg,
Germany is the red-light district.
So you tell me what a St. Pauli girl
does after she takes off her apron.
And l always thought
the little bitch was smiling just for me.
- You got a cigarette?
- Yeah.
Oh, man, you don't know,
this ban against smoking,
can you believe that shit?
So here's what we got
on Dino Ortolani's murder, Ryan.
Jefferson Keane and his crew did it.
Really?
Yeah. l don't know which one actually
lit the match yet, but makes sense.
l mean, Ortolani
put Keane's brother in lCU.
That kind of thing
don't go unpunished around here.
What has me fucked up is,
who arranged for the guy
who did the deed to get in the hole?
l mean, that would have to be
a pretty well-connected son of a bitch.
l mean, connected to two officers
on duty.
Well, the niggers could've just paid
a hack to let them in.
No. An inmate arranged it all.
- And now l know who that inmate is.
- You do?
Sure.
Same guy connected enough
to get moved from Gen Pop
into Emerald City.
Same guy Ortolani shot in the chest.
You.
Me? You're kidding me, right?
Eventually, l'm gonna get
the little fuck who killed Ortolani
and he's gonna start singing.
And the only name
that fucking nigger is gonna rap
is the skinny-ass white boy's.
My advice to you is to give him up now
or shut him up soon.
Thanks for stopping by.
Mr. Schibetta,
l know who killed Dino.
Can l help you?
Black 1 0 on the Jack.
- Thanks.
- l'm very sorry, Nino.
She's been sick, you know.
For the past year.
Cancer.
So it's not unexpected.
- Even so...
- ls there anything l can do?
l'm very grateful for your concern.
l'd just like to be alone
for a little while.
Sure.
Let me know if you need anything.
Sorry about Ange, Skipper.
Such a good woman.
Such a patient woman.
l'm not the easiest man to live with,
you know.
Yeah, l know.
l want Angie's funeral
to be magnificent.
l want a gold and bronze casket.
Red velvet interior.
At the wake, l want,
on both sides of her, calla lilies.
She held them on her wedding day.
And get that actor she likes
to be one of her pallbearers.
- Which actor?
- You know, he's a big movie star.
What's his name? He was
in that movie where the thing blew up.
Oh, yeah, l know who you mean.
Tall guy.
- Yeah. And Lena Horne.
- As a pallbearer?
Sing a hymn.
Tell the Cardinal
to go easy on the incense.
The smell makes-- Makes my--
Oh, Jesus. Angie.
l'm gonna ask you this once:
Who paid you to kill Dino Ortolani?
Fuck you. Fuck you.
Fuck you, fucking dago.
Before l did it,
l fucked him up the ass.
Kill him.
Start with his dick.
What the fuck you all gonna do, huh?
Fucking dagos.
Fuck you.
Sex and death.
They're different but the same.
To reach that final moment,
that climax,
you gotta give up control
of your body,
of your soul.
Another inmate at Oswald State
Penitentiary was murdered yesterday,
the second such incident
in as many weeks.
John Post,
a drug dealer serving life,
was found in a utility closet
at the prison mutilated,
his fingers missing
and several stab wounds to his heart.
Authorities are investigating
both murders
but still have no suspects.
ln a related story, state legislators
have overwhelmingly passed a bill
banning conjugal visits
between the inmates and their wives.
Governor James Devlin
has hailed the vote
as a victory for law-abiding citizens.
And love? Well, if sex is sweet
and death is bitter,
love is both.
Love will always and forever
break your heart.