Ask any towheaded schoolboy
how many senses we got,
and it's likely
they're gonna say five.
Five?
Are you kiddin' me?
What about my sense of balance,
entitlement, fair play?
Problem is five is about the most
our tiny little brains can handle.
But sometimes we have so many
senses cluttering us up,
so many ways to feel
about a thing, we blow a fuse.
And what's
that lead to?
Senseless violence.
Yeah, senseless violence...
it comes in all shapes
and colors.
For a second day, riots have rocked
the east side of the city,
ignited by Governor Devlin's
comment
that he would pardon
Mayor Wilson Loewen
if Loewen is convicted
for his role in the 1963 murder
of two small
African-American girls.
In response
to the rioting,
city schools
and offices are closed.
All state correctional facilities
are under tight security.
A verdict is expected
sometime this week.
Guard, guard!
No!
Your father was stabbed
with an ice-pick...
once in the back,
several times in the stomach.
Who? Who murdered
my dad?
We're investigating,
searching cells for evidence,
for the murder weapon.
Man, this is bullshit.
I-I want to go
to the funeral.
I'm sorry. We can't permit that.
We're in lockdown.
But, Warden,
my parole hearing is tomorrow
and there's
a fairly good chance
that I'm gonna
go free anyway.
Because of the riots
your hearing's been postponed.
Guess what we found.
But why would Clarence Seroy
kill my father?
I don't know Seroy.
It makes no sense.
This is Oz, Beecher,
nothing makes sense.
Maybe it's these riots.
There's a lot of
racial tension out there.
No, more likely
the Aryans hired Seroy
or planted the ice-pick
in his cell to throw Glynn off.
This is fucking
Schillinger's doing.
Killing Beecher's father,
man, what a rush.
It's better than
a case of Red Bull.
The fuckin' hacks haven't
a clue who did the deed.
Hey, Clarence!
How's it going?
Man, this is bullshit.
They'll never figure out
who really did it... -
Shut the fuck up!
The jury found Mayor
Wilson Loewen guilty
of murder in
the second degree.
Fuck!
I believe
that Mayor Loewen is innocent
and I believe that this trial
was a mockery of justice.
However, due to the volatility
of the situation,
I will not pardon him.
I won't pardon him, yet.
We'll let the smoke clear,
wait a few months,
then we'll
get him out.
Why send him here?
Put Loewen in a nice cushy
minimum security prison
like Hecht
or MacArthur.
That won't
placate the mob.
They want the mayor
to suffer.
The most important thing
is to keep him safe.
What's the safest place
in this charnel-house?
Unit "J"...primarily
we put bad cops there
so they don't face retaliation
by the rest of the community.
Who's in that
cell block now?
Alvin Yood,
Tobias Beecher.
Are either
of them black?
- No.
- Okay.
Well, hear this.
Wilson Loewen
is my friend.
If anything happens to him,
Leo... anything...
I will burn this building
to the ground.
- Mayor Loewen.
- Hello, Leo.
The last time I saw you was
at the big fundraiser in Morrisville,
back when you were running
for lieutenant governor.
We brought in a shitload
of cash that night, huh?
I was disappointed when
you dropped out of the race.
I always thought you had
the makings of a fine politician.
Look, whatever relationship
we may have had in the past,
that's over.
You're my prisoner now.
That simple, huh?
Or do you think I actually
killed those little girls?
You were found guilty.
Well, as a black man
you ought to know
that don't mean dick.
Take His Honor
to Unit "J."
Thank you, friend.
The streets are
once again calm,
though the damage to the east
side due to the rioting
is estimated at $13.7 million.
Lockdown is over!
About fuckin' time.
Phelan, where'd they
put Wilson Loewen?
Don't know.
Probably Unit "J."
"J"? Shit.
- Let me the fuck out!
- Shut up, Cutler! I'm coming.
Beecher's in "J."
He'll try to hurt the mayor
to get back at me.
I want you to put
the word out, Winthrop.
I want Beecher to know
he better not touch a hair
on the old man's head.
We were in the Oval Office
and the President says to me,
"Wilson,
if it weren't for you,
I wouldn't be sitting
in this chair."
And he gave me
these cufflinks. See?
Got the presidential
seal on them.
Mr. Mayor, you're
the only one I know
with a bigger
appetite than me.
Appetite...
yeah, for power.
I hear you're not gonna
resign from office.
You're forcing City Council
to vote you out?
Well, the honorable
James Michael Curley
served the good people of Boston
while he was incarcerated.
Hell, he even won re-election
while sitting in stir.
I could do the same thing.
The people love me.
- I might run for governor.
- Hell, why not run for God?
What the hell?
Oh, Jesus.
How are you doin',
can you talk?
Oh yeah,
I'm all right.
I just... choked on...
He gave him
the Heimlich maneuver.
He... he what?
Beecher saved
Loewen's life.
What does Schillinger
want with me?
I think it's better
if he tells you himself.
I don't want to hear
anymore of his lies.
You know, this is
probably just some trap
to fuck with
my parole hearing tomorrow.
I'll admit Schillinger
has conned me in the past,
same as you, but l...
this time it's different.
Beecher.
What do you want?
Wilson Loewen has always
been there for my family...
for me.
When my pop
couldn't find work,
he gave him a job
in the Parks Department.
When Martha and I
couldn't afford a honeymoon,
he gave us
airline tickets.
The man is my hero.
You saved his life.
I am now
indebted to you.
So I want you to know
that I won't do anything
to try and stop your parole.
If you can get out
of this fuckhole... go.
Bullshit.
Whatever you're selling,
Vern, I'm not buying.
- You grateful to me?
- It's true.
True?
I can give you a list
as big as my tattooed ass
of things you said were true.
- Do I have to stay here?
- No.
Beecher, if my backing off
wasn't what you were after,
why'd you save Loewen?
Because I saw
a man dying...
and my instinct was
to save his life,
my gut instinct.
After all these years in Oz,
I still have that instinct.
That's something you
don't know shit about.
Due to recent circumstances...
the death of your father,
your saving
a fellow inmate's life,
as well as your continued
outstanding behavior,
the board has decided
to grant you parole.
You're a free man,
Mr. Beecher.
The processing
takes a few days,
but for all intents
and purposes you are free.
- Thank you.
- Good luck.
Pinch me, Sister.
I'm dreaming again.
No, Tobias,
you are not dreaming.
- Oh oh oh, my goodness.
- Holy fucking Christ!
Oh my God!
Oh my God.
Lopresti, my lawyer was supposed
to be here an hour ago.
Can you call down
and find out what's going on?
- You haven't heard?
- Heard what?
I got good news
and I got bad news...
The bad news is
Beecher's father's dead.
No.
The day we went into lockdown,
murdered right down the hall.
I guess that puts
a kink in your appeal.
What's the good news?
Your girlfriend
got paroled.
That's right,
Beecher's going home,
and from what I hear,
he's in such a hurry to leave,
he won't even have time
to come say bye-bye.
You know
what they say?
When one of
your senses fails,
the other ones compensate
by getting stronger.
Like if you go blind,
your hearing
suddenly perks up.
Can't smell?
Your tastebuds bloom.
So what happens
if you lost them all,
if things no longer
make any sense?
You've got to rely on others
to get you through the day,
and in Oz
that could be dangerous.
Rise and shine,
you little fucks!
Get up!
I can't, I'm sick.
Bullshit.
If you think you're taking
a siesta in the hospital
just 'cause White did, you're in
for a rude awakening.
Now get the fuck up!
Jesus!
Claire, we got
a problem over here.
What the fuck
is this, Ebola?
Fuck you, Martinez.
Yeah yeah,
cha-cha-cha yourself, Carlos.
Fuck you, all right?
You better calm down,
Mr. Martinez,
or I will put you
in restraints.
What is he, the nurse's pet?
Glynn, Nathan won't
give me more painkillers.
So?
Call the A.M.A.
What's the emergency?
Penders, White and Martinez have
methylene chloride poisoning.
- Did someone poison them?
- Not someone, us.
- What?
- Oz itself.
Methylene chloride's
found in aerosols,
paint removers, metal cleaning
products, polyurethane...
basically everything
that was used to rebuild this place.
- Guess where the residue settled?
- In solitary.
Shit.
So what's the prognosis?
Well, when caught early, treatable
respiratory and gastric problems,
but these guys, it's all they've been
breathing in 24 hours a day.
Martinez's
liver is shot.
Penders and White
have lung damage,
and to say nothing of
the neurophysiological effects.
These guys are
gonna get crazy?
Or it may
make them sane.
But Martinez needs treatment
I can't provide.
I'd like to send him
to Benchley Memorial.
No.
Well, he'll get
better care.
For the moment
let's keep this close to home.
I don't think we need
to spread the word just yet
that Oz is toxic.
Well, then I want
to go on record.
You're a good doctor,
Gloria.
You saved Pancamo after
he caught a staph infection.
We didn't go public
with that, did we?
I have faith that you'll pull
these guys through too.
- Don't you knock?
- Sorry.
Didn't think you'd be doing
anything that needed knocking.
I'm here to transfer
Martinez back to solitary.
He's not going back
to solitary...
- That's what the paperwork says.
- I don't care.
Unless you get Glynn
to tell me different,
- Martinez is going.
- I'll be right back.
Excuse me.
So...
what ails you,
Martinez, huh?
You gonna die?
Oh, I love it
when you go all silent on me.
But I don't want
you to die,
at least not till you tell me
who paid you to cut my tendon.
And you will tell me,
Carlos,
'cause I have friends
in solitary.
When you get back there
they're gonna...
I have the warden on the phone
in my office, line three.
Buenas noches,
mi amigo.
Hey hey,
you two make
a really cute pair!
Jackhammer
Miss Sally style.
And side, and side,
and three.
Add more and do-si-do,
and four and five,
and side,
and two and three...
This is the best
Miss Sally ever.
And jump it out
and work those legs...
Officer Murphy,
I got an ask.
I'm in no mood
to be tender, Morales.
I want to shift jobs.
I've been working at mechanical
- since I got to Oz. I need a change.
- To where?
I'm thinking hospital.
I got a couple of pals
who are orderlies.
I thought maybe
I could do some good.
Some good for yourself,
you mean.
What do you think,
I'm an idiot?
Your pal Martinez
is in the ward
recuperating from something
he caught in solitary.
Carlos is in the hospital?
I didn't know that.
I made it a priority of mine
to keep you and Martinez
as far away from
each other as possible,
that is until Martinez admits
that you ordered him
to attack Dave Brass.
That old song
of yours again?
Yeah, when he does that,
you're doing down.
You're going down down down
to the lowest pit with no bottom.
Fine, I'll ask McManus
for the transfer.
- You go do that.
- I will.
- Yeah. Bye.
What if Martinez
jabbers on me?
He hasn't yet.
He never will.
Now and never is not
the same thing, Chico.
Being in solitary
can wear a man down,
and if Carlos is sick
the hacks are withholding
medicines until he turns.
What could we do?
Kill him.
Enrique, no,
he's one of us.
Yeah, but for how long?
Lights out!
A lot of times when
a woman gets pregnant,
her sense of smell
changes for the worse.
Suddenly roses
are putrid,
and freshly-baked bread,
Jeez, it's more like ammonia.
Epileptics got
something similar.
They can often tell when
they're about to do a backflip,
because they start to smell
things that aren't there,
so at least they got
a chance to sit down
before the seizure hits.
With pregnancy
and epilepsy,
you've got a pretty good
sense of impending doom.
Too bad we've got no sense
of how to avoid it.
I'm here to work,
Stella.
Hi, Robert.
Give me a hand?
I'll need you to take
the book cart around today.
- William Blake.
- That's right.
- It's the cover to...
- "Songs of Experience."
I never expected to find
a Blake fan in here.
I'm sorry, I have to ask:
Why are you here?
Why would you work in Oz
as opposed to some city library
where you wouldn't be
surprised to find a Blake fan?
Well... one day
about a year ago
I was home taking a shower
and I heard a noise.
I came out of
the bathroom,
and there was this kid
standing in the hallway
with my DVD player.
There I am, au naturel,
and though I consider
my body a beautiful sight,
the kid freaks
and jumps out the window.
He twists his ankle. A couple
of minutes later the police pick him up.
It seems he's robbed
other people as well.
So I go downtown to testify
at some pretrial thing,
and there's
the kid, Germaine...
so small, so sweet...
sitting next to his mother.
I think,
"He's going to jail."
Then I think, "Christ, he can have
my DVD player."
You could have
dropped the charges.
I did, but everyone else
held firm.
I went and visited Germaine
at juvenile detention
and I said to him,
"Why aren't you in school?"
- And you know what he told me?
- He couldn't read.
It broke my heart.
I went to Plymouth House
every week and taught him,
and he took to words
like a plant to rain.
His mind was so sharp,
so alive, so thirsty.
That's wonderful.
He got stabbed and died.
And even though
I knew there were
others like him
in Plymouth,
I couldn't go back.
I also knew I couldn't
stop what I'd started.
So... ta-da!
You came to a place filled
with old books and bad attitudes.
The truth is, Robert,
every book
on these shelves
is new to someone
who hasn't read it.
You know Blake,
he said,
"There is a moment in each day
that Satan cannot find."
That's right.
You know what
my ultimate goal is?
To make that moment
last a lifetime.
Hey, Rebadow, man,
I'll take a novel.
- Which one?
- I don't know.
A long one.
I'm out of toilet paper.
Hey, Agamemnon,
recommend something?
You got any pop-up books?
I love pop-up books.
- No.
- Then I'm not interested.
Reading confuses me.
Agamemnon.
I know what you're gonna ask.
The answer is no.
Come on.
This is the third straight
visiting day Norma's come.
Then tell her to stop.
I've got nothing to say to the woman
who left me at the altar
and then wham, boom,
shows up a couple of months later
carrying some other Joe's child.
Don't you even want to know
if she's doing okay?
- If the child is?
- Well, I'm assuming they are.
Fine, assume away.
Why, is there
something wrong?
Stop yanking
my chain, McManus.
- Is Norma all right?
- Ask her yourself.
So Norma was here
again today?
So we're both in prison?
- Excuse me?
- I'm sorry.
I thought we were
asking questions
that we already knew
the answers to.
I think you should see her.
I was talking
to Stella about it and...
What's Stella have
to do with anything?
She's a very
smart woman.
She reminded me
of a Blake passage:
"Some are born
to sweet delight,
Some are born
to endless night..."
Oh, I get it, I get it.
You're sweet, I'm endless.
No, that's not
my point at all.
What Blake is saying is
that every day you're born
and it's your choice.
See? This is why
I like pop-up books.
There's a condition
called synesthesia.
It makes you associate
letters with colors,
sounds with touch.
Imagine reading a book
and being constantly awash
in a cascade
of green and purple,
or hearing a guitar chord
and feeling it like your lover's lips
against your neck.
Why they call it a condition
I'll never know.
It sounds more
like a blessing,
and just goes to prove that
even the most basic reality
is totally different
for each of us.
Belial, bring back the spirits
of those who have gone before,
those dark
and troublesome souls
that spent the last hours
of their lives on death row.
Kirk, you scum fuck,
quit that shit!
Praise Hell.
Praise Satan.
Oh, Mukada, you gotta
get Kirk to stop.
He's driving me
fuckin' crazy.
Believe me,
that's why I'm here.
Somehow I knew
we'd meet again.
You wrote a letter
to the cardinal
claiming that
I sexually abused you.
You touched my penis.
You licked my ear.
That's a lie.
I have a meeting later this week
with the Archdiocese and the cops.
I'm gonna tell them
all the "sin-sational" details.
By lying,
you tarnish
the legitimate grievances
of the men and boys who have
been abused by the clergy,
and you do harm
to the many priests
who have lived celibate
and spiritual lives.
According to Nostradamus,
the Roman Church
is almost ready to fall.
I want you
to tell the truth.
Let me at him!
I'll squeeze the truth out of
his scrawny little neck.
Hoyt, you'd think by now you'd
realize that's not the answer.
He's gonna die anyway.
What's the difference how?
You asked me to perform
an exorcism
to free you from
the devil's hold.
I don't know
how to do that,
but I've contacted
an expert who's a priest...
Too late, Mukada,
as always... too late.
When I am executed,
you will be stripped
of your ministry,
you will be abandoned
by Holy Mother Church
and you will spend
the rest of your days
wandering aimlessly
and without hope.
In death...
I will be
triumphant.
A fashion layout?
Yes.
- With the prisoners on death row?
- Yes.
- In "Maxim" magazine?
And why do you think
this is such a good idea?
The governor's press secretary
believes a photo op
will give a positive spin
to the prison system.
It seems,
I don't know,
unethical.
Or for the boys on death row,
a last hurrah.
This thing is gonna
work like so...
Each of you clowns is gonna
be photographed individually
in various sets of clothes,
and then a group shot.
Questions?
- When's the magazine come out?
- January.
Oh, good, I'll be able
to see it.
- My execution isn't until April.
- Great.
Okay, good.
Let me see a little smile.
That's good.
Hey, ladies.
- Okay, big smile.
- Jericho can smile.
That's good.
I need to change the glass tube
in that lamp.
Okay, great.
Let's get this
over with.
Okay, we're ready
for the group shot.
Let me get you
right behind him.
Let's have you
in the back.
Let's get you
behind him also.
You and me, Jazbo,
captured on film for posterity.
Hey, great, guys.
That's good.
And look butch.
- Oh, fuck!
- Shit!
This time you die,
motherfucker!
I just got a call
from the Vicar-General.
Because Kirk is dead,
Monsignor Slon
has convinced the police
to drop the investigation
against me.
- You're back.
- Yes.
My prayers
have been answered.
Pete...
I prayed for Kirk to die.
I just finished reading
Augustus Hill's memoirs.
It's remarkable, isn't it?
You know, the way he describes
people and the way things work,
it's the best book about prison life
I've read in years.
I completely agree.
- Yeah, so what do we do with it?
- Well...
I've just taken
the liberty of sending
the pages along
to my publisher.
He wants to publish.
That's terrific.
Have you told Redding
about it?
I tried.
He didn't seem
to hear me.
Oh, fuck.
There he goes again,
going around in circles.
Hey yo, Burr, man,
you gonna be done soon?
We trying to ball.
Great, not only ain't
he focused on business,
he gone deaf too.
I'm telling you, man,
that old
motherfucker's done.
We need young blood
to run the tribe.
You, man.
I ain't no
number one, yo.
I already tried it on
and the shoe does not fit.
Then who?
Till we figure
that out, bro,
we're stuck with
old Burr here.
Oh, yes!
Yes...
In these tough times,
it's essential
for the state government
to work hand in hand
with business to create
new economic opportunities.
Today I am pleased
to announce
that privately-owned
enterprises
will be set up inside
our penitentiaries,
employing prisoners
full time
on a merit basis.
The first programs will be
set up in the Oswald
and Parker Women's
Correctional Facilities.
Oh, shit.
Said,
I've been thinking
about what you said,
how I'm a leader
who does not truly lead.
I've been dwelling on all the shit
that I done caused.
I got Augustus killed.
I got young boys
out there slinging tits.
Well, I can't
do it anymore,
and I won't let them
do it either.
I'm very happy
to hear that.
I got this idea,
but I need to talk
to McManus upstairs.
But Burr Redding, he ain't
got much credibility anymore.
So what do you want me to do,
go see him for you?
I want you
to be there with me.
Your presence is gonna
give me voice.
Okay. But what's
your idea?
Well, in order to get my boys
to stop selling them tits,
I gotta give them
an alternative.
We're gonna
get real jobs.
The young lady at the other end
of the table is Donna Degenhart.
She's the owner of this
new enterprise in Oz. Donna?
Thanks to all of you
in advance
for helping me
create my company.
- What exactly is your company?
- Telemarketing.
I'll hire inmates
to man phone banks
and control databases
for businesses on the outside.
Like who?
Long-distance providers,
public-opinion pollsters,
charities, airline reservations...
you name it.
You do this, what happens
to Kentwell Communications?
- I'm sorry?
- The telemarketing company.
Well, we're not putting
anyone out of business.
The market can bear
two companies.
And you know this through
your extensive experience?
I know this because
36 other states
have implemented
similar programs,
and the benefits inside far outweigh
any small complications
- that may arise outside.
- Oh... gee.
Seems I hear that every time
we kick-start something.
And how often does that
work out for us?
For Christ's sakes, do you got stock
in Kentwell communications?
No, a brother.
We want to get involved
in this new business that's coming in.
So fill out
an application.
Well, we was thinking
about something
- a little more proactive.
- Proactive?
What, you been
coaching him?
McManus, I know what you suspect me
of doing inside these walls,
and if you believe
your suspicions,
you gotta admit,
I run a business better than most.
- So you'd both serve as foremen?
- Exactly.
You know, see,
I really don't have the money
in my budget
for two positions.
Ms. Degenhart, that brings me
to a question that I have...
Your employees,
they make minimum wage?
No. No, not even close.
So they make
a pittance.
Well, I mean no disrespect,
Minister Said,
when I say it's honest people
who deserve an honest wage.
Besides, Said, this is more
than the $2.50 a week
you're currently making
in receiving a discharge.
That's like telling
a slave it's not all bad
'cause he gets to work with his family,
inside the master's house.
Come on, the woman just trying
to get the operation off the ground.
At whose expense?
Look, I have no intention
of exploiting anyone.
Sometimes that
just comes naturally.
Sadly, the thing about
business at its core,
it is always
just business.
I've decided.
The Muslims...
will not participate.
Excuse me.
Well, ain't but
one thing I got to say:
Fuck him. I'll work for nothing
until you hit your profit's bull's-eye.
- Well, my foreman.
- Yes.
"And life to me
is-is-is about living,
feelings and all
and trying not to fall
into them hard places
inside you
created by them
hard places around you.
It's a l-don't-
give-a-fuck song,
set to the tune of the bullshit
that bore you,
the place between dreams is-
is a situation signifying nothing.
So to me,
I'm just fixing my mind
to just enjoy the dream,
'cause everything else
when I ain't asleep is gray,
and life is about wherever
you gonna get to, getting got to."
Man, Augustus,
this poem is for you.
The meeting
didn't go well.
How can you tell?
- Your eyes are filled with rage.
- Hmph.
Arif, my heart is filled
with disappointment.
How come all good things have
to have a bad thing attached to them?
"If faith were easy,
everyone would believe."
- Those are your own words.
- Yeah, hmph.
There's gotta be
a way, Arif,
to do business
without cheating all the workers.
- Economics is not my strong suit.
- Yeah.
Where you going?
To think.
Just to think.
Man, I wish to Christ I could
figure out what Redding is up to.
Rumor is he's walking away
from the kitchen,
that he's gonna be foreman
of that telemarketing business.
That don't mean
he'll stop slinging.
And what we need
is some information.
Alvarez, join us.
You want me
to sit with you?
Yeah, I figure you
and Guerra made peace.
You won't be stabbing each other
with the silverware.
Besides,
I got a question.
Nine inches, baby.
- You friendly with any of the niggers?
- No.
- Poet a little bit, maybe.
- Yeah.
He knows you and us
have been at war.
I want you
to talk to him.
Find out what Redding's
real plans are.
Spy.
Well, yeah.
I ain't hungry
anymore.
Do this, Miguel.
We'll welcome you
back into El Norte.
You know, I'm...
I'm glad me and Chico aren't
at each other's throats anymore,
but that's as far
as it goes, man.
I got my parole
in three years.
Until that point,
I'm Mahatma Fucking Gandhi.
You want
the peach cobbler?
Miguelito...
you look great.
Yeah, and you look
really young.
What's up with the visit
after all this time?
Do I need more of a reason
than you're my son?
Didn't matter much
before, did it?
Maybe I haven't been here 'cause
you're always in solitary or the hole
or escaping and not even
coming to see me.
When would I have
a chance to visit, huh?
You just came here to make my life
more fucked up, right?
Thank you.
Be Mr. Macho Muchacho
all you want,
but if you're so tough,
think what that says about
the bitch that bore you.
You're a tough bitch.
Yeah.
You do bore me.
Okay, I'm glad
you came.
You know, when I escaped,
I didn't come to see you
because I thought that'd be
the first place the cops would look.
It was.
How's Maritza doing?
She's wonderful.
She fuckin' anybody?
She's working
as a travel agent
sending people to Europe,
Japan, Australia...
Ma, I asked you
a question.
I speak to her once,
maybe twice a month.
I don't think she is.
You tell her that
she gotta come visit me.
That would mean a lot more
coming from you.
I ain't gonna ask.
I ain't gonna beg.
She should
just show up.
Shit.
Hey, it's Maritza.
I'm not home,
so please leave a message.
Hey... Ritz.
Thinking about you
a lot lately.
Ma told me how good
you were doing, you know,
sending people all over
the world and stuff.
You know, I hope
you don't forget
that I'm still
part of yours,
because, baby,
you're still most of mine.
I know that I haven't
been the best...
you know...
of anything the last
couple of years,
but if, um...
you could use some
of that travel agent,
you know, magic
to arrange for a car
go to Oz,
damn...
I'd make
that trip worthwhile...
I promise.
All right.
I love you.
And I miss you,
Maritza.
Yeah, I really do.
Please come.
Yeah, please come.
Let's say a young man
mugs someone,
a young girl steals
20 purses from Sears,
a young mother
drowns her daughter.
The one thing they're all said
to lack is common sense.
Somewhere along the way
they lost their ability
to think correctly.
Well, look at Oz.
Common sense creates
the common criminal.
The desire to do right
is probably the most
uncommon sense of all.
Father. Father,
what's the matter?
- Help! Help!
- Bring in that crash cart!
- Father Meehan's dead.
- Oh, fuck.
Hey, O'Reily,
I heard your pal Father Meehan
crashed and burned.
That must be tearing
you up inside, huh?
- Yeah, he was a good man.
- Yeah.
Well, I guess now you got
a little taste of what it felt like
- when you murdered my father.
- We're done talking, bitch.
Oh, I was just wondering how you're gonna
feel when Cyril dies.
We're appealing
Cyril's case.
And your ma.
What?
Your ma.
You go anywhere
near my mother,
I'll fuckin'
skin you alive.
I don't have to touch her.
I got the evil eye, remember?
Yeah, whatever.
Okay, that's what
killed Meehan, you know?
My wife's grandmother put
the evil eye on the fat fuck,
he was dead within hours.
You know, Schibetta, you really
do belong in psych, man.
You're fuckin' nuts.
Meehan gave me
his rosary.
That's all you need... a possession
of the person you want cursed.
I gave the rosary
to my wife
to give to her nana...
arrivederci, Meehan.
I'm gonna put the curse
on every single person you love,
and when you can't stand
the grief one more second
I'm gonna
put it on you,
and I'll be smiling when you're
twisting in your own shit.
Hey, you fucking dago,
you motherfucker!
- Fuckin'...
- Easy, O'Reily.
It's okay, man,
that's just a momentary lapse.
- Yeah.
Okay, come on,
let's take 'em down.
Hey, Chucky.
You got a minute?
For you, O'Reily,
I got only 28 seconds,
but the way you double-talk,
it should be plenty.
Peter Schibetta.
Now he's walking around saying
he can put curses on people?
The evil eye, sure.
He says his wife's
grandmother's got the power.
Petey's got
two screws loose.
Oh, man, I feel a lot
better hearing that,
'cause not only did he say
that he put a curse on me,
he said he put
a curse on you.
Yeah, that's
what he said.
I think he still blames you for him taking it
up the ass... twice.
The fuckin'
little prick.
Maybe you should
go talk to Peter, huh?
- Yeah, maybe I should.
- Yeah.
When you say, "Screw your
courage to the sticking place,"
what you're saying is,
"Have some balls.
- Keep on track."
- Oh.
"But screw your courage
to the sticking place
- and we'll not fail."
- Good.
- Then I explain the murder plan.
- Right.
All right, that's it.
We start up again
tomorrow at 3:00.
All right, thank you very much.
We'll see you later.
Suzanne, I've got to tell you,
I'm having the best time.
I've got to go meet
my wife right now,
but I can't wait
to tell her all about you.
Thanks,
we'll see you later.
Hey, have you heard
from the lawyer
about the exact date
of Cyril's appeal?
Well, all Zelman said
was sometime this week.
- Damn.
- What's the matter?
I can't find
my car keys.
- What?
- I was sure I left them right here.
Oh, Christ, Mom.
I'll bet Schibetta stole them.
He's gonna put a curse on you.
I gotta go.
- Oh, Ryan.
- No, I gotta go.
- Slow down, O'Reily.
- I got an emergency.
- What emergency?
- I can't explain. Let me go.
- You ain't going anywhere.
- Fuck.
Yo yo yo,
Petey, baba.
Chucky, boys,
long time no see.
- Petey, where you going?
- Visit with my wife.
- We called and canceled it.
- Why?
- You and me have a little chat.
- About?
Life and death.
My life,
your death.
Chucky, no!
Warden, you better come
and see this.
Well, I can't say
I'm sorry Schibetta's dead.
What's that?
His eye.
Lockdown! Lockdown!
What the fuck
is going on, man?
O'Reily, catch.
There's that
little prick.
Robson, you shanked me
and I almost died.
- You're going to wish I had.
- Officer! Officer! Officer!
You fucking cunt!
Outta here,
let's go.
Holy shit.
Yeah.
- Vern, I need your help.
- Keep walking.
After all I've done for the Brotherhood,
you owe me.
Hey, you heard the man,
keep walking.
Watch your mouth, prag.
I'm not a prag anymore, pal,
and as for watching my mouth,
you're the one with
the nigger gums. Bye-bye.
You know what
true boredom is?
True boredom is when
you want to get yourself off
and you don't want to
at exactly the same time.
Listen, Cutler, the wops
have got it out for me.
I need
your protection.
In return, I'll steal,
I'll shank...
you name it. I need your clout
to keep my ass safe.
Well, if that's
what you want,
I'm afraid your ass
is the one thing
that's not gonna
be safe... prag.
- I'm no bitch.
- Then ciao, baby.
If you want to stay alive,
come get Poppa
out of his boredom.
I don't really have anyone else
to talk to in this place.
That's what
I'm here for.
You ever been
scared of dying?
Oh, yeah.
My first year here,
a man named
Warren Sticks,
we were in the middle
of a session
and suddenly he leapt
out of his chair
and started
to choke me.
I blacked out,
and when I came to
I was lying in
a pool of blood,
his blood.
He had slit his wrists
with the edge
of my tape dispenser.
I realized he was...
attempting to
knock me out
so he could kill himself.
You remember
that sensation,
thinking you were
gonna die?
Is that how
you feel now?
I've felt that way
every day
since as long
as I can remember.
How far back is that?
Much further
than I'd like.
I was Gerald Robson's
only child.
Even as a kid,
you do what you gotta do
to survive,
'cause when you're six,
running away is not an option.
- Did he beat you?
- Oh, yeah.
And worse.
Did he abuse you
sexually?
It's funny,
here I am 36 years old,
and I got nowhere to run.
You know?
And I-I guess what...
what I want to know is:
Is it okay to do
whatever is necessary...
to survive?
- Is what okay?
- Or should I die?
- No no, but...
- That's what I figured.
Thanks, Sister.
Sometimes
the worst thing,
- the worst possible fucking...
...fuckin' state of being
is having all your senses
workin' full tilt.
How can that be bad?
Well, there are
certain things we do...
when seen, touched, heard, smelled
and tasted all at the same time...
that'll make you wish
you were dead.
Lick this.
That's right,
lick it real good.
Now give it
back to me.
Drop your pants.
Now bend over.
What?
You and me,
we're gonna spoon.
Now bend
the fuck over.