Oz.
The name on the street
for the Oswald
Maximum Security Penitentiary.
Oz, where after months of tension,
a riot erupted.
Hey, this sucks, motherfucker.
The unit known as Emerald City
was overtaken by its prisoners.
The governor ordered
his troops to recapture it
by any means necessary.
When the smoke cleared, literally,
six prisoners and
two correctional officers were dead.
Thirty-four others were injured.
Some overcome by the gas.
Some from the beatings.
- Show us.
- Why don't you hold this bitch up?
Some from rifle wounds.
Among those shot,
Tim McManus,
who invented Emerald City
and some say,
ran it into the ground.
The rest of the prisoners
were moved to Gen Pop--
Somebody named people.
You're a motherfucker.
Meet your fucking--
- Asshole.
- l'm gonna kill you, motherfucker.
Fuck you. Let me at you.
Fucking bitch.
--except for the riot leaders,
who were drop-kicked into solitary.
By dawn peace descended on Oz.
Yeah, right.
Let me just say this about that.
l've already started to put together
a gubernatorial commission
to investigate
one, the causes of the riot,
two, the criminal activities
of those prisoners involved,
and three, the appropriateness
of the response to it by Warden Glynn.
Governor, who will the chair
the commission?
Well, l've just spoken to Alvah Case,
who's the dean of law school
at Kaufman-Ferber University.
He's agreed
to lead the investigation.
To my mind, there's no more
respected jurist in the state.
l can assure you his findings
will be fair and complete and impartial.
Fuck you, governor.
What, am l asking so much?
You want me
to come out on your side,
you wanna close down
Emerald City permanently,
you want me to say that the prisoners
are guilty of everything
and that you were totally justified
in bringing in the SORT team.
You want your hands clean
of the blood of those eight dead.
My hands are clean.
- My conscience is clear.
- Well, then, back off.
And let me do
what you appointed me to do.
Okay.
But keep one other thing in mind.
Marvin Suttle is stepping down
as state's attorney general.
l'm looking for just the right man
to replace him.
Come in, warden, we're done.
Find truth, Case,
because the truth shall set your fee.
Truth. What is the truth, Leo?
ls Devlin guilty?
Are you?
Leo,
depending on what l do find,
you could be the one who gets fired.
Yeah.
You may be doing me
one huge fucking favour.
How's it hanging, Vern?
C.C., hello?
Yo, something fucked.
Oh, great. More Em City prags.
You fucks have a hissy fit,
now the rest of us
gotta sleep on top of each other.
Hear me, boys, and hear me good.
This is my cell, this is my bunk.
- You got a problem with that?
- No.
Feel like a candy star--
Hey. Hey, l'm talking to you.
Hey, either of you hear what happened
to Dobbins or Vahue?
- No.
- Shut the fuck up.
Were they in the hospital?
l was only in the ER.
l couldn't see into the ward.
- Shut the fuck up.
- How do you like your--?
Beecher!
Shut the fuck up.
- Tits. l don't care.
- Beecher!
How do you like your--?
Shut the fuck up.
Fuck.
Chill, little brother.
Who the fuck you calling
little brother, man?
Get off me, man.
- Get off.
- Get him off me.
Let me go!
Ladies and gentlemen,
let us now pray.
Please stand.
Lord,
we pray for the souls
of our friends and colleagues,
Officers Edward Hunt
and Anthony Nowakowski
and we pray for the souls
of the six prisoners who died as well.
You got a little brain damage there,
don't you?
We pray for the recovery
of Officers Joseph Mineo
and Jason Armstrong,
and for Tim McManus.
And Lord,
we ask your blessing on this place.
We ask for understanding.
We ask for patience.
We ask for the strength to forgive.
We ask to be forgiven.
l said no negotiations.
l say we cut off Em City's water
and electricity,
then tonight when they're sitting
in the dark, we fire tear gas.
What about the hostages?
- Hopefully, SORT will reach them.
- Hopefully?
So that we might renew ourselves
in this important work that we do.
Amen.
- Amen.
Blame is a beautiful thing, baby.
Blame keeps this whole planet
spinning.
You can point your finger
at the next man,
you can shift the weight onto him,
you don't have to carry that shit
around yourself.
You can slide into bed
and get a good night's nap.
Yeah, right.
Mr. McManus?
Mr. McManus.
Alvah Case.
Yes.
Our grand inquisitor.
- This is not an inquisition, sir.
- Bullshit.
Devlin's been trying to dismantle
Em City since the beginning.
This is his chance.
Leo told me you'd be tough.
He says you two
aren't always in agreement,
but he admires your vision,
your ideals.
What is it you want, exactly?
l wanna ask some questions.
l have nothing to say.
The governor is busy picking
the other members of the commission.
ln the meantime,
l'm doing some preliminary interviews.
l have nothing to say.
Look,
ultimately, it's going to be up to me
to decide
if Em City ever reopens.
l have nothing to say.
Minister Said?
Alvah Case.
l'm here to interview you
about the riot.
ls that interview, or interrogate?
l guess that depends
on what you're guilty of.
There was no riot.
Oh, really?
There was a righteous struggle
against repression and injustice.
Well, righteous or not,
there are still eight bodies
rotting in the morgue.
l grieve their deaths.
Do you mind?
Please.
l understand
that from the minute you came to Oz,
you started organizing
other Muslims?
Converting stone-cold killers,
all the while sowing seeds
of discontent.
- l spoke the truth.
- Then speak it now.
Oh, come on, Said,
you talk a good game about the truth.
But how come it doesn't include taking
responsibility for what you've done?
l didn't fire those rifles.
Did you create a set of circumstances
that caused the rifles to be fired?
The judicial system
created those circumstances, not l.
Your commission is a fraud, Case.
Governor Devlin, the one man
whose actions should be investigated,
is the man that appointed you.
That's like me getting to pick the jury
at my own trial.
Want to lick my balls?
Judge Fee and Mr. Balling will focus
on events leading up to the riot.
Bishop Callahan and Mr. Dodge will
deal with the behaviour of the inmates
and the staff during the riot.
Mrs. Eiduson and Dudley Fried.
will concentrate on their decision
to send the SORT team.
Mr. Case, how long do you estimate
the investigation will take?
Days? Weeks?
Well, it will take as long as it takes.
- ls it true that--?
- Who were the leaders?
- And you're?
- Augustus Hill.
Hill, Hill, Hill...
Hey, can l ask you a question?
Two prisoners
got released on the riot,
Eugene Dobbins, Jackson Vahue.
- Shut the fuck up.
- Somebody help him.
Dobbins was hurt pretty bad.
You know what happened to them?
My questions first, Hill.
So tell me,
in as many words as necessary,
what you think led to the riot.
Those men are violent.
All they know is violence.
The COs, man,
they treat us like shit.
Sometimes the inmates get bored.
They took away conjugals.
They took away smoking.
No, it's more than that.
You deny a man his freedom,
his family, his privacy, his dignity,
then all he has left
is time to simmer.
And eventually,
the simmer becomes a boil.
Said! Said!
We'd been hearing whispers that
the Muslims were gonna start trouble.
The Aryans are paranoid.
What caused the riot?
Two brain-dead, crackhead
motherfuckers playing checkers.
And then all of a sudden,
the world imploded.
Fucking cops.
We treated the hostages good.
They treated us like shit.
We tried to negotiate.
Their demands were ridiculous.
And then the lights went out.
There was tear gas.
Guns.
Tim McManus got shot in the chest.
l saw the side of Rodrigo's head
get blown off.
Hunt and Nowakowski
were both hit in the back.
What about Scott Ross?
What about him?
Well, according to the autopsy,
he was shot three times,
once in the head, once in the heart
and once in the testicles.
- Yeah?
- Well, it's curious.
Bullets flying randomly,
every which way
and he gets shot three times
in three very precise places?
Yeah, that's right.
They say curiosity killed the cat.
What the fuck was the cat
so curious about that got him killed?
Solitary sucks, man.
But if you really want
some company,
you just gotta go
through withdrawal.
l love you.
Just what l love.
My prison in lockdown
crawling with outside investigators
and TV cameras.
What are you afraid we'll find?
lt's not what you find,
it's the way you find it.
All these questions,
they stir things up.
And God knows, everyone's
stirred up enough right now.
Leo, who was Scott Ross?
Ross?
He was a biker, drug dealer,
three-strikes lifer. Why?
Oh, l'm not sure yet,
but Ross may have been murdered.
- What?
- During the SORT team's attack,
he may have been killed.
Deliberately.
What makes you think that?
He was shot three times,
almost execution-style.
And the bullets in Ross' body
were 9 mm's,
not double-oughts,
which were in the SORT rifles.
The SORT team uses 9 mm's
in their handgun.
- Right.
- So SORT team member A,
he enters the common room
in Em City, lowers his rifle.
Ross comes at him
from out of the dark,
he raises his handgun, fires.
That's not murder.
You throw a bullet in someone's brain,
you pretty much figure he's done.
Maybe he shot him
in the heart first,
or the balls,
and Ross just kept coming.
Yeah, but the bullet from Ross' brain
was in the wall below
the command centre by a TV set.
And the one that went through his
heart was embedded in the floor.
So unless he died falling upwards...
lt's murder.
Come on, head up. Head up.
ln all that chaos,
what a perfect chance to off Ross
and get away with it, scot-free.
That's him over there.
Officer Heim.
The bullets that killed Ross
came from the same box
as the ones
that you put in your handgun.
So?
So your gun was used to kill Ross.
Yet you don't mention
firing at him in your report.
l didn't.
Then who did?
l don't know.
Did you hand your gun
to someone?
No.
Was it in your holster
when you entered Em City?
- Yes.
- And then?
lt disappeared.
Did you feel anyone take it?
No. Things were crazy in there,
you know? Happening pretty fast.
So you're telling me
that someone lifted the handgun
out of your holster
without you knowing.
That's right.
Well, how come you didn't mention
that little ditty in your report?
Because l found it on the floor.
Officer Heim,
do l look like
a stupid fucking idiot to you?
No, sir.
Then cut the shit.
You SORT guys love your weapons
more than pussy.
You'd die
before letting anyone take it
and you'd sure as Christ
know it was gone.
Who are you covering for, huh?
Scott Ross was a lowlife scum fuck,
just like all those other scum fucks
in there.
They hurt Armstrong and Mineo.
Because of them,
Hunt and Nowakowski died.
Are you seriously
going after some CO
because they whacked
a fucking pig like Ross?
Who the fuck's side are you on?
The law.
l'm on the law's side.
Now you can go.
Thank you.
l never lie.
Not because l'm so honest,
but because l have a bad memory.
And you can't be a good liar
if you got a bad memory.
Wangler, you okay?
l need some tits, help me.
Tits is the last thing you need, man.
Hey. Come on, wake up.
- Get up for a second.
- No.
- Come on, man.
- No, fuck you.
Suck my cock, man.
Come on, man, suck my cock.
- Come on, man. Suck my cock, prag.
- Fuck you.
- All right. All right.
- Get up. Let's go.
Come on.
- What the fuck, man. Let's go.
- Okay, okay.
Come on. Come on, bitch. Let's go.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
lt's all right. lt's okay, it's okay.
- You still on the job?
- Yeah.
So are you.
Well, we had
a couple incidents tonight.
Anything l should know about?
No.
What are you doing in here?
l'm trying to figure
this Ross thing through.
There were six hostages left
when the SORT team attacked.
McManus, Wittlesey, Mukada,
D'Agnasti, Hunt and Nowakowski.
Now, Hunt and Nowakowski died
during the first moments
of the assault.
And McManus was shot,
so there's less of a chance
that he killed Ross.
What makes you so sure
it was a CO? Why not a prisoner?
Ross wasn't exactly beloved
by his fellow inmates.
That was my first thought,
that someone used the opportunity
to take revenge on the guy.
But after talking with Officer Heim,
who, by the way, Leo,
is lying through his teeth,
l realized
he'd never cover for a con.
He's protecting one of his own.
D'Agnasti.
Or Wittlesey.
Or Mukada.
Alvah, stop.
Father Mukada wasn't involved.
You never know.
How did Ross treat everyone?
He was a condescending little prick.
Did he do any harm
to you personally, physically?
No.
What about Officers Wittlesey
or D'Agnasti?
l don't remember.
l'd been beaten pretty badly.
And l was...
...terrified.
Anything else you remember?
My nose itched.
But because our hands were tied
behind us, l couldn't scratch.
Stand in a straight line.
When they come in,
you get hit first.
Through it all,
through the tear gas
and the gunfire
and the fear
and the adrenaline in overdrive,
the only thing l could think of was:
Christ, would someone please
scratch my nose?
Tits! l need some tits, some diesel.
- Man, shut the fuck up!
- Hey, fat fuck.
Did you hear anything
about Dobbins and Vahue?
l'm asking you a ques--
D'Agnasti.
- l need some tits.
- No.
Thank you.
- You junkie fuck.
- Shit.
- Shut the fuck up.
- Kiss my ass.
- l'll kick the shit out of you.
- D'Agnasti.
D'Agnasti. D'Agnasti.
- Who that?
- Can l ask you a few more questions?
- l'm working here.
- l'll be brief.
All of the hostages
were bound, right?
- Hands behind your back with rope.
- Yeah.
When did you get free?
Sometime after
the shooting stopped.
Who tied you up?
Which prisoners in particular?
Scott Ross.
Settle down, Wangler.
You didn't like Ross.
- What was there to like?
- Tits.
Shut the fuck up.
- Pretty quiet.
- What?
Well, compared to your
last assignment at Emerald City,
this is pretty quiet.
Whoa, can l help you?
Yeah, l'm here to see my husband,
Billy Kempf.
l'm sorry, ma'am, we're in lockdown.
No, no, no.
Okay, l drove 31 2 miles.
Look. Look, it says l'm supposed
to see Billy Kempf today.
Well, we had a riot here.
Maybe you heard about it?
Fuck, yes, l heard about it. l also heard
the fucking thing was over.
- Yes, it is.
- Yeah, so then, you let me see Billy.
You won't be seeing him today.
- You don't get it. l drove 31 2 miles--
- Can l help you with anything else?
- Yes, you can open the fucking gate--
l don't have to stand
for this bullshit, okay?
Who the fuck do you think you are?
l drove 31 2--
This is bullshit!
- Wow.
- Stop fucking touching me like that.
Maybe it's not so quiet after all.
Now, Diane, what happened
from the point
the SORT team entered Em City?
- l told you this already.
- l know.
Dumb-ass me, l lost my notebook.
Well, the tear gas
made it hard to see.
Tim McManus and l,
we ducked behind a column.
We heard gunfire
for what seemed like forever
and then silence.
We thought it was over.
Tim leaned out and he got shot.
- He fell to the floor?
- Yes.
And you...?
l cradled him in my arms
until help arrived.
What kind of prisoner
was Scott Ross?
What kind?
Model? Trouble?
Average.
You and me, we're joined at the hip.
And ain't nothing
you can do about that.
Thank you. Thank you.
You ask most people
and they'll tell you lying is wrong
and then immediately go out
and lie like a motherfucker.
But that's cool.
We all know
lies are necessary.
- Yes, l was talking to them yesterday.
- What'd they say?
They say Tim will be out
of Benchley Memorial next week.
Oh, jeez. l feel terrible.
l've only been to see him once.
- Hey.
- Hi.
This guy Case,
has he been talking to you?
- Yeah, he interviewed me yesterday.
- Yeah, me too.
Did he ask about me?
Not in particular, no.
Okay.
Hey, Jackson.
You okay, man?
How's Dobbins?
He's dead, man. He died.
Fuck.
There you are.
- You've been looking for me?
- Everywhere.
Balling and l have been trying to meet
with you. What have you been doing?
- l've been working this murder angle.
- Oh, Christ.
Alvah, forget about that.
Really.
You don't wanna concern yourself
with things like that.
Believe me,
you're looking in the wrong direction.
Well, it's all part of the story, judge.
lt's all part of the story.
Well, we've sedated Adebisi
pretty heavily.
He should be out
for a couple hours.
Good. l could use a break anyway.
And how about you?
You ever take ten minutes?
- Sure.
- Good.
Can l buy you a cup of coffee?
- l don't think so.
- Why not?
You make me nervous.
Who, me?
Listen, l'm the sweetest guy
on the planet.
Ask my mother.
Yeah, well, if we went out
for coffee together,
l wouldn't be sure
if you were interrogating me or--
- Dr. Nathan, l swear,
- What?
l'm far less devious than you think.
l'm a college professor,
for Pete's sake.
- l give lectures, l grade papers.
- You train lawyers.
Yes.
Okay, l'll stop being adorable
and just ask my questions.
Mr. Robson, your glans,
the tip of your penis
has been severed.
How's your dick, man?
--dick bit off.
Severed. Severed. Severed.
How's it feel?
Weird.
Oh, shit.
Get the fuck away from me!
- Hey!
- Get off me!
Get the fuck off me. Get off me.
Get them off me.
- Another junkie asshole spiralling out.
- Get the fuck off me.
Hey, take it easy.
The public outcry
against Governor Devlin's decision
to use force
at Oswald remains high,
even as a gubernatorial commission
searches for answers.
Guys, help me out, here.
What the fuck is taking so long?
You want this done right or fast?
Both.
l want you to hold
another press conference,
give them an update.
l'm tired of saying,
''Be patient,''
and l'm tired of telling them
l have absolute faith in you,
because frankly, l don't.
We'd be moving a lot faster
if Alvah could just stay focused
on the big picture.
What do you mean?
He's trying to solve a murder
that for all we know isn't murder.
- lt's a murder.
- Well, if it is,
it is only a small part
of our overall mission.
l disagree. l think it's endemic
of the whole problem here at Oz.
You are so full of shit.
Well, you know, Benji,
given the last three decisions
you've handed down from the bench,
you're the expert on full of shit.
- What is that supposed to mean?
- Don't fuck with me.
Guys, guys. For God's sake.
- That's fine, forget it. l'll resign.
- No, l'll resign.
No one is resigning.
Last thing l need is the media to hear
the commission itself is fighting.
Now, everybody,
back to your corners.
- And back to work.
- Yeah, right.
The sooner we get this done,
the happier we'll all be.
Sweet dreams, motherfucker.
Dr. Nathan.
Doctor, you know, the last time
l had a woman tie me down like this,
l married her.
Well, if she kept you like that,
you might still be married.
l feel good.
You can let me go now.
No. Before that happens,
you, Sister Marie and l
need to spend a little time together.
All right.
Hey, doctor, my dick is hard.
ls that good?
You tell me.
What are you looking for?
Your impressions of Ross.
- You're a teacher, right?
- l used to be.
Now that l'm a dean, l spend less
and less time in the classroom.
You know how teachers get
favourite students sometimes?
- Get a real affection for them?
- Oh, yeah.
l couldn't wait
for Ross to leave the office.
Did he frighten you?
That, and he had
a terrible hygiene problem.
Did he ever mention
having a sexual relationship
with anyone on the staff?
As you'll see in the files,
he said a lot of things.
He was a compulsive liar.
- Do you ever counsel staff members?
- Sure.
Did anyone ever talk of Ross?
l mean, negatively?
- Sure.
- Who?
Everybody.
Can you be a little more specific?
Come on. You know a nun
doesn't reveal a confidence.
You're not a priest.
The silence of the confessional
doesn't apply here.
As a psychologist, it does.
Then we may have to let a court
determine that.
Well, that's fine.
l want those files back
when you're through with them.
Anything else?
No.
Ryan O'Reily.
Yo, yo, that's me, man.
Vehicular manslaughter,
reckless endangerment,
possession of controlled substances,
possession of a deadly weapon,
violation of parole.
That's an amazing list of crimes.
Yeah, well, you know,
l applied myself.
Still, l mean,
even with all those talents,
you must have had a hard time
adjusting to life in Oz.
No.
- l can take care of myself.
- Yeah, l can see that.
But how?
l'm like
the Lord of the fucking Dance.
- l got moves.
- Yeah, l bet you do.
Of all the guys that led the riot,
you were the only one
with no firepower behind you.
Yet the others included you
in all the decision-making.
l had nothing to do with the riot.
- Oh, l guess l was misinformed.
- l guess you were.
Like l heard, from what l thought
was a reliable source,
that you and Ross were close.
Close? No.
You and he were lovers.
Now, who the fuck told you that?
Ross poured his heart out
to Sister Peter Marie.
Hey, look, l'm no fag, pal.
But if l were, l wouldn't put my dick
anywhere near Ross' scumhole.
That cocksucker would fuck anything
on two or four legs.
Yeah, what about the COs?
Has Ross ever fucked one of them?
How about some help
getting me out of this place?
Sorry, you're not going anyplace
until the investigation is over.
Well, then, how about a cigarette?
This is good.
When l'm done puffing on this,
l can suck
on my own secondhand smoke.
So?
Ross had a thing for Wittlesey.
Yeah?
Yeah.
He claimed they knew each other
on the outside. Makes sense.
They were always sneaking off
and whispering to each other.
What's the matter?
This guy Case,
he gives me the creeps.
Why?
You got nothing to worry about.
He'll do his enquiry, he'll be gone.
- Yep.
- Right?
Yeah, l guess.
They also say if you repeat a lie
often enough,
it becomes the truth.
Or at least, you convince yourself
it's the fucking gospel.
You run the Aryan Brotherhood,
Mr. Schillinger?
l used to.
- You have a parole date coming up.
- Yeah.
Think you got a chance
at getting out?
l hope so.
My sons need me.
Well, l'd be happy to put a letter
of recommendation in your file.
- lf l help you out.
- That's right.
Scott Ross.
Poor son of a bitch.
So you were friends?
Did he ever mention having any kind
of a sexual relationship
with Officer Wittlesey?
Sure. Ross and Wittlesey's ex
were in the same bike club.
Ross said...
...he nailed her
behind her hubby's back.
But then again, Ross was sometimes
a lying sack of shit.
So who knows if it's true?
Did anything go on
between the two of them
since he came to Oz?
According to Ross,
he was banging her pretty regular.
You think
he was lying about that?
Probably.
Thank you for getting me permission
to come to the library.
Lockdowns can be boring
with nothing to read.
Oh, no problem.
They tell me you know everything
that goes on in Oz.
They exaggerate.
Do you have any idea,
if anything, what transpired
between Officer Wittlesey
and Scott Ross?
- Cigarettes.
- l beg your pardon?
Cigarettes was what was going on
between them.
Wittlesey smuggled them in,
a carton a day.
She gave them to Ross to sell.
Everything was going smoothly
till McManus found out.
He made Wittlesey
shut down the operation.
So Ross hated McManus for that.
And because Wittlesey and McManus
started sleeping together.
Hey, got a cigarette?
You know, why would you?
Ross is dead.
lt's funny, you know,
what a guy can see with one eye.
ln the dark, through the tear gas.
Don't worry.
l didn't tell that nigger Case
a fucking thing.
So, what do you want from me?
Well, l got a parole hearing
coming up.
l think maybe the best thing for you
would be for me to be out of here.
So you think Wittlesey killed Ross?
She had motive, opportunity.
l've known Diane for years.
Don't walk in here
and talk about motive and opportunity.
Give me some evidence.
Well, in the heat of the riot,
maybe she just lost it.
No. No, it had to be a more
specific reason than that.
Ross had to have done something
at that moment
to get her to pull that trigger.
Hello?
Yeah, okay. Okay.
Officer down in ad seg
says a prisoner wants to talk to you.
Which one?
Tobias Beecher.
Hey, chief.
You asked to see me?
l got a secret.
About?
Scott Ross.
Tell me.
lf l tell you, it won't be a secret.
Would you excuse us, please?
Okay?
l bit the tip off a guy's penis.
So l heard.
You're not afraid?
Well, l've got my pants on.
l used to be a lawyer,
you know that?
Went to Harvard.
So did l.
Crimson.
l've been under a lot of stress lately.
l haven't been behaving very nicely.
Like this biting thing.
But l'm using my time in here
to turn my head around.
When l get out of here,
l'm gonna be a better person.
Because, like, this whole biting thing
just isn't working for me, you know?
So as a sign
that l'm on the straight and narrow,
l'm gonna tell you my little secret.
And then,
l'll be on the road back, right?
Yeah, yeah.
l saw the shots fired.
Which shots?
Check the bullets.
The bullets that killed Ross?
No.
Check the bullets in McManus.
Hey.
McManus wasn't shot
with a 9 mm
from a SORT team handgun.
The striations show
he was hit with a 9 mm,
probably from a Glock
or a Sig Sauer.
Sig Sauer?
Well, we know there was a Sig Sauer
in Em City during the riot.
Whose was it?
Kareem Said.
You shot Tim McManus.
- No.
- Well, if you didn't, who did?
l don't know.
You had a Sig Sauer
in your possession.
Now, if l say yes,
that's another nail in my coffin.
- l look like a fool to you?
- Are you comfortable here, Said?
Because you know it's up to me
when and if you get out
of solitary confinement.
Now, l know how important it is for you
to be among your people,
leading, guiding, nurturing them.
That's gonna be hard to do
through 8 tons of steel.
You're an academic, right?
You know about hypotheses
and theories, right?
Well, theoretically speaking,
if l had a gun
when the SORT team entered,
here's what might have happened.
l might have been
underneath the control panel
at the command station
holding that gun
when a SORT team member came in
and started to beat me.
And in not wanting to kill anybody,
l might have thrown that gun
over the side.
Where someone else picked it up?
Theoretically speaking, yes.
l know you got nothing to say to me,
but l have a couple of things
to say to you.
First, you've got balls.
You voluntarily went into Em City
to negotiate the release
of the injured officers
and Diane Wittlesey.
You traded yourself
for Armstrong and Mineo,
putting yourself into what can only be
called a jackpot situation.
Especially knowing that you'd fall
into the hands of Scott Ross,
a man you despised.
How ironic is it then,
that he was the one who shot you?
- Any last words?
- Suck my dick.
Who told you?
That Ross was the one
who shot you?
- Yeah.
- You just did.
You know,
Oz is just like anyplace else.
Everybody loves to gossip
about everybody else.
- Not me.
- Oh, but they gossip about you.
Well, maybe it's because
you're one of the few women around.
Maybe it's because
there's truth to the rumours.
Like, for example,
that you were smuggling cigarettes in
that Ross could sell.
And that you and McManus
had an affair.
Are you accusing me of something?
Yes.
Yes, l am.
You killed Scott Ross.
Me? How did l do that?
Ross picked up Said's gun.
He fired into McManus' chest.
You took Officer Heim's pistol
and shot Ross.
That's not possible.
My hands were tied behind my back.
No they weren't.
You managed to loose the binds
before it all came down.
You told me that after McManus fell
to the ground,
you, quote, ''l cradled him in my arms,''
end quote.
How could you cradle him
with your arms behind your back?
- Have you ever been in a riot?
- No.
You have to understand
what's involved.
The idea of being a hostage,
the mob mentality.
You get carried away.
You stop being human.
You become part of something else.
l have made every mistake there is.
l've fallen in love
with the wrong men,
l had a baby out of wedlock.
l drank too much,
l snorted too much.
l have done things to make money,
including this job,
which make me dread
getting out of bed.
But each time, l made the choice.
l chose to drink, l chose to stop.
When my husband got abusive,
l chose to walk.
l refuse to be anybody's victim.
These mistakes l've have made,
they are a part of me.
They are like my skin.
And l do not regret what l've done.
Do you hear me?
No regrets, no remorse.
l just keep going.
- What are you gonna do?
- When l know, you'll know.
She has a young daughter,
a mother in and out of chemo.
So what, Leo? So what?
So if you expose the truth,
you destroy this woman's life
and her daughter's.
And for what? Scott fucking Ross?
Come on, Alvah, please.
What do you want me to say, Leo?
Just say that Ross died
like the others,
from bullets fired by a member
of the SORT team
in the performance of his duty.
l just read the preliminary draught
of your report.
- Yeah, what's wrong?
- You recommend not filing charges
against Said
and the other riot leaders?
From a legal standpoint,
the evidence is circumstantial.
From a moral standpoint,
it's laughable.
l want those bastards on trial,
on TV.
Look, governor, as far as l can see,
whatever they did came about
as a direct result of your actions.
You've exonerated me.
Oh, yeah, your commission behaved
like good little boys,
but you can't have it both ways.
lf the prisoners are guilty,
so are you.
This is not the kind of attitude l expect
from an attorney general.
Yeah, well,
l've thought about it.
l don't wanna be attorney general.
l wanna be governor.
What?
l'll see you on the campaign trail,
Devlin.
Now, l've got
a press conference to do.
lt is the considered opinion
of this commission
that though the riot itself
and the deaths
that followed are tragic,
no one in particular is at fault.
lf no one is at fault,
who's responsible for the--?
We do feel
that there are certain measures
that can be taken to ensure
that an event like this
does not happen again.
Bitch.
So as it turns out,
no one was to blame for the riot.
ln fact, if no one was to blame,
that means nothing bad happened.
Nothing at all happened.
So life can pretty much go on
as it has before.
Yeah, right.