Sigmund Freud said
that the purpose of our dreams
is to satisfy certain
instinctual urges
that society deems
unacceptable.
For instance, instead of killing
an oppressive father,
which would be
too horrible to handle,
we dream of throwing
our boss out the window.
Freud believed that the mind
will often modify
our dreams in order
to keep strong emotions at bay.
And with less emotion,
a man can get up,
go to work
and be a good citizen.
The difference for us in Oz is,
we don't dream
of throwing our boss out the window,
we actually do it.
So, Alvarez,
who's responsible?
- I wish I knew.
- You didn't see who stabbed you?
No. Everything happened
so fast, you know.
Then I guess my
investigation's over.
Yeah, that's really
breaking you up, ain't it?
There.
I'm no doctor, but...
I've seen a lot
of stab wounds in my time.
If that knife had gone in
another quarter of an inch to the left,
we wouldn't be having
this conversation.
Quarter of an inch?
No shit.
Guess you
were lucky, huh?
You wanna send me
back to solitary?
No, no, no.
I mean, there's no one
I'd rather see rot
in solitary than you,
but I figure
I'll send you
back to Em City.
Maybe next time
you're not so lucky.
Hmm.
Oh-ho.
- We gotta talk.
- Oh, you want me to shank you again?
Okay.
- Can I sit down?
- Blow me.
Get up.
Have a seat.
So?
You tried to kill me.
No, I didn't. You're alive,
ain't you? That was our deal.
You were supposed to stab me
in the shoulder.
Blade went in a quarter
of an inch from the heart.
Must've fucking moved, chocha.
What can I say?
Ain't gotta say nothing.
I just want you to know
that I know the truth, man.
I'm gonna honor
our agreement.
I didn't die.
I ain't gonna retaliate.
Backing off,
wise move, Miguel.
Listen to me carefully.
I'm never gonna
welcome you back into El Norte,
but what I will do
is guarantee
- that we'll leave you be.
- What the fuck are you talking about?
All scores are settled.
Excuse me.
I want you
to shank me.
I don't know how you
came up with the idea,
but it fucking rocks,
and I see what it's done for you.
And mostly I see
how Morales is.
Him talking to you
before like
he's taking the high road,
being powerful and generous,
but behind his eyes,
he's running scared.
I want to follow you.
- You want to follow me?
- Join your gang.
You're the next wave,
and I want to be your lieutenant.
Shank me.
I ain't gonna
shank you, man.
But I understand, you think you gotta
prove yourself and shit, right?
Yes.
I'm gonna have you do
something else for me.
Anything.
Kill Guerra.
Step over here,
Morales.
Okay.
You know who I am?
Dave Brass,
the basketballer.
You played with McManus
against Vahue in those games.
You're pretty good
for a white boy.
Who cut my Achilles tendon?
I don't know.
Look, I don't care
whose idea it was.
All I want is the guy
who actually did the deed.
I wish I could
help you out.
You lying piece of shit.
You're gonna regret
that you didn't.
You know...
you had the sweetest
crossover dribble I've ever seen.
Juking right, then planting
that foot, then going left.
I don't know how many times
you dressed down Vahue with that move.
But you know
what they say...
you take away
a basketball guard's first step,
and all you got is a C.O.
With a broken wheel.
- What you doing?
- I've started a letter writing campaign
to protest the possible cancellation
of "Miss Sally's Schoolyard."
This one's signed
by Stanton.
- Yeah, he's a good guy, that Stanton.
- Stanton's in solitary.
All right,
so I fudged a few.
Wangler, Adebisi...
- Groves. Groves?
- Okay, I fudged them all.
None of those yerds out there
would rally for the cause.
- You want to write one?
- No offense,
but the only thing
I want renewed
is my grandson's chance
to beat his leukemia.
Right. Sorry. What's the latest
on his condition?
You gotta pay to play.
There's a cure to be found,
but it'll cost,
and I still haven't
figured out a way
to raise the money.
Next is Whitney Allen,
star of "Miss Sally's Schoolyard,"
to tell us about next week's
Mightyball drawing. Whitney.
- Hi, Warren. How are you?
- Very well. Thanks for dropping by...
Who are all these numbnuts
that play the lottery?
- I've played the lottery.
- Me too.
Like I said, numbnuts. Out of 51,
you gotta pick the right number,
not once,
but six times in a row.
- I say it is possible to win.
- Jesus Christ,
you'd have a better chance
of getting struck by lightning.
Approximately
1,000 people a year
win $1 million or more
in North American lotteries.
In contrast, less than 100 people
a year are hit by lightning.
...$2 million,
so don't forget to play,
because the winner
might just be you.
- Excuse me, Officer Brass.
- Yeah?
Bob Rebadow.
You've always seemed
like a sympathetic fellow to me.
What do you want?
I want you to purchase
a lottery ticket for me.
The jackpot is $2 million.
I'll cut you in.
- Cut me in on what?
- The prize money.
What in the world makes you
think you're gonna win?
God told me.
These are
the winning numbers.
Hey, Dave,
how you doing?
What's the deal with this guy,
Bob Rebadow?
Ahh, nothing.
Why, is he giving you trouble?
No. I just thought
the guy might be psychotic.
At dinner he starts telling me
God speaks to him.
Oh, yeah. He's had
an ongoing tête-a-tête
with the Almighty
for some time now.
Actually
he's relatively stable.
First time I've touched
one of these since...
my Achilles got cut.
It's a perfect fucking ball,
man... gummy, beat up.
Give you mad handle. This ball
will make you Pete Maravich.
Oh, Jesus,
Pistol Pete.
Greatest scorer in the history
of college ball.
When he was growing up,
he used to carry a ball
with him at all times,
no matter what.
In school, on a date,
didn't matter.
He'd even go to bed
with a basketball, like a marriage.
So I started doing it.
I quit sleeping with it
when I got to college,
but other than that...
- Come on. You want to shoot, shoot.
- It's all right.
- I can stick around for a while.
- I gotta go.
Got to make an extra stop on my
way home. I gotta buy a lottery ticket.
Well, another night then.
We'll stay late,
we'll shoot around.
You know how
Pete Maravich died?
Playing basketball.
Had been retired
eight years.
Was out running in a pickup game,
heart attack,
up and down the court one minute,
falling over dead the next.
Till death do us part.
He's able to live that, literally.
But I won't be able to.
So stop
fucking asking me
to shoot around
with you, all right?
Hey!
First of all, let me say
I'm glad you're fully recovered.
Secondly, I understand
you want to return to Emerald City.
And you can understand that
that's a tough call for me.
Before you got... hurt,
you continuously threatened the lives
of Morales and the other Latinos,
and plus,
Cyril O'Reily's in there.
Mr. McManus,
getting hit by Cyril O'Reily
may have been the single
greatest event in my life.
There I was
on the brink of death,
and suddenly I could see
all that I had done.
And more importantly,
if I survived,
all that I could do.
Have you ever had
an experience like that?
Well, yes, I have.
Whether or not you
bring me back to Em City
is ultimately
irrelevant,
and yet
I'm drawn there.
Why? I don't know.
All right,
let's give it a shot.
But I want you to have interaction
sessions with Peter Marie.
I'm sorry I hurt you.
Why did you
hit Kenmin, Cyril?
He was punching Ryan.
Why were you
punching Ryan?
I'd been in the cage all day.
I was feeling feisty.
- I decided to show off. It was stupid.
- Yeah.
- Ryan.
- What?
His bullshit almost got Cyril transferred to
the insane asylum.
The rules are no interrupting
and no swearing.
I take full blame for everything
that's happened to me.
Which is why
I want to make peace.
Uh, uh, uh,
sit the fuck down.
No. I want
to make peace too.
Go ahead.
Oh fuck.
Prisoner #02L333:
Li Chen:
Convicted
January 14th, 2002:
Four counts
of attempted murder:
Sentence: 32 years:
Up for parole in 20.
Okay.
- Stop laughing, Ryan.
- Ryan, behave.
I know, okay, okay, I'm sorry,
but Cyril's singing really sucks.
Now I have told you that this program
is not about becoming Pavarotti.
It's about learning how to express
your feelings through the music.
- You did very good, Cyril.
- Thank you.
- That's more like Pava-rotten.
- All right, you try.
Huh-uh, no, no.
The deal was I sign up for this class
to spend more time with you.
That's it. I'm not singing.
So this session is over,
but next Friday, Ryan,
I want to hear you sing.
Okay, Mom, but you know what?
I'll do you one better.
Suzanne, your next
two students are here.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
what's this?
I heard your mother
was teaching,
so I decided
to give it a whirl.
- Jia Kenmin.
- Suzanne Fitzgerald.
- Li Chen.
- Welcome, both of you.
- Let's go, O'Reily.
- Yeah, yeah, in a second, Brass.
- Now, fuckwad.
- Get your hands off...
Bye, guys.
So, have you had
any experience...
- What's the matter, Ryan?
- I got a bad feeling, man.
- About what?
- About that piss stain, Jia Kenmin.
I know he's perpetrating, I know
he's plotting something against us.
And l... I think he might
want to hurt my ma.
- I like her.
- Yeah, well, she likes you too, Cyril.
You want to trade?
Trade? Trade what?
I'll give you my most prized
possession if you give me her.
We don't have to trade.
We can share her. You know that.
- Really?
- Yeah. Hey,
don't I share
everything with you?
Hey, Jia.
Your mother's
a wonderful person.
- Let's see that she stays that way.
- Meaning what?
You fuck with her, you go back
into a coma. This time it's permanent.
Look, you have nothing
to fear from me.
But Li Chen,
he's a different matter.
He's one sick fuck.
You're dreaming,
you're deep into REM sleep
and someone walks in,
someone who's dead,
someone you love,
a father, a mother, a friend,
and you're happy to see
that person alive and well,
happy to have a conversation to say
things you never got a chance to say.
But then you wake up
and the person you loved
is still dead
and you get to mourn
all over again.
About fucking time.
What happened
to the pool table?
Hey. It's in dry-dock
for repairs.
Spread the word, I want
a meeting of the entire brotherhood.
We got some unfinished business
with Chucky Pancamo.
Hey, Petey.
What's shaking, man?
Schillinger's
out of Ad Seg.
So when they letting you
out of here?
I don't know.
Dr. Nathan won't say.
- Things cool with Morales?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Drugs running the same as always.
- The kitchen?
Good.
It's under control.
Hey, Petey, don't get used
to running things.
- I'm still fucking breathing.
- Yeah, I know. I know.
But we gotta waste Schillinger
for what he did to you, you know.
We'll take care of that Nazi fuck
when I'm back in circulation,
- Capisce?
- Yep, capisce.
I got news.
Schillinger's
out of the hole.
Good.
Now we can sit back
and watch the Nazis
wipe out the Sicilians.
Yeah, but that ain't gonna do
nothing about them spics.
You know they
as strong as ever,
and you know Morales is gonna
keep his pact with Pancamo.
Unless Morales sees this
as an opportunity to move
three squares forward,
change partners.
I want you to tell Enrique
I want to sit down.
The older I get,
the more I realize
that my appetites
are merely habits.
I don't crave power
anymore.
I just want it
'cause I always had it.
When I first arrived
here at Emerald City,
you made me a very generous offer
to share in the drug trade,
but I ain't used
to partners so I said no.
Ever since then, we've been rattling
the sabers at each other,
with neither one of us
gaining very much ground.
I'm beginning to think
you don't know how to die.
Oh, Christ, what's this now?
I'm gonna shut them down.
No, no, wait. Signal your men
to get ready, but let's wait.
I'm missing
the point here.
Months ago we
agreed to a truce.
Only thing is, neither one of us
meant the oaths that we swore.
I say we make
the lie a reality.
I say we work
together.
Peace.
Well, I'll be fucked.
All it means, Tim, is now
they're one big happy tit factory.
Not when Pancamo
finds out.
Fuck.
We gotta talk
to Chucky.
Fuck Chucky.
I can handle this.
- Petey.
- My father ran operations here.
- I run operations here.
- Adebisi took you down, man.
That was
Pancamo's fault.
Okay, that motherfucker was supposed
to be watching my back
- and he did fucking shit.
- So what the fuck are we gonna do?
We'll show these assholes
the Sicilians are still in charge.
We're gonna massacre
the fucking Nazis.
- Where's Said?
- Why?
Because I want
reinforcements.
I need a brief conversation
with Minister Said.
Excuse me.
May I sit?
- I'll come right to the point.
- Please do.
Me and you, we have mutual interests,
common enemies.
I want him dented
and you want him dented
and I'm hoping we can
work something out.
You were raped
by Adebisi.
Yeah, well, I'm asking...
I'm answering.
You may have resolved
the rape in your own head.
It doesn't change the facts.
Here in Oz,
you will always be known
as one of Adebisi's bitches.
No matter what you do,
you cannot change that.
No. I can.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
Peter?
What?
He's fucking right,
you know.
And we, well,
you're our paisan,
but we decided we're not
going after the Aryans
unless Pancamo
gives the word.
Fuck all of youse.
Hey!
What can I do for you?
- Came to pick up the pool table.
- Yeah, is it fixed yet?
The ball return was a little hinky,
but I unhinkied it.
Hey! You got
the toaster done?
Hold your Calvins, bocce boy.
I'm in the middle of something.
Yeah, well, I got lunch coming,
so these jokers can wait.
- We don't wait for wops.
- Someone's gonna teach you manners.
Yeah, well, it ain't
gonna be you, prag.
Oh, look out!
Get the fuck off!
No, let me up!
- You know, I always wondered...
- Let me up!
Was Adebisi's dick
bigger than mine?
Fuck you!
Fuck you! No!
- You be the judge.
- No!
I managed to stop the bleeding,
but he's still in pretty bad shape.
Take him to the psych ward.
Oh, yeah. Pool table's
working good now.
Have you been working
for the warden for a long time?
Not that long,
but long enough.
I'm the one who saved
Glynn's life, you know?
Mm-hmm. 'Cause when Clayton Hughes
was gonna stab him,
I grabbed Hughes
and I pulled him off.
Oh.
- You're very pretty.
- Thank you.
L... I've been in solitary
for almost a year,
and you're the first real woman
I've seen since I got out.
- Real woman?
- Well, there's... you know, there's...
- the female hacks.
- Penders, come in.
- Okay, bye.
- Now!
Close the door.
What can I do for you?
Well, I'm out of solitary
and I want to stay out,
so I think the best thing
for me to do is to avoid any...
altercations.
Which means as little face time
with the other prisoners as possible.
So I want to know if,
instead of working in the shop,
- if you can give me a job here.
- In my office?
- Yes.
- No.
- Warden, that...
- Don't say I owe you.
I have a very negative
reaction to that.
Your presence here would only
remind me on a day-to-day basis
of what happened to Clayton Hughes.
So the answer is no.
In fact, if you
see me coming, hide,
because the best thing for me
is to stick you back in solitary.
Stay out of my sight.
Okay? Officer!
Warden, that's not right.
That's not right.
- Bye.
- That's not right.
Wet dreams are the best.
You start having them
at like 12 years old.
Every other night
you're making love
to the most beautiful
women in the world...
Pam Grier,
Barbi Benton,
even the lovely little Jodie Jensen
in your fifth grade home room.
Then you grow up and the wet dreams
happen less frequently,
but now you're getting
the real thing, so who cares?
Until one day you realize
the woman that you're with,
maybe even married to,
don't look like Barbi Benton,
ain't fucking
like Pam Grier,
and will never love you
as purely and innocently
as little Jodie Jensen.
Wet dreams...
a boy don't know how good
he's got it.
This new law brings
the death penalty
back to our state and limits
a condemned man's choices
to either lethal injection
or the electric chair.
And I'm confident
that this version
will sustain
all judicial review.
And once again, our message
to miscreants is clear:
Stop murdering our families.
Stop the violence.
Tobias, would you
like to sit here?
No, why?
You're gonna hurt your neck
straining like that.
It's just...
Keller's coming back
from Cedar Junction today.
We know.
I haven't seen him in months.
I'm a little... anxious.
- How do I look?
- Anxious.
I was hoping you
were gonna say fuckable.
Misdeal.
Warden, I'm touched you came down
to welcome me home.
Where's the red carpet
and the marching band?
- Cut the jokes, Keller.
- Yes, sir.
You know, I want you to know
this time around
I intend to be
a model prisoner.
Gonna be the best-behaved man
in Emerald City.
That'd be fine, except you're not
going to Emerald City.
No?
Where? B?
For the time being,
you'll be in protective custody.
Protective custody?
Why?
You'll see.
After he changes clothes take him
to interview room two.
Well, well, well.
Agent Taylor, what a surprise.
Sit.
I've been riding hump all day.
I prefer to stand.
Suit yourself.
State of Massachusetts
let you out of prison
because Gaetano Cincetta
says you didn't hire him to kill Hank.
He says Chucky Pancamo
hired him.
- That's old news, spanky.
- True.
But one question though:
Why would you confess
to hiring Cincetta when you didn't?
Why would you cover
for Pancamo?
- I owed him.
- You're lying.
Prove it.
I do have one piece of new news
for you, though.
The Bryce Tibbetts
murder case.
A witness has
come forward.
Imagine that.
After all this time,
a citizen decides to step up
and do the right thing.
This citizen
picked your picture
out of a mug file.
Tomorrow you and I
are gonna drive into town
and see whether he or she
can pick you out of a lineup.
In the meantime,
we're keeping you isolated.
But don't get
too comfortable though.
Your real home's
gonna be death row.
Officer, put this...
caviar on ice.
Put an "X" on that one.
- Hey.
- How'd your meeting go with Rudolph?
- Good.
We're feeling very positive
about his parole.
- Excellent.
- Well, I mean...
I said that before,
didn't I?
Will you stop beating
yourself up, Catherine?
You did the best
you could for me.
I... have to go.
Come here.
Give Daddy a kiss.
I love you.
- Will you give daddy a kiss?
- Yes.
Mmm, you smell good. I'll see you
on Saturday, okay, dumpling?
Bye.
So, Officer Howell...
you and me gonna be spending
an awful lot of time together, huh?
Think you can
handle that, tough guy?
I know if I can't,
you'll make me.
- Sister Pete.
- Hello, Chris.
May we speak privately?
Knock yourself out,
Sister.
- How are you?
- Off balance.
Yesterday I was
in Cedar Junction
serving life
on a murder for hire
and all of a sudden they tell me,
"Oh, you're not guilty for that.
You're going back to Oz."
I'm on the bus,
I'm looking forward
to coming back here and the FBI
tells me that they got a witness
against me for an old murder rap.
I'm facing
the death penalty.
What you need
is a good lawyer.
Yeah, you know of any?
I'll find somebody.
If you need anything else,
give me a holler.
Sister Pete?
I want to spend
some time with Beecher.
I'll see what I can do.
The death penalty?
- Christ.
- I'm hoping Catherine McClain
will recommend a lawyer
from her office.
Catherine, yeah,
that's a good idea.
Meanwhile, I'll ask the warden
about all the specifics.
While you're there,
will you ask him...
I'd like some time
with Keller.
I'll see
what I can do.
- The answer is no.
- May I ask why?
You can ask, but you
won't like the reason.
- Try me.
- Chris Keller tortured,
sexually abused
and murdered three men.
Why should I try
to make him happy?
And Beecher?
Beecher is once again the victim
of someone else's excesses.
- Oh, come on.
- This discussion is over.
- Leo!
- This discussion is over!
You know when you're
driving in your car
or maybe taking a shower and suddenly
you remember some great dream you had
and that dream made you feel
so good or bad or whatever,
you can't help but try
to recapture every detail?
Next thing you know, you missed
your exit or the hot water's gone cold.
Well, in Oz,
if you take a shower
and you space off,
even for a second,
some cocksucker is sure
to shank you in the back.
Daydreams can be deadly.
What do you want?
Not a thing.
Hmph.
Robson,
get out of my way.
- Imam, come with us.
- Say another word, Robson.
Say one more word,
I'll snap your cracker neck
right here, right now.
Move your sorry ass
onward.
Yes, sir, boss.
Imam,
you have to control
the anger in your heart.
- Remember the words of Allah.
- What words would those be, Arif?
What advice
would Allah have for me?
Look, I don't mean to speak
beyond my position,
but he has got serious...
I know what you're
thinking, Ahmad,
but Minister Said
is a great man.
He's having
troubles right now,
that is why we
must not abandon him.
No, no, not abandon him.
Of course not, he's our brother.
But is he the one to lead us?
- Look, I feel that he has got...
- Enough!
Help me pick
up these beads.
- Did you ever use drugs?
- No, ma'am.
Not so much as a marijuana cigarette
has ever touched my lips.
I have.
Heroin,
crack cocaine.
- Kareem?
- What?
You thought my journey
to Allah was easy?
No, it's just that-that...
when I was using,
you never said...
That is a period of my life of which
I am not very proud of.
Hmm.
Unlike now?
- Follow me.
- Yo, man, what's up with that?
- "Miss Sally" is on the TV, man.
- I said come.
- What were you doing with Poet?
- Poet? What... nothing.
- He wasn't trying to sell you drugs?
- Come on, man.
Only titties we were talking about
was Miss Sally's.
You are not to talk to him.
Why? What's up? We just snapping.
That's my boy, we go back.
What'd I just say?
Now remember,
one word from me to McManus
and you go straight back to solitary.
Now go.
- Straighten out your cell.
- Say what?
Hey!
Now you better
obey me.
Oh, dude, you look like
you need some bounce, bro'.
A shitload of tits
came in today.
Step off, bro'. You know
I can't be doing no drugs and shit.
Motherfucker Said's
watching me 24/7, man.
Glynn having me tested
once a week and shit.
Well, yo, last year
Glynn was having me tested, man.
I got the way around that.
You know Billy Plana?
- Huh-uh.
- He works bedpan.
He'd piss for me then
switched the cups out.
You could pay, right?
Well, he'd piss for me,
he'd piss for you.
All right, hook me up.
- I got you, dawg.
- Omar?
- Oh fuck, fuck.
- Omar.
Oh, man.
- Open your hand.
- Yeah, I was just...
Be quiet.
Open your hand.
Give it to me.
Damn!
You forget
Omar White exists.
I'm not gonna
warn you again, Poet.
- Fuck this shit, man.
- Yo, yo, yo. Hold it, man.
My gap, man.
Fuck, he got my money.
I should be working and shit,
you know what I mean?
Omar didn't actually
take a hit?
- No.
- Well good.
But he will. He'll find another dealer...
by day's end he'll be high.
Well, yeah.
All right.
- Let me know if he uses.
- McManus!
That's all
you have to say?
Well, what do you
want me to say?
Wait a minute,
you asked me to help White.
- You asked me to save him.
- Yeah.
In the process, you convinced me
that if I can turn him around,
I might find a way past
my own troubles.
- Mm-hmm.
- I bought in, McManus.
I bought in hook,
line and sinker.
I'm still buying.
Now I need this to succeed,
for my own soul.
I know.
- So why you refusing to help me?
- I'm not refusing anything.
I got nothing to offer.
Said, this is all on you.
Omar White is the million
dollar question.
There's an answer,
but I'm never gonna come up with it.
I believe you can.
I'm basically a spectator now,
but I think your instincts
can find the key.
And if not,
we're all fucked.
Omar, when you finish up...
come see me.
Yo, man, look.
You're making my motherfucking head
hurt, all right?
I don't feel like hearing
no goddamn drug speech now. Shit!
- We're not gonna talk about drugs.
- Then what?
I don't know... anything.
Just a conversation.
Look, I don't want to have no damn
conversation now, all right? Shit.
We're gonna have
a conversation anyway.
You understand me?
Now what is your
favorite color?
- Answer.
- White.
White. Why is that?
'Cause of your name, right?
Huh-uh.
It's clean and shit.
Fine.
One more.
What was the last thing
that you were really passionate about?
Tell you the truth, man, I don't think
I ever gave a shit about shit.
Oh, come on, man.
There must've been something.
Come on, something you wanted
to do, something you wanted to be.
Come on, Omar. Give me something.
Give me something.
A cowboy.
Yeah, that's right, a motherfucking
black cowboy, Jack, yeah.
When I was a kid,
you know, I saw...
I saw this movie from the olden days
and shit, with...
Herb Jeffries in it.
Yeah, it was called
"The Bronze Buckaroo"
and shit. That's it.
Black B-westerns.
Black movies,
all black cowboys
made for black audiences
in the late '30s.
So guns and horses, huh?
Yo, man, never mind the motherfucking
guns and horses.
That motherfucker
Herb Jeffries...
he could sing.
So this is excellent.
- What's... what's excellent?
- You've identified an interest,
and that's an important
step forward.
Finding the right activity,
a constructive way of spending time,
can make all the difference. I'm gonna
set up a meeting with Fitzgerald.
- O'Reily's mother?
- She's doing community service here.
- Why am I meeting who?
- She teaches singing.
Yo, that all sounds great
and shit except for one thing...
- I can't sing.
- "Can't" never did anything, Omar.
What does that mean?
I don't understand. You're pissed
because we've started a music program?
No. No, I'm pissed
because I'm just hearing about it.
I'm the state liaison,
for Christ's sake.
Oh, and you have to report everything
back to your pal the governor.
Leo, there's no money in the budget
for a music program.
How do you expect
to pay the freight?
Well, Suzanne Fitzgerald
is donating her time.
The other costs are minimal.
I'll do what I always do...
take a little from here,
a little from there.
The arts are an important
part of life.
Oh really? I couldn't get you
anywhere near a theater or art gallery
when we were married,
especially if there was football on TV.
Ellie, I really think this program
can help some of these guys.
Tim, you're setting yourself
up for another fall.
You always bet everything
on the impossible.
- That's not true.
- Yeah?
Look at us.
Get an estimate
of the cost.
I'll see if I can wrangle
some cash from Devlin.
You were very smart
in marrying her.
Hmm.
She was very smart
in divorcing you.
- So l... I ain't got to sing?
- No, you don't have to sing.
I don't?
But I do encourage you to try
at least once before we give up.
No.
My voice, it ain't no good.
I mean, it's too deep.
Like Barry White,
you know, just bad.
You know what? I think
you might be more of a tenor,
so let's try this.
You try.
You know, um...
you sure are
a fine-looking woman.
Okay. Well...
new idea.
Let's...
let's try starting
with a song, okay?
I'll bet you know
this one.
? Jesus loves me,
this I know?
? For the Bible
tells me so?
? Little ones
to him belong?
- ? They are weak but he is strong.?
- I know that.
That's... that's...
that's "Jesus Loves Me."
? Yes, Jesus loves me?
? The Bible tells me so.?
See, now you... you...
you a singer.
It's your turn.
I heard...
I heard you was O'Reily's moms?
That's true.
Growing up,
- you make him sing too?
- No.
Why not?
It's a long story.
So is mine.
Omar, you know, I'm not
asking for the world...
Damn!
I mean, I try to be graceful
up here, right? I'm trying, all right?
You said I didn't have
to sing, right?
I said I wanted you to try.
Now sit back down, please.
Motherfucking liar, man.
Everybody always fucking lying!
Officer Brass!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I take it back.
I take it back. Forgive me,
I didn't mean to get angry.
Suzanne,
you all right?
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
Shh, shh, shh.
- It's okay.
- Get off the floor, you fucking mutt!
Stand up.
Let's try again.
Come on.
Sit down.
Want to try this?
I heard once that every person
in your dream is actually you.
Even if you're dreaming about you
and some motherfucker you can't stand,
you're actually
dreaming about you
and the motherfucker part
of yourself you can't stand.
Your mother got all riled up
about civil rights.
Hell, things wasn't as bad
as they was in the South.
But she dragged your daddy
on down to D.C.
To hear Dr. King,
to join the march.
- You didn't go?
- No.
I stayed in town waiting
on something better to come along.
Your parents were
part of the most
important event
of the 20th Century,
and here I am, two days
into a five-day drunk.
I miss Mama
so fuckin' much.
I know, I know.
I got a postcard
from my honey.
- She's in Maui.
- Oh yeah, Maui? Maui's awesome.
You know you can actually
climb down into a volcano there?
And the women,
they got great, great...
They got great
inner beauty, man.
- You been to Maui?
- I read it in "National Pornographic."
Lots of color photos
and shit.
Does it bother you that your girlfriend
is in Hawaii, Chico?
No, I know Consuela
still loves me
and I want her to be
having a good time and all,
but that postcard, it really
ripped my heart out, you know?
Places I'll never see.
There are worse things
than your woman going on vacation.
- Yeah? Like what?
- She could leave you.
She could send you
a letter one day and say
she thinks the time has come
to move on with her life.
I'm saying
I thought the worst thing
that could happen to me
was losing my legs,
losing my freedom.
But Annabella, that's...
like losing my manhood...
another big chunk
of who I am.
I wish I could
understand you.
Jaz Hoyt's sitting
in the hole
because of the
Reverend Cloutier.
- You work at the mailroom, don't you?
- Yeah.
Great. Make sure today that you're
the one pushing around the mail cart.
Make sure you do deliveries
to the hospital ward.
And when you get there,
waste Cloutier.
- How?
- A lot of burn victims suffocate.
- Here you go, dago.
- Fuck you, punk.
What's this doing here?
I guess Cloutier's
got mail.
Officer!
Officer! Officer!
Bitch!
Get the fuck off him!
Okay, okay.
Okay, look at me.
Look at me.
- Where's Gunner?
- In solitary.
- And Cloutier?
- Alive.
Shit!
Now I got to tell Jaz.
- Come here.
- What? What? What?
I saw him.
- Saw who?
- Cloutier.
In the hole, all of a sudden
he appears looking healthy.
- You were dreaming.
- I saw him.
- That's crazy.
- I saw him just like Jim Burns saw him.
Jim Burns is dead.
You killed him.
- We killed him.
- Okay, look, relax, all right?
Fuck you, relax.
You fucking...
Put the cigarette out.
Okay, okay.
Smoking's bad for you, Jaz.
Yeah, I know.
Oh shit.
Help!
Lopresti!
- Help!
- They cannot hear you.
I'm in your mind.
I'm all the guilt
stacked up inside your soul,
your whole life, ever since
you killed your first cat.
And I'm not going
anywhere unless...
- Unless what?
- You do something for me.
- Anything.
- Kill Timmy Kirk.
- But...
- Kill Timmy Kirk, Jaz.
Or I'll be visiting you every night
for the rest of your life.
Hey!
Put the cigarette out!
Dr. Nathan says that the Reverend
Cloutier's recovery is remarkable.
He should be talking
in weeks.
Good news.
Don't hondel me, Kirk.
You were the one who arranged to have
that biker try and kill Cloutier.
How'd you like
a blowjob?
- Kirk!
- What the fuck's wrong with you?
What are you...
Hey!
Hoyt!
Officer!
Wait a minute...
what the...
Oh, Jesus.
Oh, Jesus!
Bless me, Father,
for I have sinned.
Give me a CPC
and a chem-20, stat.
I confess to the murder
of Jim Burns.
of Ralph Gulino.
I confess to the murder
of Brian Lawlor.
of Adam Decoursey.
I confess to the murder
of David Horton.
Gloria, Hoyt's claiming that Cloutier
ordered him to kill Timmy Kirk.
That's insane. Cloutier can barely move
and can't even speak yet.
I don't know.
Hoyt really seems to believe
that Cloutier appeared
to him last night.
You think Hoyt's going for the insanity
defense to keep him off death row?
Maybe.
- Gloria.
- Yeah?
Where is he?
- Did you move Cloutier?
- No.
He was here
a minute ago.
Well,
now he's gone.
But upon entering
the tomb,
I saw a young man
sitting at the right side,
clothed in a white robe.
And they were amazed.
He said to them,
"Do not be terrified.
You are looking for Jesus of Nazareth,
who was crucified.
He has risen."
Everybody's got
their own brand
of miserable shit
to deal with in life,
but if you keep your eye
on your dream, you'll pull through.
In Oz, the opposite is true.
The way to get through the shit
is by having no dreams at all.
In fact, one of the biggest consolations
for a man doing time
is knowing 90% of people
in the outside world
don't realize their dreams.
So you see, we're not really
missing out on anything.
Are we?