-Jesus, it's freezing out here.
- Decoy Squad's in the clubhouse
We're working late tomorrow night, boys.
You got any plans, change 'em.
Uh, I got tickets forJourney.
What's goin'on?
We're getting the marked money
list out of Aceveda's safe
What?
I thought there was no way?
- Things change.
The president's in town campaigning.
- What, in Farmington?
His schedule changed.
Added a stop in Century City.
Which takes him right through our
shitty neck of the woods at about 65 miles an hour
What's that got to do with the list?
Every cop on duty's
stuck on security detail.
Which means a skeleton crew inside
the Barn all day and night tomorrow.
Yeah You forgetting
about the combination?
Aceveda's safe is county issue.
That means the combination's on file.
Anybody from Property
ever ask you for a favor, you do it
We get one shot.
After the president's gone, that's it.
This works, I might even
have to vote for the guy
All right. I'm going.
It's 6:00 in the morning
Come on
You got to stop that
It's just one to start the day
- To go with the other eight butts right there?
- Six of them are yours
Maybe you should stop, too,
for Christ's sake
That's just the hormones talking
My mom knows about the baby
Jenny opened her big mouth to my aunt
Okay So-So now she knows
- God, she's gonna milk this one.
-She can't be that bad.
Yeah? Well, I'm the only one that still talks
to her, so that means I get all her crap
All right, don't-- don't worry
about your mom, okay?
- You're supposed to be off today
- Well, now I'm on.
The-The-The president's in town
- Bye
Okay It's half an hour before
morning shift is back on duty
It's a ghost town out there
Boo
All right
- Clear Four, eight, five, two, one
Oh, shit Oh, shit
- She's here Nina's here
Get down Get down
- Hey, you're here early
- So are you
You gotta beat the bad guy
to the punch
- Where's the list?
- Ask your property guy when he
pulls his head out of his ass
Oh, Christ
- You sure you punched in the code right?
- Oh, yeah, I'm sure
- We got to figure out another way
- There is no other way.
Especially when ''employee of the month''
clocks in two hours early
I might be able to crack the safe,
if I had enough time
- You ever tried something like that?
- Never stopped me before
Look, Shane was in there 30 seconds.
We almost got caught.
If we could get the safe out some time
tonight, Ronnie could take his sweet time
And how's Aceveda not gonna
notice a missing safe?
He'll be gone
Plus we'll put in a twin
That safe is standard police issue
There's gotta be a thousand
of them floating around
- Hey, your girlfriend's back
Oh, Christ.
This I don't need right now.
- Detective
- Mrs-- Mrs Maldonado
Reina's friend give me this song
It says he killed her
It says he stabbed
and killed mi hija.
This is supposed to be hip? It sounds like
a Chihuahua threw up on an accordion
It's a narcocorrido-- a song about crimes
Very popular in Mexico
And making their way up north.
Chaydez loved her,
but he couldn't have her.
Couldn't let her go
It's a love song
- Not quite.
As they made love, he stabbed her once
for every day they were together
And buried her by the underpass
in Frogtown Flats by the river.
- A real chart-topper
- Who's this victim, Reina?
Fifteen year-old girl, disappeared
about six months ago It's Bobby's case
- I helped out for a day checking gang angles
- And?
Wasn't gang Chaydez worked for her father
He was the only suspect
I guess nothing ever came of it
Ever since Bobby took early retirement,
Mom's been coming to me looking for updates.
- Do we know the singer?
- Otilio Ramirez Self-published
The cowboy crap
is straight ranchero
Let's see if we can locate him
Also, get a canine unit and look for the body
- Why?
- Because the song says she's buried there
We gonna bring in Eminem
every time he raps about killing his ex?
Rap songs are fantasies
Narcocorridos are recorded history
Oh Learn something new every day
If we're looking for a body,
it must be Lauren Hey
Careful Boris doesn't
play well with other dogs
Oh, I must have the magic touch
Give him time to get
to know you better. Heel!
Sit!
So, um, what brings us
together this time?
Heard a song about a lovesick cholo,
buried his chiquita out here
They brought us out here
because of a song?
Look at it as quality time
You still got that boyfriend?
- Still got that wife?
- No Still got that boyfriend?
- The cook, right?
- Chef
- Find
- How's that going?
Um, he's trying to
establish his career
Been a while
Still don't see a ring
Don't worry
He'll get to it
Body
They don't write love songs
like they used to
- Body
Body.
- I need more flags
Ripped by:
Hound
Hey, can I get your autograph, man?
Yeah, like on a confession?
Pack up.
- Who are you?
- We're big fans
- The biggest
- What're you doing?
Let's go
- What're you doing with Otilio?
He didn't do nothing
- Oh, yeah?
He seems to know where all the bodies
are buried, don't you, partner?
- You can't silence me
- Hell, no We're gonna make you talk
Just get your wiry ass in the car
- Look, I know all my rights
Relax You might get
a new album out of it
Is that our corridor?
Yeah Not as tough as he sings
They pulled eight bodies out of Frogtown All
young women in various stages of decomposition
Eight? Any of them stabbed?
Some were there too long to tell
We'll have to wait for the ME
So these guys actually write songs
celebrating crimes?
- The popular ones even get commissioned.
- Musical confessions?
I'm gonna go see what they recovered
from the dead women's bodies.
- You gonna start with Otilio?
- I'll make him sing
Your song says that Reina Maldonado
was stabbed to death
and dumped by the railroad tracks--
that sound familiar?
- My songs speak for themselves
- I'd rather hear it from you, rock star.
She was 1 4 years old
when she went missing
- You sing about Chaydez stabbing her
- What are you doing?
Trying to find out why your shitty CD
led us to eight dead women.
Help! Help! Help!
-Jesus Christ!
- Y-You stay away from me
- What's your problem?
- Help! Help! Help!
- What's going on?
- Nothing
- Really
- I don't want to be alone with him
I didn't touch him.
Go look at the tape.
- No, I'll just sit in
- That's not necessary.
Everyone's on presidential detail.
I can lend a hand.
Now where were we?
I don't commit crimes
I'm a journalist
Is that what you think you are?
Did Chaydez commission that song?
A reporter protects his sources
- Reporters don't protect killers
- I just write the truth
Arrest me, arrest the L.A. Times too
- Sol Negro needed money for his family.
He planned to take it
from a liquor store on San Marco
but the shop owner
hated Mexicans, pulled a gun
Sol Negro bravely
shot him in the neck
- I remember that shooting
You remember that shooting?
- I sure do It was Christmas
Yeah It can't be this easy, can it?
Otilio's got three CD's
Who knows how many cases we might close
Run ''Sol Negro'' See what street name
comes up Show the mug shot to the victim
Who am I, the Strike Team
all of a sudden?
- What?
- That sounded like an order
It's not How do you want to go?
The same way It's just--
It's nice to be asked
- Are you arresting Chaydez?
- He's just here for questioning
- Does he know where Reina is?
- If he knows, I'll know
Listen, this could take a while
- So why don't you go home, get a little rest?
- I want to stay here
For the good news
You hear that, Chaydez?
He's singing about you.
-Just a song
No, it's a map to eight dead girls
- and I got a big bet that
Reina Maldonado is one of them
- You're wrong
What I don't understand is why an asshole
like you would put a stabbing to music.
- I didn't write that song
- No, you killed Reina
and had Otilio write it for you
- Never happened
- Narcocorridos are real They're not made up
The singer's reputation depends on it
Now he sung about a dead body
We found eight
- You were off my radar Now you're back
- Can I see you two outside?
- Later
Now, I think
We heard from the lab
Early best guess says that the deaths
look like poisoning from
long-term chemical meth exposure
Reina was hooked up with
some asshole cooking crank?
Maybe not
Her dental records are on file
She wasn't there
She wasn't one of the bodies we pulled
Oh. Maybe there's another burial ground.
So we have a meth operation that's
poisoning its workers and a missing girl.
Claudette, you run the meth thing
with Dutch Vic, you stay with Reina
- What about the singer and his muse?
- Keep 'em till we find out more
How? We're at the deadline.
We got nothing to charge them with.
Find something
The Secret Service wants to
meet with some of the captains.
I'll be back in about an hour
What did he tell me to do?
Drum up charges to hold them?
Trust me-- that doesn't work
He didn't mean it, right?
I could free up part
of the Decoy Squad for a few hours
- Then I'll cut Chaydez loose, keep a tail on him
- That's your call, not mine
Okay I'll take responsibility When Walon's
team comes into the Barn, cut him
All right, get it inside the clubhouse
Aceveda's out of the office for an hour.
Decoy Squad's on the way in.
-Just enough time to make the switch
- I really don't like this
Well, you'll pretend
- What's with all the Rolaids, man?
- I got an ulcer
- Since when?
- Since the Armenian mob started
looking for me This helps
Stop worrying your guts out, man.
We're not gonna get busted.
What are we doing breaking
into a captain's office?
We've nailed 20 guys we can lay the cash off
on, get 30 cents on the dollar
Let them worry about washing it.
Partner up with criminals?
I'm trying to find the flaw in that plan
I'm just saying there's other ways
That are fine if you want huge risk
and 30 cents on the dollar.
But I want a dollar on the dollar
- Hey Somebody moving?
- Well, we're just, uh
moving a little stuff out of the clubhouse,
make some room for you and your team
Oh. I thought you wanted us out?
I do Might as well be all
comfortable in the meantime
Listen, I heard you guys
came by to help us out
Well, it beats going home
to an empty bed
I can't help you with that tonight
Oh, don't worry I haven't
needed a slump buster yet
Hey, uh, what happened
with the Secret Service?
It got postponed
Uh, thank you for the, uh, the help
with the Maldonado case.
I was kind of glad when you,
uh, came in when you did
Listen, I-I-I just about
wrote this girl off for dead
I poked my head into it
for a little while...
but when we hit the wall,
I just checked out.
- Then make it right
- You're not hearing me
Um, Reina's father died a month ago
from a heart attack
He just couldn't stand his daughter
missing, you know, not knowing
I was just hoping to get the mom
some good news, that's all
Well,just keep trying
- How's your stomach now?
- Better when this is done
- We're halfway home
- Right
- Let's go
- Yeah
All right,you're on. We gotta get inside
this safe and make a copy of the list...
before the day shift comes back on
- Glad there's no pressure
- Lend him a Rolaids
- Three-hole punch
- Yeah. 39-73.
- Any tape dispensers?
- I got five units
Right Stapler
- Six
- Great
Only 57 more to find
And then we'll see
what our next punishment is.
Look, I told you that I was gonna go
to Aceveda and you still went out there
- It was the right thing to do.
- Maybe But you could've
also gotten hung out to dry
It was the right thing
I had to make a deal with
Aceveda to get my job back
Tell him if I saw any cops
going out of line
When I made that promise, I sure
didn't think that you'd be one of'em
One-inch binders
Got it
Liquor store ownerjust I.D. 'd
Sol Negro, a.k.a.Julio Gallegos...
as our shooter in that Christmas robbery
If we close any more cases because
of Otilio's songs, we should deputize him
Maybe I can get him to write a tune
about my cuddler rapist.
- You coming?
- Can't.
One of our dead women had a friend's
phone number in her pocket
She should be here any minute
That's Leticia
She was my best friend in Mexico
Well, her body was found
along with seven others
all showing signs of
long-term chemical exposure
What kind of chemical?
The kind they use to make
methamphetamines.
She would have had to breathe
an awful lot to die of exposure.
She never touched drugs
- When did she come to L.A.?
- I don't know
She saved up for a coyote to bring her up,
but I never saw her
- She called me two weeks ago,
but I only got a message
- Saying what?
That she needed help
But then it hung up
- And you didn't report her missing?
- To who?
To say what? That she was being smuggled
over the border and needed help?
- Sol Negro--spelledjust like it sounds.
- Any problems?
- Piece of cake
- I'm gonna jump back on the cuddler case
- I need some help
I've hit a wall ID'ing
some of the other bodies
So, what, we're just gonna
drop all of our other cases, is that it?
Since when does eight dead women
not fire your engine?
I don't want to lose momentum
on the rape case I can't do both
- FineJust give me a second
- Thanks.
Otilio! Otilio!
- Buzz me! Buzz me!
- Get up!
- You guys all right?
- Evan, get him to the ER
Make sure they take an X-ray
- What was that guy saying?
- ''There's your next song''
- Tell me I'm rich again
- I can't crack it
Well, can you pull the lock out?
- Not so you wouldn't notice
- This keeps getting better
How do we get the safe back inside
with Aceveda still here?
Let's worry about the list first.
We got one window and in about
three hours it's gonna slam shut
We'll each take turns
tracking Aceveda's movements
- Smitty could get in the safe
- No!
I wanna keep this in-house
until we absolutely have to
Oh, shit.
- Look, I'm really busy, Mara
- Guess who I just spent
four hours on the phone with?
- Can we talk about this later?
She calls me in a panic.
It's always the same old shit.
My mom says that they're gonna
kick her out of her apartment
if I can't help her with the rent.
I haven't even sold a single house yet.
- We'll talk about it later, okay, baby?
- Later? When?
Are you ever coming home?
I really need you
I'll be back as soon as I can, okay?
- Hey, Dutch, we have to do the annual inventory
- Lucky you
Yeah Listen, uh, did you
check out a departmental laptop
computer about 1 0 months ago?
- No
- According to this you did. A Dell 5 1 00.
- Well, whatever you're looking at, it's wrong
- Is that your signature?
- Yeah
- Good work out there today.
- Thank Boris
- Yeah I saw him out there
- Uh, he seemed a little restless
- He's frustrated
He gets worked up
and he wants to go all night long
Corpus interruptus
You know, one of these days we're
gonna meet up under better circumstances
- Why leave it to chance?
- Why isn't the narcocorrido in the cage?
Uh, I don't know.
I could check the logbook if you want.
- Then you go get it.
- I gotta get Koto
Narcotics called and they said that they
wanted him to sniff out an after-hours club.
- Uh, good luck
- Okay See ya
Where's Chaydez and the singer?
We had to cut them loose.
Oh, Christ
You cut them loose after I told you
to keep them in custody?
His hold time was over
We had no choice
You think you can disobey
a direct goddamn order?
He didn't I did
You?
We have to protect the case. I don't think you
realized how long we had them in custody--
I realize that I am still captain here!
And I will not put up
with shit like this again!
Hey Um, did you find
that computer yet?
- No, not yet Did you?
- No
If you don't locate it,
the city's gonna bill you.
- Yeah Um, I did remember what I was using it for
- What?
Child porn
I had some downtime, so I was
going to local chat rooms, uh, Web sites
to see if anybody was peddling smut
or trying to lure kids
and, uh, I got drawn to something else,
forgot about it
So when we find this computer
that was last signed out by you
it's gonna be loaded up
with kiddie porn?
Yeah I-I would appreciate a chance to
delete any files before anybody gets a look
I-I swear it was just work
Nina, my guys need some
new things for the clubhouse
Could you pull out your scissors
and cut through some red tape?
You have to submit a request
to each department
Ah Everybody knows
you need something done, come to you
I've got my own emergency
to deal with right now
Well, maybe I can help
Not unless you're
a licensed locksmith
Locksmith?
Smitty's your guy
I have one
Thanks Thank you
Hector Moreno? Please
Try Pelican Bay
He got sent up on a burglary
eight months ago
We've used Smitty before
But, hey, you know
what you're doing I'm sorry
Is this Smitty person nearby?
Why are we meeting
in the back of a van?
We need a little help
getting into a safe.
Listen, guys, I'm kinda turning over
a new leaf, you know what I mean?
- Yeah It's about time
- Sounds like a good idea.
I gotta be kinda selective
about the jobs I take
I'm gearing up a new business now
- Home security, right?
- Yeah.
We got a start-up gift for you
Home burglaries in Farmington over the last
two months, plus addresses and phone numbers
You say hello
to a hundred and fifty sure things
First things first
I'm gonna need the combination
- This could take a while
-Just get it open
Let me know when you get in
- Yeah?
- Five, nine, five--
Five, four, six.
All right, make a copy of the list,
get it back here quick.
- Aceveda's got some other stuff in here
- Forget 'em.Just get the list.
- Come on, come on, come on.
- Got it
- Go! Go, baby, go.
Just came from the bank Chaydez cleaned
out his account the minute the bank opened
- Who's on him now?
- Walon. Chaydez had that account in two names.
- I showed a picture to a teller
She ID'd the Maldonado girl
- Reina?
- When did she see her?
- About a week ago.
She's alive? Uh, the teller's
sure it was the same girl?
She says she remembers because
they seemed like an odd couple
Said she seemed too old to be his daughter
and too young to be his girlfriend
- Reina was seen a week ago
I knew it
I knew she was alive
How well did she and Chaydez
know each other?
Not well
Chaydez, um,
worked for my husband
Tiling
I knew he was hanging
around her too much
Could they have been closer
than you think?
No No! No
Her papa would have killed her
What if Reina kept it a secret?
She was 1 4 She don't keep
a secret like that from me
No No
Oh, no, wait Hang on
He's coming back
- Activity at Chaydez's house.
- What kind?
- Where is he now?
- In and out ofhis garage.
- He's unloading something out ofhis van.
- What's he taken out?
Boxes and a bunch of bags
Something that looks like wire or rope
He's getting ready to move something
- No sign of the girl?
- Nothing.
- Stay on him
- What if she's the thing being moved?
- Is there any way to see inside?
- The shades are drawn
What about the back?
- Same thing
- Same thing.
- Go in
- What?
He could be prepping
to kill her right now
Uh, if he's got her stashed someplace else,
we might never find her
And any evidence we find
might be thrown out
We can give him
a few more minutes
I said go in!
Get the girl!
- No sign of her?
- Some clothes, shoes
- She was there for a while at some point
- Any proof she's still alive?
Found a receipt for some makeup
bought three days ago
It's not admissible
Nothing in the house will be
We don't know that for sure
We went inside in good faith
We have to assume it's no good
So we can't even get him
on playing house with a minor?
We found her clothes
in your apartment...
- a receipt dated a week ago.
- I haven't seen her
The bank teller remembers
you two opening an account together.
That's a problem, seeing how you're still
on probation for one statutory rape.
You got something against pubes, man?
I didn't do anything wrong
Well, as you see it, you're in love
Yeah. Forget the fact
she's barely out of algebra.
You're connected to the dead women.
We'll find out how.
What I still want to know
is what happened to Reina
It's just one more.
You help us, maybe we can help you.
I can see how you liked her.
Uncomplicated.
Too inexperienced to see
what a dick you really are
I liked her, but I wouldn't be with her.
H-Her parents were crazy.
- She was 1 4
- You keep telling the mom
I had something to do with it
and she keeps coming by
my place looking for her
That's why you had him write the song, right?
To get the parents off your back
- It's just a song
- I'm talking to you!
Look at me
I liked her
She liked me
Enough to go to prison for her?
Or did you hate the mom so much
you made the song come true?
- I got it
She's not a victim.
She loves me.
Hey! Hey!
Enough! Enough! Enough!
You sit down there,
keep your mouth shut
I had to put a new door on
Here's the combination
Write him a check
Enough! Enough--
Ever see her before?
She died of chemical meth exposure
She had a phone number on her.
We checked the records,
found out she used your phone to call it
Maybe I dialed the wrong number
- And left a message doing an impression of her?
- I have a few cell phones.
I don't keep track of'em all the time
- What kind of work do you do?
- Whatever I can, whenever I can
You trying to pass yourself off
as a migrant worker?
I'm from Sinaloa.
We are migrants.
That's nice threads Must have found better
work than picking strawberries in Oxnard
Now she was found with traces of lye
and red phosphorous in her lungs
- She worked in a meth lab
- Horrible
Bullshit She worked in your meth lab
She used your phone
I don't think so
Vic, Chaydez give you anything?
Nothing Hey, uh, thanks for taking
all the heat with Aceveda
- Where is he now?
- He had to run out
Baodelo was arrested in Sinaloa last year
for manufacturing meth.
No conviction
Not even a trial
- But he was arrested.
- What, did you expect
the policia to be honest?
I expect them to at least pretend
It makes three dead ends we've hit
Uh, Chaydez, Baodelo and the narco.
- Your guy know our guy?
- I don't think so Why?
'Cause Chaydez
is chewing his ear off.
- Maybe our two cases are related.
- Hey, Dutch.
I understand you lost
a department computer?
- I saw it missing on their inventory report.
- Yeah Yeah
- Still haven't located it?
- No, not yet But it'll turn up
Well,just so you know,
I had to call IAD
- Excuse me?
- They're gonna have to investigate
Any missing city property valued at
over $500 has to be investigated by IAD
I just wanted to warn you
- Smitty do you right?
- Yes, thank you
Sorry, Dutch-boy
Um, please tell me
you put her up to that
I didn't Sorry
We'll find it
- Hey, I'm coming home soon
- I'm bleeding It's the baby
Bleeding? Are-Are you sitting down?
- No
- Sit
- Did-Did you call your doctor?
- No, I called you
- Page her Tell them it's an emergency
- Shane, our baby
Hey, call the doctor, all right? Lie down
I'm-I'm on my way home right now
Got something
Our boys, Chaydez and Baodelo,
are second cousins
Huh
So, uh, Chaydez finds out about
his cousin's meth lab cemetery
possibly helps him bury the bodies
and passes one along
to Otilio for the song
Any thoughts on how to get our killing cousins
to turn against each other?
Maybe we should take it to the press
Not only is Reina not buried by the tracks,
she's not buried at all
She's alive.
So much for yourjournalistic integrity.
But I saw a body
And now you just admitted
to being an accessory
No No, I didn't
Chaydez had a second cousin
in the meth business
Somehow all his workers seem to end up dead
That's who you saw
I thought you reporters were
supposed to get your facts right?
- That makes you a fraud
- How's that gonna play down in the barrio?
Thought you guys were supposed to be
all about the truth?
I thought it was the truth
Yeah, well, I'm gonna make sure
everybody knows it wasn't
Wouldn't want your fans paying
good money for a corrido con job, huh?
They talking?
Oh, Chaydez can't keep his mouth shut
Trish took a bath in
Southern Comfort. Gotta say, she commits.
Let's hope her Spanish is as good
as her homeless routine.
Chaydez told the truth,
the whole truth and kept telling the truth
He's been hiding her out at a friend's place
Guy's name is Joaquin
- We'll find the friend
- Also said his cousin runs
his meth lab out of a truck
Right now it's in an industrial park
in Boyle Heights
Let's go
- Go! Go!
- Go!
Okay. Let's get
the trailer open.
Hazardous fumes
Don't breathe inside the trailer
- Policia!
Welcome to the land of promise.
Come be our slave.
Yeah Heard that one before
- There
Chaydez?
Hello, Reina
We're here to rescue you
- All right, you're gonna wait in here
- Do I have to see her now?
Yeah, you do
S-Sit down
- Reina's safe She's safe She's okay
- Where is she?
Uh, she's inside
But there's something
I gotta tell you first
She, uh, she went away
with Chaydez on her own
What?
No
She knew that you and your husband
would never approve
Pero the funeral?
She didn't come
Well, she's young
She thought she was in love
- She made a mistake
- No You're wrong
She's still your daughter
Reina's only 1 5
She made a mistake Let her fix it
She needs to see you
No! Not now
Look familiar, you big perv?
- Where was it?
- Desk drawer back in the storage room
Also found your renewal card
for Tiger Beat. I mailed it in
Funny later, not funny now
You're back
Yeah I had this odd feeling
I'd made a mistake in my paperwork
- You never made one before
- You can't be too sure
Maybe you were just
hoping you'd run into me
There is a difference
between confidence and overconfidence
- Boyfriend cooking for you tonight?
- He works weekends
- I can throw parsley on a plate
with the best of them
- It's a bad idea
- Name one bad thing about it
- I'm involved
Mentally, you're already checked out
What makes you say that?
I'll explain it over dinner
- What do you have to go back to work for?
- It's just for a couple hours
We'rejust finishing something up.
I'm having a miscarriage,
and you're leaving
It's just spotting
Doc says everything's gonna be all right
But you got to take it easy
You gotta take care of our baby
Hmm
Now you sure you don't need
anything else before I go?
Just for you to stay
I'll be back as soon as I can
I promise
Bye-bye.
- You should know
- You want to try
drawing a house like this?
That's not bad
- Hey, guys
- Can we watch a movie tonight, Daddy?
Well, maybe.
What's going on?
- Can I talk to you for a second?
- Sure
Hi, honey
- Fix this
- Oh, it's okay
- Can I ask a favor?
- What?
Can you take the kids this weekend?
- I don't have them till next weekend
- Please?
- Why?
- Um, I have some things I have to do and I, um--
Um, I don't want them
to be around me like this
Has something happened?
Is it your mother?
No Um
did you know it'd be this hard,
this-this empty?
I-- I don't know
what it would be
I'm having a hard time
Uh, can you take the kids this weekend?
I really don't want them to be--
- Sure Sure
- I'll take them next weekend if you want.
- That's okay I miss them
- Okay.
Great
I'm gonna be all right.
Um... okay.
- I'm sorry. I can't do tonight.
- Everything okay?
A better offer
Two nights with my kids
- It's probably a sign
- It's a scheduling snafu Next week?
No, it feels like a sign
Maybe we'll catch another case
again together sometime
We made the case against Chaydez.
Found Reina.
Good
- What's this?
- Interrogation room tape from today.
You cut me a break when
I went off the grid for Tommy
Can't stand owing you something
- Dad, let's go!
- I'm coming, baby!
- Hey, Rigo
There a family reunion
I didn't know about?
How you doin', man?
You all right?
- What, you couldn't stop them?
- He had a gun to my head.
- You couldn't do anything?
- What would you have done?
- Does Aurora know?
- Nobody knows
Man, all I wanted to do was survive.
See my wife and--
See my wife
and my little girl again
And now all I do is make up
excuses not to go home
You did what you had to do
No one can blame you
I went after a suspect today
and I kicked the shit out of him
And the only thing that stopped me was
I started to piss my pants
I'm losing control of everything
Then take it back.
I don't know how
You're a captain.
You command 200 men.
Hell,you're gonna be
the next city councilman.
You have power, David.
You have a gun and a badge.
Now these werejust
a couple of punk assholes.
Do you know who they are?
I could find out
But even then, what?
If it was me, I'd kill them