- Anything?
No. Shit.
All right We switch
- Oh, God.
- We'll do it all again with new eyes.
- Damn.
- Shit.
We can't spend a nickel
until we know which bills are marked.
I'm gonna check
for dummy serial numbers this time.
- Who's got the Federal Reserve seal?
- Uh, I'll take it.
- Here
- All right.
- The, uh, cuddler rape case--
how many victims so far?
- Five
- We're going to the press tomorrow
- No, not yet
No, the reporters are already
calling with questions.
They've got the story
We might as well give 'em our side
We've got a list of registered sex offenders,
guys with prior robberies
- Let us talk to them first
- There have gotta be 1 00 suspects, at least
It'll take you a month
Actually, we've narrowed the list down to 1 4
How?
- We got the jail profile
- I said ''No'' to that
When I told the profiler who the victims were,
he offered to do it for half price
Apparently,
his grandma put him through school
- It's still too much
- I-- $2,500.
I wrote him a check If it doesn't work out,
just take it out of my salary
- Believe me, I will
- Okay
Now, the profiler gave us ''hot zones,''
places where the guy likely lives or works
Plus, we've got high-risk areas
for future rapes.
Talk to whoever you need to,
but you got 2 4 hours till the press conference
Wh-What if our guy has a lust for fame?
Going public now will only build his
confidence, make him more dangerous
- Give us another week
- Potential rape victims need to know the threat
and they need to know it now
You've got until tomorrow
You're early
You told me you wanted me
to check the pool filter
I'll do it before I take Cass to the game
Okay I'll go get her ready
- ''Noisy.''
- Right.
Hey, Mr Mackey How's it going?
- Hey, little man
- That's enough for today, Matthew.
You did a goodjob. I'm proud of you.
Let's pack up.
He's working on understanding concepts
as well as objects
- Like a horn's not just a horn, but it's--
- Noisy
- Right
- I got it That's good
Matthew, those don't go there
- Let's put them in your room right now, okay?
- It's okay He can get it later
- Well, he knows he needs to do it now
- I said he can do it later
I got a job for him
She's getting her uniform on
She'll be out in a minute
I'll be by the pool
Come on, Matt Help your dad
Eh, I talked to a nurse
Tavon's doing a lot better
- Oh, that's great
- Yeah, it is.
- He's off the ventilator.
- Who? Tavon?
Yeah. He's, uh--
He's still not responding to voices...
but, uh, breathing on his own
was a big hurdle
He could still have a full recovery.
I'm gonna go see him after work.
Anybody wanna come with?
Yeah, I-- I can't make it today
Look, I got another idea
on how to track those bills
You know those, uh, lists that the feds
send around to banks to track counterfeits?
You can't just walk into a bank
and ask to see their Treasury watch list
without attracting attention, man
Those lists also go around to check-cashing places
They go to Indian casinos
Anyway, I know this wink joint
He cashes checks
I go in, I tin Uncle Ho,
say I need to make sure his list is current.
- And he'll go for that?
- If it keeps me from poking
around his back room...
where he's pimping slope cooch, yeah
- Yeah, I think he'll go for it
- Huh.
That's not badJust keep it quiet
Okay
Oh All here
- You're assigned to Trish for the day
- I'll try to break you in easy
We've got gay-bashers
going after male hustlers out on the stroll.
- Where's the rest of the Decoy Squad?
- Deep cover.
Trish will fill you in on operational details
Just for the record, I have no problem
working with the Decoy Squad...
but we don't work for them.
Right You work for me
- Who the hell wrote this?
- Who do you think? Nina.
What, are we in third grade?
- Yes
- Hey! That yours?
- Tommy Hisk?
- Yeah?
Detective Kouf, Wilshire
Can I talk with you?
- Shoot
- Do you wanna come with me?
I'm about to go on duty
Just step outside
Go get the captain
Your ex-wife and son were found murdered
I'm very sorry
- What?
- I need to take you to Wilshire with me
- Wait a minute Why?
- 'Cause that's my captain's orders.
This happens and Griggs wants to sweat him?
- It's just a couple of questions
- Hey We're all cops here
You think I had something to do with this?
- It's procedure
What do you want me to do about it?
- You talk to him here
You do it fast and you get it over with
Are you all right?
Yeah
Ripped by:
Hound
Where were you last night
between 1 0:00 and 1 1 :00 pm?
- Is that when they, uh--
- Just where were you?
Uh, I don't know.
I, uh, worked late and went home
- Okay. Were you with anyone
like a girlfriend maybe or--
- I don't have a girlfriend.
- I'm sorry?
- I don't have a girlfriend
- This is bullshit
- I heard his divorce got nasty, but come on!
They'll get a statement,
see there's nothing there
Meanwhile,
the real killer's trail is going cold
It's Wilshire's case Your team's got yours
- How old was his kid?
- Four or five.
God damn it
We gotta posse up,
find out who did Tommy's family
- Who's coming?
- Okay.
- True they got him up in interrogation?
- We're gonna fix that
You talking about
just disappearing off the grid?
If the hammer doesn't
come down fast and hard
it sends a message that cops
and their families are fair game
- I got cage duty What can I do from here?
- Run a record search.
Anyone Tommy's put away, recently paroled
I'm gonna check out the crime scene
- You guys come with,
canvass the neighborhood
- All right Let's go
Change of plans
- I'm calling in sick
- Are you?
Well, I could put a penny under my tongue
or you could just take me on my word
This about that uni's family getting killed?
Look, the only reason your old boss
is dicking with Tommy
is because Aceveda took you
and your team from Wilshire
This is payback
And what am I supposed to tell Claudette?
Tell her I was present and accounted for
Oh, she spanks me, I'll spank you
- Hey, Vic I'm coming too
- No.
Look, I'm not sitting around on flamer duty
while Tommy gets boned
You got problems of your own
ifTavon comes to Besides, I need you here
- Vic, come on
- I got some bodies I'll handle it
You handle this for me
- Did you hear about Tommy?
- Yeah There's no way he did this
A bunch of us are going out there to prove it
You want in?
Yeah He was my partner
I knew his son
It's a deep blue run
Could be consequences-- a little hot water
Okay
Good You're in Let's go
Okay Did you place any calls
so we can prove you were home?
- No Look, I wanna see them
- Uh-huh.
- When can I see them?
- It's all right. We won't be here too long.
Excuse me a minute
She's been crying for you.
She doesn't understand where you've been
I'm sorry It's, uh--
It's been really busy right now
You're always busy That's never stopped you
from coming home before
I can't get into it right now
Well, we're here right now
That's all you gotta say?
Will you be home for dinner?
I don't know how long I'll be needed here
- You're spending another night?
- I don't know.
For God's sake!
What have you been doing?
One of my cops just found out
his family's been murdered and he's a suspect
and then you've been calling all day
And then you bring Sophia down here
You know, wh-what are you thinking,you know?
Calm down
Mira
Hey
I'll be home when I get home
- I'll call it in.
- Mind if we take a look around?
- You're in the wrong district, aren't you?
Uh, this was the family of one of our guys
Yeah I heard Techs are still inside
No one's gonna disturb your crime scene, man
Normally, sure,
but the captain's taken a special interest in this
- He could stop by anytime
- We just wanna help out a friend
who lost his wife and kid
Who's caught up in the middle of
a pissing match between your boss and ours.
Look I'm not trying to be a pain in the ass
Two minutes
We just wanna see what happened
Look, they can wait outside
Just me and Tommy's partner
- Two minutes, in and out
- Thanks
Came in a back window-- broken lock
The wife was stabbed a couple dozen times
- The sister found her
- Anything missing?
Off the top ofher head,
a silver tea set and somejewelry.
The kid ran to hide under the bed.
The killer found him and slashed his throat
You think God's gonna show any mercy
to the person who did this?
How bad was it?
Oh, it was a speed murder
Guy had to be cranked on something
Neighbor said
there's been a lot ofbreak-ins lately.
There's a crack house right over there
across the street
Hey, anybody check that rock house
over there?
We knocked No answer
Aw, for Christ's sake
- Hey, Vic, wait a minute
I just got my job back, okay?
I'm not breaking into this place
There's a citizen inside here
in need of immediate medical attention
See? Medical emergency
Somebody get this man an aspirin
Rise and shine, party people!
Yo, dude This is my crib
Aaah! Ow!
- Ohhh!
A cop's wife and kid across the street
were murdered last night
This looks like a good place
to round up the usual suspects
Ain't nobody here last night except myself
- Well, that makes you a prime suspect
- Y'all trippin' for real
I was too blind off a eight-ball
to raise my hand against my fellow man.
You playin' a game with me?
'Cause I know some games myself
Come on, Vic.
Ahhh-- Okay, okay.
This slanger, Darontay
came by here last night to make a delivery
- Huh?
- He sees that bitch outside
writing down his goddamn license plate
Darontay goes out to regulate
Tells her to get ghost
or be swarmed on by a nigga
- What happened then?
- I don't know, man
I-- When homes came with the product
I was too busy trying to get my smoke on
IfTommy's wife wrote down this guy's license
plate number, maybe it's inside the house
Look, I think I saw some kind of list
on the fridge
- I'm not sure
- Okay Here's what we do
I need another quick look inside
I got a call that Captain Griggs is on the move
Come on, man
I-- I'm just trying to lend a hand here
Then turn around and walk away
I thought we were all
working on the same team.
Look I don't know what this beef
between our captains is
- Well, you want me to break it down for you?
- No
I just want you out of here
before mine shows up
All right. I'm outta here.
Plate numbers I'm figuring the last one
on the list belongs to Darontay
Good Copy the last few,just to be safe
- You're gonna turn that over to Wilshire, right?
- After we run the numbers, why?
- It's their investigation
- Yeah, and they're focusing on the wrong guy
Wait a minute Breaking and entering?
Withholding evidence?
If the perp fences the stuff he stole
before we get him
it's gonna be harder
to tie him to the case
We gotta get this asshole right now
I signed up to keep Tommy outta jail,
not put myself in
Oh, please
We're just doing the job they should be doing
Julien, come on Let's go
I'm gonna see this through
- We're on patrol
- It's not like I haven't covered for you...
for a couple of hours
when you've had an emergency
- You got the numbers?
- Yeah.
Feel free to return the list to Wilshire
You know there was another break-in
last month?
- Did she tell you about that?
- She told me
Same as last night
Came in through the same window
Stole a bunch of valuables
Luckily, no one was home at the time
So why aren't you
out looking for a break-in guy?
Not a very good neighborhood
for a mom and kid to be living alone, is it?
It's shit
I tried to get Barb to move,
but she likes the house
and I don't make enough cash
to get her something better
- You fought.
- So they argued
She's an ex-wife It comes with the territory
Divorce was final, what,
two weeks ago, right?
What does that have to do with anything?
Well, like you said, it's tough to get a house
in the hills on a uniform's alimony, right?
- Why the hell is that important?
- We're here to discuss last night.
Cap, am I interrogating you or him?
I thought we were just talking
I, uh, reconned three victims' homes
last night--
all with windows facing the street
Tried to get a look inside
drapes were closed in all three instances
I can't wait to hear the punch line
I reinterviewed the victims
Before the attacks
all had their drapes up during the day,
but closed at night
- So--
- He's scoping them out during the day
- Unemployed?
- It'd be less conspicuous if he worked in the area--
uh, courier, construction--
someone you wouldn't look at twice
How's it going up there?
You guys any closer to a suspect
or are you just $2,500 poorer?
We're gonna need daily surveillance patrols
in areas of potential attacks.
Save it till after the press conference.
- Yeah I've got my notes for you
- No. Keep them.
You're gonna be doing it
The press conference?
Y-You always do those
I gotta give backup to Tommy
Um, I still think this is premature.
We should at least release the psych profile,
see if it gets us any tips
- What's the profile?
- Single or with a submissive partner--
frees him up for going out at all hours
No Enough of the profiles
Just give them what we know
Yeah I need you to run a plate
One-zero-zero-Paul-Charles-Edward
Should come back to an owner,
first name Darontay
Yeah I need an address ASAP
Hey, I, uh-- I hit that check-cashing place
Palmed a list of serial numbers
Treasury's watching
Everything's under control here
- What, you can't talk?
- Right
Soon as we're done with the bone-smokers,
me and the guys will check our cash
Uh, we don't know
if your CI's information is correct
His info may not jive
with Aceveda's expectation
- Wha-- Aceveda might be
working off a different list?
- Correct
You need to review the evidence
collected in the Byz Lats investigation
Check it against the bills
that we know are marked in property
There you go
Hey, Cacuzza
I could use a little help
on this Byz Lat investigation
There was, uh, some cash
logged into property-- last name Salcido
Can't release property
without the owner's signature
Doesn't need to leave the room
The drug residue on those bills
gives me the search warrant I need
All right
- Here it is
The marked bills we're holding for Treasury
Great Great
You haven't been back
to the house since you left?
Um, I picked upJeff
a few times outside the house.
That's the only reason you've been back?
To pick upJeff?
- You heard him.
-Jesus Christ
The thing is, uh
one of the few items that was stolen
last month in the break-in
was an American Eagle coin collection
from your father
We talked to Barb's sister. She said your son
saw the coins last week at your place.
He told his mom.
She said she was gonna press charges--
breaking and entering
That would've cost you your job
Tommy?
- Somebody made a mistake
- Yeah? Was your son a liar?
My son's dead
And you pricks won't let me see him
- Captain.
- Steve
What's going on, David?
And why isn't he in custody?
Oh You said, ''Just a few routine questions''
There is a case against him
I'm not obliged to lay it out in front of him
- Well, why don't you lay it out in front of me?
- Okay
He breaks into his ex-wife's house,
stole property
She found out
He kills her to cover it up
The son sees it, so he kills him too
Yeah? Well, you've got nothing to support that,
so why don't you just let it go?
So if I search his place,
I'm not gonna find those coins, David?
Steve, you know you don't have enough
for a search warrant
You still working with us
or are you a defense attorney now?
Cuff him and put him in the car
No He stays in my house
until you show me more
- Let's call the chief
- Sure
Yeah I think he's on the 1 0th hole
at Rancho Park
I'll make sure to tell him what a great job
the Decoy Squad's doing for me
Or you can finish up with Tommy here
Oops Next time I won't knock so hard
Put your clothes on, walk out the door
and change your taste in men.
Where were you last night, playboy?
You know Ruling the streets
then back to the crib
for a little thug passion with shawtie
There was a double homicide right down
the block from the crack house you supply
Police officer's wife and child
were stabbed to death.
See me crying?
Well, we only just got here
- Did you do it?
- I woulda, but I had on a new suit.
You wear that around your neck
and you talk like that?
Ahhh You like the bling-bling
Twenty-five grand
- Man
- Why you trippin', nigga?
Two less blue-eyed devils in this world.
Ohhh!
Witnesses saw you arguing last night
Who didn't have words with that bitch?
Tellin'folks to come correct
or get dimed on...
'cause her baby daddy Five-O
Hell Even your boy couldn't deal--
hired a straight ''G'' to come gank his own crib
No speakee Ebonics, shithead
Her old man hired some dude
to come rob his own damn house
- How do you know?
- My users tell me things of interest
Like when a fellow smoke hound
gets recruited by the po-po
- Who'd this cop hire?
- Some smoker
Probably wasn't a wise choice
- You hired someone to knock over your house?
- No.
Cut the bullshit, Tommy. I found out.
Now, we got about two minutes, tops.
Tell me what happened.
I have a coin collection from my dad--
gold American Eagles
She got half of them in the settlement
She was gonna sell 'em
So you hired someone to steal them back?
It was a one-time thing.
Christ You know, a bunch of us are out there
trying to clear your name
and you're making us all look like assholes
He was a 459 suspect I cut loose
who owed me
It has nothing to do with last night
He came through the same window,
the same broken lock
Ex-wives know how to push buttons.
One way of getting out
from under the alimony
My son, Vic You think I would do this to him?
You got kids
Yeah. I wouldn't hire some crackhead
to break into where they sleep.
Barbara and Jeff were out of town
He wasn't a crackhead
- What, did you make him take a urine test?
This guy came back for seconds,
killed them both
Jesus Christ I gotta find him
That's what I'm doing Tell me his name
- Hey! Unlock this door.
Soren Arnovic
Run his priors, you'll find him
- I didn't know, Vic. If he did this, I didn't know.
- Keep your mouth shut Let me do my thing
I said, ''Unlock this door.''
What's going on?
Just showing a fellow officer some support
Uh, the rapes appear to be
preferentially motivated assaults
Would you put that in terms
our viewers can understand?
Yes, uh, women between
the ages of 65 and 80 living alone
The perpetrator-- uh, rapist--
watches for women to leave the house,
enters and waits for them
If you live in the area,
keep your blinds drawn at all times
because he scopes out his victims
during the day.
We believe he's a white or Latino male,
age 25 to 40.
That sounds like three-quarters of the
population. You don't have any hard suspects?
We're making progress with our investigation
Sounds like you have nothing
We know he thinks of himself
as a sophisticated predator
But really he has low intelligence
and poor interpersonal skills
Probably in a menial job or unemployed
It's doubtful that he has a relationship
with a woman
If he does, he's domineering
and can come and go as he pleases
And he, uh, struggles with impotence
Thank you That's all
- One more question, Detective.
- I'm sorry No, no
- Impotence?
- I said he struggles with impotence
- He never ejaculates
- Dutch--
It's a solid tactic Emasculate him in public
You draw him out or you defuse his impulses
Or piss him off
What if he uses this as an excuse to rape again?
He's raped five women that we know of
He doesn't need an excuse
Ran those bills from Evidence
They're not showing up on the Treasury list
So Aceveda's working off a different list?
- The question is how to flush it
- Hey, hey
- Hey
- I got an address.
All right Meet back here after you're done
We'll get into it
Hear Tommy might not be as clean
as we'd like to think
Think what you want to
We gotta get back on patrol
What would you be saying if it was you
in interrogation for two murders you didn't do?
Look, I'm not taking another fall
You guys go back out there,
I gotta go to Aceveda
Let's go
Tell us about the coins.
I got guys at your apartment right now.
They gonna find 'em?
According to the divorce settlement...
they belong to Barb, right, Tommy?
Part of the division of property.
- I wanna see my lawyer
- You helping us or trying to hide something?
You have anything to do with the robbery?
I wanna see my son or get me a lawyer.
A lawyer.
Not a PBA rep, huh?
You can take him
Let's go, buddy Stand up
There have been three assaults on gay hustlers
the last month, all on Saturday nights
- Victims give us anything?
- Besides big, sad eyes
Descriptions are all over the place...
but the MO tracks four to five guys
bashing and grabbing for trick money
We're supposed to be shutting down vice
in Farmington, right?
- That's the job description
- If I'm a cocksucker--
- What do you mean ''if'?
- And shit like this is going down
at my place ofbusiness...
don't I just take my moist and willing mouth
someplace else?
You may find it trivial,
but two of the victims ended up in ICU--
one with a fractured skull
Shane, you'll be undercover with the fellas
Everyone else maintains a perimeter
Hold the phone there, doll face
You got me on salami patrol?
No What about one of these guys?
- Oh, they don't look gay enough
Shane. When you want your buddy
to release...
gently squeeze the shaft at the base,
applying tongue to the glans and frenulum
- Hey, tube-steak.
I'm engaged to a gorgeous female
who's carrying my child
You're the one who actually knows
the names of dick parts
- You must be the undercover police officer
- I'm glad to be of service
- Thanks
- For what?
For watching our backs
It's been a mama of drama around here
You might wanna hold off on the thanks
I'll more than likely be running you in
next week
I didn't get your name
Yeah
Uh, I got a call-- guy claiming to be the rapist
He's demanding a formal statement from you
retracting the impotence charge.
- So he's made contact
- We've had over 1 00 calls
It could be a hoax
Well, he said he took a figurine
from the last victim's house
You could say you take a figurine
from an old woman's house...
and have a 9 out of 1 0 shot of being right
He says it was a Hummel
Danny's not gonna say anything
She wouldn't do that to me
She sure as hell isn't gonna do it to you
Listen, we find this guy?
After what he did, we don't take any chances
If he resists, he reaches for a piece,
he lifts a finger
we use deadly force
I'm not gonna give him a chance to hurt us
or Tommy
- Sir?
- What is it?
Our deal was if I saw something--
What happened?
Vic rounded up some guys
to track down who killed Tommy's family
I was one of'emJust to, you know,
make sure Tommy was getting a fair shake
But now?
But now it's gone from a fact-checking mission
into a foxhunt
- And-- And who's with him?
- Julien.
- You let this happen?
Well, I'm not his TO anymore, am I?
Obviously,Julien is responsible for himself
I thought you had some influence over the guy
Okay
Six-Paul-Eleven requesting backup
at 95 Round Hill Road
Possible 1 87 suspect
All right. You take the front.
If he sees the uniform, he runs, he did it
I'll take the back.
Hey, hey No chances
Police! He's got a gun!
He's running! Police!
Oh, shit
He's still got the gun
Couldn't get a good shot
Go out front Wait for backup
Don't come near me!
When he calls, tell him the only way
the public's gonna hear his side of the story
is for him to come forward
and tell the truth himself
- And what ifhe doesn't call?
- He's gonna want to hear our answer
You really think he's gonna give it all up
just to make it clear he's not impotent?
- Why would he do that?
- Uh, because he's mentally ill
Don't come near me!
The thing I couldn't take about prison--
the stink
Piss and shit
You're looking at 1 0 years of that
before they hit you with the needle
The worst part--
you can't fix up when you're hurting
Sometimes you can't fix at all
- Shut up!
- Me?
I'd eat a bullet right now
Backup's two minutes out!
You got two minutes
before the cavalry gets here.
You think it over
Suspect who killed Tommy Hisk's family
Saw the stolen property in the house
Vic's trying to get him
to put the gun down and come out.
Hope he doesn't try too hard
Stick the gun in your mouth and pull
Last chance
Do it, Soren
Don't shoot!
Please, don't shoot!
Put your hands behind your head
Turn around
Take him
Come here
- Behind your back.
Thank you Bye
- Check out the wheels
- Chrome 22's. Sweet.
- How much you think?
- I don't know--a couple of night's work.
Set of Kruz Laguna chrome 22's
run you around $3,200
Throw in another grand for the spinners
Looks like our breeder
knows a thing or two about rim jobs
Rim jobs
In front of the camera,
so the cops can't do nothing to me
I can arrange that.
I'll say what I gotta say,
but he's gotta take back what he said.
No one there except you, me and him.
You mean Detective Wagenbach.
He needs to apologize.
I'm putting one of my men in
with the camera
No, not unless you know someone
who can run a Sony D-600.
You get the arrest,; we get the video.
I've done this dozens of times.
My camera guy was in the middle of Baghdad
when Desert Storm started
I want at least two guys in close proximity
- I can handle it
- Three backup teams...
with radio contact, and everyone's
wearing a vest, or you get no video
Back home, I had a Chevy 1 500.
Four-barrel carb on a high-rise
Slapped them paddle tires on every summer.
Sand-dragged the shit out of it
I had an F-1 50 with a NOS system
- so the nitrous shot straight into the manifold
My brother did that to a Dodge short bed.
- Aw, that was a bad move.
- No shit
Threw a rod, sent it sideways, tires smoked--
-Junked the whole engine, huh?
- Yeah
- Hey, faggot!
- Hey! Come here, punk!
- Yeah! Come on! Come on!
Move! Move!
Hold it! Police officer! Police officer!
- Drop the bat! Drop the bat right now!
- Police! Stop right there!
- Turn around!
- You! On the ground! On the ground!
Turn around! Turn around! Get over here!
Get over here! Against the wall!
Stop! Stop right there!
Nice tackle
- What's this?
- The collar you and me been working on all day
Oh, right We're good
DA says this case
has got the makings of a hate crime
Yeah, that'll work,
but they're also in it for the money
- Got a confession outta one
- Spilled his guts.
Football players
After the game, they go knock back a few
and then go looking for a few queers
to beat up
Rip 'em off for their trick money,
pay the bar tab
- How'd the Strike Team do?
- Fine.
That one's a natural born
undercover cum-guzzler
- Hey, I heard that, bitch
You went off the grid today?
Who told you that?
I knew Tommy didn't do it Didn't like
that Griggs asshole trying to prove otherwise
Today was a one-time thing, got it?
Got it
You weren't at the basher sting tonight?
I was there in spirit Bust got made
You never disappeared for a couple of hours
to help another cop?
You look like hell
Is everything else all right?
Long day, that's all
I replaced the gasket on the filter
- It's working just fine again
- Thanks for doing that
Matt having another session?
Not tonight
Owen's here a lot lately, isn't he?
Matthew's improving
Something you wanna tell me?
- About what?
- About you and Owen
Did Cassidy say something?
No
You walked by the doorway in your panties
without batting an eye that he was inside
- I don't have to discuss this with you
- Yes,you do.
I want him the hell away from Matthew
- He's not his father.
- No, but he's here for him
I'm not shelling out my own money...
so the hired help
can play Daddy to impress you
Get rid of him!
He's an amazing teacher
and that's what you pay for
Anything else is my business
You know he has a record?
He got busted for weed in college
- You've been checking up on him?
- You're damn straight!
He's alone with my son!
So he smoked a joint 1 5 years ago
It wasn't possession It was for dealing
It couldn't have been that serious
if he got his teaching certificate
You date who you want, but he's out of a job
I talked to a buddy over at Wilshire
Arnovic's given a full confession
- Good
- Not good
He's telling them about how Tommy had him
break into his ex's house last month
- What's that gonna mean for him?
- Probably his job
I didn't have a shot
I know
You did the right thing riding with me today
People saw you stepped up
I'm going to church tonight
I'll say a prayer for him-- for his wife and kid
Say one for all of us
It's now four hours past
the designated surrender time
of the alleged rapist
who's been terrorizing elderly women
in the the Farmington District of Los Angeles.
Is he sending a message
that it's your department who's impotent?
You may as well turn this off,
'cause it's never gonna air
- We're chasing our tails
- We would've been better off
if the money train never happened.
- Give me a break
- Calm down, girls.
Now, we know Treasury's got Aceveda
checking bills on any bust over a grand
- So?
- One of the unis just logged
two large into Evidence
We don't let that money out of our sight,
we'll find the list he's working with
Here's your phone list
and your schedule for tomorrow
Did you call Aurora back?
- Not yet
- You really should.
I'll do it when I do it
- What?
- Something's bothering you
- If it's anything that I did--
- It's not, Nina
Please,just check the bills in Evidence
like I asked you to
- What do you need?
- Shane thinks he forgot
to sign that evidence envelope from that 21 1
- No, he signed it
- All right. Great. I'll let him know.
- He was never coming.
- No
I embarrassed him;
he wanted to embarrass me
Probably.
It's more self-control
than I gave him credit for
We still got some time
before we have to get back to work
You could buy me breakfast.
I'm broke
We know...
where he lives, where he hunts.
Now we've got him on tape
Voice analysis will tell us his ethnicity,
personality traits
We're getting to know him
I was wrong
You were right
Maybe a little
Come on.
I'm buying
Hey, Nina Could you, uh, help
with the computer in the briefing room?
- It's not taking my access code
- I can't right now
You know, it's really kinda urgent
It's, uh--
I'm trying to access this database
I'm working on something for David Sorry
- Thank you
- Have a good night
Close it
The list's in Aceveda's safe
- Well, so that's it
- Not necessarily
- Well, what do you mean?
- Ripping off the money train
was 1 0 times more complicated
It's in a safe in a captain's office
inside of a police station.
Without that list,
none of that money is any good
Yeah.
There's gotta be a way