Bang! You're dead.
Now, on the day, there'll be two guys
with Glocks at 11:00.
Damn, I thought you said it was 9:00.
That's why
we're rehearsing.
- Mind getting that thing off of me?
Gives me the creeps.
There'll be no one inside that bay.
Vans will pull in there.
We'll be waitin'for 'em.
- Secrecy over muscle.
- Yeah.
So how much dirty money
is this thing gonna be carrying?
Enough for the four of us
to retire.
- Sorry I'm late.
- This job depends on the four
of us having our act together.
- Where the hell were you?
- I've been driving around in circles.
I thought I was being followed
by some Mexican.
- One of Armadillos's boys?
- I don't know.
Maybe. Uh...
Maybe it's just some pizza delivery guy.
Stalked by a cheese and sausage.
- This greenlight thing is serious.
- You been gettin' enough sleep?
Yeah, just being cautious.
Okay, good. All of us should be
extra careful till we find this prick.
Now that paranoia boy's here,
you gonna run through this thing again?
- Till we get it right.
- All right. Let's do it.
Marcy Lindhoff agreed
to a plea.
How much time's
she getting?
Eight years, in exchange for testimony
against her husband.
Eight years?
The D.A. agreed to that?
To avoid shining the light
on our screwup, yes.
We had the victim alive
in a car trunk...
in our own parking lot for hours
until you released the main suspects...
at which point she died.
The D.A. arranged for you
to take Marcy's statement.
Confirm the facts she gave him
jive with your investigation.
Dutch, the chief
called me personally.
He's not pleased,
and to be honest...
I'm concerned about
your performance as well.
Uh, I'm going through
a rough patch.
- It happens to everybody.
- Claudette says you're moody, distracted.
She said that?
You need to start
closing cases...
and closing them
without incident.
Okay.
Detective!
It's Doug
from the front desk.
Detective!
Detective,
that couple's at it again.
Aren't you going to do something?
Goddamn it.
- You want me to back you up?
- I've only done this about 3,000 times.
Okay, if you need me,
I'm here.
- Yes?
- I live across the street.
I'm here about the noise.
I'm sorry.
I had the TV set up too loud.
Let me in. I wanna talk to the jackass
who's beatin' on you.
- I'm fine, really.
- Is he still here?
No.
It was just an argument.
- I see he talks with his hands.
- I didn't call the police.
Yes, you did,
through my closed windows.
- Look, it won't happen...
- I can't lay in bed and listen
to him doing it to you, okay?
- So you're either gonna move...
or get some help.
- We can't afford to move!
I don't need any help!
If you're not gonna move,
then you're gonna get some help. Let's go.
- You gonna be okay?
- Yeah, I'm perfect.
Congratulations
on your plea.
- Thank you.
- The plea's bullshit, Marcy.
You deserve life
just like Bob.
No, I mean, thank you.
I guess the D.A. didn't
want this to go public.
You need to be 100% open and honest
with me, or you lose your deal, understood?
- Yes.
- The peephole... Who put it in and why?
That was Bob. He liked how Kayla looked.
He wanted to see more.
- You were okay with this?
- Bob liked bringing other women into our bed.
I wanted him to be happy.
Did Bob want to bring Kayla
into your bed?
He asked me to talk to her.
I did. She wasn't interested.
So you lured her over
to your apartment one night?
Bob was... obsessed.
He thought
she was so pretty.
Bob said it was your idea
to cut off Kayla's arm.
Yeah.
After that, she, uh,
she wasn't so pretty.
Okay.
Me and Shane are gonna clear the roof.
Ronnie, you disarm this guy.
Lem, you hit the ground,
grab the truck.
- Hit 'em fast and leave 'em reelin'
- It can work.
Why are we even talking about this
when Armadillo's got a hit out on us?
We got feelers out on the street.
We get a call, we'll grab him.
And when we do,
Vic and me got a plan.
We're gonna tie him up, stick him
someplace safe till we hit the money train.
Then we're gonna leave him dead
in the getaway truck.
The Armenians and cops
will think the Torrucos are responsible.
- Two birds with one stone.
- Only one problem.
- Besides the fact we don't
know where Armadillo is?
- Stop being such a pussy.
Excuse me for wanting
to stay alive.
Then let's stick
to the job at hand.
What are we gonna do
with the money?
- It's too much to spend right
away without drawing attention.
- We launder it.
Got a friend who just bought into a restaurant.
Practically an all-cash business.
That's what I.A.D. is gonna look into.
We can't do this alone.
You're sayin'
let someone else in?
Someone we can control, who's gonna
be more afraid of us than going to prison.
You used to know
a guy named Tio?
- Why are we not in a police station?
- Theodore Osmond, drug dealer.
Guy you helped to buy
a comic book shop in another building.
Tio, sure. I heard somebody, uh,
burned him to death.
- That's terrible.
- So you did sell him the store?
I brokered that deal.
I'm a licensed realtor.
- Then you know Tio sold
narcotics out of that store.
- No.
He bought the place cash.
Where'd you think he got his money from?
I don't ask my clients
where they get their money.
Is that because most of your clients
are drug dealers?
I think you specialize
in buying property for drug dealers...
so they can launder money.
- Isn't that right?
- This is ridiculous.
Checked your files,
Leith.
Tied you to four
major dealers.
How'd you like to see
our police station now?
I don't touch
any of that.
I just buy and sell
property.
The only property you're gonna be
sellin' now is bunk space in Pelican Bay.
Please.
Wh-What do you guys want?
Real estate.
She'll have to be wait-listed
at another shelter.
Can't you pull some strings?
She's a neighbor. You're a friend.
I filled my last bed this morning.
What about a hotel?
She can't afford a hotel.
I might be able
to double her up someplace.
Do, and I'll owe you dinner.
Even if I find a spot,
she's not gonna go.
And I'm partial
to steak joints.
They don't leave until they call
from the street or the hospital.
She didn't even call.
It's a waste of time.
Just find a bed.
I'll put her in it.
Is that everything?
Yeah. We're done.
Why'd you do this?
It just kind of... happened.
No, I mean, uh...
what made you think
you could fool me?
I didn't fool you.
I just let you
fool yourself.
Dutch, how'd it go?
- I got everything I needed.
- Good, 'cause we got a case.
Woman strangled to death
in Fairview Park.
You sure you want
my help?
According to Aceveda,
I'm moody and distracted.
He said that to you?
Why am I even in a police station?
I didn't do anything.
Fine. Go home.
Next time Prince Charming starts using you
for sparring practice, keep it down.
Look... I know it's hard
to leave your home.
- It was hard my first time.
- I don't need a damn shelter.
Sometimes staying away even one night
makes him realize he's crossed a line.
If you don't do it now...
you might never get
another chance.
- I don't even have any of my stuff.
- Here, give me your keys.
- I'll bring you whatever you need.
- I don't want you in my house!
I'll get you some clothes.
You can't make somebody
get help.
Sure you can.
Keep working on her.
You don't know
what you're talking about.
So eight years as a street cop cleanin'
up messes like this means nothin'?
It's a different game when you're the one
on the receiving end of a fist.
That's why the next time this guy wakes me up,
I'm gonna have a chat with him.
It'll stop. Trust me.
Stop violence
with violence?
Why do men
always have the answers?
That's a good question.
- Any witnesses?
- No.
Couple of teenagers smoking joints
discovered the body.
Found her purse and wallet
in the bushes.
Her name's
Leah Madson.
Never seen a victim strangled
with an over-the-shoulder boulder holder.
I'm not in the mood, Ray.
M.E. said no prints
on the victim's body.
Doesn't appear to have been forcibly
removed. Bra's not damaged either.
But the clasp is missing.
- Probably fell off when he strangled her.
- What are you thinking?
I don't know.
Uh, rape turned homicide maybe.
What's this?
Chocolate?
It's on her fingers.
Means she helped him remove the bra.
This didn't start off
as a rape.
- They knew each other.
- Yeah.
Guess I'm wrong again.
Downtown just faxed
a list of promotions.
Stewart and Hernandez
got the two senior lead officer spots.
I was next in line
for that.
I know.
This has to do with the complaint
the widow's been filing against me, huh?
The marijuana I.A.D.
found in my car.
I.A.D. believed you. There's no reason
that should have any bearing...
Come on!
That promotion was a lock.
You're telling me this has nothing to do
with the bogus complaints put against me?
Of course that's what this is about,
but the brass will never admit it.
You're gonna have to
ride this out.
Detective Vendrell.
There's somebody here
to see you.
Well, well, it's the penis flytrap.
Hope you're not a daddy.
Hey, Georgia.
Can I talk to you?
I'm, uh...
I'm a little busy right now.
I got a case.
Illegal activities.
My ex, selling 'scrip drugs
to illegals, grannies...
anyone looking for
a cheap way to medicate.
- Sounds like you found
yourself a real winner.
- I said my ex.
Bastard was banging my neighbor while I was
sweating my ass off at the strip club.
Figured the best way to pay him back
would just be to drop a dime on him.
Still all class, huh?
Are you still upset
about what happened between us?
Nothing happened
between us.
Come on.
It was just fun.
No. It was blackmail.
Seriously.
My ex,
he's a bad dude...
and I would only trust
a really good cop with this.
Look around and take your pick.
I'm not your guy.
So why aren't we following up
on Tulips's lead?
She's a lying whore.
I trusted her,
and she screwed me.
From what I saw that day,
the screwing was mutual.
I just don't want to
be around her.
So we lose an easy bust on our record
because you got played for a fool?
Fine. Fine.
Brent. Brent, it's okay.
I got it.
You, come with me.
Groovy.
You know this woman, Stu?
This girl at the rib joint I work at
set me up with her.
- Went out with her last night?
- We met at her place at 9:00.
How long did you stay?
I didn't.
I wasn't attracted to her.
I figured,
why waste both our time?
- Where'd you go then?
- Home.
- Anyone who can corroborate that?
- I don't think so.
I just went home,
watched some TV.
Any word on Stu's alibi?
No one to confirm
or deny.
- What about his coworkers?
- I'm heading over to talk to them now.
Long as I'm not too moody
to change my mind...
or too distracted
to lose my way.
Why is what I said to you in confidence
about Dutch coming back to me?
Because his results lately
are a concern.
I was concerned about Dutch personally,
not about his job performance.
It's not just me.
This is the chief.
Bob and Marcy were a serious
black eye for us.
It happened right under the nose
of our civilian auditor.
- Is Lanie behind this?
- She hasn't been here in a few weeks.
Who knows who
she's talking to?
Until further notice, you'll be
lead investigator on all your cases.
Oh. How is Dutch supposed to get back on
the horse when you cut him off at the knees?
- I just don't want to see him screw up again.
- He won't.
I hope not.
- Because if he does,
I can't protect him anymore.
- Why?
Too busy protecting Vic?
Who the hell are you?
What the...
- I'm a cop.
- What do you want?
Look, I don't know what she told you,
but she's a lying bitch.
She said it was all her fault.
You didn't touch her.
The lying bitch.
Hey, where you going?
Where is she, man?
What, you sleepin' with her
or somethin'?
Answer me, man!
That's not hers. It's my sister's.
Give it back.
I said give it back!
Thanks, asshole.
- You just made me a very happy man.
- Ow!
Thank you
for bringing lunch.
Wait till you see the spread you get
when you're actually my husband.
So it's okay if I drop off Randall later
when I get my dress fitted?
- Sure.
- What's wrong? You seem a little distracted.
- Uh...
- Don't tell me. Cold feet.
No, no. No.
- So?
- Um...
The prayer group that I go to
on Thursday night isn't just Bible study.
What else is it?
- It's also a sexual reorientation group.
- Reorientation?
I've made some bad choices
in my past.
- Bad relationship choices.
- We all have.
- It's okay.
- Mm-mmm. Mm-mmm.
Um...
I used to be attracted
to men...
but through counseling and the grace of God
and Jesus, I've straightened myself...
- You're gay?
- No. No, I am not.
Oh, God. God.
- Randall looks to you like you're his father.
- Vanessa. Vanessa.
I am the man that God
intended me to be.
I am with a beautiful woman.
I'm about to start a family.
I love you.
I just didn't want any secrets.
- When was the last time you were with a guy?
- It has been months.
I've been in this group
for months.
You had sex with a man?
I... I have made mistakes
in my past...
but I am begging you for your
understanding and your forgiveness.
I need you.
I need to think.
Hey, hey, baby! Baby!
Baby, tell them it's all good with us!
You said you wouldn't arrest him!
He's on parole!
If he goes to jail, he loses his job.
I lose my apartment.
- You stay alive, and I get some goddamn sleep.
- Keep your hands off her!
- He didn't hit me. Let him go.
- Stay back.
- I'll take her.
- Baby, get me out of here.
- Call Skeeter. He knows a bail guy.
- Shut up.
A couple can hit each other,
hate each other...
but tell them they're wrong
for each other, they look at you
like you're speaking in tongues.
Gee, I never heard that before.
You actually thought she wouldn't go back
to him? Are you unromantic or just dumb?
I just didn't want to
hear 'em in my living room anymore.
It's harder to get out
than you think.
- Like the bad boys, did we?
- It had its appeal for a while.
And then it didn't.
She hasn't hit bottom.
She's not ready
for me yet.
He touches her again,
he's mine.
You just can't stand
anything you can't control.
That's part of my dance.
Your, uh, coworkers say you're a bit
obsessive about your weight.
Summers at fat farms,
dozens of diets...
weight training,
yoga, running.
- All true.
- What happened with Susan Lane?
Aggravated assault
when you were 12 years old.
That's what they called it. She didn't want
people to think she was a slut.
Now, you and some other kids
were playing spin-the-bottle.
On her spin,
the bottle pointed to you.
She was supposed to kiss you.
She refused. You were humiliated.
So 11 years later, I killed some chick?
Come on!
A few days later, you followed
Susan home from school.
You told her to kiss you.
She refused.
You struck her.
You broke her nose.
She tried to kiss me.
I wouldn't.
She slapped me,
so I hit her.
You were the last person
to see Leah Madson alive, Stu.
- Except the killer.
- Yeah, except the killer.
Pretty quiet in there.
Any thoughts?
Uh... hard to read.
- Let's check his apartment,
see what we can come up with.
- Yeah.
Keep it short and simple.
Tell him I got a supply, I need a buyer.
Just, uh, get a time and place
and then hang up the phone.
- How come you don't look at me?
- What?
You don't look at me.
Just make
the goddamn call.
God.
It's me.
Mmm, look,
I don't want to fight.
I've got a guy who wants to
hook you up with some product.
Hell, yeah, I'm still pissed,
but you know what? A buck's a buck.
- Danny, find the bra clasp?
- Nothing yet.
I'm guessing it's here
or in his car.
Maybe on a shoe or, uh...
We find that bra clasp,
we've got this guy dead to rights.
We're lookin'.
Odd place.
What's it tell you
about our guy?
Uh... I don't know.
You must be thinking something.
What's your gut tell you?
There are red flags
everywhere with this guy.
- Red flags for what?
- Possible serial predator.
- Think he's a serial killer?
- Or a rapist.
He has the makings of one...
the obsession with detail...
the, uh, reliance
on fantasy.
They're warning posts.
He's young, and if he is one,
I'm guessing Leah's his first or second.
- You know, it's a bunch of crap.
- No, no.
We got nothing else to go on.
It's worth exploring.
- We need to find the bra clasp, people.
- Our guys are already on it.
Let's go back to the barn,
get a confession from Stu.
- I don't have anything to work with.
- You've done it before.
I'm gonna head back to the crime scene,
make sure those guys didn't miss anything.
Three, four million, I can get you
a few 10-acre lots in Castro Peak.
They'll appreciate nice
in a few years.
Nothing in your name,
but you'll have total control.
- All cash.
I usually get
a five-percent commission.
- Why don't we make it ten percent?
- Uh...
Ten?
Good faith.
Plus a little extra money,
since you're taking the extra risk.
What extra risk?
Well...
if you even think
about rattin' us out...
we tell the four drug dealers you've been doin'
business with that you ratted them out.
Bang, bang.
I understand.
Look, you guys searched
my apartment, right?
There was nothing there.
I'd be hearing about it if there was.
If you're so innocent, maybe you'd like
to take a lie detector test?
No.
Afraid of something?
No, I just hear
they're not so reliable.
What if I took it, and it said
I was guilty when I'm not?
He's suspicious but clean.
Dutch has a theory though.
What's your theory,
Claudette?
I don't have one.
Ask Dutch.
It's nothing.
He thinks Stu's guilty.
He shows signs
of being a predator.
- We have any proof?
- There are definite warning signs.
He refused to take a lie detector,
talked about getting a false guilty reading.
Nobody who's innocent
does that.
Thinking he's guilty is one thing,
proving it's another.
Find out who did it
and close this case.
A night at a shelter is a good first step,
so how do we get her to take it?
- Not by forcing her caveman style.
- I do have to get some sleep.
And I wanna see her
stay in one piece.
I have been known in dire times
of resorting to trickery.
If I spend a night
in the shelter...
Dez won't have to
spend a night in jail.
It's a new city law.
We have to hold alleged
abusers overnight...
for the woman's safety.
Okay, then. I wanna try your place
for a night.
Good.
Nice tits.
How much they cost?
Hundred percent natural.
Jealous?
- Is she legal?
- Born in Inglewood, bitch.
- I meant is she 18, stupid?
- Yeah, and I take her everywhere with me.
- She doesn't piss me off.
- Screw you.
- Not anymore.
- Ah, and you miss it. He gets it all now.
So this asshole's
your new boyfriend?
- Yeah, it's a relief not
having to fake it anymore.
- Can we get down to business?
So what you got?
- Uh... Ex, oxy, pot, mash, stash, Rx.
- I need Viagra.
Yeah, you do.
Anything to make it bigger
like my man's?
- I need "V" and Ex. That'll be all.
- How much weight you need?
Start out slow.
How 'bout five-grand worth?
Five grand?
Yeah, I'm your man.
- Don't forget about my cut.
- I pay loverboy.
You get your money from him.
- That wasn't the deal. That was not the deal!
- Is now.
- Just get in the car, dear.
- Anything you say, honey.
Here you go.
You got the money?
Here's your 5K.
- If this stuff sucks, I'm comin' after her.
- Be my guest.
- He doesn't mean that. That's love talk.
- Let's go.
All right. Let's go. Piggies in the air!
Right now!
Turn around!
Come on! Turn around, high life boy!
Let's go! Hands on your head.
You too, darling. Let's go.
Hands on your head.
You dumb a-hole! You just got busted
by my new big-dick boyfriend!
How does it feel, you fag?
Aah!
- How does it feel?
- Bitch!
Will you shut up?
Damn it.
You ever know
somebody's guilty...
but you just don't
have the evidence?
- On occasion.
- How do you handle it?
You wearin' a wire?
I'm tired of people
gettin' away with murder.
Sometimes the evidence
fits the case.
Sometimes you gotta
make the evidence fit the case.
If you know the guy did it.
We're still working it.
- Hey, still didn't find anything?
- The place is clean.
- I'm gonna take one last look.
- Sure.
- Well?
- You sure you were thorough?
- Yeah.
- Do me a favor. Check one more time.
The trash, uh, his clothes.
- You gonna sign for the overtime?
- Yeah. Just be sure.
Yeah?
I think
I left somethin'.
- You okay?
- Yeah. You?
Actually, I'm not.
I'm having...
A really bad day.
We busted him, didn't we?
This whole thing was about you burning some
guy who dumped you for somebody hotter.
It was not.
And no way was that taco tart
hotter than me.
- You don't think so, do you?
- I think you use people.
You're really upset
with me.
- You got what you wanted.
Just get out of here.
- Oh... my God.
I really hurt you,
just like he hurt me.
- I'm sorry.
- Doesn't matter.
I'm always falling
for the wrong guys...
when I'd just be better off
with someone like you.
Yeah, you would,
but you'll never know.
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
I got like six hours
left on my shift.
Oh.
Well, don't you have to, um,
interrogate me or something?
You know, just to wrap it up.
- Come on. I'm bailed. Let's go, baby.
- She's not going home with you.
- You stay out of my business, bitch.
- Emma?
- I'm doing this for you. It's the law.
What law? They can't keep us apart.
Come on. Let's go.
She needs a break from your macho bullshit,
so go hit somebody else tonight.
You want some too,
bitch?
Dez!
What's going on?
Hey, hey. Stay still. Stay still.
Oops.
It was self-defense.
- She pushed a man off the balcony.
- He was attacking her.
It happened on our property.
There are legal and civil considerations.
- I don't want her in the cage.
- Then bail her out.
Thanks for your help.
- Come on. Let's go.
- Where?
- What are you doing?
- Had some bad mojo in there lately.
I need a new room.
It's all yours,
Dutch-boy.
You couldn't take a lie detector
if you wanted to...
because the wire wouldn't fit
around that thick wrist of yours.
- What?
- You know what word you never use, Stu?
"Fat." I bet people don't call you that
to your face either.
They're too polite.
They should, though, because... you are fat.
You were a fat baby.
You were a fat little kid...
and now you're just
a goddamn whale.
I-I've busted
black killers...
white killers,
smart killers, dumb killers.
Never anybody
as fat as you.
See, the bra you used
to strangle Leah with...
the clasp was broken.
Your, uh, fat fingers
weren't nimble enough to unclasp it...
so you just ripped it off her,
didn't you, Stu?
Which means that bra clasp
is somewhere in your house...
your car, your extra, extra,
extra-large clothes.
I don't need
a lie detector, Stu.
I can get you
on physical evidence.
And let me
tell you something.
A jail cell feels small...
to someone my size.
He's going too far.
- You can't get me.
- I'm gonna get you right here.
I'm unstoppable.
Hey, big guy,
your mom's here.
- Hey, baby.
- Hey, Mom.
Baby, keep your grandma company.
She's in the car.
- I parked it out back, okay?
- Okay. See you, Julien.
See you later, big guy.
- You should've told me sooner.
- I know.
I'm sorry.
I believe you when you say
that you've changed.
- I believe in the power of our Lord.
- Thank you.
But...
if you ever feel...
like you want to be with a man...
- I won't. I won't. I never...
- I need...
I never will be again.
I'm gonna make
the two of you so happy.
Kiss me.
Okay.
Well, uh, I have a hundred things to do
before the wedding.
Okay.
So, um...
so the wedding's
still on?
Don't keep me waiting
up there, okay?
Never.
- She's a beautiful girl.
- Yeah.
I guess I must have
missed somethin'.
Last person I saw you kissin'
was a little more... male.
- You sure you know what you're doin'?
- Yeah.
In that case,
congratulations.
When was the last time you saw
your dick without using a mirror?
Shut up.
So you got set up on a blind date
with Leah Madson.
Oh, wow.
I mean, her friend was cute.
You must have expected a hottie.
Nope. Instead
it's big, fat Leah.
I mean, you deserve better, right?
- I get better.
- No, you don't.
Women won't sleep
with you.
So you're horny.
You figure, what the hell...
park's dark.
Wh-What's the old joke
about fat chicks?
Roll 'em in flour
and aim for the wet spot.
Hey, is that...
is that what it's like?
- I wasn't attracted to her.
- I know.
Leah was fat. She couldn't stop eating.
She had no control.
You hated that.
But there you are...
on that park bench...
hating yourself for every minute
you can't control your little hard-on.
You had this
in your fridge for years.
Never took a bite.
Mmm.
The chocolate bar
was the trigger.
You wanted to get laid. All she could think
about was the candy in her pocket.
She pulled it out,
and you just lost it.
Strangled her with the same bra your
fat fingers were fumbling to get off of her.
That's not who I am.
- Yeah.
- Tell him you found the bra clasp.
Good to know.
We found
the bra clasp, Stu.
It was in your car.
- I'm not fat.
- Yeah, you're not fat.
I'll kill you too!
Say I'm fat! Say I'm fat!
I'm gonna be thin!
I am! I'm gonna be!
Help! Get some help!
Get off of him!
Come on! Get off!
Get off!
Don't move. Don't move.
Cuffhim up.
Hey, Ronnie.
Shane got the pictures back. I don't want 'em
lying around for anyone else to find.
- Can you run 'em by my place?
- Sure.
Listen, while you're there,
can you get my checkbook?
How come?
State won't pony up the money
for a decent burial for Connie.
I figure it's
the least I can do.
Hey, careful out there. I hear the Thai food
delivery guys are packin' heat.
- You guys are dicks.
- Jesus!
Take a joke! God!
If he's freakin' out now, how's he gonna
be takin' down the money train?
Or when it comes time
to take care of Armadillo?
You trust him every day
bustin' down doors.
Doesn't mean I trust him to sit
on a few million for a year or two.
Money does strange things
to people.
All right. We'll keep
an eye on Ronnie.
- You finish up with Tulips?
- Yeah, it was a clean bust. No hitches.
- Nice work.
- Yeah.
Nice job.
Don't sound so surprised.
Well, I was just worried
about you for a little while.
You should have had
more faith in me.
- Nice work.
- I know.
- I'm glad.
- You should be.
I break cases nobody else
in this division can.
I deserve a little more goddamn respect
than I've been getting around here lately.
You wanted me to close a case
without incident?
I did it.
I guess he's back.
I guess so.
You run off to Mexico and miss your
court date, you owe me three grand.
You play with fire,
that's the chance you'll take.
Is he okay?
Unfortunately.
- Guess I should feel bad.
- Don't.
Sorry.
- Hello?
- Matthew's been asking for you.
- He wants to say hi.
- Great. Put him on.
Okay.
Say hi to Daddy.
Matthew,
say hi to Daddy.
O-On the phone.
Talk into the phone.
Say... Say-Say hi.
Matthew? Hey, buddy.
Hey, it's Daddy.
Did you go to school today?
Did you have fun?
Matthew?
Um... you know,
I'm sorry.
Uh, h-he was talking
just a second ago.
- It's okay. Thanks for trying.
- Okay.
- I'm sorry.
- No, no, no. It's okay.
Thanks.
I'll see you.
Your dog or your kid?
Kid. One of three.
I'm more a dog person.
Wife?
Separated.
- Wait. Wait.
- What's wrong?
What's that smell?
- What's goin' on?
- Shh. Get down.
Stay down.
Ronnie!
- Oh, my God.
- Call an ambulance.
Ronnie.
Vic.