- Move!
- Go, boy!
- Here we go. Get him!
- Get outta town.
- Ohh! Blast right now.
That's me.
- Love ya.
- There you are.
- Ohh! Get out!
- Damn it!
Respect me, bitch
I love you too, baby.
- All right. We're goin'again.
- Everything cool with Mara?
- Yeah, why?
- I don't know. Seemed like she was
in a mood or something.
Shit Everything's fine
It's just that this first trimester's
like a 90-day P.M.S. ride.
Yeah Maybe she thinks you're not
takin' it so seriously?
- We're gettin'married, aren't we?
- What,you set a date?
- No, not yet
- What about a ring?
Bought her a Lexus
She can wear that on her finger
- She knows I love her
- Yeah, dude, but
a ring lets her show the rest
of the world that you love her
You gettin' your vagina waxed
next week? Ow!
- Man, you gotta stop that
Well, you gotta pony up
for the rock, man
- Yeah
- Hey It's me
I need you down at
the storage unit ASAP
- Where's Lem?
- He's with me.
- Is there a problem?
- Not on the phone
Got here as quick as I could. Figure we'd catch
another case. Who knew it would be this soon?
- Maybe it's a sign
- What's the situation here?
Actually, it's pretty quiet
Seems to be a total lack of a situation
Well, the message I got said that there
was a drug dealer working out of here
Oh, I may have ''over-exaggerated''
the uh, police nature of this call
And, uh, I suppose you've got
a key to one of
those rooms in there
Look. We been dancin'around
each other for a couple of years now.
Just wonderin'what would happen
if we, uh, ran out of excuses.
- I'm on duty
- I'm not.
You got a pager if they need ya
- I've got a boyfriend
- We already established that
- It's really not a good idea
You're right
You should get back
What am I supposed to do with Koto?
- Do you need to get that?
That's what voice mail's for
- That's the ''Hello'' line
- Quiet!
- Hello?
- Hi, Mama It's Toya
- Trish You all right?
- Nothin'Just chillin'
Um, listen I ain't gonna
make it by for dinner
- Can you say where you are?
- I'm gonna kick it with some friends tonight
Holler at Walon for me, all right?
I love you too, Mama
- Trish is in trouble Walon too
- No more calls
- Why? What's up, boo?
That white dude
you hooked us up with is a cop
- Ah, mm, no, no
- Undercover
- Oh, quit clownin'
- I just got confirmation
- Where you heard that?
- What do you know about him?
Tips good Drinks scotch
Shitty marriage You know
I thought we were comin'
here to have some fun
We could be in some shit
You included
Fifties can't do nothin'
You ain't even done the whack yet
No, but I agreed to
You'll stick with me
Till I can get this shit taken care of
A'ightJust let me check my face
- Who is it?
It's me. Open up.
What's goin'on?
There's money missing
- How much?
- We're seven G's short
I was going through the stash,
getting rid of the marked bills
couldn't find a few.
So I did a count.
We're missin'seven thousand.
Including some marked money
- You sure you counted right?
- I triple-checked.
- Somebody dip in before the shit hit the fan?
- I didn't take squat
- Don't even look at me
- If somebody did, speak up now, it's forgiven.
The important thing is to figure out
where the marked money was spent.
before Treasury gets a whiff of us
I'm serious.
We're the only people who knew it was
here, and the only people with a key
Last chance
Aw, come on!
We've been a team through all of this
Now who took it?
Ripped by:
Hound
Trish was able to make the call,
so let's assume
her cover's still intact,
but Walon was made for sure.
- What's the emergency?
- Walon and Trish
- Any idea where Trish was making the call?
- We're tracing it
I'm gonna need four units
ready to roll
Decoy Squad's been working undercover
on a murder-for-hire sting
Farmtown Twelves'been
doing contract hits...
makin'them look
like drive-bys.
Since when is
the Decoy Squad a gang detail?
The feeling was Trish was
our best way into the case
Walon's supposed to drop the money
for the hit this afternoon--
where, we don't know, but we've got
to get him before the Twelves do
- You tried his cell?
- He was worried he'd be searched
Which raises the question
how this happened.
A more important question is,
how are we getting our people back?
Claudette's got us on goddamn
janitor duty the last month
Meanwhile, Walon's out
hunting down banger trophies
I didn't take that money
Okay
Think there's any chance
Tavon swung with it?
It's not enough you and the missus
put him on life support?
Now you gotta call him a thief?
Look, if he knew about the money,
he would have come to us for a piece
Just so you know...
I'm gettin' Mara
an engagement ring
All right
Just don't go hog-wild
I'm not
I'm goin' through Taylor
You're usin' a fence
to buy your wife her ring?
He knows this guy
who sells 'em wholesale.
- It's all on the level.
- Why not just go down to theJewelry Mart?
'Cause Taylor's guy is cheaper
And I don't speak Farsi
- May I help you?
-Just gotta get my cornrows tightened
- What up, homegirl?
- Man, I'm straight with you
- I need another favor
Yeah, well, you're fresh out
of favors, One Time
You're not hearin' me
too well under there
Yeah, I can see why
Pretty Boy drops the cheese...
to keep his female lookin' tight
Think he'll still keep her laced when he hears
she's been goin'out the back door on him...
- with a Spooktown soldier?
- Still sleepin' with the enemy, Desiree?
- No
- Trick question
- We know you are
- I'm just tryin' to get my hair did
I need to know who in the Twelves
is selling contract hits
Pretty Boy don't talk business with me
Coo in his ear
You got a half an hour,
or I start cooin' in his
- Hands where I can see 'em. Now!
- Hands up!
Let's see your hands
Clear in the back!
- Storeroom clear
- All clear! Canvass it
What's goin'on?
The Farmtown Twelve made a call
from this phone an hour ago
- Where'd they go?
- Don't know
- What were they doing here?
- I let them use my office sometimes
- Why?
- Beats having them burn it down
- Desiree 30 seconds to spare
I was just about to call Pretty Boy Let him
know his number one cooch was on the loose
Kaliel Wilks
Street name, Li'l Psych
Any idea where we can find him?
Yeah, well you work on Pretty Boy
- He gives you anything, you call me
- I'm runnin' it
Got the address where
Walon's making the meet
I got the name of their guy
who runs contract hits:;Kaliel Wilks.
- Got a reputation as a bit of a psycho
- Ever hear of him?
No, but Shane's on it
- Have any idea how their cover got blown?
- Maybe they tailed Walon
Walon might stink,
but he's not sloppy
The rapist works in the area--
delivering pizza
cable TV guy, meter reader--
who knows?
So he uses his job as camouflage
and scopes out his next victim?
Exactly. Thanks for comin'out
on your own time.
- I'm learning tons
- Still
Got to be raisin' hell
with your social life
- Please. I kicked my social
life to the curb last week.
This guy I was seeing bought me this
tennis racket so we could hit together?
Then he insisted that
I leave it at his place
- Talk about control issues
- Cop?
NoJust some guy
- I play
- Yeah? Are you good?
Yes I am, actually
I'd say that we should
hit together sometime
but I'm lousy
Probably bore you
I'm not that good
You think I want
this goddamn ulcer?
- I didn't take that money
- Nobody in here took anything
- So you gonna ask Shane about it?
- I'd bet on his loyalty before
I'd bet on your math skills.
When we're done with this, I want you
to go back with Lem Count again
Check the lock for tampering
Got a picture of our homey
Kaliel Wilks, aka Li'l Psych
- What took so long?
- Had no rap sheet.
Had to go to his Marine Corps file.
- What, he's a jarhead?
- Was.
He duked it out with his CO
They booted him Section Eight
Let's see how he feels with
our size elevens up his ass
Plainclothes has already secured the area.
We'll roll out in 1 0 to take our positions.
- ID'd our trigger boy Combat trained
- Shit
- Copies for everyone
- Once Walon's secure,
I'll call to scoop up the Twelves
- What ifTrish isn't with 'em?
- Haul their asses down here
Make 'em tell us where she is
The captain and I will set up
in a surveillance van.
How long has Trish
been into this guy?
He just popped up a few weeks ago Walon
kept her on the sidelines until he needed her
She went to work at Polebusters,
got close to the Twelves.
Polebusters?
She's under as a stripper?
Cocktail waitress
She cozied up to the bangers
they bragged about their
murder-for-hire racket
she introduced them to Walon
And his murder they'll do for free
Tell me what I have to do
to get back in.
You hired a thief to break into your home.
A thief that later--
Nojury's gonna believe a
smokehound murderer over a cop.
Your sister-in-law corroborated him.
My lawyer says it's hearsay
DA's spinning it so the department
has no choice but to wash their hands
- I need you to talk to him
- Tommy, you can't come back
- It wasn't my fault
- I know you didn't mean for this to happen
And I can only imagine your pain
But I can't have you working here
I'll do what I can to try and make sure
you don't serve any jail time
-Jail time?
- You have to look out for yourself, now
And you still have friends here
- Tommy? What are you doin'?
Aceveda's makin' me
clean out my locker
- Walon and Trish are missin'
- They fell off the grid a few hours ago
- Let me help. Tell me what I can do.
- Tommy--
Why don't you come over to the house
this weekend? We'll watch De La Hoya
Sure
- What the hell is up with that guy?
- Doesn't look like he's bird-watching
- Hang on, pal.
- What's up?
- You want to tell me what you're doin' back here?
-Just now?
Check the occupant
Turn around Hands behind your back
- Oh, I-I have permission
- Hands behind your back
Sorry to bother you, sir We just apprehended
a man looking through your window
Yo, girl! It's all good
Dude with her
- What's wrong?
- Honey, tell them to take these off of me.
- Do you know this man?
- Married to him long enough
- He's your husband
- Told ya
- Look, no one's breakin'the law here, Officer.
We'rejust--
- Playing
Right Role-playing?
On the way to work?
With our, uh, friend
Six hours out there
All we get is a practicing cuckold
You see something like that, you wonder if
we all shouldn't stay home and read the Bible
Thanks My partner
already does that
- How you gonna solve this one?
- Well
you don't hope for another victim,
but the fact is
this guy probably hasn't made any mistakes
that's gonna get him caught yet
- Sorry
- Yeah
Well, thanks a lot
See any Twelves yet? Or Walon?
No Nothing yet
Sit tight
Farmtown crew comin' in
Any sign ofTrish?
Negative
Psych's not with 'em either
- I got Walon.
- Where?
- You should see him
- Shit. Trish isn't with him either.
- Pick up Walon
- Give Trish a few more seconds
They're gonna make him
Pick him up
I got it
Psst Cover's been blown
- Okay Ready?
- Let's move on these assholes
Trish called the Hello line
It's a setup
- Where is she?
- Still missing
- What do we know?
- Not much
- Stop those guys
- We're gonna shake 'em down
Find out where Trish is
No, Li'l Psych will make her
as blowing the whistle
- Let these guys check in
- Walon says we should let these guys go
- Keep Trish's cover intact
- Trish can take care of herself
- Pull them
- Shane Ronnie Abort Abort!
I think I forgot my wallet
Let 'em go.
What do you mean,
he didn't show up?
Well, how did he know
not to show?
I got one morejob to do.
I gotta grease that witness, pick up a quick
ten grand, and we can get the hell out of town
Just sit tight
- Hi
- What you got for me, Daddy?
How do you say
you met this cop?
I didn't know he was a cop Why do
we gotta keep talking about this, boo?
- Ow! Ow!
You know something,
better spit it now
He's just some white cat that I met up
in the club, wanted his business partner killed
Please stop Please
- How long you know him?
- Few months.
If he's a cop,
then I'm in deep shit too
Hear me?
I know
I'll take care of both of us
Yeah, I'll bet you will
Here
Sniff this
- Real power shit
No
I want a clear mind
our first time
We lost the Twelves in the subway.
Didn't you have
a surveillance detail in place?
Well, the plan was to take
everybody down You had us abort it
Look, every available unit
is in on this
- Who's shakin' the trees?
- We're takin'off right now.
- Any idea how you got made?
- Any idea?
- It's the mole
- What mole?
The mole in the system The one I told
you about Keeps warning the Twelves
every time a warrant or a wiretap
request is put through
- We never discussed a mole
- I.A.D. is trackin'it for me.
It's in my case notes
Last week
- I didn't see that!
- It's in the case notes.
You have people in the field
and no clue what they're doin'?
Hey, easy If there's a mole, it's not
Claudette's fault that you got made
It is if she's submitting
wiretap requests for us
- I sent one yesterday
- Aw,Jesus--
All right, I'll uh, I'll call IAD and see
if they're zeroing in on this mole
- What else aren't you readin'?
- You and Trish's names
were not used in the request
I only used the case number.
Her cover is still good.
- What if it's not?
- I-I must have read this quickly
This mole thing
just didn't register
I don't get her back in one piece,
I'll use every goddamn favor I've banked
for the last 1 4 years
to get your lazy ass fired
Come on!
Everyone seems to have heard of
Li'l Psych, but no one can locate him for us
- What have you got?
- IAD's preliminary look into the mole
- They've only had the case a week
- Lemme guess They got shit
Not exactly They've narrowed it down
to court offices on Hoover
- How many employees there?
- 26 F. T.E. 's.
- Give me five minutes with them,
I'll find your mole
- What does five minutes entail?
- A shortcut you can live with
- I'll come with you
- Ligature marks
- Both strangled manually
- Time of death?
- Off the top of my head, four hours ago
Oh, for Christ--
I was three blocks away then!
Landlord found them when
he brought the mail in.
Said this one's her daughter
Been lookin' after her mom
every day, apparently
- Goddamn it!
- You get this worked up over a crime scene?
I been after this guy for a month and a half.
Now two people are dead...
- because I didn't catch him
- Presence of semen...
- on the older victim's abdomen
- The other victim wasn't raped, obviously?
Have to wait for the coroner's report.
Three blocks Horseshit
It's gotta be the cuddler Daughter
came home, interrupted the rape
killed her, finished his business
- and murdered the older woman
- He's never gotten this violent
- What makes you so sure it's your guy?
- It's him
- Witness give you anything?
- What witness?
Saw a man leaving
the building this morning
Uh, excuse me, ma'am, you saw someone
leaving this house earlier?
Yeah, about 8:00
I-I was walkin' my dog
- Did you get a good luck at him?
- He walked right past me
I was pickin' up
after my dog at the time
You know, not enough people
in this neighborhood do.
If you hear anything about Li'l Psych,
you just buzz me pronto
All right?
These aren't stolen, right?
- I'm not givin' my fiancée stolen shit
- No, no, no, no
Look, it's on the level, all right? Hey
Check this one out, right?
This brother caught his fiancée bent over
pullin' a train with his groomsmen
Now, you can imagine his desire
to relieve himself of it
I'm tryin' not to
What else you got?
Okay. Uh-- Oh, that's
a killer piece of ice.
What's the backstory?
Diamond guy I know had a bad run
at the racetrack.
So he unloaded a little inventory
on me below cost
Yeah, it's beautiful
Check out the four C's:;
cut, clarity, carats and color.
Yeah, what about the fifth ''C''?
Cost
- Two grand
- Two grand.
But listen, you give a bitch
a rock like that
she will get on all fours
for you and bark like a dog
- She's my fiancée
- Two G's will keep her that way
Ruff, ruff, ruff
You get pounds of paperwork
comin' at you every day
Detective duty on top of that--
anyone could have missed it
Yeah
Your real problem was goin'
with the Decoy Squad...
and leaving your starters
on the bench
The gangs are our thing.
- Okay, listen up!
- Attention, please!
- Police! Everybody on your feet!
- Let's go
You, you, you, you back there,
and you two in the corner
- Come with me
- What's this about?
- Police business. Keep typing.
- I'm getting Judge Banks
Faster than that!
- Where are you from?
- Detroit
- Santa Monica
- Go sit down. You?
-Jersey City
- Compton
- You go, you stay You?
- Leimert Park.
- Inglewood
- Where'd you go to school?
Belmont.
- How about you?
- Wilson
Oh, that's bad for you.
It's not in Compton.
- I moved to Farmington when I was ten
- What block did you live on?
- Earl Street
- You two, split
- You know any Farmtown Twelves?
- Who didn't?
- You been giving them
a heads-up on our warrants?
- No.
Sure you did. You gave up
a wiretap yesterday.
- You gave up a cop!
- N-No
- Here come de judge
- Listen, I'm gonna have the big boy here...
crawl up your ass and find out
who you been hangin' with
How much do you want to bet
he finds gang ink on your taint?
Answer now or spend the next
eight to ten wishing you had
Raheem Parems
''Pretty Boy''
What the hell is goin'on here?
Judge Banks
We need a warrant
I'm gonna barely be able
to make rent this month
But the look on Mara's face
will make it all worth it.
You think there's any chance
Vic took that money?
What?
He's gettin' a divorce,
a mortgage, rent--
Kid with special needs
It's not like he hasn't taken
the money before without tellin' us
Just shut the hell up
Who's ''Nancy''?
- Police, open up!
Hey, man Ease up on my door
That's real oak
- Ain't that Home Center shit
- Hands against the wall, Pretty Boy
Ah, Desiree Spending a quiet day
at home with your man, huh?
- Must be love
- Turn around, honey Spread 'em
Go on and search
Ain't nothin' on me
- Sit your ass down, skidmark
- Lookin' for your boy Psych
and some bar skank
he's hanging with
- We ain't seen or spoke in weeks
- Really?
'Cause I got a county clerk cryin' about how
she gave you and him some police intel
just yesterday.
Just tell us where
Li'l Psych and the woman are.
- We'll forget we were here
- Y'all don't know nothin'
Aw, I know a few things.
Maybe a few that might surprise you.
- Wanna know what I know, Chunk?
-Just go on and tell him where Psych at, Raheem
- You shut your face, girl
- Look, you said yourself
he wasn't nothin' but trouble
Why you think
they call him Psycho?
Don't let that fool
bring the whole crew down
- Call him up
- Hell, no!
You know what? Forget this
I ain't messin' with no fool
And I damn sure ain't waitin'
around for no jailbird, neither
Now you call him
or I'm out the door!
Mm A little rounder
Yeah Yeah, like that
That's perfect
Let's see
- I thought you said you got a good look at him
- Yeah, that's him
This is an ear attached to a head
- It's a pretty good drawing
- Did he have a couple of eyes,
maybe a nose and a mouth?
- Don't take that tone with me
- This doesn't help us
He walked by quickly
As I think I mentioned
I was scooping poop
at the time
Just heard.
You okay?
Aceveda didn't
lift a finger for me.
What am I gonna do,
work security?
We all end up there
in 20 years anyway
Hey, Tommy You got some pretty big stuff
hangin' over your head right now
Hey You got him to give
you your job back
Different situation
Yeah, but you know what to say.
Maybe he'll listen to you.
All right
- You don't want to talk to him
- No.
- Look, I will.
- You think this was my fault
- No, I don't.
- You just name a night.
Vanessa and I will have you over for dinner.
We can talk about where you should go.
Oh, you mean God's plan?
Yeah, thanks
Appreciate it
Gotta do this hit
and get paid Let's go
I don't know why you're draggin' me into
this, Kaliel I don't wanna see that shit
You brought that cop in to buy a hit
That makes you just as guilty
- Might as well be in on the shit.
- Yeah!
- Li'l Psych Where you at?
- Goin' to that job on Doyle Street
- Oh, really?
- I'm about 1 0 minutes out.
- You know the spot, right?
- 21 30 Doyle Why?
I'm just makin' sure you know
You holler back when you finished
- I'll cash you out
- What the hell are you doin'?
- Got you an address, man
If I told him to stop, he'd have known
something was up
The mark's in there?
Ratted on a ''G'', so his
Christmas has been canceled
Look, boo, the cops are
after us
Maybe we shouldjust
bounce on outta here.
I don't get my paper
till this snitch starts leakin'
It's on
- What are you doin'?
- What the hell you doin'?
- Trish!
Get an ambulance!
- Can you talk?
- Gray Monte Carlo
I got the plate
- It says, ''To Nancy, Love Donald''
- Really?
I checked our computers It was
reported stolen two weeks ago
Yeah
That sounds about right
- I told you to get me a ring that wasn't hot
- But-But you gave me the code
- What code?
- Well, you winked
Like this was all on the hush-hush
- I didn't wink!
- Yes, you did
- No, I didn't
- How did you expect to get
a $1 0,000 rock for two? Huh?
Look, can you get me one
that's on the level or not?
Yeah, but it's gonna cost you
like three or four
- Well,just get me a ring that I can use
- Okay Okay
Paul and Chris spotted
the license plate number you gave us
I had 'em hang on,
so you could hook him up
Thanks
At least your stuff was good
It's a relief that you're all right
A little worse for the wear,
but I was never the Miss America type
I had to do some coke
to keep my cover
I'll put an injury on duty
for you
- Do you need to see a doctor?
- I should get checked out for STD's
- Get the morning after pill
- Son of a bitch!
Well, if you feel that
you need to talk to somebody--
I put a guy out of
the murder business I'm okay
- So sorry, Trish
- Oh, that's cool
- 'Course, that may be the coke talkin
You ready?
Hi Didn't expect
to see you so soon
This is Hunter,
my boyfriend
- Can we talk to you?
- Uh, sure
Tell him what you told me.
Tell him.
What happened today was a mistake
It can't happen again
And?
I'm with Hunter
Don't call me
Got that?
Elderly victim,
same geo-profile
Apartment was visible from the street,
just like all the others
- It's gotta be him
- Lucas said they found semen at the crime scene
I thought your guy
didn't ejaculate
Maybe he found killing arousing
This guy makes the first
two killings of his life
and then spends
the next couple hours cuddling?
I thought the other rapes were in
the early evening This was early morning
Danny, uh,you saw me
put my gun in my locker, right?
- Yeah I think so
- I can't find it
Be right back
Tommy?
What are you doin'?
Walk away
- Okay Get out of the car
- My lawyer says I should plead out
You don't have to do
anything you don't want to
That way I'd get less than a year.
Goddamn prison.
- We can make sure the truth comes out.
- Truth is I deserve more
No, you don't Come on
We can talk about this
Look, man, you got people
inside who care about you
Julien, me We know
what you're goin' through
Yeah, I can see that
Let me talk to Aceveda He's got pull
He can use it if he wants to
I can make him
change his mind.
- So now you'll talk to him
- Yeah I should have done it before
Tommy, you still got family
Let us help you
Okay Get Aceveda
- Gimme the gun
- Let's hear what Aceveda's got to say first
Okay All right, good
Hey, officer in distress!
Outside! Officer in distress!
- Officer in dist--
- This way.
- Shot fired!
What's goin'on?
- Somebody radio for a paramedic.
- Radio for a paramedic!
- All right, come on. Let's go.
The department's providing
a counselor tonight.
And you two can
leave early to attend
- He was a coward
- He thought thejob was all he had left.
Yeah, and we have to clean up
his mess again.
The session's at 8:00
at the Fischman Center
Thanks I think I'll pass
- So?
- We're seven G's shortJust like Ronnie said
- And the lock?
- Not a scratch
Besides, who's gonna steal seven grand
and leave a fortune behind?
So which one of us did it?
Huh?
None of us did it
Look, this whole Tommy thing
has got us all a little raw
Ronnie reported
the money missing
Lem didn't even want
to steal it in the first place.
So when are you gonna
talk to him?
- Day from hell, huh?
- Yeah Worst on record
Even if they don't realize it yet,
you're the one who got 'em back safely
- I thought you were talkin' about Tommy
- That too.
What about that murder/rape?
At first it felt like the cuddler,
but then I threw that out.
Your first instinct's pretty good.
What's your gut say?
That the daughter showed up unexpectedly
He killed her to keep from getting caught
Murder excited him
So much so that he finally orgasmed
- Gets off on murder?
- Why would he cuddle for hours afterwards?
Witness saw a man leaving the house
well after the time of death
- Maybe he left and came back
Came back to the house.
The bodies hadn't been discovered.
- See what he'd done
- Show the whole world how potent he is
Sick. But it's plausible.
You gonna see that counselor?
There's something else
I've been putting off
Listen,Julien Sometimes suicide puts
thoughts in people's heads, you know?
Why don't you go with me?
See what that guy has to say
Well, I guess that's the last thing on my
mind right now I'm in a much better place
I've got Vanessa, Randall--
- We're gonna start our own family
- All right
- Call me if you want to talk
- Okay
It's pretty late, sir, and you've already
missed your last three appointments
I'm a cop My schedule's kind of crazy
Can you just get me in now?
When you're done,
place the specimen here
There's some visual materials
there, if you like
Okay
Where is she?
- Whoa! Take it easy, man
- Stay out of this
Hey! I'm with you
Come here
She belongs behind a desk, not messing
with what we do on the street
It doesn't mean anything She's got
Aceveda and the chief in her pocket
You think I give a shit about that?
She's been playing both of us
against each other from the jump
Now, we start playin' ball together--
She can't command
if we don't let her
Great minds think alike
Do you need anything?
We're closing up in five minutes.
I'm fine
- Yeah
- It's me
I'm sorry about before
He caught me in a lie, and
he kept wanting more details
- and I just didn't want to lie anymore
- How are you?
I have some things
I have to work out
- I've been with him for four years, and--
- I understand
- Listen, don't do anything on my account
- I know
- Sorry you got put in this position
- I'm not
- Okay
You think you can buy me off?.
- Sit down
- I'm cleaning
I need you to sit down
Why don't you sit down?
Playing my favorite song
is not gonna work either
- It's for the baby
- What if it's a girl?
Just open it
It's incredible
I've just been such a pain
It's just that being alone and--
- Don't worry about it
- and dealing with my mother--
You're not your mother
And I'm nothing like my father
This thing's gonna work
Oh, baby!
- I love you
- I love you too
Vic?
Hey!
What's goin' on, man?
- Bad timing
- No We, uh--
Wejust got engaged.
Officially.
Look
- That's nice
- What's up, man?
It can wait.
- You sure?
- Yeah You celebrate, celebrate
Hello?
Uh, Detective Wyms
Sorry Can I help you?