Elisa. Be a good bitch. Get out here.
- Ready?
- Yeah, let's go.
Let's go, let's go.
Ah Detective Wagenbach
Craig Milne Pleasure
This is my partner, Claudette Wyms
The minute I saw the scene,
I thought of your case
Strangled, sexually assaulted
Semen on the abdomen
- It's him
- He's moved his hunting grounds
- We're canvassing, but so far, nothing
- Point of entry?
Back door. I know your guy steals figurines,
but this lady was a clean freak.
There's no dust
It's hard to tell if anything's gone
I contacted her kids They'll be able to
tell us more about her movements tonight
- Help establish a timeline
- Great. After you've done your report--
Oh, absolutely I'll put a rush
on the DNA and keep you posted
We should cross-check our notes
for similarities
Workin' on a name for the baby yet?
Uh, no, we're gonna wait
till we find out if it's a boy or a girl.
Let me look at your ring again
Oh!
- You found yourself a good one this time
- I know
A real Southern gentleman.
Ma, I, uh-- I need to talk to you
about that money that we gave you
You don't know how much it helped
We're not asking for it back
See, one of my clients gave it to me
A two percent kickback for moving
their bid to the front of the line
People do it all the time
in the real estate business It's just--
- It's just that it's not exactly--
- Legal?
Look, it's not a big deal
What Mara didn't know
is that this guy, he's, uh--
he's a bit of a player
I found out that the feds are investigating him
and that the money could be dirty
So, if anyone comes asking
you can't say
that it came from me 'cause--
'cause I could lose
my real estate license
It wouldn't be the first time
I covered for you, would it, sugar?
Yeah
Where's the goddamn money?
Let her go, man!
Do it now!
- Put the money in the bag!
Let's go
I need money! Hurry!
I swear to God,
I'll blow your head off
- Stop screwing around!
- Okay, okay!
- What the hell, man? Move your ass!
- And the coins too, asshole!
And the coins too!
Okay, okay! Don't shoot!
Let's go, let's go! Now, bitch!
Police!
- Get down! Get down!
Call 9-1 -1
Ripped by:
Hound
Two in the 1 0 ring Nice
- Yeah
- Two got away, and you hit one of them?
Yeah, in the, uh, arm
or the shoulder
I'm gonna have to
take your weapon, Captain
Well, it's my personal piece
I, uh, was running errands
when I saw the robbery go down
When we get an I.D., check your gang
contacts, see who his running mates are.
They're Byz Lats
I'll rattle a few cages
You wanted back on the street,
promised you'd be more valuable there
I want to know every pressure point
this gang has by morning
The dead guy watched me shove a bong
down his buddy's windpipe
Twenty bucks says his buddy's
one of the other shooters
Captain out here in the middle
of the night, he runs into them?
- It's a pretty big coincidence
- Unless it's not a coincidence
What if these are the guys Diagur sent
to get the money out of the freezer?
What, the ones you told him
to send over?
If it's true, then these are the assholes who
kicked the shit out of Aceveda, took his gun
which means he was tracking them here
when this thing went down
He might track 'em right back
to us and that marked cash
Let's not get premenstrual
until we talk to Diagur Come on
Jesus, Diagur!
Who are these guys, huh?
Every time I see you, you've got
your mouth wrapped around a clam
Throw something on
We've got problems
Killing Ricky was payback for him
and Juan getting his gun off him
Ricky,Juan Those are the guys
you sent for the marked money?
- Juan, he was in on this robbery?
- Yeah
- What about the other guy?
- Talking about Vido?
One of my boy's cousins
He wanted courting in
Nice initiation,
shooting at a cop
They told me they were
gonna rob some slant-eyes
- They check in yet?
- No
When they do, you tell them
to get their asses out of here
I'm not talking about a long weekend
in Eagle Rock I mean Mexico
I'll take care of the rest.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine
You didn't call
I just saw it on the news
I'm trying to track down
the two guys who escaped
David, you shot someone,
they shot at you
Come home
Whatever's happened
you need to come home now
I'm not finished
How's Matthew doing
with his workshops?
Very well. His aptitude
for cognitive reasoning's accelerated.
Ideas and thoughts are often clearer
- How's he doing with other kids?
- He's internalizing less
So he's making friends
He still keeps mostly to himself
but he's getting more curious.
These are great
The children's assignment
was to draw a picture of their family.
- Where's Matthew's?
- I took it down
I didn't think you should see it
without an explanation first
What kind of explanation?
Matthew's picture was
ofhis mother, his two sisters...
and his therapist, Owen
It's often common for autistic kids
to become confused
- during changing situations, right?
- Absolutely.
I can get you the drawing,
if you want
- Sure
- Okay.
- Yeah
- My mom wants more money
What?
She did the math
Two percent of a $600,000 sale
- She said that adds up to more than seven grand
- She said that?
- When?
- As soon as you walked out the door.
She waits to get me alone
to pull her shit
Well, maybe you just misunderstood
She asked me
for another three grand
- What did I misunderstand?
- Your mother is blackmailing us
Look, let's just give her
the money, okay?
No
Ronnie, could you close that door?
I know who took our cash
from the storage locker
It was Mara
It was all the midnight runs we were doing
She got suspicious
- She thought that I was hiding
something from her.
- I don't believe this
Look, she found a key.
She tracked down the storage place
from a receipt
She thought that the cash was mine
- I'm sorry. I was careful--
- Does she know about the money train?
No, no She thinks that we've been
skimming off drug busts or something
''We''?
She knows that we're involved?
We need her help
with the marked bills in Indio
Why? Who's in Indio?
- Mara's mother lives there
-Jesus Christ!
-She sent her a few grand,
before I knew she had it.
- So the mom knows too?
- No, but she thinks there's
more where that came from
- This is beautiful.
We're already in deep shit with the marked
money if Aceveda tracks down Diagur's errand boy
- Now we gotta sweat
your future mother-in-law?
- I'm trying to wrap her up
I'm trying to wrap her up, but the broad is
a piece of work Mara's got horror stories
How come every piece of ass you hit
is more trouble than the last?
- Hey, I'm marrying this girl
- Well, I'm not, all right?
- So unless she's got a pussy that cures cancer--
- Shut your mouth right now!
Hey, hey.
Look, Mara's having my child
We can trust her
You know what I would do
if I had her in interrogation?
I'd tell her the only way
to save her kid's daddy
is to give up
the three guys he works with
It'd take about 1 5 minutes
to flip her
- We can trust her
- 'Cause you say so?
Mara's not the problem
at the moment
The mom is.
They don't get on to her,
they can't get back to us
- I will keep working on the mom
- No.
We have to erase the trail
without her knowing
And how are we gonna do that?
We gotta think--
Juan Lozano,
one of the guys I shot at
Pretty quick ID
Yeah, I checked the dead guy's priors,
looked for known accomplices
Follow me
I want you in on this too
Lot of manpower for a robbery
You weren't the one with bullets
flying past your head
Juan Lozano, Byz Lats soldier
Take a look at the map
of their territory
Turn every block over
Anybody catches this guy, I'd like a call,
as a professional courtesy...
so I can bring him in myself
All right, that's it
Vic, uh, what were you
able to find out?
What businesses
are the Byz Lats into?
- They got some juvies running rock
- What else?
Some gambling joints
A body shop that moonlights
in crap shooting, poker
That sounds profitable
Let's take a run at it
- I'll talk to my CIs, and I'll organize a sting
- No
Right now, you and me
Assistant Chief Phillips just called.
He wants you to send copies of all
your cuddler files to the Hollywood Division
- Why?
- No clue
He's reassigning the case
to the hotshot
- No one said that to me
- Makes sense.
We've had five victims in two months,
and I'm down to working scraps
Probably didn't help making an ass
of myself in front of Phillips
I appreciated that
Maybe it does need
a new set of eyes.
This is still our case.
I, for one, could use a win.
So what's the plan?
Oh, not much of one
I checked out guys who got more
than one parking ticket in a hot zone
week prior to an attack
In case he's driving the area,
scoping out women on foot
Yeah, but it's pointless None of'em
are registered sex offenders
Maybe we should go back to
our original list of probables
see what they've been up to
this past month
- How many parking tickets you got?
- Four
Okay Let's start with them
Call them in first Rule it out
All right
Go, go, go! Give me the gun!
Hands in the air right now!
- Your hands right now!
Stay right there, fat boy
Who runs this place?
Call your boss,
get him down here
I never read those damn signs,
but I thought I paid my outstanding tickets
- Am I in trouble?
- This is regarding an unrelated case
Actually, we're looking for a white
or Latino male, so you're in the clear.
-Anyone else drive your car?
- No, I have a fleet of five trucks for my crew
- Crew?
- I'm a contractor
Okay Well, thanks
for coming down anyway
Well, what's this about?
Maybe I can help
We've got a man
breaking and entering homes
He hangs around the neighborhood
during the day
spies on his victims first
- That's terrible I'll keep my eyes open
- Thanks
Teenage girl, drops offher baby,
says she'll be back to pick him up.
That was three hours ago
Why'd she leave her baby with you?
She said she ran out of gas and didn't have
no money, begged me to give her a tank
Said she'd go get some cash,
and we'd square it up later
- She say where she was headed?
-Just that it was an emergency
I told her to leave her driver's license
and gave her some gas
So you have her driver's license?
She didn't have one Offered to leave
her baby instead as collateral
- Wh--
- You agreed to that?
Boss don't like me
giving out free gas
and who abandons her kid?
- Diagur, right?
- Yeah
I want your boys who shot at me
He's one of them
I don't know where they are
What other operations
does this asshole have?
Something about running rock
out of a panaderia on Virgil?
That's a start
One-niners will appreciate
a new customer base
When business gets bad enough,
call me
Keep him away from a phone
till I get to his rock store
We tried calling you.
There was a mix-up at the phone company
We were temporarily disconnected
We're looking into parking violations
for license plate number
3PCI499
Uh, that's Will's car
My husband
- Is he home?
- No, he's working
- Oh What does he do?
- Can you tell me what this is about?
Oh, it's routine We're checking all the
residents who received tickets in this district
Does your husband work
in the Farmington area?
No, uh, he may make deliveries there
He's a courier for a law firm
Cute kids
They're from my class
I teach third grade
Does your husband
let anyone else drive his car?
I take the bus I'd end up driving
on the wrong side of the street
- That's 0 for 4
- We should talk to the husband
- He doesn't fit the profile
- He's a courier
Parking tickets place him in the hot zone
prior to two of the rapes
He works for a law firm
She teaches
They're not lower class enough
Only the lower classes rape and kill?
Our guy's uneducated If he has a wife,
which I doubt, she isn't so--
British. Pretty.
I was gonna say independent
- This is all screwed up
- Are they on the way to TJ or not?
I found Vido He's holed up
at Dr Ausanta's house, getting sewed up
- Shoulder's a mess
- We'll be gentle
- Where's Juan?
- Still no answer, man
You better figure it out,
and do it quick.
My vatos are spinning
They think I'm losing control
When I track down Juan, they want me
to give him up to your boss
If you do that,
you lose everything
The captain is taking everything
right now!
- How much does Juan know
about your operations?
- He's way inside.
You don't think he'll give up
you and your buddies for early parole?
He's gonna bring
the whole goddamn gang down
Shit, man
Makes you think
Is he really a problem worth having?
If not, you get rid of him
-Juan's my dog, man
- You're the big dog now
It's time your balls dropped
Police! Don't move!
Hey, this one's pretty serious
- He's gotta get to an E.R. immediately.
- Please.
Get him to Mission Cross
- Nice setup.
A.M.A. know you're operating here?
Look, my son has a problem,
a drug problem
His dealers asked me to help them.
I do a favor like this,
they won't sell him drugs
So aiding and abetting a fugitive's
gonna get him clean?
- He's my son.
- There's another man we're looking for
He came in alone
- Get him to the Barn
- Come on Let's go
- I thought you said they were both here
- That's what I was told
At least we know you scared Diagur
into cooperating
What's up?
Here's Treasury's new prime suspect
Neil O'Brien. Who's he?
A violent multiple offender
who's not gang-related
Six years, armed robbery
Assault with a deadly weapon, two and a half
- He's on Treasury's radar?
- As soon as he puts some of our
marked money into the system
So we plant money on an innocent?
If you can say that
with a straight face
The guy's been ass deep in it
since junior high
Best part about it is
he's got two brothers in Indio.
The feds are gonna be
falling all over him
And off Mara's Mommie Dearest
- Your prisoner's all patched up
You can take him now
- Thanks, Corrine
Listen, about Matthew's picture
We're both his parents We both need
to be involved in these decisions
I think that the job that Owen's done
with him is amazing
Matthew seems to be
coming out of his shell
But you're his father, and if you're not
comfortable with Owen dating me
and tutoring Matthew
then we can find
another therapist for him
Good That's what I want
Social Services is sending someone
to pick him up
- You want me to hold him?
- No, no I'm fine
- Maybe we should get him some formula.
- Hey!
- Ohh!
Oh Vanessa and I
are gonna have a baby
- She's pregnant?
- No No
I just know everything's
gonna work out fine Hey!
Ooh Hey!
- Where's Juan?
- I barely know the guy
You know him well enough
to take a bullet with his name on it
I was just in on the ride.
Lats say go, I go.
Now Simon says you're being a moron
You showed up at the doctor's alone Your
Byz Lat big brother at least give you cab fare?
- He ditched me
- Where?
Stop asking I just met him last night
He came by Elisa's--
- Who's Elisa?
- No one!
His cooch? Huh?
- I'm done talking
- Track down the drug dealers
who arm-twisted the doctor
- What for?
Because they're drug dealers and they
extorted him for medical services
That can wait How 'bout I find out
who this Elisa is instead?
No, I got it
You get the other thing
Hey, what's going on?
Call Diagur Tell him we're looking
for some chick named Elisa
Elisa
Elisa Ortiz
- We're looking forJuan Lozano
- So am I, half the time
Do you mind if we look for him inside?
Put back any shit you move
- No, no You stay outside
-Juan ain't here!
Clear!
- I told your stupid ass
- Your boyfriend's a fugitive,
armed and dangerous
- Clear.
- I have a few questions.
Legal firm Will Faulks works for--
Ponte and Cruz Immigration
- ''You want to stay, we'll find a way''
- Excuse me?
They're not even lawyers
For 50 bucks, they'll fill out
your visa application
They've got Will and 1 0 other guys
plastering cars and doors with flyers
He's a flyer guy
The wife said he was a courier
Records show he also works
for a 2 4-hour video store
Great excuse for the wife...
on the occasional nights you feel like
hiding naked in a woman's closet
Still, he's got no record
of sexual assault
He's never even been charged
- I can't see our guy not having a history
- Maybe he's got one
We just don't know about it
- Detective.
- Mr Freeman
Uh,James, please
I did some thinking about your case
I'm in that area all the time,
and I remembered seeing a guy
A suspicious guy
He was hanging around the buildings
At first I thought he was a gardener,
but he wasn't dressed like one
Well, we already have a viable suspect,
but we appreciate your lead
Okay Sure
Just thought I should report in to you
Uh, leave the details with
the desk sergeant We'll look into it
We have another viable suspect?
That was cold
He could have phoned that in
He likes you
- You're just figuring that out, Detective?
- So?
I'm working
I don't know whereJuan is
- Tell me everything you know about him
- So you can send him up?
- Forget you
There ain't no cop house up here
Let me out!
Take these cuffs off me.
I need to talk to my lawyer.
You'll get a lawyer as soon
as we get back to the station
Hey I hear you went on
some run with Aceveda?
- Yeah
- Where were you?
He picked up the suspect's girlfriend
They back yet?
- No Uh, how long ago was this?
- Half an hour
No sign of Aceveda He's somewhere
talking toJuan's girlfriend
He could be getting close to Diagur and us,
and we got nothing
One problem at a time
You sure you got the rest
of the marked money from our stash?
- Almost 30 grand
- All right
You two drop the money where
you're sure our Irish patsy'll find it
- No problem
- Try not to be too obvious
- Shit
- Yeah?
- Woman just called in a shooting
Dead guy fits the description of
Aceveda's robbery suspect,Juan Lozano.
Thanks
Well, looks like
Diagur's balls just dropped
What are you doing?
What's going on?
Help me!
Let me go.
Tell me everything you know
aboutJuan Lozano
starting with where I find him
That's notJuan.
Byz Lats ink.
Hey, dumbass
Right gang, wrong dead Mexican.
This isn'tJuan Lozano.
Neighbor saw the whole thing He said Lozano
was the shooter after this guy pulled first
Aceveda been notified?
We've been trying to get ahold of him
He's not answering his cell
Mrs Faulks, you have time
to answer a few more questions?
- About parking tickets?
- Is your husband home?
No, he's still at work
What is this?
The truth is, someone made
an anonymous call
stating that your husband's car
was involved in a string of robberies
That's ridiculous Please
Chances are, Will cut someone off in traffic;
they're trying to make his life miserable
Easiest thing is just to let us
take a quick look around
We don't find 50 VCRs stashed
in the closet, end of story
Uh, we would need you to sign
this consent to search form
Oh, my God!
- Is he okay?
- He was left at a gas station
He was with my babysitter, Taniesha
When I got home,
they were both gone
Is Taniesha black, around 1 6?
Yes Is she okay?
A girl fitting that description
left your baby at a gas station.
What?
Come this way
I need you to fill out some paperwork
I'm getting a stomachache already
- Is that our guy?
- I don't think so.
- No, no, no It's him
- Man, I thought he'd never come out of there.
- Come on You see it
- Pick it up
Pick it up, you Irish prick
That's it That-a-boy
Congratulations You just got yourself
a spot on Treasury's Most Wanted.
Arroyo, he was mi mejor amigo.
I don't listen to you, he's not dead
Then you should have sent more than one
vato, made sure you got the job done right
That captain? I'm giving him a call
I'm giving Juan up
- You know whereJuan is?
- Yeah, he's holed up
- He's freaking He needs supplies
- Good
This time send a small army
You know what? You do it yourself
Otherwise,
I'm gonna give the big man a call
That's not necessary
You tell me where he is
Sancho?
No
On your knees
On your knees!
- Police!
- Clear!
- Check the back room.
Yeah, we're clear in here.
Found him, huh?
Yeah
Cuff him
Put your hands above your head
In back
Will's a writer. He still uses that.
- What does he write?
- He's trying a novel
He's written a couple of short stories
- Has he been published?
- No.
It's hard to get published
You collect figurines
My husband gives me knickknacks
Ever since we started dating
They're sweet, really.
I just don't know where to put them.
He turned it off
He's gonna scare him
into giving up Diagur
who'll tell him that we knew about the marked
money, told him to send someone to pick it up
Diagur's not who he's after.
- If it was, he'd be in the cage by now
- Then what?
Sit down.
I said, sit down
You followed me to that stickup?
How long you been following me for?
How many chances you have to pull
the trigger on me and never could, huh?
What's that say about you, lawman?
Shut up and sit down
Why don't you suck my dick?
Again
A different room,
but you the same bitch
We'll have surveillance on the house
until we get the warrant
just in case the wife tips him off
Did you talk to the rape victims?
Any of the figurines match?
There's a little boy fishing, ballerina,
girl holding a four-leaf clover
- He's going to need the luck
Unis are ready Let's go
- I'll grab my stuff
Thanks for inviting me
to ride with you
- I haven't made many arrests of this caliber
- No problem
- How old are you, by the way?
- Thirty-three
I was 3 5 before I got a table
in the Detective Squad
- You must have aced the exam.
- I did okay
What'd you get?
Come on
- Uh, 97
- Wow
Yeah Let me go hit the head
We could be out there a while
Uh, right there
- I got a 98
- Oh! Let's get moving
No, I did
I talked to some of my guys
got a good description
of the man I told you about
and the building addresses
Thanks I really can't talk to you right now
We just got our guy, so--
Oh Well, that's great
Well--
So if you'd like to skip
to the part where you ask me out
hurry
You don't like a man
to play hard to get, huh?
- Uh, can I use your pencil?
- Yeah
You're running for mayor
or something, right?
How people gonna feel when they see you
blowing my big jail-cell cock, huh?
I got a Kodak moment, remember?
You remember
You mean on this?
I deleted the photo.
So I put it on disk, man
I'll tell you what
You get me out of this trouble
I'll make sure no one ever sees it
You put it on a disk? How?
Huh?
How did you do it?
Take me through the steps
You're too stupid
to change a lightbulb...
let alone figure out
how to download.
You didn't show the pictures,
and you didn't tell anyone
- Oh, yeah?
- 'Cause bragging about what you did...
to a cop--
Even you're smart enough to know my force
would've ripped apart the Lats to get to you
No way you'd want your boss
knowing you're the reason...
business was getting shut down.
No
This was your little secret
So I'll just tell everybody now
I ain't got nothing to lose
Right
You talk now
it's a desperate attempt
to avoid the gas chamber
Or did you forget?
I killed the only witness you had
I spent the last few weeks
getting to know who you are,Juan
Do you know your girlfriend Elisa's
been banging someone else?
- Yeah, right Uh-huh
- Someone you know Horatio
When you go play cards
with your boys twice a week
- She likes it too
- Yeah.
Think I care what that bitch does?
Nah
I know you've got
a grandmother who's sick
Only got a couple of years left
She spends every day worried
that Immigration's gonna send her
back to Mexico to die
Maybe I should send a few border boys
to knock on her door, hmm?
No
I know your mom's late
on her mortgage payments...
and she's involved with some pyramid scheme
to make money to save the house
I barely even talk to that drunk.
I know you're working
stolen credit cards for your gang
and you're skimming profits
off the top
even though Elisa keeps telling you
it's gonna get you killed.
I know about the headaches you get
I know about the uncle
who molested you when you were 1 2
I know about your cousin who's trying
to get a scholarship to UC Irvine.
I know which magazines you jerk off to
that you think Elisa doesn't know about
I know about your brother in Fresno
I know the inmate who tried to
shank you twice at Terminal Island...
is Koren Hennessy Denton.
And I know the number to call
to clear up a bunk in his cell just for you
So you sucked on my dick
and then when you had the gun on me,
you couldn't pull the trigger, huh?
You think I couldn't find
the courage to kill you?
I spent the last three weeks...
finding the courage
not to kill you
Don't think for a second
it means I don't believe in revenge
You tell just one person some wild story
about some incident that never happened
you, the people you love
will find out about a dozen
different kinds of revenge
You will learn
the things I know,Juan
the things I can do
It's back
Where's my gun?
Find Rodriguez or Wagenbach
He's ready to give his confession
Man, all I did
was take the girl to dinner
- Where's the kidnapping in that?
- He didn't do nothing I did
- What happened?
- I was babysitting when Anquoin
called and asked me out
I needed someone
to look after the baby
I was gonna pick him up after,
'cept there was an accident on the freeway
You dumped a baby with a gas station
attendant to go out on a date?
- I'm gonna kick him
- You see Anquoin?
Sometimes you only get one shot
with a boy like that
Mrs Faulks, we have a warrant
- What?
- Freeze, right there!
- William Faulks? You're under arrest
- What are you doing?
You saw he didn't steal anything
For the rapes of Diana Peabo,
Isabel Nelson and Layla Gist
- Rapes?
- For the rape-murders of Dory Smythe
Debbie Reese
and her daughter Crystal
- Will!
- Mrs Faulks, step back!
- Why are you doing this?
- Will gave you figurines as gifts
- They were keepsakes stolen from his victims
- That is a sick lie!
You're arresting him because of those?
That's not what you said you were looking for!
I did not give you permission for that!
- You gave us permission to search the house
- No!
- We didn't specify what we were searching for
You said there were crank calls,
robberies! You lied to me!
Joanna, stop it
Calm down
- Will!
- Take him.
Get the crime scene geeks in here!
I don't want anybody to touch anything
until they've been over every inch.
...most of the time.
- What took you so long?
- Ma had to see where you worked.
Vic take good care of you?
- Nothing's sexier than being
around three men with guns
- I gave her the tour
We werejust leaving.
Bye, Vic
She-- She got a message
on her answering machine in Indio
From who?
From a guy from the US Treasury
He wants to meet with her
Okay
We'll talk about it later
- The mom is poison
- She got a message from a guy with Treasury
He wants to meet her
Tell Stella to wait a week
before calling back
Hopefully, by then Irish will have
spent some of his newfound cash
and he'll be Treasury's
new prime suspect.
Okay
In the meantime
we've moved our stash
to another location
Where?
Mara found out once before
We think it'd be safer
if you-- if you don't know
- Hi
- How was work?
- Good
- We're gonna have a child
- What?
God spoke to me today through a baby
We're gonna have our own child
Baby? Baby Baby
Julien
Baby?
Jesus!Julien!
- Nice work on the extortion case
- Thanks The same
Must feel pretty good
Getting the guys who shot at you
Yeah
I hear the Korean community's
calling you ''the sheriff'' Big hero
What's been going on?
What happened yesterday?
I wrapped things up
David I--
- There he is. Captain, over here.
Captain Aceveda?
Captain, the shooting of one of the suspects,
the minor? What's his condition?
Thank you all for coming
- Captain?
- Yes, Carlos?
It took a lot of guts to take on
three armed men, come under fire
then get right back into the field.
I'm inspired, on a daily basis,
by the bravery exhibited
by the men and women
who work under my command
I just try to live up
to their standards
Was this robbery one
of a number of increasing...
gang-related crimes
in the Korean community?
On the contrary, there has been
a substantial reduction of gun violence
as you'll see in our quarterly report
Is it true you have a meeting
next week with the Korean Chamber--