Yeah, hold on!
Hey, Vic, it's me! Open up!
- What's up?
- You see this?
- What?
- I thought Lanie's report
wasn't coming out for weeks.
- It's not.
- What's it doing there in black and white?
- Are we named?
- Yeah, Strike Team's mentioned.
You bitch.
Well, at least we're not alone.
Aceveda's name is mentioned...
more than three times.
Will you get me a towel, please?
- See you downstairs in a few minutes.
- All right, man.
- Yeah?
- Just reading the newspaper. Have you?
Lakers cut it pretty close last night.
They're not the only ones.
That about the Armadillo thing?
I just don't like not liking my job.
Well, lucky for you we might not
have jobs in a couple of weeks.
We better talk,
get our stories straight.
I don't have time to talk. I have to
manage perhaps the most dysfunctional...
inefficient precinct in the city.
- Yeah?
- Vic, Gilroy called.
- What?
- Gilroy. He called here at the house.
- You spoke to him?
- He left a message on the machine.
He said he was coming over.
I thought he was in jail.
Well, he's out on bail, but he's
supposed to be under house arrest.
All right, I'm on the way.
Is the alarm on?
Yes! What if he gets here first?
Keep the doors locked
and the alarm on.
I just got married. Now is not
a good time for me to be losing my job.
That's not how it works.
They start by offering older
officers early retirement.
Then they cut
the discipline problems.
They're not gonna take a young
black officer off the street...
not in this district.
- The only one that's in trouble is me.
- No way.
Do you know they practically
blamed me for Armadillo's murder?
Just a sec.
I need to clear my name
on this Armadillo thing.
- How can I help?
- You were the lead on the case.
If there's anything you know
or discover, would you fill me in?
- I'll keep an eye out.
- I patted that guy down.
There's no way
I missed a knife that big.
Maybe you didn't.
The only thing I can think of is another
inmate must have given it to him.
- Or another cop.
- Why would a...
I probably shouldn't have said that.
Wait. What are you talking about?
What do you mean?
Sarge wants us
on the street. Now.
I'll talk to you later.
- I want to apologize!
- Go away!
- I want to say I'm sorry!
- You said it! Now go!
Please, I'm not here to hurt you!
I need to speak to Vic!
Hey! Are you kidding me?
I need to talk to you.
You wouldn't pick up the phone!
- Vic, get rid of him!
- Corrine.
Shut up. Go back inside.
I've got this under control.
- Vic!
- Go inside!
You were supposed to be
under house arrest.
- I cut off my ankle transmitter.
- You've gone fugitive?
- Let me explain this.
- Save it! I'm hauling your ass in.
Sure, and you can start
sizing up the cell next to mine.
The D.A. wants me
to give you up.
There's nothin' to give up.
There's places you don't
want them lookin'.
I can't go to prison, Vic.
The best my lawyer can do
is eight years.
My liver can't do seven.
I'm not gonna rat you out,
but I'm not gonna go back to jail.
- You're running out of options.
- Help me get out of the country.
No!
Once I'm gone,
you're in the clear too.
They wanted me to wear a wire.
I told them to go to hell.
We haven't got a lot of time, Vic.
We gotta do this now.
- I'm not gonna do this.
- Then you better put a gun to my head...
because if you send me
back to prison...
I'm not gonna hold out
much longer.
Just help me
get across the border.
Get in the car.
What a stupid bastard you are.
Fresh clothes.
You owe me $200.
- How you doin', Shane?
- Great.
All right, your picture's gonna be
plastered at every border crossing...
so you're gonna need paper
to survive on the other side.
I'll need American and Mexican
passports and I.D. and money.
Oh, you lookin' for a loan from us,
you can tickle my zipper.
This key here opens up a safe-deposit
box. The money's in there.
- How much?
- 75,000.
That's all you got left
from your land schemes?
Sedona disappeared
with most of it.
Seventy-five grand
isn't gonna last very long.
Ah, I don't need much.
A hut on the beach and rice and beans.
I'll make it last.
- They'll look for you in Mexico.
- I know a guy in Brazil.
I just need a ticket
from Mexico City to Rio.
Jesus, what do we look like,
we're wearing little headsets?
- Where's the money?
- Tellmare Savings on Vermont.
- I owe you, Vic.
- Shut up.
- Your report wasn't due for two weeks.
- That isn't my report.
I was supposed to have advanced copy.
This is completely one-sided.
Someone stole my notes, then
leaked the damaging portions to...
- Who has access to your notes?
- That's what I'm trying to find out!
The chief's office just called me!
Do you have any idea
how much this screws me?
Look!
Look, the fact is
nothing was embellished.
All the incidents
in the paper happened, David.
I am sorry that they don't
show you in a good light...
but they all happened.
Aceveda and I picked out a new
Strike Team guy. He starts today.
Talk about crappy timing.
Lem, you keep him occupied.
Test him out. See how he runs.
Why do I have to
baby-sit the new guy?
Somebody's gotta handle our car-ring sting
while Vic and I clean up a little problem.
- What problem?
- Gilroy skipped bail.
Shane and I are gonna
slip him out of the country.
I thought that we were gonna keep our
noses clean till we hit the money train.
If Gilroy goes back inside,
starts cooperating with the D.A. ...
there won't be any money train
or anything else.
Gilroy said the D.A. came to him...
so the question is who's
going to the D.A. about us?
- Lanie?
- Or Claudette.
I'm thinkin'Aceveda.
Whoever it is, timing on this
and the morning headline...
- is no coincidence.
- And you think they're related?
I think we gotta be
extra careful.
Look in every dark corner.
Yeah?
- Tavon.
- Hey.
Tavon here has been
in Special Crimes the last few years.
It's a job.
This one sounds better.
- Lemonhead, Shane.
- What's up, man?
Hell of a first day.
We still have jobs?
All the assholes in this city...
we'll always have jobs.
- So what's on the agenda?
- We have a one-day window...
to sting the head of one of L.A.'s
biggest car theft rings.
We've been targeting this guy
for a while, but he knows our faces.
We've never been able to get close.
You, however, he doesn't know.
- Here's his file.
- It's a one-day trial period.
Lem here'll fill you in.
- Let's go.
- I guess it's on.
What's the deal
with Mr. Special Crimes?
Seems a little too cool
for school, don't you think?
Let's give him a chance.
I remember the last guy
we gave a chance to.
This time I did my homework.
I spoke to him a couple of times.
- He seems straight up.
- Yeah, we'll see.
Toni Jahnes, 71, widow.
- Looks like the intruder entered here.
- What's missing?
Nothing that couldn't travel.
No appliances.
Someone did go through
the jewelry though.
Robbery-homicide. Looks like
he hit her head on the mantle.
Being so old, probably
couldn't put up a fight.
You know I closed three robbery cases
last week, one homicide?
Way above departmental average.
Think that gets mentioned
in the report?
No.
- No.
- Sorry.
Yeah, so am I.
Just doesn't seem fair.
- Looks like she had two daughters.
- I saw that. How are yours?
Good question.
Look, Quazi's gonna get the money,
make the fake I.D. 's...
and Gilroy will be out of our lives
for good with no blood spilled.
I know you got a soft spot for Ben,
but if he goes sideways...
I'm not gonna let him
hurt us, Vic.
- Morning, Chief.
- Sorry I have to meet like this.
I understand.
You're a busy man.
- So.
- I was supposed to have a chance...
to respond to the report
before it went public.
- Respond to it now.
- It's completely biased.
Compared to other divisions...
Farmington has the steepest
reduction in crime rates in the city.
Our arrest records far outweigh
any allegations of misconduct.
What would you do in my position?
- My first instinct would be to fire me.
- So far, I'm with you.
And then I'd think
how that might look.
Fire me on the day
this news breaks...
you give the charges credibility.
Then when the whole truth
comes out...
that the barn has a first-rate
return against crime...
a real success story...
I suggest you withhold judgment a while
before shaking things up.
I've heard about this kind
of slick shit of yours.
It doesn't work on me.
You're running for office.
I'll leave you as captain
until that run is over.
If you win, you graduate
to city council...
and you remember that
I gave you another six months.
If you lose the primary...
you need to spend
more time with your family...
due to the strain...
and you resign quietly.
Relax, David.
Every campaign has a crisis point...
which is why we always have
a contingency plan.
- What?
- Campaña de ataques.
A smear campaign? No.
Dirty tricks might be the norm
in Mexico, but not here.
Half of your voters
were born in Mexico, David.
To them,
this is a way of life.
Look, if I do this,
where does it stop?
With you beating Karen Mitchell.
No. No, I'm going
to rearrange the barn...
and if I'm lucky, I can
get things back on track.
I can turn things around
before the primary.
Not soon enough.
Whoever leaked this...
was coordinated and determined.
We have to be all that, plus smarter.
No. There's got to be a better way.
You think Aceveda's the one
who went to the D.A.?
- Yeah.
- Backstabbing bastard.
Who knows? Maybe he
caught wind of the report...
figured he'd have us take the hit.
Look, I don't like the timing of
this whole new Strike Team guy.
Aceveda signed off on him.
Maybe he knows something
that we don't.
It's just one day.
He'll be gone tomorrow.
Okay, he's got it.
Oh, crap.
I guess intelligence
is his second language.
He can duplicate government documents
flawlessly. He can't tell his left from his right.
- He's nervous.
- I just hope he remembers
where the meeting place is.
- Drop the weapon! Let go of her!
- Freeze!
Get your hands off of her!
Hey, you, come here! Stop!
On your knees!
Get on your knees now!
Put your hands on the ground now!
Open your mouth.
Spit it out! Spit it!
Turn over!
Turn over.
Jesus Christ.
We talked to some of the girls
in your neighborhood.
They said this isn't the first time you started
a fight in the last couple of weeks.
You're eight months pregnant. You want
to tell us why you're mixin' it up?
Just because I'm pregnant doesn't mean
I have to stop bringing it.
- You're a little old to be brawlin'
- You want to try me?
Why don't you tell us about
the father, this Antonio.
- I don't know, and I don't care.
- Maybe he cares.
- Well, it ain't about him.
- No, it's about the baby.
You don't want to hurt it, right?
Right?
You trying
to lose this baby?
Look, whatever happens happens.
I'm just gonna keep
doing my thing.
And what about that
little boy inside of you?
That's right. It's a boy.
Which means it's gonna look like
Antonio, sound like Antonio...
and I don't wanna be looking at a little
Antonio for the rest of my life.
Have you thought about that?
She worked for the Parks
Department for 30 years.
Outlived both her daughters.
One was killed by a drunk driver.
Other died of ovarian cancer last year.
I ran a check on like crimes.
- Three break-ins the last two weeks.
- That the report there?
- No.
- What is it?
Win list. I'm compiling
a folder of all my wins.
Your wins? What have you
got to be worried about?
- You've got a great jacket.
- You weren't mentioned in the report.
- People remember headlines.
- M.E. sent over Toni Jahnes's prelims.
You can close your folder.
- Wasn't a murder.
- What was it?
Uh, she died of a heart attack,
not the blow to the head.
When did she have
a heart attack?
They haven't determined that yet.
Why?
Because maybe she had it when
she saw the burglar in her house.
File that under "we'll never know."
Should I contact next of kin?
She had no kin, no heirs,
no friends that I could tell.
Heart attack probably
doesn't qualify as a win, does it?
Ben? Ben!
These were my last two beers,
the only booze I had left in the house.
- Goddamn it. Come on.
- Where we goin'?
Nearest bar.
- Here are my buddies right now.
- You the police?
- Yeah. Why?
- He got physical with my customers.
When I go to remove him,
he says he's a cop.
I called 20 minutes ago about this guy.
- Good thing I wasn't being robbed.
- Okay, we'll take care of it.
- Stand up now and walk out with us.
- Hey, Vic, listen.
You know how long it's been
since I've had a drink?
- Fifteen seconds?
- Four months in jail.
I want to buy you guys a drink.
- The cops are on their way here.
- Let's buy them a drink too.
- Stop making a scene, you dumbass.
- Oh, no! You!
This could be my last chance here.
It is your last chance. Get up!
Ooh! God...
Oh, geez!
Grab him.
Hey, I can't do this thing.
- Come on.
- I can't do it.
When our backup shows,
you tell 'em we took care of it.
- Hey, who's gonna take care of the tab?
- Go ahead.
Louis, you want a break on this
drug charge, you're gonna help us out.
Denon's my cousin.
I can't dime him out.
- Why not?
- He's my cousin.
It'll screw up Christmas...
and I'm not lettin'some
cracker cop ruin the holidays.
What'd you say to the man?
What'd you say?
Get off of me!
Get off me, man!
Easy, brother.
Dude, there's cameras in here, man.
You gotta watch your shit.
I heard we did things
different around here.
Well, you heard wrong.
Listen, you go along willingly...
or I release you right now and tell your
homo homies you're my snitch bitch.
All right?
You're gonna help us.
It's up to you
how much it has to hurt.
Come on now, Louis.
This boy's just your cousin.
Ain't like he's
your brother or nothin'.
What'd he say?
He's drunk. He wants him
to sober up first.
Oh, no, ese, uh-uh.
- Where's my money?
- We're holding on to it for now.
Why don't you wait until Quazi
does your I.D. makeover?
- What?
- We got the cousin to roll.
Meeting with Denon's
set up for this afternoon.
- Aceveda wants a progress report.
- Okay, tell him we're on the way.
Sting's happening. Let's go.
We gotta get down there.
- Where's Claudette?
- Not sure.
- What are you doing, Dutch?
- Little homework.
How about a little police work
instead of dusting off your résumé?
You, uh, saying I don't need to?
Shooting with casualties
on Penn and Sunset.
- Find Claudette and get down there.
- Yes, sir.
Hey! Where you been?
Been lookin' all over for you.
Nice try.
- How's Tavon doing?
- He seems to be trying hard.
Yeah, we all should be
doing that about now.
If you've got a case that you could close,
today would be a good day to do it.
What, are you worried
about keeping your job?
I'm a Latino police captain.
I could find a spot tomorrow
in a dozen cities.
- You're the one who should be worried.
- Well, if we stick together...
neither one of us will have to worry.
I'm still willing to honor our deal.
What about you?
Our arrangement's
more important than ever.
Aceveda's definitely screwing us.
- How do you know?
- He's saying all the right things.
Only wants to know about the new guy
and our car thief bust.
- Nothing about Gilroy.
- Well, it must be an epidemic.
The assistant chief of police is on the
run, there's not one single news story.
D.A.'s too embarrassed to put
the word out on the news yet.
We gotta take advantage
of the time while we can.
You track down Coyote Jack yet?
Yeah. He's delivering a shipment
of illegals in about an hour.
Got the drop point from my C.I.
We're good to go.
- You back from the scene?
- Yeah.
- How many casualties?
- Just the one.
Still trying to figure out whether she
was dead before or during the break-in.
- What? This is the shooting on Penn?
- No. I'm working the Jahnes case.
I thought that got knocked down
to a simple B-and-E.
Not by me. If the burglar caused her
heart attack, he killed her.
- The law doesn't see it that way.
- I do.
You were to move on to a priority crime.
- Where's Dutch?
- I don't know.
I guess he's got
his priorities straight.
And you?
I'm finishing what I started.
This is a break-in with no victim.
Move on to a real case.
I am working a real case!
And if you spent more time
letting me and less time stopping me...
maybe these people wouldn't have
to worry about their families...
how they're gonna feed them
because of a bunch of crap...
they know nothing about
and had nothing to do with!
Damn it!
No wonder this precinct's upside down.
Saving these people's jobs
should be your priority.
Damn!
- Are you okay?
- Am I being graded?
Sorry.
It's going to be hard to back away
from the things leaked in those notes...
no matter what
my final report says.
- So some of us are gonna be swept away.
- That is the way it looks.
But maybe you can help me point
the broom in the right direction.
Maybe.
- Hola.
- Policía.
¡Vamos!
¡Vayanse! ¡Vayanse!
Coyote Jack, looks like you
brought a full load north, huh?
Get out! Now!
- This is I.N.S.?
- No. That's downtown...
about three miles away from here.
- We can drop you off there too.
- Look, those people were hitchhikers.
I picked them up
outside of Oceanside.
We want to hire you to drop
someone back across the border.
What? You want me to smuggle
somebody into Mexico?
Yeah. How much
for something like that?
- I never charged anybody before.
- Come on.
We know the tunnels run both ways.
Now, you can either help us
deliver our package...
or we can deliver you
inside to booking.
I'll get your package
across the border.
I thought you were
at the Penn shooting.
I'd rather be working with my partner.
- Broke easy, huh?
- Caught the guy two blocks away...
.22 still in his belt.
Another win. All we gotta do now
is file the paperwork.
But I came here before I did that.
Congratulations.
Check the kitchen.
- What's up, Louis?
- What's up, guy?
- A'ight.
- This nigga here got a bead, man...
- on a fleet of Expeditions, man.
- A'ight.
Yo, I ain't never seen you before.
Where your hood at?
Detroit, man. Guess that's why
a nigga's into rides, right?
- Who you run with?
- Fourth Street Clown Posse here.
So I hear you're movin' trucks.
- Yo.
- What condition?
Factory fresh.
Straight outta Motown.
How's it work?
A'ight. My boy's a truck foreman.
He assigns the routes.
Driver of the rig, he gets a small
piece of the action, you know?
A'ight. I'll pay you
10 G's a truck, 11 for leather.
Hell, no. That ain't
what I get in Detroit, man.
- This ain't Detroit, bitch!
- You better back up off me, bitch.
- Are you callin' me a bitch?
- Oh, no.
Hey, yo, kill that, man.
Nah, man, nah.
No, this your turf,
so they're your terms, a'ight?
- Damn straight.
- A'ight.
Look, just tell me when and where
you want the wheels, and we good.
What do you got?
Well, someone took all her lipstick.
A girl could never
resist free lipstick.
I got three empty bags of cookies
and a half-eaten bag of brown sugar.
- Junkie girl.
- Should I check with Vic...
- see who's running junk on the block?
- I don't need a special team.
I'll do my own police work.
Evening.
Your mama know you're hanging out
in a bad neighborhood?
- Got me a note says it's a'ight.
- What's your name?
- Long John.
- The pirate gangster, huh?
Okay, let's empty your pockets.
Hands up.
We're lookin' for
one of your customers.
Don't got no customers.
And I talk to you,
I ain't got 'em no more.
We're looking for a girl.
Probably bought last night.
Maybe tried to trade
jewelry for rock.
Oh! Didn't think I could
reach that, did you?
Oh, my.
L.J., come on.
- I walk on the rock, right?
- Depends.
This transie, calls herself Mancy.
It was her.
Is Mancy a transie
or a cross-dresser?
- Is there a difference?
- Fairly large one.
- Anything?
- No.
No A.P.B., no sheriff's request,
no bench warrants...
no Department of Corrections
notifications.
I'm tellin' you, man.
There is no one lookin' for Gilroy.
- That doesn't make sense.
- Guy cut off his ankle transmitter...
- and bailed eight hours ago.
- Maybe it's a malfunction.
On the same day that Lanie's report
gets leaked to the press? It's unlikely.
Goddamn it.
There's something very wrong.
- I don't buy it.
- You were worried about your job.
You asked for answers.
- Make your own conclusions.
- Look, I know Vic.
He wouldn't do
something like this...
and hang me out to dry for it.
He wouldn't.
Sorry to waste your time.
- What's he keep saying?
- He says stop smiling.
- It makes you look gay.
- Just take the picture, monkey.
- You done?
- Yeah.
Plane ticket. Plus, we had to take
10,000 out of the 75 for expenses.
- Expenses for what?
- Coyote who's gonna give you a ride.
Okay, yeah, sure.
I know you guys don't
want to talk about this...
but the D.A.'s been
asking me about Terry.
Just been... I think they're gonna
reopen his shooting.
I didn't tell them how I warned you
Terry was looking to take you down...
but they're still
sniffing around.
There's nothing solid tying you
to his dying, right? Is there?
Terry got killed in the line
of duty by a drug dealer.
Come on, Vic. It's just us.
I'm trying to look out for you.
What are you doin'?
You already did...
Goddamn it.
No transmitter.
Just a tape recorder and a mike.
We checked him twice.
That's what the trip
to the bar was about, wasn't it?
- I'm sorry, Vic.
- Son of a bitch. What'd you tell 'em?
- Nothin'!
- What'd you tell 'em?
I don't believe you!
What do they know? What do they know?
Th-They're surveilling me
outside the building!
They're surveilling me.
What?
If anything happens to me,
they're gonna know.
Oh, this is not good. This bastard
has guys following us?
What do you think
they've seen? The bar?
The bank? Quazi?
Coyote Jack?
Even if they have,
it doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter.
They can't use any of it against us.
He asked us for our help.
It's entrapment.
The tape. It's the only thing
he can use against us, and we have it.
Know what they have? They have
our asses, is what they have, man.
- We've been harboring a fugitive.
- Not anymore we're not.
You're going to Mexico
just like we planned.
- How am I gonna live?
- On the 75 grand, dipshit.
- Tell you what. Make that 65.
- It's not gonna last me a year.
What about the hut,
the rice and the beans?
I wasn't really going.
Oh, you're going, all right.
Get up. Get dressed.
Oh, for Christ's sake.
I didn't want to do it.
They made me.
It took every drink
that I had to do it.
Sorry, Vic.
I'm sorry, man.
Ben, we need you now.
Listen, you pull
yourself together.
We can still all win here.
I'm just gonna need you to lose
the tail on your own now.
- What?
- Just gotta make sure...
that whoever's watching
sees us leaving without him.
We're putting our success
in his hands? Jesus!
Relax!
Ben's done some of his best work
soused, haven't you, Ben?
How'd I get here, Vic?
How'd I get here?
Let's just cut our losses
right now and turn him in.
The guy's been nothing
but poison from the start.
- No. He can do this.
- Vic, come on! He's tanked, man!
I'm not depending on this guy,
not for anything.
We send him back to prison.
He starts talking. He makes our lives hell.
He can do it.
- Captain?
- Yeah?
Ben Gilroy skipped bail.
- What?
- How do you know that?
He came over my house, asked me
to help him get out of the country.
- Just now?
- No. This morning.
- Why didn't you bring him in then?
- I...
I've known him for 15 years. I was
trying to get him to come in on his own.
He wouldn't.
I want to help the guy...
but I'm not gonna
commit a felony doing it.
Where is he now?
He's still at my apartment. You're gonna have
to send someone to pick him up.
He's drunk. He's crying his eyes out.
I wasn't gonna
bring him in like that.
I'll call it in.
Vic, Denon just called. He wants
to move those cars right now.
- Now?
- Yeah.
- Supposed to be tomorrow.
- He changed his mind.
- It's now or never.
- Denon, the stolen car guy?
- Yeah.
- He's major. Go get him.
Okay, round everybody up.
I'll meet you out back.
- Can we talk?
- I'm in a hurry. Later, okay?
All this shit's going down.
People could be losing their jobs...
especially me.
I'm at the top of the list
because of this Armadillo thing.
Look, you shouldn't have
been suspended for that.
It was unfair, okay?
Word is that Armadillo dying
could've been good for you.
- What word is that?
- Look, this is my career, goddamn it.
Took me six and a half years
to get here, and I'm not gonna lose it.
Who's been talking about me?
Claudette?
What happened in that cage?
I don't know. These guys hide things
sometimes. Sometimes cops miss them.
No. You know damn well
I'm not gonna miss something like that.
You had something
to do with this, didn't you?
- No.
- Yeah, you did.
Danny. Jesus Christ,
think about what you're saying.
Jesus Christ,
I know what I'm saying.
Goddamn it, and after all
that I have covered for you...
everything that
I've done for you?
I've never said a word to anybody
about anything, and you pull this on me?
Goddamn it, I know what I'm saying.
You stay the hell away from me.
Mancy!
You know where she is?
Where's Mancy?
Mancy.
Good Lord.
Let's get her to a hospital.
He says Gilroy's still in the apartment.
Can your men see him?
Where is the rest
of the surveillance team?
No. Just go in now.
Make sure you get the tape.
Everyone, listen up, please.
Could I have your attention?
I should have said this
12 hours ago.
We're a team.
A family.
And I'm gonna fight like hell...
to save every single job
in this building.
In the meantime, let's just
focus on what we do best.
Protect and serve.
Nice speech.
Could be my last.
So you caught the, uh,
B-and-E guy?
Yeah. He saw the body,
decided to break in.
He was not the cause
of the heart attack.
At least now you know.
Death was natural.
She had her time.
That's some consolation.
Not really.
She died alone.
We can put you in lockup,
we can talk to a judge...
and have you detained
till that baby is born.
Go ahead. Put me in County.
What? You don't think
there's other ways to do it?
Fighting's just the way
you get the most props.
If you don't want the kid, it's okay.
You can give him to somebody else.
Yeah, like who? Antonio?
Did you talk to him?
Yeah, we talked to him.
What'd he say?
Does he want me back?
Does he want to be
the daddy of his son?
Look, we can find a good foster home for
your son. At least give him a chance.
You ever try giving away a brown baby?
Come on, now.
Not even his daddy wants him.
- Do you want him?
- I will do everything that I can...
to help you find the best
possible home for your son.
I'll take him.
- What?
- I'll take him.
I can make this work.
I want him.
I ain't giving my baby to a white cop.
I'd rather kill him
with my bare hands.
Now get out of here.
Get out!
Vic! Vic!
Told you.
I made it.
How many wine coolers
did it take you to get here?
- Is this really necessary?
- Yes, it is.
- You do everything I told you to do?
- Yeah, I'm here, aren't I?
You took the bus, crossed the plaza,
went down to the subway station?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I paid the coyote the $10,000...
and then he gave me this.
You lose the tail?
I know how to lose a tail, Vic.
Good. Everything's in place.
- Time to go.
- Who's this?
Coyote who's taking you
across the border.
- Who was the guy in the subway?
- The hit man you paid $10,000 to...
to kill you if I ever call this number
and tell him this code.
You made me pay
my own hit man?
I'll bet you really
need a drink now, don't you?
You ever get caught, come back
on your own, doesn't matter.
You're all done.
Vic, we were friends.
You were the one
who threatened my family.
- It was a bluff!
- This isn't.
You had the chance to pull
the trigger on me, and you couldn't.
You're not gonna do this either.
Maybe not, but Shane will.
I guess this is good-bye.
It better be.
- Get in.
- Hey, Vic. Vic.
Vic!
I got greedy.
I lost everything.
There's a lesson there, Vic.
Whatever.
I didn't agree to buy no stolen rides,
man. Thought they was on the up and up.
You got time.
Think of a better story.
Our stolen car ringleader?
- Not anymore, sir.
- Good. It's nice to have a win...
on a day like today.
Hey, Tavon.
- These guys treat you okay?
- Yeah.
Good.
Well, looks like
we survived the day.
Yeah, well, we always got tomorrow.
We'll survive tomorrow too.
- I wish I had your confidence.
- Yeah, a lot of people do.
- Gilroy's not at Vic's apartment.
- What?
He was there when I left,
lying passed out in a drunken stupor.
Well, he must have sobered up
and walked away.
All they found were his clothes
and a tape recorder.
- Tape recorder?
- Unis are sweeping the neighborhood...
but it looks like he's gone.
Well, he couldn't have gone far,
not in his condition.
Well, it looks like
I owe Aceveda an apology.
The whole time I'm thinking he's the rat...
- when the real rodent's sitting drunk
at my apartment.
- Jesus.
In 24 hours, Gilroy will be
Rio de Janeiro's problem.
- How did Tavon grade out?
- Flying colors, man.
- The guy's got cojones.
- It's not having them...
- it's using them that counts.
- Tavon's cool. He's a hard worker.
A bit of a mean streak,
but under control.
I think we may have
lucked out with this guy.
Don't cream all over this guy
before you see him naked.
He's no Ronnie,
and he's no you or me for that matter.
I'm just saying he could open up
some new avenues for us...
you know, being black and all.
Transfer papers all signed.
Just need to call my old commander...
let him know if I'm staying
or if I'm going back.
Tell him you're staying
a little longer. Extended trial period.
- You got it.
- Decent start.
Just be ready for something a little
more difficult than auto capers.
Can't wait to follow your lead.
Great.
Hey, Danny, you were serious
about keeping that kid, weren't you?
It was a stupid idea.
No, not if you really wanted to.
I didn't, all right?
I just thought I did.
Vanessa and I are taking Randall
to dinner, then we're going to church.
- Why don't you join us?
- You trying to convert me now?
No. It's been a long day...
and you don't have to be alone.
I haven't been to church
since I was, like, nine.
- God remembers you.
- Yeah, well, I forgot about him.
I put you on the Strike
Team. I know what you guys do.
We don't take
any crap, if that's what you mean.
Vic, come on.
The law doesn't apply to you.
Look, out there,
it's not what you do.
It's what they think you'll do.
- So the beatings, frame-ups...
- Fairy tales.
The assholes fear you,
they don't cross the line.
Rep's everything on the street.
Aceveda is right.
His unit is clearing cases at a better
rate than anywhere in the city.
You want me to bust up
that squad over crap like this?
There are all kinds of irregularities.
And Aceveda will be the one
to fall on the sword for it.
- After the election, he's gone.
- Forget Aceveda.
The Strike Team is at the center
of this shit-storm. Mackey's dirty.
You haven't proven that
to my satisfaction.
I would've had all the evidence...
if someone hadn't stolen
my notes and tipped him off.
That's between you
and the city council.
Turn in your official report.
This is done.
Frank, I want to see the budget
allocation numbers by 3:00 and...
You can go, Ms. Kellis.
- What do you got for me, Bill?
- Chief...
- You almost done?
- No.
Logging this report is the only thing
keeping me from going home.
Fascinating.
- What are you doing?
- I'm E-mailing my daughters.
Look, you better figure out
how much you hate me...
and how you're gonna
deal with that...
'cause I'm not going anywhere.
Neither am I.