You had Vic arrested?
- I just filed a complaint.
- Well, he's spending the night
in jail right now.
- I can't even bail him out till the morning.
- He broke into my house.
Oh, come on. He worked his ass off
to pay for this house, Corrine.
- What are you thinking?
- My kids are sleeping. Good night.
- I really need for his head
to be in the game right now.
- Then go tell him.
He's worried about you, and that kind
of distraction can get him killed.
- Me and the other guys too.
- That's not my fault.
Go home, Shane.
Would you just back off?
Just leave him...Just leave him alone!
- What were you thinking?
- Hey, where I come from...
when a guy's lady jams him up,
his buddies have a talk with her.
- Not in the middle of the night, Jethro.
- I'm sorry.
But you need to be able
to concentrate right now.
- Are you okay?
- Where are we with the money train?
- It's definitely pulling out tonight.
- What's the new collection point?
Well, we don't know yet.
What about the guy who ran
the last site, shut it down?
- We ran his plates. Got an address.
- His name's Chorekian.
- He's the advance man.
- Follow him. Maybe he'll
take us to the new site.
Took us two months to scout the last site.
You want to do this one in a few hours?
We still got the truck, the equipment,
the plans. All that stays the same.
- Might stay the same.
- Never get another chance like this again.
Let's remember where
this Armenian money's coming from...
prostitution, drugs, robberies.
And the rest of this cash is just gonna
finance more of the same.
They didn't earn it.
I don't feel bad about taking it.
We get a little for ourselves,
set the Armenian mob back months.
Ronnie, you gas up the truck,
ready the equipment.
Shane, Lem, you get on
this Armenian advance man.
- See where he takes us.
- All right. Come on.
- David, who'd you vote for?
- I'll give you a hint.
- He's Latino.
- And he's handsome.
Any comment on the report
you recommended the chief fire...
the anti-gang unit you oversee?
I didn't feel they were meeting the high
standards we expect of our officers.
The report also suggests
you offered yourself up as well.
I'm their commanding officer.
They were my responsibility.
If I'm gonna hold them to a high standard,
I should expect the same of myself.
Chief Bankston, it's good
to finally meet you.
Captain Aceveda seems to think
your team is a real problem.
He's recommending that I fire you all.
My team is responsible
for more than 50%...
of drug and gang arrests
in that district.
The results are impressive.
It's the methods that have me concerned.
Aceveda and I don't always
see eye to eye on tactics.
Well, that won't be
a problem for long.
After he loses
the primary today, he's resigning.
I don't know what kind of latitude
the last chief gave you...
but I believe in doing things well
and doing them right.
So do I.
I know when a cop has
his toe over the line, Detective.
Are you going to be able to maintain your
stellar arrest rate without crossing any lines?
- Absolutely.
- Prove it to me...
or I'll have no problem acting on
your captain's recommendations.
You put my team on the termination list
you gave to the chief?
I don't have time for you.
I've gotta tell 27 people today...
the chief's office
just fired them.
That's right, and I'm not one of them.
You are, aren't you?
Consider yourself
on desk duty for the day.
- Where do you get off trying...
- I heard about your arrest.
Congratulations.
Go clean up your own house...
instead of continuing
to mess up mine.
The chief wants me out making cases,
and that's exactly what I'm gonna do.
- I gave you an order.
- You're a goddamn lame duck.
- An order you'll goddamn follow.
- Or what? You'll recommend that I'm fired?
Been nice knowing you.
Can you read his lips?
Even if I could,
I don't speak Armenian, bro.
That's his third call in the last five blocks.
He's definitely notifying the troops.
All right. He's moving again.
He's moving.
Follow the money.
Let's go.
Claudette, there's been
a homicide on Dresden.
- Great. We're ready to roll.
- No.
- The victim's your ex-husband, Jeff Franklin.
- You're kidding.
Your daughter Bonnie's there.
She's supposed to be
in Florida. Is she okay?
I think so, but she's a witness.
Dutch, you take the case.
You'll have to be limited to observing.
Uh, I've got a personal involvement,
granted a tertiary one.
Shouldn't you hand it off
to Brent or Marlon?
We're gonna be a little shorthanded
today. The case is yours.
- Brent, Marlon.
- Yeah, Captain.
Can I see you
up in my office, please?
Here it comes.
- You ready?
- Not really.
- Mom.
- There's blood. Let me get that for ya.
- He-He shot him.
- I know.
He's gone.
I know, honey.
- You got it.
- I'm sorry, Bonnie.
There's not a single damn witness...
none that we could find...
except the daughter.
- That's Claudette's ex-husband?
- Yeah.
Tell the M.E. to move his ass. I want
the body released as soon as possible.
Gotcha.
Christ, is this guy
on quaaludes?
He don't want to get pulled over.
It's a good sign.
- Means he's close to a go.
- Goddamn it. Get your ass in gear, granny.
Did he just hit him?
I'm sorry. I didn't... I didn't think
you were gonna stop.
- It's goddamn yellow. What's wrong with you?
- No reason to get upset.
No reason for you. You drive a piece
of shit. I just bought this car.
- Relax. I'm covered.
- We're gonna lose the
goddamn money train over this.
- What do we do if...
- I don't know.
- Oh, no way.
- Try getting outta here. Go around the block.
- Shit.
- Cover up.
- You saw him hit me, right?
- Yeah, he rear-ended you, man. It sucks.
You be my witness for insurance?
- You would do that?
- Sure. Yeah. I guess I could do that.
- Yeah.
- Give me your number.
You know, I tell you,
I'm always on the road.
Maybe we should just
exchange cell numbers.
- Otherwise, you know, we'll
probably never hook up.
- Yeah. Okay.
It's always the ones that don't
give a shit about their cars...
- that run into yours.
- You don't have to tell me.
I'm Armin Chorekian.
- Cletis van Damme.
- Thank you for your help.
I call you.
Cletis van Damme?
There's nothing major
going on right now.
Streets are up for grabs, and there's not
one gang case in the last 24 hours...
- we can sink our teeth into?
- Sorry.
Hey, what's the rush?
The chief's evaluating our unit.
We have to appear busy
and irreplaceable.
I know Dutch is working
on a homicide from this morning.
I don't know the details.
Uh, Dutch-boy,
what are you workin' on?
Claudette's ex-husband
was shot and killed.
Her daughter Bonnie
witnessed the whole thing.
Oh, man. What happened?
They were sitting in a car,
black male walked up, said something...
then just shot the guy
ran away.
- It's a gang thing?
- I don't know...
and Bonnie's been
too upset to talk to.
I still don't know
why she and her dad were there.
Let me work the gang angle.
See if there's anything there.
Great. I'll make a copy
of my notes up till now.
If he's in here,
I'll recognize him.
There are a lot of pictures
in there, so take your time.
You need to take a break
to eat, anything, just ask, okay?
Okay.
You do me a favor.
You see him in there, you tell me first.
- Don't say anything to Dutch, okay?
- Why?
Because there are
a lot of ways to make a case...
and being a star eyewitness at a murder trial
doesn't have to be your first option.
Not with the kind of guy
who did this.
- This is Dad we're talking about.
- I know.
I don't care what I have to do.
I know you feel that way right now,
but I'm only watching out for you.
God, Mom.
I can't believe you.
I'm not talking about
letting whoever did this go free.
I just don't want you to get into
something you can't get out of later.
If you see him in there,
you tell me first.
I hear you called Julien's house.
Told his little boy
that he was gay?
- I think you got the wrong guys.
- I got the right assholes.
The both of you have been shooting your
mouths off about how much fun you're having.
I got no problem with someone
being gay out there, but in here I...
If it's so cool, why doesn't he just
come out and say it?
Why is he lying
about who he is?
I'm putting you both on notice.
Fun's over, or I end it myself.
- Herman, what do you got?
- Something.
But what's in it for my boys?
We lay off that gambling joint
you're running near MacArthur Park.
- What gambling joint?
- The one in the back
of Morty's Sporting Goods.
Oh, that one. Okay.
So you all heard
of the E-ParkJohnnies?
- Not recently. They still kicking around?
- They still breathing.
With Armadillo and the Torrucos out
of business, everything is opening up out there.
The Johnnies are looking to get back
on top of the bangers heap.
Good luck.
Jesus Christ, Herman, pick that up.
Pick it up!
Hey, sorry, man.
Strictly for medicinal purposes.
So what does the Johnnies
trying to bring back the glory days...
have to do with some dad
getting shot in his car?
All I heard was the Johnnies were bragging
about throwing some kind of April Fool's party.
- April Fool's party?
- Yeah, that's all I heard, man.
- Bonnie.
- Yes?
- Hi, I'm Detective Mackey.
- Hi. Tavon Garris.
- Hi.
- I'm sorry about your father.
- Thank you.
- I just have one question for you.
The shooter...he said something
to your dad before he fired?
Yes. I...I couldn't hear him very well.
The window was up.
Did it sound like,
"Johnny says April Fool's"?
It was something
like that, yeah.
I couldn't hear it clear, but...
What does that mean?
Bonnie?
- What are you doing?
- Answering his questions.
He's not involved in this case.
Look, 10 years ago,
the E-ParkJohnnies...
were the predominant
gang in Farmington.
They controlled drugs,
sex, everything.
Until the Mexicans
started outnumbering them.
Compton gangs started moving in,
squeezed the Johnnies right out.
I talked to my
old partner, Joe Clarke.
He says the E-ParkJohnnies
used to throw what they called
April Fool's parties.
What are those?
Every year they tally up how many
members got killed out on the street...
then they get the whole membership
together, and they pick dominoes.
- Dominoes?
- Yeah. You pick the right one...
you get to be one of
the shooters.
- Who'd they shoot?
- Didn't matter. Walk right up to 'em...
and say, "Johnny says April Fool's,"
boom... they'd shoot 'em.
And, uh, that's what your daughter
heard the shooter say this morning.
The April Fool's parties dried up
about 10 years ago...
but looks like
they're back on.
Thanks for the tip.
Dutch'll take care of it.
- Is there a problem with
us helping or something?
- No, it doesn't concern you.
Dutch will take care of it.
Run the gang database for Johnnies
that were killed in the last year...
and get a current address
for their leader.
Uh, street name's Lops.
- Lops?
- He's got a lopsided head.
- I don't know his real tag.
- All right. I'm working it.
- You lost him?
- He got in a fender bender
right in front of us.
- We're his witnesses.
- You gotta be shittin' me.
Once he saw our faces and our ride,
we couldn't stay too close.
We stayed back for a while,
tried to follow him. We lost him.
Everything's ready, and you tell me
we still don't know where to go?
We got his cell number.
Maybe we can trace it.
- Not without a warrant.
- Yeah, and it's a trail we can't leave.
Where's Radiohead's
crib these days?
Radiohead?
- Ugh!
- Oh, my God! What, did he die in here?
Radiohead,
show us your ass!
Hey, put the gun down!
I told you guys to stop
barging in on me like this.
God, man! When was the last time
you took a shower?
- The water got shut off last month.
- Ever heard of a sponge bath?
- I'm boycotting all things French.
- We got tracer software.
We know you trace cell phones for
the Baja Diablo cartel.
- You pick 'em right out of the air, right?
- Yeah.
We need a location
on a cell phone.
I can pull the cell
phones off the towers...
but if he's not transmitting, I won't be
able to triangulate his exact location.
We'll settle for an approximate.
Ronnie's gonna run the numbers.
The rest of us are headed for
fresh air.
That's really nice, you sending your fag
hag partner to fight your battles.
- I'm working.
- How come you lied to us about who you are?
How are we supposed to trust you with
our lives if you're gonna lie like that, Julien?
I'll do my job. You do yours.
You know what bothers me the most?
Is that you're a hypocrite.
You gave that faggot a blanket party, knowing
you'd like to be under the blanket with him.
You call my son again,
and I'll kill you.
You know, maybe I should've called
Social Services.
See if that kid
still has his cherry.
You understand me?
Call him again, and I'll kill you.
You think you could do
this job by yourself, huh?
You don't need backup?
'Cause they're never gonna show up.
- I want to see a show, man!
- Easy.
What's wrong?
Maybe, uh, Jeff's murder...
wasn't part of some gangland
April Fool's prank.
Bonnie's being, uh, vague...
about what they were doing
in that neighborhood.
That area's a known drug market.
Stop right there.
I did some checking on Jeff.
He had a bit of a rough go of it
after your divorce.
A couple of dope charges.
Disturbing the peace.
Is there anything you wanna
tell me about him?
He had his demons.
None that deserved
to get him killed.
Okay.
Anything yet?
No.
Was your father doing something
down there he shouldn't have been?
- Mom...
- Something to do with drugs?
You always thought
the worst of him.
- No, I didn't.
- You did.
You don't remember.
You were very young.
Why didn't you tell me
you were in town?
Dad wanted to see me.
It was only for a couple of days.
I just didn't wanna be
running back and forth.
Did you find him?
His signal has appeared somewhere in
the sector between these three cell towers.
This is mostly
unoccupied industrial area.
- Same type of place as last time.
- That's gotta be where
the money train's pulling in.
Do some recon. See if the old plan
will work at the new site.
Hey, I got that
crib address on Lops.
- I'll have a warrant within an hour.
- That's great.
- What are y'all doin' in?
- Can't stay away from this
place, even on our day off.
I'll leave you two to your work.
- How long till you get down here?
- Soon, I promise.
Machado called. Your interview's
playing all over the tube.
- People are responding.
- But we were four points back just last night.
The exit polls are encouraging.
- How's Hispanic turnout?
- Better than expected.
Machado says we really have a chance, baby.
We really do.
Uh, I'll see you
as soon as I can.
- I love you, babe.
- Me too.
Randy. Come on in.
- Yeah?
- Hey. We found it.
It's almost identical
to our last site.
One way in, one way out.
Even has a Dumpster we can use.
- They're still settin' up.
- So it's doable?
- It's absolutely doable.
- Let me talk to him for a sec.
Hey, boss, look,
if they change locations...
maybe there's other aspects
they've changed too.
Let me see it.
Look, it's right in our
comfort zone, Vic.
Okay. What's the vote, then?
I'm good.
He wants a vote.
He's in, so am I.
- What about you two?
- Let's do it.
- Okay.
- We're good to go.
Thanks for
inviting us in, Lops.
- You didn't get no invite!
- Sure we did.
I can back him up on that.
- What you want, man?
- How are the Johnnies these days?
Black is back.
You lost three of your Johnny bros
this year, huh?
And loved them all.
You like playing dominoes, Lops?
You're bringing back
the April Fool's parties, huh?
I got one man dead already.
A black man, by the way.
When are you dumbasses gonna shoot up
Beverly Hills for a change, huh?
There are two more shooters
out there, aren't there?
I don't see any
double threes here, Lops.
That's the magic
number this year, isn't it?
- Double threes for your three dead homies.
- Whatever, man.
Who are the shooters?
You better step off, man,
before I get my Cochrane involved.
You think we playing, Lop-head?
Hey, come on, man. You ain't gonna
do nothin'with that.
You know who your buddy
killed today, Lops?
Look, man, I don't even know
what you're talking about.
- That was the husband of a cop.
- A cop we work with, asshole.
She's a friend of mine,
and you...
- you killed her husband.
- No, man!
Goddamn!
You only got five more
wrong answers in you, boy.
Now, who... are...
the shooters?
The only thing worse than killing a cop
is killing a cop's loved one...
so you know I will
pull this trigger.
We'll just write it down as another nigger
in the wrong place at the wrong time.
Mmm!
- Who are they?
- This is gonna be the one, Tavon. I can feel it.
Yeah, me too.
I better get my raincoat.
Okay! Okay! Okay, man!
Okay! Okay! Okay!
Just put the gun down.
You put the gun down,
I'll play ball with you, all right?
What happened with
you and Jackson?
Nothing we can't
handle ourselves, sir.
I know what's going on, Julien.
What you've been subjected to.
I don't care about your personal life.
What I do care about is intolerance.
If you have a complaint...
now is the time to lodge it.
Like I said, sir,
nothing I can't handle.
Okay, then.
Okay, they're here.
Do me a favor.
- Ask them if they can give you
a ride back to the barn.
- Is everything all right?
Oh, yeah, I just gotta be somewhere for
an hour. I'll check back in on you then.
Your partner's a goddamn psycho!
Yes, he is.
Then you tell that
asshole he's too late.
Too late for what?
Charlie there's already at
the street fair right now.
Too late, man.
Hey, you tell him that.
Yo, Tavon!
- Yo!
- Go get my truck, quick.
Let's go. You!
Come and take this man!
Find out where
there's a street fair in this area.
Get every unit.
We got a shooter down there.
- Yeah?
- I'm gonna be
running a little bit late.
You and Shane are gonna have to
start without me.
- How late? What are you talking about?
- I can't explain right now.
- What's he sayin'?
- He might not be makin' it.
Are you serious? Vic, we'll never
get this chance again.
- Please!
- Put Shane on.
- Vic, what's going on?
- I'm gonna make it.
You're just gonna have to start
the plan without me.
- What if you get stuck or something?
- You can still do it.
- No. No way. Not without you.
- You planned for three. You still got three.
- That's when you were one of the three.
- You could still do this.
I trust you.
I'll be there when I can.
I'm driving.
Goddamn it.
What three-person plan?
- You were ready to do this without me?
- You always had reservations.
It was only Plan "B."
- Fine. Let's go with Plan "B" then.
- I don't know.
Until we see if Vic's gonna make it,
it's too risky.
We don't get on the inside now, the whole
thing will be ruined, even if Vic does show up.
- All right, I vote we go now.
- Me too.
Okay, we're looking for the guy on
the right. Pass it around. He's armed.
Follow me. Come on.
Fan out. Fan out.
Take that way inside.
Guys, come on!
Double threes.
- Take him!
- Take him.
Don't move. Don't move.
- That's not bad for a day's work, huh?
- Yeah.
Hey, listen.
You could do me a favor.
- I gotta be somewhere.
- I'll take care of the paperwork.
Thanks.
Only two more vans to go.
What's this?
What the hell
are they talkin'about?
What, like I speak
European hick?
Goddamn it.
What the hell is goin'on?
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Jesus Christ.
Holy sh...
- What do we do now?
- I gotta stop Ronnie.
Maybe the best thing to do
is just stick to the plan.
We don't even know
if Vic's made it yet.
- And I'm callin' Ronnie off.
- Look, they got sidearms. We got rifles, man.
No. The whole plan
was no bloodshed.
It's all screwed up now.
Oh, Christ.
Look, it's not their money. They're not gonna
die for it, okay? We can do this.
Look, I'm not gettin'
you two killed.
- Goddamn it!
- What?
There's no reception.
I gotta get a signal.
Will you stop movin' around, man?
They're gonna see us.
Hey, listen, there isn't
cell service here, remember?
We're in the black hole.
That's how we found this place.
Sir, I need to talk to you about
Jackson and Carlson.
Is this about the fight with Julien?
Yeah, and the homophobic flyers
and the gay bashing.
- They're behind all of that.
- I talked to Julien. He didn't mention names.
Right. Look, I'm not a rat, sir...
but those guys have been making noises
about not backing us up on the street.
I mean, that's Julien's life and that's
my life. I'm not gonna let that pass.
Thank you for
mentioning it to me.
Since you're here,
I need to talk to you.
You know that the chief's
put together a list...
- and we've gotta cut 20% of the force.
- You're kidding me.
Your name's on the list.
Armadillo's death in the cage.
I got suspended for that. I paid
the price. You're firing me for it?
It's the chief's call.
I'm sorry.
Have you talked to Vic and the Strike
Team about how that guy got the knife?
- I've heard the rumors.
- Yeah?
Who's looking into it while my career's
being flushed down the goddamn toilet?
Right now... nobody.
Here's Ronnie.
- He must have heard the shots.
- Ohh, oh, this is not good.
- Where is Vic?
- We gotta do this now,
before he's hung out to dry.
Look, I'm gonna take the guy
with the MP-5.
You take the skinny guy with the beanie
and the blowgun.
Come on, man.
We gotta do this now.
On the goddamn ground!
- Get down right now!
- Get down!
Everybody down now!
Get your ass down! Down!
Get on the ground!
Get down! Get down there!
- You good? You clear?
- Clear!
Goddamn it, this guy's hurt.
- Face down!
- Oh, shit. It's the last van.
Guys, don't move,
don't move. Do not...
Okay.
Go. Go get him!
Don't move!
- Stay right there! Hands on the wheel!
- Go, go, go, go, go!
Thank God
you made it, man.
What the hell happened here?
We got dead bodies?
It wasn't us.
They turned on each other.
Ronnie heard the shots.
The whole thing went down a van early.
Jesus!
- We gotta go. If anybody heard those shots...
- We also got a wounded Armenian.
If this guy doesn't get medical help,
he's gonna bleed out and die.
That's not our problem.
We didn't shoot him.
Now let's load up
and get the hell outta here.
Yeah, so we didn't shoot him,
but we can save him.
I don't want that blood
on my conscience.
Me either. We better hurry.
Let's go.
- Do you want to live or die?
- Live. Please.
Well, then, you listen
very carefully, Dach.
- We're gonna get you to the doctor.
- Thank you.
Then we're gonna stop by your house
and hide some of this money...
and since you're the only guy
who's gonna be missing from here...
your buddies are gonna figure that we took
care of you because you were our inside man.
They'll come looking for you...
and the only thing they'll find
at your house is their stolen cash.
And then they'll know
you were the one...
who tipped us off
about the money train.
- I don't even know who you are.
- Well, that's gonna be our little secret.
Once you get fixed up, you're running
away, Dach, and never coming back.
Yes. Just get me help, please.
Do you see the man
that shot your father?
- What?
- If this goes to trial...
I don't want Bonnie being a witness...
in a gang killing.
Understand?
Yeah. Yeah, I understand.
If I were to question these men...
any idea who I should
start with first?
I'd start with number two.
You and your two friends...
You all drew the double-three dominoes.
We found one on each of you.
Two of you didn't kill anyone,
but one of you did.
I don't know nothin'
about no killin'.
Okay, we'll see who your two friends
point the finger at...
'cause one of you is going to jail.
Hang up!
I don't want to go to jail
for something I didn't do...
just 'cause one of them
said I did.
Then put someone else there.
I don't care who.
It was Mouser.
He did it.
Hey.
- Make it in time?
- Where?
- Wherever you were going.
- Oh, yeah.
Just an errand.
Got it handled.
No biggie.
Anything happen around here?
We got the other two domino shooters
without any other killings.
- Dutch is upstairs sorting them out.
- Sweet.
Anything else happening?
Nah. Other than that,
it's been quiet.
Good.
- What's up?
- I just got fired.
- What?
- Yeah. My name's on the casualty list.
- Any guesses why?
- Jesus Christ. I'm sorry.
You're the one that's always talking about
your boys being such stand-up guys...
You and I both know that my name
doesn't belong on that list.
Let's see how much of
a stand-up guy you really are.
- What?
- You fired Danny?
- The chief's office did.
- She doesn't deserve that.
You got to do something.
Armadillo died because Danny
didn't properly pat down the prisoner.
- Ah...
- Unless you have something
to share with the chief...
this conversation's over.
Do you?
Or are you a coward?
Too bad.
She was a good officer.
It was Mouser.
He did it.
Ohh, man!
I can't believe
he'd just give me up like that.
- I didn't do it.
- You ready to give him up?
He killed that man.
He wanted to be the first one
of the three of us.
Real important to him.
How do I know you're the one
telling the truth?
Yo, I fill you in
on where he hides his gun.
- I hear we got the shooters upstairs.
- Looks like it.
Well, not to pat myself
on the back or anything...
Results don't excuse bad behavior.
Tell you what.
It's clear you and I
have some issues...
so why don't we agree just not to work
with each other anymore.
The question isn't whether
I can work with you.
It's how you're gonna handle
working for me.
You?
Me.
Fired for cause.
This is bullshit!
They're gonna have the most P.C.,
useless force in the country.
Julien gets outed
and throws a bitch-fit...
and we take the fall
for some friendly ribbing?
Maybe they just don't get
your sophisticated brand of humor.
You trying to tell me this place is better off
with him than the three of us?
Don't put me in your corner.
I didn't deserve what I got.
I have prepared two speeches
for this evening.
I hope I get to use the one
in my left pocket.
But whatever happens, win or lose...
I thank you all.
Your support
has been a blessing.
To my lovely wife, Aurora...
te amo.
Tu eres mi estrella brillante.
Danny.
This isn't fair.
No, it's not.
Look, um...
I can't tell you...
how much I... I've
learned from you.
Well, here's one last thing...
You watch your back
around these people, okay?
- Any sign of Armenians yet?
- Nope.
- How's our bleeder?
- Dropped him off at a clinica.
Backroom doc's sewing him up
as we speak.
Our bleeder's gonna make it,
and he's gonna shake out of town.
Good. Let's finish this.
Although statewide turnout has been
somewhat lower than average...
- How deep you wanna bury this?
- Not very.
These transplants from Brighton Beach
are more beach than bright.
In the city council races...
- Hey.
District three is reporting in now
with 89% of the vote.
Nah, nah. A little more clever
than that, okay?
The fifth district is still tight,
with Elliot Orlon edging closer...
to incumbent
Barnard Fortain.
Hey. This is good.
Police Captain David Aceveda
won a tight primary race...
against challenger Karen Mitchell
to become that district's...
first Hispanic
Democratic candidate for council.
And since the district
is 82% Democrat...
it's a safe bet that Aceveda
will soon be the first elected...
Hispanic representative
on the council...
from the Farmington District
of Los Angeles.
- I thought he was gonna lose.
- He was supposed to.
What does that mean?
It means Aceveda isn't gonna be gone
as fast as we thought.
And six months from now,
he's gonna be our boss's boss.
I can always tell
when you're lying to me.
No, you always
thought you could.
What were you and your father doing
on that street today?
There's a flower store there.
He wanted to go in
and pick up some flowers.
For Jenny...
his fiancée.
Jeff was engaged?
- What... Why didn't you...
- I didn't want to hurt your feelings.
Dad told me once...
how much you liked it
when he surprised you with flowers.
He really got his life together.
He was... happy.
He was waiting for the right time
for us to tell you.
Oh, what was stopping you?
I don't know. You just...
seem lonely...
lately.
I'm just glad nothing
happened to you.
I lost my partner.
That's not nothing.
I know. Thank you, baby.
I hope she's okay.
Thank you, sweetheart.
We'll do what we can for her.
Um, let's talk
about this later, okay?
No!
I would've called. I just didn't have
the new number.
You can't be here. Uh, tell Shane
not to come back either.
I didn't send him.
He shouldn't have done that. Please.
Thanks.
We're not supposed to be
talking like this. You should go.
I know. Uh, I won't come back again
without permission.
I just was so worried about the kids,
spending time with them. I...
I got lost somewhere
in all this.
I never meant to hurt you
the way that I have.
I'm so sorry about that.
I want you to know,
uh...
you're gonna be taken care of.
The kids?
They don't have anything
to worry about either.
Tell 'em I love 'em.
And, uh...
call my lawyer and let him know
when a good time to see them is.
Mama!