Bring your behind out here! I see you, fool!
Why you hidin'? Why you hidin'?
I see you hidin'in there, punkass!
- Drop the hose
- Get your ass out here
- I called. Can you
get this under control, please?
- Drop the hose.
- What happened?
- He's always startin'trouble.
- Who?
- Mr Super Soaker in there
- He sprayed us first.
- You wanna step outside, please?
Sir, did you spray these women?
Wait till Juicy get ahold
of your ass.
I was watering down my sidewalk.
If some crack whores...
happen to get wet,
that's just life
We got the right to walk public streets.
You don't have the right
to work them
- Look,you can't spray people like that.
- I was just hosing down the hos.
Well, it's a public sidewalk
That's a crime
What about them sellin' ass
in the front of my store all day long?
Or what about them dope dealers
selling crack rock-- is that a crime?
You need to worry about
yourself,comic boy.
- You don't wanna be making threats.
Come with me.
- Wait tillJuicy gets your ass
- He'll wrap that hose around your neck
till your eyes pop
- This hose right here?
- Yo, right here
- Drop--
A hundred and ninety-five
thousand All that's left
- That's split three ways, right?
- Yeah Yeah
- Sixty-five grand apiece
- Turns out Lem's cut was 2.8 million in ashes.
So we got the goddamn Armenians after us,
Treasury, for, uh--
for 65 grand
Look, we can't show up
every time you see a hooker take a stroll
- Plus, there's no one out here
- These whores see you drivin' up
and they get ghost
Soon as you leave,
they're right back out here
Antagonizing them is gonna
make things worse for you.
Well, I'm tryin'
to make things better, man.
- Your primary concern needs to be
your own safety
- I can take care of myself
And I'm not leaving.
I'm not goin'anywhere.
Everything else'll be exactly the same:;
the same school, same friends.
You'll just
be living with me
And weekends with me--
just a reverse of the way it is now
- How do I get to school?
- I'll bring you when I can, and I'll get some help.
Just like Camilla
helps Mom
What about Matt and Megan?
Megan will live with Mom.
but that just means
I'll have you all to myself
Cassidy, do you want to
talk about this some more?
Why are you mad at me?
I'm not mad at you, baby
Cassidy, your mom and I just love you
and want to spend time with you, that's all
It-- It's just my turn
for a little while
Okay?
That hobbit we found hiding in an oil drum
finally spit out the truth.
- The Armenian heroin bust?
-Just one small slice of a much larger pie
that Margos has smuggled
into Tinseltown
- How much larger?
- Frodo says 1 0 to 1 5 times
the size of yesterday's haul.
- Holy shit
- Margos has it stashed in a residence.
Once a week, they pick up enough
to feed their suppliers
- Tomorrow's delivery day
- Great
Uh, you showed up
on Shane's door last night
wanted to see
some storage locker of his?
The Armenian money train cash is still
unaccounted for, so's the prime suspect, O'Brien
It was suggested that I look into
your team's involvement
- Dutch?
- After this Armenian thing
gets cleared up, I need you...
running the AGC
car surveillance sting
but not if you're gonna be under suspicion
for something like this
And Wagenbach's
still pushing you?
I haven't been able to convince him
that it's a dead end
- What are you doing?
- You got Aceveda lookin' into me?
Kitchen's closed
You whisperin'
into my boss's ear?
You don't have the sac
to face me head-on?
You knew the name of the bar where O'Brien
says he found the marked money
- I already explained that
- A little too smoothly, in my opinion
How you comin' along
finding O'Brien?
Not too far
I been bustin' half the Armenian mob all week
Why is it Shane Vendrell
had an empty storage locker
under the name ''Cletus Van Damme''--
the same name he gave to an Armenian
who witnessed the money train robbery?
If that's all you got,
I wouldn't be lookin' so smug
- Absence of proof isn't proof of absence
- You're back on my shit list
- Excuse me?
- Number one with a bullet, Dutch-boy
You look into me all you want.
You're back to being a joke in this building.
- Let's go!
- Hands on your head!
Put that phone down! Drop that phone!
- Hands on your head.
- Get on the couch! Sit down right now!
- Get your ass on the couch!
- We're clear?
- We're clear!
All right
Where are you hidin' the hell dust? Where?
Last chance before
we start renovating
Claudette Wyms,
ADA Rommi Cohen
We've met before
I brought Rommi down here
to discuss the Lisa Kensit situation
- I know you had some worries
- Good work on picking up her shooter.
Thanks
I'm just pulling things together
I was gonna contact your office in a few days
You have some suspicions of
possible drug use by the victim?
More than that
I've got her dealer and her hook-up
Marlon Gault. Says, off the record,
he supplied her for over three years.
He'll go on record if your office can provide him
with some consideration
He shot her in the face He's a dealer
Why would we shave years off?
Well, because if it's true, some ofher clients
may not have received adequate counsel.
No, she's a junior P.D.
All ofher cases are signed off on.
Trust me
They got adequate counsel
You can be sure there wasn't even one mistake
in almost 300 cases?
You wanted it brought to the DA
She'll look into it
Now you can get back
to the rest of your caseload
She means well
She just doesn't see the big picture
Well,you seem
to have her under control.
Phil's having Gault's statements
about dealing to Kensit suppressed at his trial
We're not going
to let it get far
As long as you pull the files
and everything's aboveboard
Well, most of the arrests originated here.
Maybe we could...
get together for dinner later this week
and discuss a game plan
Or drinks?
My wife and I
have a rule about me
having dinners alone
with female colleagues
Oh. I'm sorry. I--
I didn't see a ring.
Oh, I, um, must've forgotten to put it on
after the gym this morning
Just an accident
I'll let Phil know how, uh, helpful you were
Thank you
And thank you
- Nothin'
Shane, anything?
- Nada
- Goddamn it.
Keep lookin'
Enjoying the show?
Margos moved the heroin yesterday
when you captured Kail
- Where is he?
- Right now, no clue
- He's gonna find me after I have your answer
- Answer to what?
You've done
a lot of damage to us.
He wonders if maybe there's a way
to stop this war?
- What does he want?
- Move the heroin up north
He wants you
to provide security
And what do I get?
Five percent commission on the sale.
That'd be about a half a mil.
Plus, Margos leaves LA
and guarantees the safety of you and your men
Otherwise--
They want us to escort the heroin
from this address
- in two hours
- Well, how do we know this offer's even legit?
- We don't.
- It would get us back to even, but, uh--
Workin' with these psycho assholes
is off the table
- Yeah.
- Question is-- What's their angle?
- You think it's a trap?
- Only the three of us, no backup--
- Which leads us to the next problem.
- What?
If we bring in extra bodies, and Margos is there,
some other cop can take him alive.
And all he's gotta do is get a message
to his lawyer.
We take a bullet
while he's eatin' three hot ones in county
No We've gotta take him down
in a way that clears departmental review
- Listen, Lem--
- Yeah, I got some time coming,
about eight weeks.
I'm gonna take it
When I get back, I'll put in for a transfer
Okay.
Margos is still after us
We're safer together
until we've got him
Maybe you should hang with us
until we get it sorted out
Yeah
Ripped by:
Hound
All right, there it is
Quiet street Only one way in
I don't like that
We could go in hard
Without knowin'
who or what's inside?
We don't show, Margos
almost has to come after us.
We may not know what's inside,
but they don't know when we're comin'
Unless they have a spotter
Margos was watching
our drug bust from on high
Now, see, there--
maybe top floor,
one of the three or four with a view.
- Hey!
- Don't move!
Nice lookout.
Is it a trap?
- Is Margos inside? Get up!
Tryin' to get us killed,
you little prick? Huh?
All right
Write Write!
L-I-F-E
New word New word
S-U-X
Ronnie, open that window.
Looks like you're gonna die
a bad speller
Wait! Wait! Wait!
Inside, waiting for you, to kill
- No, no, no
- Is Margos inside?
No
- Is he inside?
- No!
- Who sent you here?
- Goma Goma Magar
- Who's he?
- American
Scruffy guy, about six foot?
Yeah I met him
this morning
- Here Eat this
No Margos, no heroin?
- Nah,just guns Call for SWAT
Have 'em flush 'em out
- Yeah
Lisa and I were close, but after a while
it was just better for her to move out
Her shooter suggested he'd been providing her
with drugs for years
- What difference does that make now?
- She handled a lot of cases...
a lot of people
who went to jail
Who deserved to go.
Isn't this something the D.A.
should be looking into?
I'll need more evidence before they'll touch it.
I need your help.
She might die
I'm not ruining her reputation
and if she lives,
I'm not ruining her career
She made some bad choices,
but she's still my friend.
- Can't you talk to him?
- We have.
I mean, the guy comes off
like a regular citizen, but
he's probably flyin' around
that store with a cape on
- He's just standing up for himself
- Oh, come on,Julien.
He's not just pissing off hookers and pimps
It's drug dealers too
- The guy's gonna get killed
- If other people on that street
stood up like him...
the drugs and the girls
would already be gone
Sure, and I can just put on my genie outfit
and blink 'em away.
Keep talkin' to the residents
and find out how bad this problem is
- What's goin'on?
- I rescued these on a bust.
I'm just tryin' to give 'em away
before the pound drops the gas on 'em
- You want one?
Oh, look at that face
How could you say no?
He's just thinkin'of all the times
pussy told him no.
Pussy said yes plenty
Uh, no thanks
- How's it goin'?
- D.A. won't deal.
If Lisa Kensit was handling cases
high on Oxy for three years
they don't want to know about it,
Aceveda either
- That's a lot of plea bargains
and convictions at stake
- I spoke to her old roommate
She won't corroborate
the drug use
Look, you've done more
than the job calls for
Wh-Why keep pushing this
and pissing everybody off?
I could ride this one solo,
and if
Aceveda and the chief come down on me,
it's one more time
You don't have to put
your job on the line too
Okay
Listen, uh, Lem's dad's not doin' too great
He's gonna need to take some time
- I'm sorry to hear that
- Well, depending on what happens
he might not be back at all
With Tavon gone, now Lem too, I'm not
gonna be able to do it all with just three guys.
I'm gonna need
to bring on a man or two.
When I reduced your team
to buy-busts
it was because the chief was evaluating
special units throughout the city
to see what would happen
- And?
- Crime went up
but not enough tojustify the lawsuits
and bad press over the last few years.
The police commission has advised
phasing them out
- They're dumping Special Teams?
- Chief won't admit failure by disbanding them
but he's not going
to re-man them either
So, wejust wither and die.
If Lem leaves,
the Strike Team won't be functional
You can still cover the AGC sting, but--
but no gang or drug detail
- Are you kidding me?
- So now Lem's boned us twice.
Money train was my idea
Everything that came after started with me
I'll set it straight, but we might have to try
to talk Lem into staying
I'd rather break up domestics in Van Nuys
than worry if Lem's got my back
You don't really
believe that
Got an address
on that Goma guy
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Got it Here
- Oh, great Fido's home
- I got an idea
- Hey, hey!
- You don't need to shoot him
- I don't need to, but I'd like to
- What's your idea?
- Ronnie, go around back, bang on the door,
draw his attention
Go, go, go
- Come here, puppy! Come here
Come on.
Come here, puppy. Whoo!
Sorry to step
on your happy
Right there!
Hey! Hey! Come on!
- Oh, shit! Get out! Get out!
- Damn it
- He saved you a bullet
- Cost him a pair of tighty whities
- Looks like you found something
- Ah, like most cases, they're all judgment calls
Well, if she was high,
her judgment was off
These on top are the sketchiest:
iffy eyewitnesses, no evidence, no follow-up I--
- I'd start here
- Thanks
Was that the public defender
Ben Horton?
- Yes
- What was he doing here?
Dropping off
Lisa Kensit's files
Goddamn it, I told you to leave this alone
Are you in on this too?
- No
- No These are public records
- Why would you commit career suicide like this?
- Myjob comes before my career.
You know, she's just trying to make sure
nobody innocent's sitting in jail
We're all trying to uphold the law, Dutch
It'd be nice if she remembered that sometime
Speaking of which, um, whatever happened
with you lookin' into Vic?
I didn't find anything
Did you try?
Actually, I did
- I got nothing promising.
- I have a bunch of receipts here.
- For what?
- Uh, dry cleaning
- What else?
Well, they're for thousands of dollars, though
These are oriental rugs
You don't dry-clean
oriental rugs
My-- My mom had some
She made me hand clean 'em when I was a kid
They used rugs for a front for their drug running.
Ayla cooked the books for 'em
Can you talk?
Listen, I, um--
I talked to the guys
at INS
They're doctoring your paperwork
to make it look like you were deported.
This way the bad guys back home
won't know that you helped us.
When do I go back to Armenia?
As soon as we get Margos
You recognize these receipts?
I do, um, invoices for these
But the work
was never done, right?
No dry cleaning. No.
There's no, uh, store name or address
You know where this place is?
I, uh, delivered papers once.
I know where it is
Goma, right? It's your unlucky day, asshole.
Come here!
- You remember me?
- You tried to kill me today
- You here to do your dry cleaning
or to see Margos?
- No
- Where is he?
- I don't know
- Think again
I'm just here
to check on the heroin.
- The drugs are here? All of it?
- Uh-huh.
- How many men are usually inside?
- About a dozen
- Cuff him and keep him outta sight
Call Aceveda and tell him I need a warrant
and every available cop
- What?
If Margos is here, one of us has to separate him,
make sure he goes for a gun
- Do you understand?
- Christ
He wants us dead He can do it
from his prison cell He can't do it from his grave
- If this is too much for you,
why don't you just go home?
- Christ. What is that, blood?
- My ulcer.
What I've been doing every night the last month.
- If you don't have the stomach for this,
maybe you--
- No No!
I'm with you
- Find anything?
Mmm. Tons of guys got crappy deals,
but they all look guilty.
Well, maybejustice can be blind
and stoned.
This guys doing five to 1 0
for robbin' a diner
No evidence
Sole witness is over a block away
- Vic Mackey is the arresting officer
- I'm sure it's by the book then.
I'm gonna take the drive out
to Victorville
and see what this guy Walter Clifton
has to say for himself
- He's gonna say he's innocent
- Well, we'll see if I believe him
- Go, go, go!
- Everybody down!
Get down on the ground!
- Get your hands on your head!
Move out! Move out!
- Come on. Let's go!
- Palms, flat, right now!
Gimme your ID
Captain?
- Vic!
Vic!
- Nice haul
All right, bring 'em out.
Must have been 1 0, 1 2 million worth of''H''
in there, man Thanks for your help
- I didn't help you
- Come on We couldn't have done it without you
- What are you doing?
- Showin' you the love
Crack, get off the block!
- Dial 911!
- Hey!
Get off the block!
Crack!
I told you to put the camera down,
you asshole
- Come here so I can see your face
- Get away from him!
Get off of him! Get off him!
- Get up You all right?
- Yeah Never felt better
Uh-huh You got locked up
How you feel now, crack?
- Got you thrown in jail Who laughin' now?
- Shut up!
Lock him up!
I'm gonna clean this place up!
Get off the block!
What happened exactly?
Our comic book guy videotaped him dealing
- He started swinging.
- He's not backing down
All he wants to do is to get those people
offhis block. Instead of trying to stop him...
maybe we could make
his problem go away
All it will do is move the problem
down a block
Then, when someone on that block
calls with a problem, we'll move it again
I'll assign some unis
Organize a sweep
Where do you see yourself in the department
a year from now?
I don't know
Detective, maybe?
I liked doin' that undercover work
with the Strike Team
You can't apply for those positions
without P3 status
- Yes, sir I am aware of that
- That's why I'm bumping you back up
You're proactive You take charge
You've lived up to our deal
Run the sweep
when you're out there today
Five to 1 0 for armed robbery is pretty much
what you would have gotten if convicted.
- It's not much of a plea bargain
- She said~witnesses put me at the diner
I've already got two felonies
If I went down for this, it'd be my third strike
- Five's better than 20
- Sounds like you came out ahead
- For somethin' I didn't do?
- Why should I believe you?
I don't give a shit
if you believe me or not
I got a new lawyer
who's gonna look into my case
And find what? Two other armed robberies and
you runnin' around with the Farmtown 1 2 in here?
That was all about survival
I didn't wear no colors on the street
- Time's up.
- I just started
- Warden says it's over
Look, I don't know
who this witness was...
- but he didn't see me 'cause I was never there
- What the hell is this?
- Looks like I've pissed off the right people
You think this is funny?
Where's your stuff?.
- Lisa Kensit's clients
- Oh, yeah
- What's going on?
- Some cowardly shitheads messed with her desk
- I'll look into it
- Yeah, right!
- Excuse me?
- Don't tell me you're not a part of this
I just got carried out of Victorville
I spoke to Ben Horton's boss
and the chief
He wasn't too pleased to hear
what you'd been doing.
You mean to tell me this entire house would
rather me pack up and leave than look into this?
Chief and I did discuss this house
and who's gonna run it when I leave
He's decided
to go another way.
- Bring in somebody else
- Now she's not getting the captaincy?
- You gotta be shittin'me.
- It wasn't my choice. It was hers.
She understands
Okay You've had your show
Now go to hell!
- Yeah, I'm talkin'to you, Stone.
Yo, it's my booty,y'all. I'm out!
- What's your name?
- What do you want to arrest me for?
All right. Get her. Bring her in. Come on.
- Yeah See?
- 1-Tango-1 3. We're at Sunset and Laveta.
- We got the area blocked off
- That's what I'm talkin'about. Yeah.
What am I always tellin'you, Benjamin?
You can live with it, or you can change it.
Thank you, Miss Officer
I really appreciate it
Operation is Code 4
All right, bring 'em in Come on!
- What, not hungry?
Anything else I can get for you? Huh?
Next show I put on for your pals
is handin' you CI cash
and lettin' them loose on the phones
''Collect call for Mr Margos''
Okay I don't know where he is now,
but there's a guy who helps him with his travel
He's a Greek guy Mihalis
Runs a small limo service
and, um, gets him tickets, fake passports,
places to stay
- Thanks, pal
- Hey
Remember Walter Clifton,
armed robbery on Creston, the diner?
- A couple of years ago?
- Yeah.
- How is old Walter?
- He's rotting away
because Lisa Kensit cut him a shitty deal
I guess you get
what you pay for.
I'd like to look at your notes.
I wanna talk to everybody in that diner.
- The arrest report's a little lacking
- So's Dutch-boy's dick
- but I ain't helpin'lookin'for that either.
Oh, and, uh, for the record,
I didn't screw with your desk...
but that's just because
I didn't think of it first.
Where the hell
is Vic at?
He went to get
something to eat Greek
Didn't Vic eat
like an hour ago?
Oh, shit Shit
Hey, ''Gomer'' Wake up
Where's Vic at?
- I'll be with you in a minute
- You'll be with me now
- What do you want?
Your favorite frequent flyer,
Margos Dezirian
I don't know--
Oh! Oh, my God
- Margos!
- Oh, my God I don't know, man
- I'm just leaving messages to him
- Good I'll dictate
You dial
You tell him that Goma called
Sounded strange
He wanted a one-way ticket to--
- Where would someone go to hide from Margos?
- Hell?
Venezuela
Good. You tell him...
that Goma wanted the ticket
delivered to him at his house.
Try not to sound
too stuffy
- Asshole!
- Will you be careful?
- I saw him Besides, that's not even a crosswalk
From now on, they're gonna look for
every opportunity to get rid of you
- You'll have to be perfect
- Then I'll be perfect
Trust me. It's hard.
- Mr. Papi, do you know
what a time card scam is?
- When you get your buddies...
to punch you in at work while you play hooky.
You ever do that?
- I'd be fired
- We went to your print shop
Pulled your time card the day you say
you saw Walter Clifton in the school yard
Says you were workin'
- So which is it?
Marta!
I was in the school yard.
I saw the man running, not Papi.
- So why'd you say you saw him?
- These gangsters would hurt her
if she'd said something
Let them try
to mess with me
- I understand
- Detective Mackey know any of this?
No. He show me pictures.
I picked out the one...
closest to what Marta
said he looked like
- Hope you're pickin' up tips
on how to reattach body parts
- So, did Mihalis help you?
No, which means
our friendship is over
- Hey, hey, hey
- Munroe
got that CI cash ready?
Here's the first 300
We'll give you the rest when you give us more
information Make sure they get their phone calls
- I did not help this guy!
- Yeah. Wejust found that heroin by smell.
Margos will kill me, man
- Where am I supposed to go now?
- Anywhere but home
Looks like Vic was here
- Please help me, guys
- Yeah Sure thing, Nero
- Nero was Roman
- Yeah Sure thing, Zeus First-- hey--you help us
- The guy that was here What'd you tell him?
Goma!
- Margos!
Drop it
Now turn around
Yeah
I've got an officer-involved shooting
- My detective is poking her nose in Kensit's files
- I thought you told her not to?
I did. I--
Walter Clifton, armed robbery
Sole eyewitness now admits he faked it
- Why?
- To protect his granddaughter
She saw the robber
Grandpa didn't want any reprisals against the girl
- Can she give us anything?
- Not now. Too much time's gone by.
Well, this is good.
It'll speed things up a bit.
So you'll look
into the Kensit files?
I told you we would.
I just wanted to be discreet about it.
Any more foot-dragging, and I'll call the press
You won't have a chance to be discreet
All right. You've made your point.
Spare us the sermon.
- What do think you've achieved here?
- We freed an innocent man
- How many guilty ones go free?
- As many as it takes to fix a wrong
Don't rub our noses
in your moral superiority
This isn't superiority
It's decency
And I have to give that up to play ball
with you and the chief
I'm glad you're keepin' your job
- Hey!
- Everything okay?
- What happened, man?
- Margos He had a gun
- Hey, they just saw you get here
You stay in sight.
This one's all me
You're goin' home
on Friday
I've arranged for your sister's body
to be on the same flight
- He's in prison?
- No
Dead?
- How?
- I--
It was me
Uh--
All right
Okay
Hey, uh, Ayla
No You don't --
All that's left
is the fugly, blind runt?
Real classy, people
New friend?
Uh, somethin' for me
to take care of
Thought you were supposed to be
takin' care of me? Isn't Kim allergic?
Um, she moved out
a few months ago
What?
- She left around the time of the cuddler rapist.
- Ah,Jesus, Dutch
I didn't wanna make a big deal out of it
I didn't want people to think I was distracted
- Guess what I'm gonna call her? Claudette
- No, you're not
- Yes, I am.
Ah, baby Damn
Baby, don't leave.
- Hi
- There's a lot of heat out tonight
- Really
So what do you like, huh?
'Cause I'm up for whatever
- Bet you are
- This is a real nice car
Nice clothes
You a nice man?
You want a bad girl tonight?
I'll do whatever you like
- Be my pleasure with you
- Okay.
That just gets you a discount, big man
I don't ever want to see you
out here again
- Whatever you say
Officer
She's got Dr Breen next Tuesday
The orthodontist?
Right Um,
I'm gonna need that address
- That appointment took two months to get
She can't miss it
- She won't.
She's petrified
of getting braces.
You really need to talk to her
and tell her everything's gonna be okay
- I know how to talk to my kid
- You need to hear what she's saying.
Ten is complicated
She's never direct
- She's really sensitive
- That's why I'm doin' this
So she can get more attention
We can get to know each other better
Where are we going, Mommy?
Matthew, honey, don't you remember me
telling you? Starting tomorrow
Cassidy's going to be living with your dad,
and we're gonna be staying here, okay?
- Why?
- Mommy...
I'm leaving my stuffed animals here for Matt
and for me on the weekends
- Great
- Okay. Come here, tiger.
It's gonna work
Can't let you
leave us now, man
Not after goin'through somethin'like this.
We've been to hell and back a few times.
That's gotta count
for somethin:
- Is that what you want?
- Yeah
How 'bout you?
Yeah
Oh, man,you guys scared the shit outta me,
bringin'me out here.
Yeah, well, we didn't want
the Barn to hear us beg.
Plus, we figured once you said yes,
we'd go have a couple of beers
Okay Yeah Great
- Good
- I knew you'd see things eventually
- Yeah, see what?
- That burnin'the money
was the right thing to do.
- I wouldn't get into that call.
- Yeah, but as long as you know
I was doin'it to protect us.
You know, it didn't protect us The only way
to protect us was to kill Margos, what Vic did
You burned our futures
The only reason that you're even here--
Hey, hey Whoa!
Hey Come on Leave it Leave it
- No, tell him
- Stop it
What?
Aceveda will disband us
if you leave
- So we're stuck with you.
- That's not the only reason we want you back
Of course it is Otherwise,
I wouldn't be breathin' the same air as him
That money is gone There's no reason why
we should lose the whole team because of it
I can't do this anymore I can't--
I can't do this anymore
Stealin' drugs, money Always hiding
I mean, I'm pukin' up blood, for Christ's sake
You torched enough cash
to buy a thousand doctors, you dumb shit
- You dumb shit!
- You know what? Forget it, man
- Will you shut up?
- NoJust let him go
No
We gotta talk about this
- The guy doesn't care He--
- Shut up, goddamn it, I said
- He didn't give a shit! Let him go!
Stop! Don't do this
Lem, come on!
He doesn't give a shit about his friends.
Let him go.
They are going to disband us!
No, they're not No, they're not
Go after Lem Try to talk him down
Shane and I are gonna go to his house
in case you miss him Let's go
- What are we doin'?
- It's not what we're doin:
You're gonna go apologize.
- Make this right.
- Lem's the one that should be apologizing
I did not go through this shitstorm to lose
our whole team over your goddamn temper!
Hey, I didn't ask you
to go alone after Margos
I was right there next to you
You ditched us
- To protect you
- I didn't ask to be left behind.
- I don't need protecting
- Oh, yeah? What about Tavon?
You know, you talk--
you talk like we're brothers
Yet you treat me
like I'm a little brother
- Where'd you get that line-- Mara?
- Hey, she's my wife now
Start wrappin' your head
around that
She might kiss you in all the right places,
but when the time comes
she'll turn on you too
- Is that the way you want this to go?
- Come on. Right now.
- Right now.
- Yeah? You better watch out
'cause your wife isn't here to hit me
in the back of the head with an iron
I've made some mistakes.
You never let me forget 'em.
You even come down on me
when I didn't do anything You thought I took
that seven grand from the storage locker,
didn't you?
- I didn't know who took it
- Oh, bullshit!
- Bullshit You thought it was me
- Nothin' else made sense at the time
I told you the truth
I looked you in the eye, and I told you the truth
And you still thought
I was a liar in your head
- I was with you every step
of the way on the money train
- Like I had to drag you into it
- You wanted that money as much as I did
- You're goddamn right
You're goddamn right And now you're backin'
the guy who burned it over me
- I never-- I never put the money above us
- Do you think that's what I did?
That's what
you're doin' right now!
This bitch has you so turned around
you don't even see it!
Well, I'm goin' home to that bitch
Who the hell are you goin' home to?
- My daughter
- Oh, yeah?
Yeah, the good father?
How long do you think that's gonna last?
You f--
We've been through a lot,
you and me
I'm givin' you one chance to walk away
You take it
Shit