- Jesus, between your snoring and the phone--
- Yeah?
- Rise and shine, gorgeous.
Time to go to work.
- Where are you?
- About five feet from your door.
- I guess we're up
Hey, man
I set up a meet with the Byz Lats.
We're gettin'those guns back tonight.
- Should I make some coffee?
- Nah No time Thanks anyway
- I was asking him
- Don't worry about it, darling.
Just go back to sleep.
I'll be home
in a few hours.
Grab your gun.
Leave the badge.
We're not cops tonight
We're neo-Nazis
- Bye, baby
- Mmm
All right
Ready?
Yeah
I see someone parked
a new Lexus in your parking spot.
Mara needed it for work
And it's pre-owned
Yeah, and I told you not to buy it for her.
We're gonna talk about this later.
So this Garza guy's just gonna
give us his guns? Why?
It's called commerce
Here, you carry the money
- Holy shit
- Army-issue MP5's don't come cheap
- Aceveda signed off on a wad like this?
- Not exactly
Look, I didn't have time to go
through the proper channels
- This is from our money train stash?
- It's for display purposes only
Then it goes right back where it came from
I told Kern that I'd get the guns back
It's gonna make our jobs
easier and safer
So you dipped into our life savings
to keep a promise to some scumbag
Aceveda wouldn't sign off on time,
so we're gonna do this one off the books
We won't even get credit for taking
these goddamn guns off the street
- We're gonna talk about this later too
- Yeah
You Garza?
You have a shipment of MP5's
They belong to our organization
- Which is?
- The Sword of the Creator
If the gats are yours,
how come I got 'em?
We put down a deposit
The dealer got nervous
and dumped 'em
Half to your crew,
other half to the niggers
Only the niggers got busted, which leaves
my eses with all the firepower
Look, it's not your fault
our deal went sideways
Which is why we're willing to compensate you
for them rather than taking them from you
Trust me, doing business with us
is preferable to doing battle
Besides, we're still gonna need somebody to
mow our lawns once this race war's over with
- Gracias.
- De nada.
Whatever you shelled out
for those guns, I'll pay double
Look,
you got two choices
Either you put some money
in your pocket
or Elwood here dimes you
to the ATF
I got a brother-in-law
over there.
Ever have the feds crawl
up your ass before?
Half the money up front
Then gimme half
the guns up front
- Meet me in an hour
- I pick the place
And I want
all 36 weapons
- Get him. I'll clear the car.
- Let me see your hands.
Let me see your hands!
You hurt?
He's dead
One tango four. Code six.
1 949 Coronado.
Two victims down. Request three additional
units and a supervisor for a crime scene.
- You guys set?
- We're good to go.
We got a 4Runner.
Driver and a passenger.
Extra muscle in the back
Two They're strapped
How'd I know this guy
was gonna bone us?
I got the guy in the hat.
- All right. Fat Boy's mine.
- Any sign of the guns?
- Oh,yeah.
- Okay, well, hang tight. We're 1 0 minutes out.
Damn How many rounds went off here?
Multiple shooters?
- Who's that guy?
- Passenger in the backseat.
- Bawling his eyes out when we got here
- Hey.
Found this in the alley
back there
Oh! You don't need more than
one shooter,you're packing that.
Tell the two assholes hiding
to drop their guns
and come out with their hands
where I can see 'em
You been watching me, homes?
Actually, we're gonna need the money
and the guns to help with our expansion.
- Don't do something goddamn stupid here
What's up,yo?
Get down, man.
- Tell them to let him go right now, asshole!
I've lived five years longer
than I ever thought I would
The vatos I came up with
in the game, they gone
Go ahead, shoot
Make me a hero
But Byz Lats are walking away
with that cash
Your guy so much as twitches, my guy's
gonna put one in the back of your skull
- Shoot the prick
- No! Don't!
Ronnie, put it down.
Him first
Ronnie, go on.
Mow your own lawns, putas.
Ripped by:
Hound
Rough night?
Hey, sometimes Mommy just won't nut
no matter how hard you hit it
Shut up
All right
Here's the plan
We're gonna set up Garza
in a drug sting
and use the takedown to leverage
these guns off the Byz Lats
- Who's Garza?
- Their soon-to-be ex-leader
I need you to get with your contacts.
I'll get with mine.
Let's find out who's dealing
quantity to this crew.
- I already know they're getting
their skunk outta Humboldt
- I want Garza on the hard stuff
Tougher prison sentences
on the asshole
You chase the rock
I'll find out where he's getting his ''H''
All right.
So what about
our goddamn money?
Our priorities are guns off the street and
Garza rotting in jail knowing we put him there.
Oh, ''our priorities''?
I don't remember being consulted Do you?
Hey, man, look It's my fault
for letting a guy get behind me
- But you never should've
been in that situation.
- Shane's right
What happened last night was an error
in judgment on my part
We were out of position, outmanned
It won't happen again
And in the meantime,you guys will
never see that hundred grand again.
Yeah, that's on me too So stop whining and
take the money out of my goddamn share
- Deal
- No Look, man
It's the cost of doing business, all right?
We should all take the hit
Shane needs the dough.
He tell ya?
He bought the new squeeze
a sweet new ride
Against my orders
On this job, you're the boss
But when it comes to the money train deal,
we are partners.
- And I can live my life just fine
- Then go ahead and live it
Count your money
and wash your Lexus
We can get Garza
and the guns on our own
Morning news is the Byz Lats jacked
some white dudes tryin'to buy guns.
One bald head,
the other a dirty south crackerwood
Save it Three Byz Lats
went down wet
and one of'em's not getting up
on account of your guys
Look, man, I can't control
every dog in the pound
I mean, they see the Byz Lats strapped
with goddamn MP5's? I mean, shit--
Your hollow-points seem to be
getting the job done all right
That was a tooth for a tooth My boys
gonna do some desperate shit, they got to
- They talking about capping Byz Lats'
girlfriends and kids next
- You gotta stop them
- Man, I can steer the ship,
but I can't turn it around
- I'm gonna get the MP5's
And I'm gonna get this
Garza asshole good
Tick-tock, man I'm just here to let you know
it's about to jump off in a second
- That's real spit
- Yeah, well, I'm here to tell you
any more One-niner drive-bys,
I'm holding you personally responsible
- Mayor's office and tell them I need a meeting--
- Chief Bankston
I've had trouble
getting you on the phone.
That's because I've been
ducking your calls, Detective
Uh, am I wrong, or was I not
offered the captain's job?
That was when thejob was open.
Captain Aceveda has a plan
for cleaning up Farmington...
- and he wants to see it through personally
- Yes, I know all about his plans
Look, if the promotion in Farmington
doesn't happen, put me someplace else
Your value's
at the Barn
Besides, I don't have
any positions open anywhere else
- Be patient
- So you're telling me...
that a chief has been
outpoliticked by a captain?
When Aceveda takes office,
do I have your word I'd move up?
You have my support
But you might try playing
a little politics yourself with him
Let's go.
I thought
you were working.
I got into something with Vic
- You want me to make you a sandwich?
- No, I'm not hungry.
- What's the problem?
- Not important.
Well, it must be for you
to be all torqued up like this
It's about me
- Me and this goddamn car
Why does he even care?
- Look, it's not that
Look, we can return the car
I-I need it for work,
but we can figure something out
No.
We're keeping the car.
This thing between me and Vic--
it's complicated, you know?
Sometimes brothers fight.
So why is he always making you
the little brother?
That's not how it is
Dutch?
- Aceveda said you had some questions for me?
- Your missing guns
- They're MP5's, right?
- Yeah
- It was an MP5 used in our shooting.
- Who were the vics?
Two Latino bangers
They sound like One-niners?
No, we disarmed them
What's the neighborhood?
- Coronado
- Ah, that's Byz Lat territory
Don't worry
I'm on it
- Anything on Garza's cane slanger?
- Gotcha
Got a description of a cat
driving a blue 7 40 on Lexanis
Those rims alone--
two grand a pop
What'd the DMV kick out?
Got six of those registered
in Farmington Plate numbers
Lonzo Wang
My guy did say that the Byz Lats'
heroin supplier is a black Asian
- So their heroin dealer's also their crack dealer
- Makes it easy.
Get me an address
- Everyone all right?
- Yeah, fine
I just got my new work schedule,
and I thought we could go over it
- Oh Not now
- Okay You know what?
Take a look at it
Call me at home or the hospital then
- Which hospital?
- I'm back at Mission Cross
What, in the ER?
That's becoming a war zone
down there
We respond to brawls
twice a month
They have a high turnover rate That's
how Heather was able to pull some strings
get me my old
job back
You've got two
night shifts a week
You hiring
a nanny nights too?
- I thought you would take the kids
- I can't--
- I thought you wanted to
spend more time with them
- I do, but I--
I spent 1 1 years working
around your schedule, Vic
Divorce means occasionally
working around mine
- Hi, Corrine. Nice to see you.
- It's nice to see you too.
Um, I gotta go
Call if you have questions
Thanks for this
I'll work it out
Getting back together?
Not exactly
Look, I got a tip, could put the Byz Lats'
dope supplier out of business
- Yeah?
- I need a warrant
- How good's the probable cause?
- My CI's got a stellar track record
- I'll see what I can do
- Look, this is time-sensitive
How long for the paperwork?
Depends how solid
your paperwork is
We could use this to pry something loose
on Dutch-boy's shooting case
I got it, Vic
There's a system in place
Feed your warrant request through it
- Anything else?
- Not at the moment
Raymond Montes--
He was the passenger, right?
Arrested a month ago
for possession.
And this Calva guy--
Narcotics convictions, assault--
I can't even count the DUI's
You, on the other hand,
graduated cum laude
National Merit winner
Me too
Wasn't easy, was it?
So what were you doing
with these two losers?
Raymond wasn't a loser
He was my friend
Since high school
He found out these guys
were beating on me
- stealing my stuff--
- High school can be hell
Yeah
Raymond made sure everybody knew
that if anybody hurt me
they'd get it back worse
A guardian angel
with a rap sheet six pages long?
I don't know
He just did what he did
And now he's gone
Sorry about your boyfriend.
Raymond's friends say you're making
threats against a guy named Garza.
You think he shot
Raymond and Calva?
Come on Come on
What's the question?
Calva was a Torruco, right?
So what? Uh
Garza thought Raymond was a traitor
for hanging out with him?
You got the 41 1
Why you sweating me?
All we're trying to do is catch
the killer of your boyfriend
Garza marked Calva's ass for leaving
the Lats and joining the Torrucos.
What was Raymond doing
with Calva?
Warning him
Trying to get him
to come back to the crew
Garza saw that as talking
with the enemy, retaliated--
You better get that puta
before I do.
We'll certainly do our best.
- Where the hell's Tavon?
- He'll get here when he gets here
If we hadn't got him involved in this,
we'd just go in there and pop this asshole
- Use him to get our money back
- I'm trying to put this prick Garza away
Which means I need a legal, solid case
against this guy to get him to cooperate
Well, if Aceveda's got
so much juice
how come he can't cut through the bullshit,
get us a warrant while I'm still in my 30s?
- He's on the move.
- Goddamn it.
He's going back inside.
- Come on.
- Here's Tavon. Let's go.
- We got the warrant.
- About time
Don't blame me
Judge had a Pilates class
Don't move
Can I help you?
Not only can you,
you're going to
Have a seat
Clear!
Clear.
Whoo! Oh, check this out.
My God.
Hey, boss!
Ho!
I hope you got something
for a headache, 'cause I'm it
It's a regular Rite Aid in here, Lonzo.
My lawyer's gonna read
this warrant.
If there is even
an apostrophe missing-- Poof.
Why don't you roll the dice on a 20-year
stretch. See how good we spell-check.
Or you could your ass
on the phone with Garza
and tell him you got new shipments of''H''
and coke you're selling at deep discounts
Poof
Garza's late
Yeah, our, uh, boy here
says he's never on time.
How long you gonna keep
Shane on the bench for?
He'll come back
when he's ready
Tavon, tell your girlfriend
to stop looking so nervous.
Relax, man
Here we go
Game time
That's our bag
from last night with our money.
Shit That's not our guy
It's not our guy
It's Diagur,
one of his lieutenants
Well, how we gonna bust Garza
if he's not doing the deal?
Tavon, give him the drugs
Tell him you'll get the money from him later
- What?
- Just do it.
- What the hell are you do--
- We let this guy skate now
then we take him down for the money
later on without Tavon around
Tell him that you think your
place is under surveillance.
Hey
Mind holding onto that
for a little while longer?
- We got some heat on the crib
It'll be safer that way
- Right
Besides, it's not like
we don't trust you folks.
All right
Ain't no problem
Later, dog
Yo
What the hell was that?
You're letting him leave
with the drugs and the money?
Vic! Vic!
I told you going to the chief wouldn't help
Look, for the last 1 0 years,
Farmington has been the place...
people come to buy their drugs,
sex, fence their stolen goods--
- I want to clean it up
- Spare me I'm not one of your voters
You had two years
to clean it up
And I'm finally in
the position to do it
Anything else?
I'm gonna need someone overseeing
the practical elements of my plan
Your plan?
You would have command over the
Strike Team and the new Decoy Squad.
- Think of it as a promotion.
- I had a promotion
You took it away,
remember?
Hands on the wheel!
Hands on the wheel now!
Get 'em up there!
You again? Damn
What's your problem?
I'm on a little dope hunt Why don't you
pop the trunk, see if I bagged something
- Damn
- Where's Garza?
Garza, you're only 27
already CEO of one
of the biggest gangs in town
You've taught yourself what guys spend
years in business school trying to learn
Leading men
Maximizing profits
I decide to take the Lats
public, I'll let you know
Let's talk about, uh,
where you were last night
Midnight to 1 :00
Candi's Lounge
I got a VIP table
Well,you're
a very important person.
You like trim?
'Cause I could get you in
Is that all?
Man, 'cause I'm missing
an appointment.
Uh, relax
The wheels of industry can turn
without you for a couple of hours
You gonna take the fall
for your boss on these drugs?
'Cause that's exactly what's gonna happen
unless you tell me where these guns are.
Man, I don't know nothing
about no drugs or no guns
- Come on, man Where do we find Garza?
- No clue
Look, I got nothing
against you personally
But I had a really beautiful plan
to take down Garza
and you stumbled
right in my way
How come we're not conversating
in a real cop house?
I take you in,
you're in the system
I lose control
of the situation
What happens to you gets decided
by some guy in a suit
who doesn't understand
how valuable you can be
I'll never be valuable to you
Oh, sure, you are
You just need
some convincing
Esteban, we've got a suspect
in the shooting.
I need you to look
at this lineup
Take your time
I told you. I--
I didn't see anyone.
Sometimes you think
you didn't see anything
Then you see a face,
and it all comes back to you
No
This, uh, group of guys
in my middle school
hated my guts
Every day, they'd, uh, think up
something worse to do.
They'd spray-paint my locker, steal my
homework, charge me 1 0 bucks to get it back.
That was in the Midwest
I can only imagine
what things are like here
So I understand
You gotta be pretty scared
No one in this lineup
can see you, son
I know you want to do this
For Raymond
I didn't hear anything
I didn't see anything
Okay.
We'll get there.
- He saw Garza do the shooting
- Yep
Kids growing up
in this cesspool--
You finally meet one
that's on his way out
and he ends up in the back
of a banger's car covered in blood
You gotta ask yourself,
what's the point?
Aah!
- You okay?
- Let me see your hands!
Don't fight us!
Give me your hands
Sorry
for the interruption
- What the hell's he doing here?
- He's Kern
We like him Kern?
Meet the new leader of the Byz Lats
- Whatcha talking about, man? Garza's mi jefe.
- Garza's out of a job
He just doesn't know it yet
I'm grooming you
So you two are gonna draw some lines
and we're all gonna
leave here happy
You having
a chronic moment, homey?
- I ain't trucing with no spook
- I know Taco Boy didn't just call me spook
There's no need
to go racial here
No one wants to settle this thing in a
locked steel container with our bare hands
Right, Kern?
So you two start talking this out,
and I'll check on you in a couple hours
Lem, you stay here
- Glad you're back
- You're the boss.
But my personal life
stays personal
You wanna tell me what
that little dance was about?
The dealer we were supposed
to take down waltzes
with the drugs, money,
and a stroll?
He's agreed
to cooperate
Now we're gonna set up Garza
and get those guns back
I had to snag a goddamn
ride here with our snitch
Lucky for you he drives
a Beemer with $2,000 rims
- Mm-hmm
What are you doing?
Figuring out how much I've got
in savings and partial pension
See if you can
afford to quit.
- You're too young to quit
- And I'm too old for this
Aceveda's just trying to
shore up his cop credentials
Another couple of months, the numbers
will turn around, the job'll be yours
- I wish I had your faith
- Hey
You're the best cop
I've ever worked with
Well, thank you
Nobody else ever came close
to keeping up with me Hold that thought
- Do I have to?
- Question, Vic.
Make it snappy, Dutch-boy.
I'm drowning in something.
Suspect in our shooting
heads up the Byz Lats Name's Garza
Wondered if you guys have
a profile on him.
Garza? That's the asshole
who's got our guns
- We've been looking for him all day
- I-I just cut him loose
- He was here?
- Kid wouldn't ID him, but I know he did it
I just need to prove his alibi's bullshit
Says he was at Candi's Lounge
Yeah. Yeah, I may have
heard of that place.
- Itjust happens to be on your way home?
- Hey, we're all about the job
Dutch, Crime Reconstruction
called. They're ready for us.
Thanks
Garza goes down
for a murder charge
we won't have to prop up
a shaky drug bust with our own cash
Which means it goes right back
into its hidey-hole, no questions asked
Let's go knock down this
asshole's alibi
Ah You seeing what I'm seeing?
Literally rained bullets
And not just
into the front seat
Okay, let's lose
the art project.
Are you kidding? Do you know
how many hours I've been at this?
Take your pictures
Then tear it down
First crime scene, son?
Hey
Garza's alibi checks out
He was at that club doing body shots
off some stripper named Poundcake
- Titties for everybody
- I didn't need to hear that
Hey Vic, that warrant check out--
the Byz Lat supplier?
Not a goddamn thing
- I thought your intel was solid
- The dealer's house was clear
I had to pullJudge Davies out of Pilates class
to expedite that warrant
We're trying to connect Garza to the
shootings, but he's not the triggerman
We know He is
Sorry about this I gotta do this, uh,
witness statement thing
It's procedure
No problem
I talked to administration
at UC-Santa Barbara
They said you didn't
re-enroll for next semester
Moved back to LA?
Hang out?
I guess
- What are you planning on doing?
- How's it going?
Still at the friendly-chat stage,
which for Dutch might go on all day
- You applied anywhere?
- No, not yet.
Look, is this gonna take
much longer?
I'm sorry Um, you know,
get up, walk around
I know this room can feel
a little claustrophobic
Come on. Would you just scare the crap
out of this little shit already?
Think you can scare him
as much as Garza does?
- Actually, yeah
- Let Dutch do his thing
Okay, uh, I-I know
you didn't see anything
the night that Raymond
and Calva were killed
Are you sure
you didn't hear anything?
No I told you
- The music was bumping too loud
I couldn't hear anything
- Right, right, right
- So how'd you hear the shots?
- What?
You must've heard the first couple of shots
and hit the floor pretty damn fast, right?
Otherwise, we're not having
this conversation
Okay
Here we go
You look at the crime scene reconstruction,
it's amazing the bullets missed you
I mean, I know
you're skinny, but, uh--
Why am I even
in this room?
You know why
you're in this room
- You think I had something to do with it?
- You did
- Why would I kill my best friend?
- My partner and I did a test
From where the shooter was standing,
you can't see the passenger seat
- You only meant to kill Calva
- I didn't even know Calva
You wanted to come back to LA,
hang with Raymond, make a little money
Best way to do that
was to join the Byz Lats
No Raymond wouldn't even
let me join
Which is why you went
behind his back
Asked Garza to jump you in
Taking out Calva was your initiation
- No
- You did the shooting
then you went down to the car,
and you saw Raymond
You know why
he was there, by the way?
He wanted to give Calva
one last chance to come back
because he didn't want
to see any bloodshed.
You were right about Raymond For a banger,
he turned out to be a pretty good guy
I didn't mean to do it.
- Who gave you the gun, Esteban?
- It was an accident, man
The gun that killed
your best friend?
Garza did
Ohh!
Can you help me?
Please?
Not anymore.
It's still Esteban's word
against Garza's.
To convict, we're gonna need
corroboration.
Well, I'm Mr Corroboration
Don't ask
So? How goes
the peace process?
Middle East'll be a love-in
before these idiots sort their shit out
- What's the roadblock?
- This fool ain't offering me dick, man
And he ain't got
nothing to deal
We're the ones strapped.
- See what I mean?
- Shit, man.
Hey!
I'm gettin' the feeling you're not appreciating
the battlefield promotion I gave you
It doesn't matter to what I agree out there
Garza's the one to call the shots
Garza's going to jail
He's got his own guys killing each other
You ain't got nothing on him
He already punked you once
How smart was it sending
a 1 9-year-old bookworm to do the hit?
The college boy gave him up
You can't tell me
Garza's a businessman
I got his money, his drugs,
and his top lieutenant
You tell me one thing
your boss hasn't screwed up
Your choices are climbing up the ladder
or going down the drain
- If the vatos know I spun him out--
- Who's gonna know?
This is between you and me
I just need proof he ordered
the hit on this Calva guy
and the throne and the crown
are all yours
Look, all I know is
he gave Esteban a gun,
the address
and he printed out a map
how to get there
That's all I know
Good
Let's finish this thing
- Knock it off Now!
Sir. Sir.
- My appeal was at 1 1:;00 this morning.
- Give us a minute, please
- Where were you?
- It's been hectic here
You promised that you
would be there for me
Look, the vote's gonna be
two to one in your favor
I put in a call this morning
It's a done deal
- I got my job back?
- You'll get official word tomorrow
- Thanks
- You got it
- But I am really busy here, okay?
- Okay Sorry
Thanks
- He scared the holy hell out of them
- What was I supposed to do?
Hey, man, you're in church on a Monday afternoon,
your life could use a little excitement
Guess what?
They're bringing me back
- Really? Congratulations
- Thanks
- That's great
- They upheld your appeal? Wow.
What desk you have to bend over
to make that happen?
- Sure as hell wasn't yours
- A guy can dream, can't he?
How's he working out?
- He's doing good
- Made a few arrests
Well, I just thought
I'd give you the good news
- I'll talk to you later
- All right.
You better make sure
your people deliver on this truce
- And if I don't?
- Hey
You owe me I'm the one keeping
the One-niners from being wiped out
We'll see I mean, you got Garza,
but you still ain't got the guns
No
But I'm smelling 'em
Baseball cap's our signal
Garza's inside.
- Gave up his buddy, huh?
- What separates them from us?
Loyalty, that most
disposable of virtues
One, two, three
- Where's Garza?
- I got him I got him Don't move
- Hey!
- Goin'out the back.
- They're runnin' Let's go
You have about two seconds
to tell me where the guns are
- Suck me hard, bitch
- We got him
Hey.
- Managed to stop him before he got away
- Don't move, buddy.
Hey, homes! Hey!
Hey, Captain
What's up?
The pastor from the church
lodged a complaint against you
- Oh,Jesus
- What's he saying?
- Excessive force.
- That's crap
The guy was tweaking
He wouldn't go down
It took four of us just
to get him in the cage
Tommy, give us
a minute, please
- Come on, Captain
- Tommy, please
Fortunately, the pastor's a friend,
so I think the complaint will go away
I just want to make sure
you're all right
Sir?
How would you characterize
the incident?
The amount of force
was necessary to effect the arrest
- And everything's okay with you?
- Yes, sir Everything's great
Even if we don't get him
on the homicide
this should put him away
for a couple of decades
Call me greedy--
I still want him for the murder-for-hire
- Me too
- Hey, Dutch-boy
Might wanna grab
this prick's computer
- See if there's anything in there
that ties him to Esteban.
- Right.
Uh, bag the laptop
separately.
Where's my phone call?
We got your laptop
Downloaded records
of your recent online activity.
The porn sites
were illuminating
I especially liked
the map you printed out for Esteban--
directions from his house
to Calva's.
I talked to the D.A.
You turn in the remaining 35 MP5's...
she's willing to take
the death penalty off the table.
Put the needle right here. Now, show me
where the goddamn phone is.
We're gonna get you
a good lawyer, all right?
The guns!
Look, man, word's out
you got popped
Torrucos and One-niners
are coming at us hard
Tell me where those cohetes are at
So we can protect what's ours
Huh? All right
Get a truck Pick up the guns
Wait for my call
Oh, and put a few aside
for emergencies
How we gonna explain to Aceveda
how we got all this artillery?
We can't, so we won't
Put this with the rest
of the money train stash
It's 20 grand light
Byz Lats overhead, I guess
It's better than losing
the whole hundred
The way I figure it
I guess everything
worked out okay, huh?
Got lucky
- So we cool?
- Course
You got the Decoy Squad
for sure?
They start next week
Supposed to be great
How'd you get Griggs
to give them up?
Well, he hasn't yet But he's gonna
call Councilman Docknovitch
to get me to back off
Not knowing that Docknovitch is gonna need
my support next year on his zoning application
Which you'll be only
too happy to give
I think we need a series
of high-profile busts
using the Decoy Squad
to flush them out
and the Strike Team
to step on them.
In a very public way,
you change perception, you change reality
Does this mean
I can welcome you aboard?
Anything I can do to help
Shall I give Vic the good news,
or do you want to?
- Shane's not home
- I know.
I wanted to apologize for
barging in on you last night
- No big deal
- Look, seems like you and I got
off on the wrong foot here
- We should really get to know each other.
- Why's that?
Well, you're becoming
a big part of Shane's life
which makes you
a member of the family.
Never really been big on family
Or cops, really
Shane's the exception
Look, I'm just trying
to find a way for us to get along
And I've seen that same smile
on about two dozen guys
who thought a wink
and a three-dollar gin and tonic
was all that it would take
to get me to bed with them
I do something
to piss you off?
I don't like the way you treat Shane
But that's his problem
You don't understand the world
that Shane and I live in
Shane works for you,
but he comes home to me
- You've known him for two months
- I know enough
I'm not exactly sure
what your problem is
Maybe it's 'cause you couldn't hold onto
your own family that you're scared
- Shane's all you got left.
- Excuse me?
Whatever the reason, I got enough bullshit
seeping into my life without inviting yours in.
So please, don't pop in
if Shane's not here.
What?
I called Treasury to see if any of these
marked bills have shown up yet
- And?
- No Whoever's got 'em
is either sitting on 'em or spending 'em
someplace where they can't be traced
I wouldn't sweat it No one steals
money to sit on it their whole lives
I'm sorry about that
- Why?
- I know you had a connection
Just when I thought
he was a victim
The minute I found out he was
the shooter--just another loser.
So, uh, you sticking around?
Can't retire on cat food
Yeah
You'll never leave me
Hey.
- Need some help?
- No, I got it.
You know, I was thinking, if we both
talk to Aceveda about teaming up
he might put us
back together
What?
You were my training officer,
but I'm not a rookie anymore
Actually, I've been
bumped back to P2.
So officially we're equals
That's how it'd be
Maybe But
I like the way
things are for now.
Okay
Glad things are
working out for you
I need to meet with you and your guys
in the briefing room next Tuesday, 3:;00.
Sure
What's up?
David's bringing in the Decoy Squad from
Wilshire. They're gonna be working with you.
Oh Uh, great
I'm gonna be in charge
of both teams
I'll fill you in
on the details on Tuesday
3:00
- I just spoke to Claudette
- Good
Sounds like
an interesting experiment
It's more than
an experiment, Vic
It's your assignment
for the foreseeable future
Yeah, I thought Claudette
was taking your job
Well, you'll just have to stomach me
for a little bit longer
How much longer?
Just so I can warn my stomach
Maybe working under Claudette
will actually produce results.
I've been
producing results
Not today
You had a drug warrant
blow up in your face
Dutch and Claudette
beat you to a gang bust
and those 35 army rifles you've been so
hell-bent to get are still on the streets.
Doesn't seem like
your finest hour
I guess not
All right
Let me throw one in
Bon voyage