Open up!
She saw you, asshole! Peeping Tom!
- Put down the bat
- That prick saw my mom naked!
- Peeping into our bedroom window
- He saw me!
- Drop the goddamn bats!
- What about him?
- Hands behind your head
- There he is!
- I want them both locked up
You werejerkin'off in the window.
How am I gonna get off
on those big, saggy tits?
She shouldn't leave
her blinds up, huh?
- Lock 'em up.
- Shut him down
- Step inside, sir
- Close the door, sir. Hands behind your head.
- There's nothing to look at.
Julien!
Am I working alone here?
Dinky's having a slow morning.
We're killing our morning
babysitting a third-string dime-bagger
- Can't get much lower than this
- Every bust's a good bust
And one step closer to
cashing in on a small fortune.
Playing by the rules keeps IA from
sniffing around our retirement fund
Fills the chiefs arrest quotas,
keeps our noses clean.
Yeah, in your case brown
- Shut up
- What's up, man?
Plus I get you two assholes
to keep me entertained
- I got you, man
- Packing already?
-Just tidying up
You and Claudette
wanna take a run at this?
I'm already working
two open cases
- I'm sorry we're so shorthanded
- I had some budget ideas about that
If you could give me early access
to those personnel files
You're still on detective duty
for a few more days
So why don't you
stick to that for now
Better get down there It's a double
homicide with special circumstances
What special circumstances?
Someone forgot their fins
Armenian immigrants,
both had multiple arrests
And both did prison time
Postmortem cuts
One foot's a trophy.
Four's just plain weird.
They were dumped here
Killing zone's somewhere else
Given any thought to who you're
gonna bring on as my new partner?
Like the captain said,
I'm still a detective
Three more days
I hear there's a Detective Ruiz
in Hollywood that's good
Gabrielle Ruiz.
Uh, Gabrielle's quite a looker.
Is she?
- No?
Oh Wait, ah, ah
Okay, run this. ''4UOP2 1 1. ''
Hey, Ronnie, Tavon,
you seeing this?
Yeah, we got 'em. Looks likejuveniles.
- R Mark Lindman, MD
- Oh
- I hope the doctor's kids
know some lawyer friends
Bust it out!
-Shit
-Hey, you Give me your keys Right here
Hey, don't do it!
Don't you-- No!
Goddamn it!
- Stay right here!
- Son of a bitch!
Get the kid!
All right,
get your hands on the wheel
- You're gonna lose him.
- Go, get out of the way. Goddamn it!
6-Paul-1 1 in pursuit
of a mid-'80s Monte Carlo
headed south on Water
towards Palm Heights
- We're losing him
Chopper's got him
He's not going anywhere
Besides, we're staying out of trouble.
Let some other unit wreck their car.
6-Paul-11,
your suspectjust ran a stop sign...
is now traveling southbound at high
rate of speed along Cesar Chavez.
Gray Monte Carlo is turning
onto Chicago Street.
Uh-oh, look out. Oh! We got
a C.A. involving multiple vehicles.
This is Air-9 requesting R.A.
for the intersection of Cesar Chavez--
Stop!
Lem, handle this!
You all right?
Are you all right?
Cut him off
Stay down
I got him
Gracias.
Yo, I need a knife
His seat belt's jammed
- Shit!
- Where's it coming from?
- I don't know The van?
- Lem, get out of there!
- I almost got him
- Lem!
There's no one inside!
Ripped by:
Hound
Sir, take it easy
He's got a few burns, mild shock.
Well, he's in for a bigger one
- What the hell happened here?
- The car we were chasing caused a smash-up
The van swerved to avoid it,
caught fire
- The back was full of ammo
- A hell of a fireworks show
And your chase
caused this accident?
Felony pursuit Under control
We followed regulations to a ''T''
Well, give me
that report right away
- I want all my ducks in a row for downtown
- Quack, quack
Hey, Dutch-boy
I got a case for you
Actually, I'm working
a double homicide
Yeah, well, I need a detective to hand this off to
so I can get back to dealer duty
Rodriguez might be back in tonight
How important is it?
I don't know yet
All right, thanks anyway
Hey, uh, you know of any
internal Armenian mob beefs?
- Not offhand
- How about ''off-foot''?
Found these two guys
this morning
Harbor found two more
last week, same shape
Don't know them Looks like
old-country retribution though
Somebody sure pissed off
the bosses back in, uh--
- Yerevan
- Right
Let me show these to my guys,
see if they recognize the stumps
Great Thanks
They killed these Armenians
looking for our money train cash
Which means they still
think it was an inside job
What happens when they run out of feet
and realize it was an outside job?
There's only four people
who know we took that money.
And they're all sitting right here
We stick to the plan
Low profile,
business as usual
- You pull that driver's sheet?
- Ain't got one He's an out-of-work cement mixer
A van full of ammo,Jesse?
It is not against the law
to have bullets
Well, it is if you drive them
across state lines
You wanna tell me why you took
a Greyhound to Yuma, Arizona
picked up a van, filled it with a half
a ton of nine-millimeter shells...
- and drove it all the way back here to L.A.?
- Told not against the law
Who told you that?
Your son, Diagur?
See, he's a player
with the Byz Lats
Is that who you're
running ammo for?
He float his out-of-work pop
a day job?
Diagur is not in this
- There's no sign of a struggle
in either victim's apartment
But both their cars
were parked in their spots
It suggests they went along
willingly with whoever killed them
Someone they were
comfortable with
Other Armenian mobsters
Anything more specific?
You remember Margos Dezirian,
theJesus look-alike?
The Armenian drug guy who
killed a man in our cage?
- Then escaped the paddy wagon
- You think he's involved?
It would explain the severed feet
Margos is a big foot-fetish guy
How do you know that?
When he was in custody, the only words
he said were ''delicious feet'' to Danny
I gave her a call She said he was constantly
staring at her feet like he was obsessed
Well, it's not the only
lead we're chasing
If I'm right, Dezirian's back in town
I want to bring in the feds
- Based on a possible foot fetish?
- If Dezirian's here, everybody wants him.
Us, Washington, Interpol.
Fine
Hey, uh, when I was
talking to Danny...
she mentioned her final appeal
with the police commission is tomorrow
A good word from her boss, future
city councilman, might go a long way
I'm aware of the situation
- You almost all packed up?
- What can I do for you?
- One last favor before you ride out of Dodge.
- What's that?
Well, it looks like one of the Latin
gangs is arming up for Armageddon...
- and I can't find a free detective to look into it
- We're understaffed
I got a van-load of ammo
driven by a Byz Lat dad
- Where there's bullets, there's guns
- Did the driver confess to guns?
- No It's gonna take some
legwork to prove I'm right
- And in the meantime
I've got actual murders, actual
armed robberies that take priority
You're not interested in preventing
murders before they happen?
- Why don't you look into it yourself?.
- Fine.
Talk to the chief Get him to back off
this arrest quota I can't do both
And I can't get in the middle of
whatever arrangement the chief has
- Can't?
- Won't
What, more important things to worry
about now than a few guns on the street?
I'll assign a detective
when one frees up
Hey, did you finish up the paperwork
on this morning's car accident?
Yeah
- Lem, you finish that accident report?
- Yeah
- You said he wanted me to write that report
- He does You done?
- Hi, guys
- We in your way?
- No, we're just, uh--
- We're just finishing up
Sorry to interrupt.
Just needed to ask a question...
and sneak a kiss
- You buying a car?
- Yes. Yes, we are.
I'm getting my Realtor's licence next
week. So I need a respectable ride...
- to show homes
- Really?
Yeah, I'm just helping out
with the down payment
He's the best
Yeah, the best
So we're gonna meet
after work, right?
- Dream Motor Cars, off Sepulveda?
- Yeah, okay Okay
- I'll see you there.
- Okay.
- Bye
- See ya.
Bye-bye
Go with Lem and Ronnie,
keep the dime-bag bust rolling
- I hear you.
- Let's go.
Come on, lover You and me
are ditching school today
Interpol's dossier
on Margos Dezirian.
He's suspected ofkilling
three coca farmers in Chile.
- All found with their feet chopped off
- Let me see.
I need to run his known aliases against
international flight manifests for the past month
- He's in town.
- Detectives, you have visitors
The two men
you find dead this morning.
I know who did it
I see him waiting
at my home to kill me next
My mother, my sister,
her children
If you protect us,
I tell everything
I know you, yes?
I don't think so
Yes, you and your friend
Cletus.
The accident that day.
The guy paid up
I never had to call
- All right, yeah That's good
- Cletus?
- I did not know you worked for the police
- Yeah, I was off duty
I'm on duty now
I gotta get back to work
You've known this girl for two months.
You buying her a new car?
It's pre-owned I'm just
covering the down payment
She'll take over the monthly
when she makes her first sale
What happened to keeping
a low profile, business as usual?
I'm using my own money
I'm putting it on my Visa
Yeah, but it looks like you're
buying your girlfriend a new Lexus
It's pre-owned And being up to my eyeballs
in debt is business as usual for me
Nice try
No sale, you got it?
- Vic
- What?
Dutch is interviewing the guy
that saw us the day of the money train
- What guy?
- Armin, the advance man.
- So what's he doing here?
- I don't know, but he recognized me
- And he remembered your name, Cletus
- Cletus Van Damme?
You gave this guy the same alias you used to
rent the storage unit where we hid the money?
Well, it makes Lem laugh
Hey, Lem. You gonna ride
with the A-Team today or what?
You were following this guy
the day we stole the money
Ifhe starts stringin'
together the facts--
Yeah, if Dutch does
He heard the guy
That's it
We move the money tonight
New location
New name
That is not the man doing the killing.
Are you sure?
His name's Margos Dezirian.
That is Margos?
Yeah, I've heard
of the name, but
it is Lyor Slavok you want
- Lyor Slavok?
- He is a soldier
Who gives him orders--
Margos, someone else--
I do not know
It's all because of
this damn money train
I heard a rumor a while ago about
a money train Somebody ripped it off?
Yeah, and the Armenians are gonna keep
dropping bodies until they find out who
Shit
Our latest quarterly
crime statistics...
jumped up double digits
in all areas
Well, the best thing
you can do for us in city council...
is to find the money
to fully staff this place again
I don't take office
for another six months
I'm worried about right now
You said you had a few ideas
about adding personnel?
Oh, the undercover Decoy Squad,
uh, working Wilshire?
- Yeah?
- Their original mandate was to
rotate among all districts.
Well, Captain Griggs has used his
Miracle Mile clout to hold onto them
Well, that's why their numbers
at Wilshire look a lot rosier than ours.
- The unit's had great success
- Well, Griggs will never give them up.
I was thinking of appealing
higher up the ladder.
To the chief?
You don't have anything to offer him
It will make you look naive
What other ideas do you have?
Hey, strike a pose, boys
You-- get out of here, man
Get out of here
I'm gonna go out
on a limb-- Diagur.
What, are you psychic?
Yeah I predicted your old man
would crash a van-load of live ammo
He's fine.
It's you he's worried about.
- Me too
- Vic.
Those nine-millimeter shells
aren't for these little cap guns
You guys expecting
a new shipment of hardware?
Who's running
this boys' club now?
Yeah,
we missed the last election
You guys looking to shoot your way
back into business and territory?
Well, you know,
we do what we gotta do
Really?
I find out you're arming yourselves
with anything more serious than this
I will turn the Byz Lats
into my personal piñata
Which means we shove candy
up your ass and beat you with a bat.
You pass it up the daisy chain
Vic Mackey, my nigga
Ain't seen you boys
around here in a while
Yeah, we've been enjoying the sun
New stuff?
Religious erotica
Where in the Bible does St Schlong
visit Our Lady of the D-cup?
Hey, man. I'm giving the believers
what they want right there.
So what's the news? You find out if
anyone's selling guns to the Byz Lats?
Nope. But I found out
who's buying.
- Yeah? Who?
- You know the cat
- Lovely.
Let me see you,
uh, spin around.
- Nice
- Hey
- Oh, drama.
Hey, ladies, ladies, ladies
Could y'all bounce for a minute?
Everybody, come on
Sweet setup.
I thought you were broke, Kern.
Whoa, whoa, whoa
Slap, easy, man Easy, easy, baby
This is my boy, Slap.
He got my back.
Whatever makes Slap happy
So who's financing
this hot spot?
- You know, found some investors
- Really?
- One-niners buy a share?
- Let's just say...
- sometimes you can go home again
- Come on, Kern
What's a gangsta rapper
like you investing in heavy metal for?
- We know you're making a gun buy for your boys
- Well, you know wrong
Really?
You know what?
I'll bet we could make half our narc quota
by emptying the pockets in this room
-Let's go Everybody, hands on your head
-All right.
Calm down, Hee-Haw. All right, man.
Yeah, I'm buyin', okay? But not
because I want to, 'cause I got to
The Byz Lats armin' themselves
to the mother tit with MP5's
-Jesus Christ Fully auto SMG's?
- Three dozen.
My boys just looking for
a balance of power
- The Byz Lats already have 'em?
- I don't know.
Same guy that's sellin' to me
is sellin' to them too
- Who's runnin' this arms race?
- He's regular army
- When's your buy?
- What about the Byz Lats?
They got it in their greasy little heads
that south of Vermont belong to them
- I'll disarm the Mexicans
And I'm supposed
to believe that?
You forget last time we did business?
How you just shit all over me?
That was a one-time war crime,
and I apologized
Now what time's the buy
and where?
You make me find out on my own,
you'll be facing a charge too.
- Detective Holland Wagenbach?
- Yeah?
Agent Quigley, US Treasury
- I asked for FBI
- You got me
I understand you have an Armenian
wiseguy who wants to come clean
- Already has
- Who's the boss around here?
We've been concerned with
the Armenian mob's propensity
for shipping US currency overseas
About four months ago,
my office instituted a sting operation
What kind of sting operation?
In San Jose, the Armenians were
extorting a local businessman
He allowed us to insert $50,000 of marked,
traceable bills into his payment to the Armenians
so we could track the loot and see
what banks were washing the money.
- And?
- Not a single bill has popped up in three months
It's mystified us. But then today I was notified
by my counterpart in the F.B.I....
that you were investigating
a possible robbery of the Armenian mob
And four related murders
We may have blown
our laundering case
but if any of these
marked bills show up
they might lead you
to your killers
- Someone inside?
Hey, I thought
I heard you guys in here
Oh, I'm Albert, Albert Kreeg
I'm the manager
Uh, looks like you guys
got everything in okay
- Yeah, we're all set, Al
- Ah, Albert Like the prince
- Yeah We're good, Al bert
- Okay
Okay, uh
Did you just
move out of a place?
- Yeah, I'm getting divorced
- Oh,yeah. I had a feeling.
Uh, oh. Which one of the two
of you is Mr. London?
- Oh, that's me.
- Oh, okay I got those spare keys you asked for
Thank you
All right then Night
- Night
- Night.
Get new padlocks I don't want Prince
Curious having a key to this place
- Yeah
- Yeah?
- Vic, we need you down here
Someone slapped Slappy.
Byz Lats got their guns
So much for passing this case off
- An hour late This guy ain't showin'
- Where is he?
I guess he got spooked
That's bullshit
Your homies are chillin' like it's happy
hour You thought I'd buy this pony show?
Look, man You best just
back up off me, all right?
You're pissed off
about losin' your boy Slap
How would you feel
if it was one of your boys?
That still doesn't give you
licence to bend me over
Look He didn't show, okay?
Ain't my fault he--
- Whoa, whoa, whoa! Hey!
- Don't even think about it
- You reached
- I didn't reach, man
- Get your hands out of your pockets right now
- Yo,just do it, son
Vic,just take it easy,
all right?
I'm tellin' you the truth, man
When you get a new time and place,
you'll let us know, right?
Call you as soon
as I know something
Straight?
All right, Vic
Let's go
I'll be waitin' for your call
Why don't you just
calm down, man?
He's lying
Why did you say you would help me if
you couldn't? This is so embarrassing
I'm sorry, all right I wanna help you I do
It's just that I've talked to some friends
and this is the kind of thing that
can add stress to a new relationship
- What friends? Vic?
- Come on It's not like that
- I worked my ass off to get this Realtor's licence
- Yeah, I know that
I need to make a living Would you
buy a half a million dollar home
- from somebody driving a '97 Neon?
- From you? Sure
Because your mother doesn't want you
bouncing off the walls all night That's why
- Mommy, can I have some ice cream
- Shh Come on
Go Put on your PJ's And come on,
get dressed Let's go Come on
- No fair
- Go, go, go, go
- Hey, what's going on?
- Shh, shh Look, look, look
- And what's this?
Daddy and me
That's great.
This is your favorite
part, right, Matt?
Here you go, princess
Go play with your sister
Okay, this is where
the song ends, right?
- Bye, song.
Wow
See you next time
Okay, champ?
Bye Bye, Daddy
I love you, Matt
He's got a great energy
Uh, that classical music
you were playing there
It's the Tomatis Method
Matt's learning to use his ears
as his primary source of hearing
so his other senses
don't get overwhelmed
- And he's responding really well
- Yeah
- Remember to do his drills with him
- I will
Mr Mackey,
it was nice to meet you
- I'll just let myself out
- Okay
So I'll see you next time.
I told you he was amazing
Matthew's actually talking
We could have Owen two more nights
a week He has another job offer
but he wants to work
with Matthew full time.
Ah, things are
kind of tight right now
- How much is it gonna cost?
- An extra 300 a week
Okay Look, I gotta
get back to the job
Book him I'll figure out
how I'm gonna cover it
Actually, you know what?
I only need for you to pay for half
I'm gonna take care of the rest.
I'm going back to work
There's a nursing shortage,
and the pay is good.
- Full time?
- Thirty hours a week
- to start.
- How's that gonna work with the kids?
I don't know, but, uh, we're
gonna have to figure it out
because it's something
I wanna do
Danny, hi.
Sir
I'm temping here
till my appeal
- And how's that looking?
- My lawyer says not to get my hopes up
I'm thinking of adding
a few more bodies to the Barn
I'd be filling the slots with people
who can get with my program
What program's that?
I need officers who I can trust
play tough but fair, keep me
aware of anyone who isn't
- You're looking for rats
- No.
No, I don't want what happened
to you to happen to anyone else
-Just tell the truth if any big lines get crossed
- You mean by Vic?
By anyone
You interested?
- You saying I can get my job back?
Think about it Give me your answer
when school gets out
What?
Word is you're a little
unsure of yourself out there
- Is that what my partner's saying?
- What do you say?
- I'm doing just fine
- Look,Julien
I'm not the one
riding you here
But you got a little problem
with respect in this house
People are wondering what you're
doing about the beating you took
Look, detectives
haven't made much progress
They still can't
prove who did it
Everybody here knows who did it
And they're watching you
Where do we stand
with our Armenian triggerman?
Judge Molina's clerk says we should
have the warrant within an hour
- Good
- Somebody say ''warrant''?
Need me to knock any doors down?
Damn, I was gonna
ask her to the prom
This warrant
for that Armenian double hit?
Turns out the mob's pissed off about a shitload
of stolen money ticketed for the homeland
Now they're whackin'all
the players trying to find it.
- Armin was scared he was
gonna be the next stumpy
- Where's Armin now?
Feds took him.
Witness protection.
The good news is, finally got a break
on two unsolved murders
that have been screwing up
my perfect record
- How's that?
- When this robbery went down...
two mob soldiers got killed
Three, four guys in masks came roarin'
in, took the cash, left the bodies
Hey, man
What's up?
Armin told Dutch that the guys
who robbed the money train
killed those two
Armenians that night
- We didn't kill no one
- Why in the hell would he tell him that?
My guess is Armin knew those
two guys were stealing from him.
Armin's the one who called
the shooter down there that night
He's scared enough
to admit to money laundering
but not scared enough
to admit to his part in a 1 87
So if the robbery
leads back to us
we're on the hook
for a double murder.
- Jesus.
- Right
Here are the keys
to the new space
With this new heat,
we should wait
another six, nine months before giving
our cash over to the real estate guy.
- Nine months?
- We've already been sitting on this--
Well, I didn't mean to interrupt
your secret Klan meeting
- We left our hoods at the dry cleaners
- Come on, Tavon.
Why is it that every time I enter
the room, y'all stop talking?
Maybe it's because we're
captivated by your winning smile
- Or blinded by yours
- Hey,you two done pissing?
Sit down I'll tell you
what's going on
The Byz Lats just
opened fire on our turf
Aceveda doesn't have the manpower to
attack this and Kern's not playing nice.
So we gotta do it ourselves
and do it fast.
We're gonna tap Kern's phone,
find out when this gun buy's going down.
What, you gonna set a tap
without a warrant?
- No time.
- Not enough hard evidence.
You got a problem with that,
speak up now
Two weeks ago, 1 2 cases of MP5's
were stolen from Fort Irwin
And that's 7 2 guns on the streets
in the open market.
I already picked up one body
I don't want any more
Set up the tap on Kern
- Hey, look It's the Village People
Stand by, Vic We're tapping
I don't believe you.
Jamir said all the skanks you hired
are light-skinned with fine bodies.
Come on, baby.Jamir's half
white. What's he know about fine bodies?
I know you, Kern.
Don't play me with this innocent--
Sounds like Kern's not too big
to be a little whipped
Next thing you know,
he'll be buying her a new car
- Don't cut me off
- Let me know when the call comes in
- Where you going?
- Corrine asked me to pick up
Cassidy at school
- How long we staying here?
- Until the call comes in
The conversation
will probably be in code
Shit I told Mara
I'd take her to lunch
Four different guns so far
We'll run them all through ballistics
Look what the Dutchman found
He mailed an international overnight
package to Greece this morning
- Look at the name of the recipient
- ''Marcus Dreliozis''?
Sound like a Greek alias of Margos Dezirian
to you? Check out the comments section
Contents contain dry ice
I think we found
our missing feet
I'm sorry
Yeah, I'll try
All right, me too
Yeah, I love you too
Okay, bye-bye
Oh, blow me
Dude, we're rich
- At least we're gonna be
- Yeah
-Just gotta ride things out
- Yo,yo. Let me talk to Kern.
- You got him.
It's Lex. Guns are ready.
Get all the cash yet?
Yeah, man.
I'm sittin'on it.
- Be there in half an hour.
- Right here.
I think I just broke the code
The gun boyjust went inside.
With six crates and four army pals.
- Four?
- Yeah
- We need backup
- Backup? Vic, we're here on an illegal wiretap
- 6-Paul-1 1 requesting additional units
- What are you doing?
- I'm getting these guns back
- Vic, we don't have a warrant
He's right, you know Maybe we should
just keep a low profile on this thing
Roger, 6-Paul-1 1. What's your location?
Hey, it's five-on-five
You guys wanna go bullet to bullet
with 3,000 SMG's?
I know what I'm doing
6-Paul-1 1
- We're at the corner of Fletcher and Riverside.
- Roger that.
My client denies
any involvement in these killings.
We've got an informant
in the organization that implicates him.
This informant may have heard some stories,
but he saw nothing with his own eyes.
What did he mail
to Athens this morning?
- Books
In dry ice?
This isn't even
his name on this
- He just said he sent it
- And the receipt was found in his place
The only question is why were you
stupid enough to keep the receipt?
- I'm not gonna ask him that.
- Okay.
Why is he whispering? We don't
understand what he's saying anyway
Margos Dezirian is gonna be at this
address in Greece tomorrow, isn't he?
We're having the package
rerouted to us
We'll see for ourselves
Four of them That way
Go in the back Take your cue
from those guys Don't get in the way
- Hands on your head!
- Hands on your head now!
- Get down!
- Get on the ground!
- Rabbit, rabbit, rabbit!
He ducked into a back room
- Kern, where's that lead to?
- Nowhere The window's barred
Hook these people up
Hook them up and get them out
- Turn that off
- Everybody grab a gun
Load 'em
You inside
It's your 800 rounds a minute
versus our 4,000
I'm gonna give you three seconds to toss
that weapon, or we're gonna open fire
One, two--
Come on out
These are the serial numbers
of the marked bills
If they get spent, make their way through the
banking system, they'll eventually get flagged.
- Maybe we can flag them earlier
- The money was stolen here,;
it'll probably be spent here.
We should do cursory checks
on all big money busts
- Any luck siccing the Greek
authorities on Margos?
- Not yet.
I talked to the American embassy in Athens
The Greek authorities aren't gonna move
unless they hear from somebody
higher up than an LA detective
- You have any connections in Washington?
- I've been to a few parties
Taking guns from our soldiers,
selling them to gangbangers?
You must be very proud, asshole
God bless America
- Come here Come here
- We got it, man
Hey, Vic
You tell me
Who bought the guns for the Byz Lats?
Yeah, like I'm just gonna admit
I sold guns to another crew?
Uncuff him
What are you doing?
Instant court-martial
A trained soldier
grabbed my spare gun
and tried to run for it
- Yo, guys.
- Evidence Around there
Now you either tell me
who bought the guns for the Byz Lats
or you and me are gonna
play some run and gun
- Yeah
- Then run
- You're out of your goddamn mind.
- Run
It's an OG named Garza
He's king of the Lats
That's a good
little soldier boy
You want Treasury's list of marked bills,
or you want me to hang onto it?
I'll keep it
I saw you talking to Vic
Has he been asking about this case?
I was asking him some questions, 'cause I know
he has experience with Armenian organized crime
Well, from here on,
keep him out of the loop
- Okay Why?
- Because that's the way I'd like it
Detective,
you've got a package.
- Size 1 0 1 /2
Hold on. Kern and his guys
were in on the sting. They set it up.
- That's why we didn't need a warrant
- That's right
Little always ready
to help his brothers in blue
Give him to me,Julien Come on
What the hell was that?
I thought you'd be a little
bit more appreciative
since I just saved you
from a felony arms arrest
- Call us even
- Nothing's even
One of your guys ain't dead.
Look, we're just gonna get different
gats Go see the Mexicans It's on
It's off My next stop is the Mexicans
You have my word
- Yeah, well I used to trust that
- You still can
You just give me
tonight to prove it
You got tonight
- What?
- I thought we were playin' it tight
- We are
- You put us all at risk
without lettin' us have a say
over guns that we've
got nothing to do with
- And I'd do it again
- Well, I wouldn't
I wouldn't
I talked to my boss in D.C.
Here's the problem.
The Greeks don't wanna help us
- They're a little pissed off at the moment
- Why?
'Cause we make up reasons for going to war
and then act like the world's policeman?
That and the missiles
we sold to Turkey
We're not the only ones
who want Margos
- Paraguay, Chile, Belgium.
- It's not Brussels who's asking
them to conduct this raid.
Maybe in a couple of days
we can go through back channels
- and figure out a way we can--
- Whoa, whoa, whoa
We know where Margos
is gonna be tomorrow
It's already tomorrow in Athens I just
need a few police officers to pick him up
He's wanted for murder
in four countries.
- Can you get Leo to tell you
where Margos is going next?
- No.
He's not talking
Even in prison you need feet
Sorry, I've done
everything I can.
Assistant Chief Phillips.
Claudette Wyms.
- I remember, Detective
- What's going on?
I think you should talk
to Captain Aceveda
Why?
He's not stepping down yet, is he?
You should go talk to him
I'm supposed to be
captain in two days.
I still have some unfinished business
- How long?
- Until I take office.
- In six months?
- It's a volatile time in Farmington right now
I can't leave the Barn
underfunded, understaffed
- You're gonna bring in more personnel
- Yes
- The undercover Decoy Squad?
- You're stealing my ideas
- I'm implementing them,
along with some of my own
You are stealing my ideas,
and you're taking my job
I've got the power to make those ideas happen
I can still make a difference here
- I can make a difference
- Not like me
- This is my job
- Not yet
You're the reason for half
the problems in the first place
Well, that's your opinion
I'd keep any others to myself
I will not let you
do this to me
There's a bigger picture, Claudette,
and you're smart enough to see it
The chiefs not gonna help you.
He's gonna need me
The army scab who sold the Byz Lats their
guns says the buyer's name was Garza
Garza?
I thought he retired
Well, maybe his pension ran out
'Cause he's back
I need you to get
in touch with him
Tell him that
you found a buyer
offering to pay
double what he paid
That's all I got
I'll cover you on the back end
Hey, man Top's down pretty tight
on the Byzantine Quarter these days
That's at least
a couple days' work
You got two hours
- Danny?
- No, no I'll hold
- You got the guns, huh?
- Uh, half of them.
Byz Lats already
have the other half
Trying to put together a buy
while they're all in the same hands
- I need some cash
- How much?
- A hundred grand
- Right
Just to show them that we're real
I just need it for a couple hours
- Then put in a request through central
- I need it now, tonight
I'm not bending
the rules for you.
- Hey, look I didn't even want
this case in the first place
- Then why did you take it on?
Because, obviously,
I'm the only one who gives a shit
- about the damage these guns are gonna do
- You're not
I've spent all day calling
in favors to make sure
things change in Farmington
in the next six months
- What's that mean?
- It means that you have to
file the proper paperwork
and wait a couple of days
for the hundred grand
Or you can stop by an ATM
The guy's wanted by Interpol
I'm giving you the address
All you have to do
is pick him up
What's so goddamn
hard about that?
If my tone sounds superior, it's because
I'm American and you're Greek.
- Trouble in Armenia?
- Athens actually
What's going on?
Nothing
It's just the usual bullshit
Whom shall I fear?
You are the stronghold
of my life
- Whom should I--
Jesus Christ
What are you doing here?
Confess
To what you did to me
- What?
- I just need to know
Look, I just--
I just need to know
What the hell
is your problem, man?
The truth
Just tell me the truth
I didn't do anything to you
Oh, shit!
Though an army besiege me,
my heart will not fear
Even though war
breaks out against me, even then--
-Julien, please!
Oh, God