- I hear you're the best.
- Heat it up.
What's up, boss?
While you two
were out playing putt-putt...
Shane and me were taking down
a slice-and-dice gem operation...
an Armenian kingpin,
two dozen of his crew.
One guy who shall remain faceless.
I can't believe
we missed out on that, man.
It gets better. It gets better.
We found out the Zeroun family...
isn't only making illegal money,
they're also cleaning and shipping it.
So we're going to take down
a money-laundering ring? Sweet.
Yes, it is. We're gonna bring it down,
pack it up, and save it for a rainy day.
We found out how and where
they distribute their dirty cash.
This is it, boys.
This is the one we've been waiting for.
One big hit. In and out.
We're set for good.
- What?
- Told you he'd be speechless.
You're not serious.
You wanna rip off the Armenian mob?
Shh. We have two months to plan this.
We can absolutely do this.
- No. Not me.
- What are you saying? It's all of us.
No, man. It's crazy.
It can't be that easy.
We'd have the mob chasing us
on one side, the law on the other.
What about you, huh?
You bailing too?
No. No.
It sounds interesting.
Lem, no one's rushing into this.
- Do you know a Connie Reisler?
- Yeah. Why?
- She's here.
- Oh, man.
Hi, Vic.
- You're clean.
- Yeah.
- I did 90 in County.
- It must have been hard on you.
It's what I needed.
What do you need from me?
I wanna help you. Provide information
on a professional basis.
Look, Connie...
I'm here for you.
But I don't have throwaway money
like I used to.
I'm talking about making it official.
I met someone inside.
Told me that the state
can give C.I.s a contract.
I can do that.
I hear things all the time.
I blend in on the street.
- No.
- Well, I'm tired...
of sucking on pipes and balls, Vic.
You know my résumé.
Who else is gonna give me a job?
- It's not as simple as all that.
- I don't need that much to live on.
Without it, you know,
I gotta go back to trickin'
I start trickin',
it's back to being a junkie.
I heard about this guy...
who's selling heroin to kids.
- Yeah?
- This tip's real solid.
Okay. I'll see what I can do long-term.
In the meantime,
tell me about this dealer.
Teenage kid.
Felipe Gomez.
I know his sister.
He just started dealing to kids.
Where?
Opposite direction. Which of
Newton's laws of motion applies?
Police.
Which one of these kids is Enrique?
Schoolmates say you've been
flashing thumbnail bags of heroin...
that you got
from some guy named Felipe.
- Smack got your tongue, Enrique?
- You got the wrong Enrique.
Oh, really?
Well, let's pat you down then.
- All right.
Up against the wall, "wrong Enrique."
- Can he do that?
You're in public school, Beaver.
You got no rights.
It wasn't just me, man. Felipe was
hanging out by the east gate...
- handing them out to everyone.
- Handing them out?
Giving it away. Like free samples.
I come out to go to work,
and I find my car like this.
What do you expect me to do?
This isn't my district.
Sir, the widow did this.
She knows where I live.
Are you sure it wasn't random?
A prank?
You heard her threaten me.
"Justice will find you."
Well, you need to file a report
with Hollywood division.
I take those reports.
It's a waste of time.
- If it's her, you need to document it.
- I guess.
Look, not to overburden you,
but the board's been on my case...
to get them Julien's six-month review.
I'm almost finished with it.
I need it today.
We had officers search every student,
every locker.
If they found drugs,
I told them to keep their lockers open.
I think you should
start calling some parents.
I can't believe
Lem's being such a pussy about this.
Uh, who knows.
Maybe he's right.
- We don't need him to pull this off.
- Yes, we do.
Lem doesn't care
if we ride solo on this thing.
Well, I care.
Either we're all in, or we're all out.
One guy knowing who isn't accountable,
isn't an option.
We're a team.
That's the only way it works.
My educational reform
if middle schoolers are high on heroin.
And if the police can't
keep drug dealers out of our schools...
is there anyplace
our children can be safe?
Sir, how do you answer
your political opponent's challenge?
I'm here as a police officer,
not as a candidate.
I want to remedy the situation, not turn it
into political hay. Excuse me.
Jesus, what the hell went down here?
Some scumbag was handing out tastes
of heroin like they were goddamn cookies.
Heroin?
Not your daddy's smack either.
Pure and cheap.
Snort it, smoke it, same high as shooting up
without the float... addictive as shit.
You're responsible for drug busts
in this district.
- I thought you had a handle on things.
- I did.
Then my handle got burnt
at the stake by Armadillo.
That drug dealer, Tio.
You wanna know
what my relationship with him was about?
It was about not letting things
like this happen.
I gave him slack, but I gave him rules.
He never dealt to kids.
With Tio out of the way, somebody else
saw these kids as an untapped market.
- So how do we fix this?
- Well...
No. No more arrangements with drug dealers.
Crack down on them... publicly and hard.
I can do that too.
Police!
Get your hands in the air!
- Down! Down! Get down!
- Get down!
Word is you think
you can start selling at schools.
Turn kids to clients.
Nope. No heroin here.
Here either, boss.
None in here either, boss.
"A," "B," "A," "B,"
"A," "B," "A," "B."
"A," "B," "A," "B," "A."
All the "A's," on your feet.
Tell your fellow Torrucos that the next
asshole I catch selling dope to kids...
I'm gonna find a soft, dark place
to jam this stick.
Now get out.
"B's" on your feet.
You're all busted! Whoa.
Whoa. Felipe, where you going?
You're not an "A."
You were handing out samples
at Truman East Middle School today...
which makes you a special kind of"B"...
my bitch.
- This guy's probably gonna need a medic.
- Okay. Call it in.
Get the rest of these guys
carred and barred.
- One-Tango-13, we need an R.A.
- Hello, Officer.
- Can I help you?
- You work with a Detective Mackey?
- Maybe. Why?
- I sometimes have information for him.
- You one of his C.I.s?
- Not officially.
I need to get a message to him.
I lost his number
and, uh, it's important.
- What's the message?
- The guy he's looking for isn't stopping.
And I'm afraid if Vic isn't careful,
he might start talking.
- That's the message?
- Mmm.
What's your name?
Tell him about the face.
He'll know.
Look at you, Felipe.
You barely got hair on your nads...
and you're already dealing
hard stuff to kids.
I'm not going to jail.
What fantasy world are you living in?
I'm 15.
Minors don't get time.
Unless the crime's serious enough.
You moved heavy weights of "H," amigo.
To hundreds of kids. You're done.
- But... But I'm a minor.
- In a major pile of shit.
- But... But I was told that...
- You were told wrong!
It's all right. You can cry.
You wouldn't be the first.
And you damn sure
won't be the last.
Nah.
Everybody's got game on the street.
Then you get caught.
Reality sets in.
Life as you know it is over.
- I was just following orders.
- I know.
- Go ahead. Let it all out.
- You don't understand.
You can't say no to him.
- To who?
- Armadillo.
You work for Armadillo?
You've seen him in town?
No. Everything goes through Duardo.
- You know where we can find Armadillo?
- No, but Duardo would.
- Armadillo's back?
- You start kids off for free,
get customers for life.
- I'm throwing everyone I have on this.
- No. You can't do that.
- Why not?
- The last time you couldn't
read between the lines...
so this time let me
draw you a clear picture.
Keep other cops...
Claudette especially... off my ass.
- What's your plan?
- Armadillo knows the law.
He's using minors to distribute
because they can't serve major time.
He'll also know that they can't be used as
undercover C.I.s in a major sting operation.
Okay.
I use Felipe as an undercover informant.
He leads us to Duardo.
Duardo leads us to Armadillo.
- Absolutely not.
- Are we going to do this or aren't we?
I'm for doing it in a way
that will actually secure a conviction.
- It's illegal.
- My way would be more of a gray area.
The last time we used a kid,
Armadillo raped and tattooed her.
Think of something else,
and do it fast...
or I am putting every unit I got
on tracking him down.
- Vic.
- What can I do for you, gorgeous?
- Got a message for you.
- Yeah, from who?
I guess you know the guy.
Left side of his face was scarred...
like he'd been in some sort
of fire or something.
Armadillo's declaring goddamn war.
What does he mean,
"You don't want him talking"?
Means he's gonna explain
the grill marks on his face.
Talk about how we were
protecting his drug competition.
- If somebody else finds him before us...
- Can't happen.
- We have to find him first.
- And what? Hand him over to Aceveda?
He'll pull his gun.
We'll have no choice.
- You see a better way?
- No.
Asshole should have gone back to Mexico
like you told him.
- What about Lem?
- He's not down with
ripping off the money train.
How the hell you think
he's gonna feel about this?
Keep 'im away from the action. Watching the
door or something. You know the drill.
What's up?
- What's goin' on?
- Aceveda wants us to find Armadillo.
We're just trying to figure out
the best way to do it.
My grandfather had Alzheimer's.
I know how hard it is.
I was only gone an hour. I mean,
the cleaning lady said she'd watch her.
We'll find her.
I promise.
Is there anyplace where she might go?
People she might visit?
No. Most of her friends
have been moved or passed away.
- Any other family members in town?
- No.
- I'm her only child.
- Good news is I talked
to the morgue and hospitals.
No matches on a Jeannie Sutton.
Listen, uh,
we've notified our patrol cars.
We're going to distribute a flyer
with your mom's photo.
Someone will find her.
Dutch and I will oversee the search
until someone does.
Hey.
- Uh, you busy a week from Sunday?
- I don't think so. Why?
- Actually, I'm getting married.
- Married? To who?
- Vanessa.
- The mom you've been seeing, like,
for a month?
- It's been seven weeks.
- Please, tell me this is a joke.
Uh, no. I love her.
She loves me.
Julien. Jesus.
- How goes it?
- Good. Good.
- I'm getting married.
- Holy crap.
- Yeah.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
- Better you than me.
Yeah, that's what I hear.
Look, it's gonna be a small ceremony...
- but I really want you to be there.
- Julien...
- you are gay.
- No. I was misguided.
But with the help of God,
I'm now on the right path.
I've heard all about that reorientation crap.
It's completely twisted.
- That is just anti-religious propaganda.
- Julien...
- They are not helping you.
- They are helping me.
I just need to know whether or not
you're coming to my wedding.
She took three bags
of candy and then what?
Then I yelled at her to stop and pay me.
But she was really out of it.
You know, like, loco?
I was really worried about her.
If you were so worried about her,
why didn't you stop her?
I'm gonna tackle some old lady?
I called you, didn't I?
Yeah, I know that store.
My mom used to work there.
- She did?
- Yeah. A long time ago.
Used to be a soda shop...
called something else,
but that was her first job.
What other things did she do back then?
- Where've you been?
- Uh, I felt like a sandwich.
Your break was over two hours ago.
We've got a case here.
I was hungry.
And I wouldn't exactly call this a case.
Jeannie was spotted in a store
she used to work in as a teenager.
Now, if she's in a delusional state,
she might be going back into her past.
- If we do our homework...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
We're not going to find her by
psychoanalyzing the last 60 years of her life.
God knows how many
defining moments she's had.
- You have another theory, pitch it out.
- She's an old, white lady...
wondering around in a black and Hispanic
neighborhood in pajamas and slippers.
- Somebody's gonna call her in.
- Detectives.
Someone spotted your woman trying to get
into a locked apartment an hour ago.
960 Chester Avenue, number 16.
- See?
- How much you wanna bet
that's a blast from the past?
- Uh, excuse me?
- Yeah, excuse you.
No, asshole. You bump into somebody,
show some manners. Apologize.
- That's funny to you?
- Yeah.
How funny would it be
if I knocked those oversized teeth out?
Why don't you back up, Dutch-boy, before
you find my boot print halfway up your ass?
Whoa. We got more important
things to do. Come on.
- What's the matter with you?
- Nothing. Just not going to
take shit from people anymore.
- Come on, man.
- That's not my lawyer, bro.
Sit down.
Your baby brother's
stupid enough to stay in town.
You tell him that
I got some new rules for him.
- No more dealing to kids.
- I don't talk to Armadillo.
You can get him word.
Farmington is my house.
Nothin' gets dealt there
without my approval.
You keep it away from the kids.
There's plenty of junkies to go around.
Armadillo doesn't like rules.
See that One-niner over there?
I've done a few favors for his crew
out on the street.
He's willing to pay me back.
One phone call from me
and you're greenlit.
- Greenlit?
- It's an American prison term.
It means you'll be
shanked in the shower, asshole.
Bleed out before the guards
even know you're late for breakfast.
You tell Armadillo about my new rules...
and if he says one thing
about me or my crew...
I'll make that call.
- You greenlit Navaro?
- No. I just threatened to.
Greenlighting Navaro's a bluff.
Hopefully...
it'll get him to contact Armadillo,
give us his location.
If Navaro or any of his crew
make a call, the county guards...
will monitor it and let us listen in.
- Ronnie, work on tracking those calls.
- I'll wire us up.
And if Armadillo's
on the other end, we just bring him in?
I mean, what if he talks about,
you know?
We're cops. He's a fugitive.
We got a job to do.
- I don't know, man.
- Maybe he'll buy this whole
greenlighting thing.
Keep his mouth shut to save his brother.
Okay.
She was banging on my door.
Jiggling the knob.
I opened up, and she just
started yelling, "Who are you?"
This the woman?
Crazy.
Yeah, that's her.
She was babbling mostly.
Kept asking about Earl.
- Earl?
- Yeah. "Where's Earl?" That's what she said.
Earl, you lived in Apartment 16,
960 Chester Avenue?
- Yeah, a long time ago.
- 1946 to 1948?
If you say so.
- Do you remember a Jeannie Sutton?
- No.
What about her maiden name,
Jeannie Russell?
Jeannie Russell.
Yeah, her I remember.
You date her?
Yeah, for about a year on and off.
Right after the war.
- I met her at a soda shop she worked at.
- Mmm.
- You two keep in touch?
- No, no. I haven't seen her since...
I don't know.
But if she still looks as good
as she used to, give her my number.
Well, Earl, Jeannie has Alzheimer's now.
She's lost. We're trying to find her.
- Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
- Detective.
We think she might try to contact you.
- If she does, would you give us a call?
- Oh, absolutely.
A civilian saw one of my flyers. Called in, said
she saw Jeannie hanging around Echo Park.
- Sorry to waste your time.
- Thanks.
This is a C.I. contract.
D.A.'s grateful for your school tip.
You'll be required
to provide four tips every month.
Tips that lead to arrests.
- And I get paid?
- Two thousand a month.
It's not free money, Connie.
Four tips every month, and you gotta
stay legit. You'll be tested at random.
- Why are they gonna test me?
- Because they care where their money goes.
- Why, you worried?
- No.
I just don't like peeing in a cup
three times a week.
- When do I get my check?
- As soon as you give us a tip.
- I gave you a tip.
- That was in good faith.
Clock starts as soon as you sign.
I'll take a look.
What happened?
A three year old opened a packet
of candy from his brother's backpack.
- Except it wasn't candy.
- The free "H"?
- Jesus Christ.
- Poor kid.
His brother over there
says he got it from school.
He's too young to go to Truman East.
He doesn't go to Truman East.
He goes to South Torres.
Armadillo's running this shit
through the grade schools too?
I'm sick of this. Whatever you're
going to do, do it quick.
- I've already done it.
- Well, do more.
- Yeah, like what?
- I don't know. Anything.
You can't use Felipe
in an undercover capacity.
Even though he'd lead us
to Armadillo, he's a minor.
And it's illegal to use a minor as a C.I.
Right.
How'd that two hours in the cage feel?
Huh? How's 20 years gonna feel?
I can't go when someone's watching me.
You better get used to it.
I'm gonna be watching you for a while.
Wh-What do you mean?
You're gonna do a good deed, Felipe.
Make the Boys Club proud.
What kind of good deed?
The State of California has a problem
with me using minors undercover...
so technically,
we're just gonna let you go free.
Keep an eye on you...
for your own safety.
Keep an eye on me?
You try to lose us,
you go right back in the can.
You're gonna reconnect with Duardo,
find out where Armadillo's hiding.
Yo, ma'am, shuffle broad.
Hey! Hey, hey!
Police. Hold it.
Hey, who taught you you could
treat an old woman like that?
She can't tell. Crawling around,
clawing at the sidewalk.
- She's crazy.
- Okay, honey. It's all right.
- Get out of here. Go on.
- We'll get you home to your daughter.
You all right?
Got her.
- Danny, right?
- Hi.
Vanessa. We met before.
Is Julien around?
- Uh, he should be right back.
- We're going over floral arrangements
for the wedding.
Right. Congratulations.
Thanks.
It's all happening so fast.
Yeah. Well, Julien's a special guy.
I have never met a man with such integrity.
He's gonna make a great father for Randall.
I'm really lucky.
Hi.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Hey, Julien,
can I see you for a sec first?
I'll meet you at the car.
- My God. You haven't told her yet?
- It's not necessary.
Julien, she is a single woman
with a child.
- It's in my past. It is not important.
- She has a right to know.
- Every mistake I've ever made?
- About something
as important as this? Absolutely.
So you tell every man you've been with
about every shameful thing you've ever done?
You know what? If you don't
tell her before the wedding, I will.
- What are you gonna do with your cut?
- What?
Your cut.
From the money train.
Look, we discuss this
only when we have to.
The more we talk about it,
the more chance someone else hears.
- Our fugitive's calling in.
- Yeah, I got it.
I'm telling you, this money train?
It's a sure thing.
Taking mob money... that's not
why I signed up, joined the force.
Goddamn. You get any softer,
you're gonna start lactating.
You know, all the stuff we've been into,
there was a reason, a point to it.
Where's the good in this?
Money in our pockets
instead of those Balkan bastards.
I don't know, man.
You think I'm doing this for me?
Vic's got a sick kid,
tuition payments...
doctor bills kicking his ass.
I mean,
the guy could be facing a divorce.
He really needs this.
- Heroin in grade school.
- It's awful.
I'm gonna have to go on the attack now.
Find a way to turn this into votes.
Baby, what's wrong?
- I don't know how I got here.
- Hard work. Intelligence.
- That's not what I meant.
- You'll catch whoever's doing this.
- Or Mackey will.
- Mackey?
It's his investigation.
- Can you trust him?
- No.
- Then why?
- It made sense when it started.
And now there's so many loose threads...
To even pull just one...
- Oh, Christ.
- David. You're gonna win.
Well, that's what
everyone keeps telling me.
And if I don't, I embarrass myself...
embarrass you.
We have a daughter.
The only way you would embarrass me...
was if you weren't doing
everything you could...
to make those schools
as safe as possible.
Are you?
No.
What's stopping you?
I want a wide net.
Hit the streets hard.
Check out all the schools.
Grill every kid who got a free sample
and find out where they got it.
Sooner or later,
it's gonna lead us to Armadillo.
All right? Talk to all the gang-bangers
who got pushed out...
when the Torrucos consolidated
and call me with anything.
All right. Let's go.
Armadillo's in town?
Yeah. He's the one
dealing drugs in the schools.
- And you didn't tell me?
- I just found out.
- I need to talk to him.
- I know.
And as soon as I find him,
you'll get first shot.
And you and Mackey won't interfere?
No one will get in your way.
We'll give you a head start. You go in
and ask for a new batch of samples.
Phone.
I'll call you
10 minutes after you're in.
If the drugs are visible,
you pick up and say something clever.
If you don't answer,
I'll know they're not out.
- I'll keep calling until you pick up.
- Then what?
We'll make a little house call.
Pick up you and your buddies.
Once we get you back to the barn,
we cut you loose because you're a minor.
- No one knows we had this little arrangement.
- Okay.
- Cheers, little "G."
- Cheers.
- Thirsty, huh?
- Yeah, I guess so.
Hey I got some kids asking for more of
that stuff. I guess they like that shit.
All right, all right.
Cost them 20 now. Got that?
- Yeah, yeah. I got it.
- All right.
Yo, give him something
to carry this with, man.
Yo.
What, bitch?
I told you not to call me.
- Little "G" settin'
the ho's straight already.
- Yeah.
Hey, wh-what's the matter, dog?
That's what I wanna know.
Let's see who called you.
Get down!
Down on the ground. Down!
Stay down!
- You're dead.
- Shut up!
- You okay?
- No. I'm dead.
You wanted to see me?
Uh, yeah.
Close the door, please.
- I just got a call from the police.
- About my car?
Sit down, Danny.
- What?
- The call was from Maryland.
Your mother died.
- A car accident.
- What?
I'm so sorry.
- Can I call my dad?
- Yeah. I'll be outside.
Dad. It's me.
It was a goddamn prank.
It was a prank. My mother's fine.
- Slow down. What?
- I want that bitch's records subpoenaed.
- We have to prove that
she made that phone call.
- Danny, stop.
- I want a cop tailing her.
- Just calm down.
She destroys my car, and then she tries
to ruin my career. Now it's my family.
Okay. All right. We'll take care of this.
I'll take care of this.
- The doctor said she can go home now.
- Great.
- Thank you for all you did.
- Anne, hold on a second.
Your mom must have been 17, 18
when she dated Earl?
Pretty conservative times back then.
- Excuse me?
- Dutch.
You said she was going back
into her past. I didn't believe you.
But then Jeannie went back
to the store she used to work at...
an apartment
where her old boyfriend lived.
So why go back to a piece
of sidewalk in Echo Park?
- Why?
- According to the L.A. Times archives...
a newborn baby was found smothered to death
in that park, November 18, 1947.
Buried in a shallow grave.
You wanna know
where that grave was located?
Right where your mother sat today,
clawing at the asphalt.
They built a sidewalk over the garden.
Three blocks from Earl's old apartment.
No.
- That's impossible.
- Someone in there helped
kill a baby boy, didn't they?
I'm not even going to
waste my time with you.
You're running Armadillo's drugs
through the schools. Where is he?
Arma who?
Tell me. Tell me.
Vic!
- Vic, open this door.
- Cállete.
You ready?
- What's going on?
- I'm interrogating the suspect.
Duardo here runs the drugs
through the schools.
- Isn't that right?
- I'm taking him back to the barn.
- I'm not done.
- I'm taking him with me. Hand him over.
Come here.
You gave me the green light
to get Armadillo. I'm one step away.
I'm a little uncomfortable
with the steps you're now taking.
I saw the underage C.I. outside.
His cover's been blown?
We both knew that was a risk.
You've done a good job getting this far.
I just need to take it from here.
- Hey, you want Armadillo or not?
- I do.
- And Claudette and I will get him.
- Claudette?
She overheard.
There's nothing I can do about it.
We've got to do it by the book now.
Shane, put him in my car.
I spoke to Aceveda.
He said I passed my performance review.
You deserve to.
He also said I had communication and stress
management issues that need addressing.
- Look, you passed. Okay?
- This is because I didn't
cover you on that shooting.
You still think
I'm holding that over you?
- Or maybe it's because I'm getting married.
- It's because it's the truth.
Look, I think it's about something else.
Maybe it's because somebody's...
messing with your car or they called on your
mom, and you're going to take it out on me?
Hey, you are way past out of line.
I deserved higher marks on that.
That... That review goes on my jacket.
Truth is, Julien, I could've been
a whole lot tougher on you.
Your inability to communicate
is a serious problem.
You have this bottled-up pressure
because of your personal life...
and no release valve.
Things I've seen...
Your review could have been a lot worse.
I thought about
what you said about Vanessa.
- Good.
- I'm not gonna jeopardize
the only good relationship...
I've ever had because of something
I'm not and will never be again.
If you wanna tell her, fine.
That's on your conscience.
We found the heroin, your little sample bags.
We establish the ties...
to the schools, and you're sure to get
the death penalty for that little boy.
The only way to avoid it
is to give us Armadillo.
He's your boss, right? Your supplier?
How does he contact you?
Where is he?
- Yo, what's up?
- I got something for you.
This pimp's getting his girls
to roll johns in an alley off Western.
Okay, we'll check into it. But, tips like this
you can give over the phone.
Okay. Vic.
I really need to know where Brian is.
I need to see my son.
Connie, you can't.
I want him back, Vic.
I'm clean. I've got a job now.
He's with a new family.
You signed him over.
I was high then.
That's why you gave him up.
No. No.
I gave him to you
to take care of him for me.
You knew I'd get clean.
You saw how hard I was trying.
You don't know what this is like...
to lose your kid.
Please, Vic.
Brian's gone.
You have to accept that.
Okay.
- I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry too.
Uh, that tip I just gave you?
I need a cash advance.
Thanks.
Navaro make any calls yet?
- Nope.
- They get Duardo to roll?
I don't know.
I'll be back.
- Hey, Carlton.
- What's up, Vic?
See this guy?
He's with the Lancaster Gang Unit.
He got you a spot
on their Clean Slate program.
- Is that like juvie?
- It's better.
Get rid of the ink, balls'll drop,
come back in a couple years a new man.
No one will even recognize you.
Hey, I had to pull a lot of favors
to get this to happen.
- Okay.
- Well, I'm waiting.
- Thank you.
- Go.
You killed your baby, didn't you, Earl?
You and Jeannie.
"Baby Boy Doe buried in the unidentified
grave section of the L.A. County Cemetery."
We're gonna dig him up, Earl,
get your D.N.A. ...
prove you were his father.
You really think Armadillo's
gonna reward you for your loyalty?
When we bust him,
he's gonna think it's because of you.
He's got a lot of friends inside.
You're gonna end up
burned to death in your cell.
And we're gonna get him.
All you guys think you're so brilliant.
We got you, didn't we?
What happens if I tell you where he is?
We'll make sure you're safe and sound
in Ossining, New York.
I can only tell you
where he's been staying lately.
- What's up?
- Duardo gave us Armadillo.
He's at a place in Inglewood.
- Great. I'll go get my guys.
- Not necessary.
- SWAT's already on their way there.
- SWAT?
I'll let you see him as soon as we
bring him in. All right, let's go.
Vic.
- Hi. What's up?
- I was thinking that...
we could get together tonight.
I can't do it tonight.
Rain check?
Name the time and the place.
You know,
I don't think that I can do this anymore.
Sure you can.
Just another time.
No, you know what? Um, this isn't working
for me the way that it used to.
I gotta get out of here.
You're wrong, Detective.
You don't know my mother.
I just wish you had a chance
to know your brother.
Should I be worried about you?
Not about me.
Maybe about the rest of humanity.
Bunch of sociopathic
little narcissists out for ourselves.
Begging, stealing,
lying, screwing, raping.
Killing our babies.
Whatever it takes to have a good time
and save our own asses.
I can't even believe in an old woman
who's too sick to feed herself.
And it's not sad. It's not some big surprise.
It's just nature.
We're animals.
Nothing more.
And you know what?
I'm learning to be okay with that.
- Navaro's on the phone?
- Less than a minute.
- Prison switchboard confirms
he's talking to Armadillo.
- Give me the number.
This is 323.
Aceveda's going to Inglewood.
- That's 310.
- He's got the wrong address.
Go get the right one, quick.
- What's he saying?
- Um, Armadillo's asking him
something in Spanish.
- Something about a lawyer.
- Vic.
- What?
- We can't bring him in alive.
- Armadillo. We can't bring him in alive.
- Why is that?
- If we take him in,
the only thing he has to deal is us.
Look, I don't like it,
but this bastard has to go, Vic.
Jail won't slow him down. You tried reasoning
with him. I'm not going to lose my job...
so some kid-raping piece of shit can bargain
down his sentence, make me his bunk-mate.
Uh-uh.
- You talk to Shane about this?
- No, but I can.
- 3938 Bonita Vista.
- Okay, let's go.
Ronnie, stay on the line.
Call us with anything we need.
Lem, you drive.
Hey, uh, shouldn't
we be taking two cars?
- No, we're good.
- Yeah?
Armadillo's
still on the phone with his bro.
First guy who gets
a good shot takes it. Go.
- Nothing.
- Goddamn it.
- Think somebody tipped him off?
- Who?
I don't know.
- Yeah?
- I hope you all made it.
Hey. Weren't you supposed to
meet me here to suck my dick?
I wanted to speak to you
one last time.
You better talk to your brother
before you start making death threats.
I've already taken care of my brother.
And now you've been greenlit.