What's up, boss?
Seen the new 20?
Yeah, man
The colors are funky
Yeah. The old ones are gonna be phased out
of the system over the next year or so.
So what does that mean
about our money train 20s?
Means we have to unload our 20s
sooner than we wanted to
before they stand out too much.
Shit
So Claudette's in charge
of our team now?
That's the way she sees it
- You had a female boss before?
- You ever met my daughter?
She's insisting
we go mini-putting.
So how do we deal with her?
Kill her with kindness. Couple of months,
we'll get our freedom back.
It's not like
we can't use the break
Catching those preppy lawyers
with their pants down.
I think you guys
got the wrong room
Wyms told us to shack up here
We're, uh, the Decoy Squad
We just transferred in
I'm Walon Eddie, Annie, Trish
Vic Mackey
It's a little crowded in here
Why don't I talk to my captain, see if
I can scrounge you guys up some new digs
- Seems okay to me
- Yeah We can make it work
What's that smell?
Oh I've been playing homeless
for the last three days Kinda ripe, huh?
Where's the, uh,
shower around here?
First door on the left
- Look. I need to go to work.
- Then go already
Well, I don't want to leave
arguing What's the problem?
Nothing.
What are you doing?
This doesn't have to be a thing.
You don't want me here
I said I thought it was a little
fast for you to be moving in
That doesn't mean that I don't
want you here when I get home
- Shit
Hey Hey
Hey, hey, hey, hey
- What, couldn't find the shower?
- Yeah, I found it Thanks
- Where's the rest of your team?
I gave Ronnie a pass. He's seeing
a plastic surgeon about his face.
- And Shane?
- Car battery died
- He'll meet us
- Okay
Our first target: prostitution
We've mapped out
four key red light zones
Phase one: Get the girls
off the street
Phase two:
Nail the johns
Temporary processing station's
been set up to expedite arrests.
Also, media crews will be filming
to discourage offenders
and anyone watching
from ever coming back.
The DA's office
has been helpful as well
Members of your team can now
show their, uh, members to the girls
Whoa We get to show our dicks?
- Time to pull out the pipes, fellas
Only to convince them that
you're not law enforcement
They can look
They can't touch
- Their loss
Chicken head, 2:;00.
Drive-through blow jobs
All right. I'm rollin'up.
We got ya, good buddy.
You lookin' for a date, honey?
- It's too nice a night to be lonely
- You a cop?
I look like a cop?
Yeah Let me see
your package
- You gotta promise not to get scared away
- Go ahead Frighten me
Okay
- Halloween's early this year Want some candy?
Well, how do I know
you're not a cop?
I am a cop
See my badge?
Go, brother!
Oh, that just made my week
Head's 50. Sex is 75.
Anal's a hundred.
- Hey. Sorry.
You wanna be my back door baby?
- Where the hell you been?
- Dealin' with some stuff
Well, next time pick up a phone
Or at least answer yours
We got an assault
in progress. You guys see that?
- Lem, hit it!
Police!
- Get off
- Come here
- I got the runners!
- Get off, you asshole!
- Freeze! Police!
- You're under arrest, princess
All right, ladies. Easy.
-Just relax
- Ow! My arm!
Everybody calm down!
Hey, I know you, right?
- No
- Yeah.
You're the cop that was there
when Connie got killed
I saw you at the funeral.
I was her friend.
You were too, right?
What do you want?
My pimp kicked me out on the street
Won't let anyone else take me in
I got no protection.
Well, looks like it's time to relocate then
Or find a new line of work
- Please! I just--
- Sorry
Connie said you helped her
Said you looked out for her and Brian
Connie was just an informant of mine
Dropping her name is doing you no good
- But I heard you helped her out ofjams--
- You heard wrong
Please You're a cop
They're gonna kill me out there
Do something for me.
I'm not gonna judge
the life you chose
but I'm not gonna get
sucked into it either
Good luck
Ripped by:
Hound
Oh, my. You two
dirty up quite nicely.
Oh, this? Just a few
rags from my closet
I'll give you a full
runway show sometime
She's not kidding.
These are hers too.
All these arrests
are for solicitation?
Assault and battery Buys us an extra
three to six months off the street
Sorry to set the bar so high
your first night on the job
Well, we'll see if we can keep up
- Thanks for coming
- Yeah I had a flat
I got there as quick as I could
I told her your battery died
It was personal
It won't happen again
I talked to the hooker who got jumped
She's willing to build
a case against her pimp
I talked to her too
She's a liar
Then she should fit
right in on your team
Work with her
I've sent a message
to the gals and johns
and I'd like to send one
to the pimps too
You're the boss
I thought
you had that hooker sting.
It's in motion
I heard you got a call
I thought I'd check in.
Victim's name is Isabel Nelson
Raped by a lone male
Guy was waiting in the house
naked when she came home.
- Left with jewelry, a little cash.
- Is that her?
That's her daughter.
Isabel's 73.
He had a ski mask
covering his head
Was he black? White?
White Maybe Mexican
Not black
Do you remember anything
about his body?
Tattoos? Birthmarks?
Anything?
All I saw was his--
And it didn't look anything
like my husband's used to look
Well, we can talk
about this later
I want to help
He shouldn't have done this!
Is it true that, uh,
he didn't leave right away?
He wanted to know where my
jewelry was, and he took it
Then he laid down
on the bed again
Next to me
He put his hands on me
Two or three hours
Was he holding you down?
No
He just--
Cuddled with you
That was the worst part
It's okay Good
Would you stop ignoring my
messages and call me back, baby?
Okay? Please
Trouble in paradise
That's one I won't miss
What's up?
I'm-I'm sorry
I went over your head
I didn't know
she was your boss.
You just don't understand
how dangerous Smooth is
I know pimps.
Only thing original
about them are their names
- Where are you from?
- San Jose
When this is over, why don't you
take a bus, open up shop there?
I like LA
Smooth'll kill you
if he finds out you helped us
Not if you protect me
Let's be clear This is
a one-shot deal, sweetie
Then we're done
The guy in the suit--
What's he in on?
Solicitation. Won't give
his name. Had no I.D.
- Nothing at all?
- Ass Invader?
I've been lookin' all over
Beverly Hills for one of those
Somebody dropped by the screw store
and said, ''Give me one of everything''
He has got a dildo in there
you could snake a drain with
I'll handle this one. Finish
the paperwork,;run it by me.
Captain's real
hands-on here, huh?
You could say that
See anything
I should take home?
How are you, David?
Better than you,Javier
That policewoman
made a big mistake
I don't want to get
anybody in trouble
but, you know,
she's acted out of line
How?
She flagged me over
Said she wanted directions
I'm not out there looking
for this, so help me
Come on,Javier I saw the bag
you were arrested with
Embarrassing
It's not illegal
Why didn't you
give your name?
I panicked I-- I'm trying
to save the district from scandal
For God's sake, do you know what would
happen to me if people think I actually did this?
So why cuddle?
Is that a guilt reaction...
or some kind
of emotional souvenir?
''Just because I raped you
doesn't mean we can't be friends''?
Thanks for the assignment
Farrah's a real winner
- What'd she give us?
- Smooth's running a glorified
whorehouse for downtown suits
He keeps a drug stash in the house
in case his guests need a pick-me-up--
you know, ''X,'' oxy, coke
I'll call for a warrant You see
if Shane slept through his alarm
- All right. That's the target.
The drug stash is in the last
bedroom down the hall
- Tavon's got point
- Tavon? What about me?
You already got one strike
against you with Claudette
If something goes wrong,
I don't want you taking a double hit
- Why would something go wrong?
- It won't
- It's on
- Okay. Give up your hardware.
Farrah says they're running clients for
metal on the way inside, so give it up.
Okay You're not packing,
so keep it simple
Get in. Get solicited.
Shane'll call in the signal.
- Who's Smooth's bottom bitch?
- She's the queen whore-- Cocoa
- So how'd you hear about us?
- We came in for the car convention
The boys from Chevy
gave me your number
- Who you like?
- What about you?
You can get the mouth,
but only Smooth gets my booty
- Suck you bone dry for 1 00
- Hope you're worth it
- Now that's mine
- Party favors?
Coke? ''X''? Viagra?
I'll take some ''X''
And get my boy here
some of that Viagra
- He can use the boost
Follow me
You got a bathroom?
Mm-hmm Upstairs
I'm gonna give you something
more than you bargained for
Hey, it's a go Two guys packin'
just inside the front door
Go! Move, move, move!
Come on Move your ass
- Go!
- Go
- Oh, my God!
Shit! It's reinforced
The door's holding
Open it from the inside
- I got it
- Get out of the way!
- It's a raid!
- Where the hell's backup?
- Can't get in
- Get out, girls!
- Hey, get her, man
Let me down there!
- Police! Freeze!
- Where's Tavon?
She's flushing the drugs!
Move! Move!
Get down! Get out of here
right now! Get out!
- We need a ram in here!
- Hurry up!
- Get the ram!
Give it here! Give it here!
Give it here!
Go! Go!
- Too late
- Get on your feet! Hands on your head!
- Get against the wall!
- Turn to the wall!
- Yes?
- I'm Detective Wagenbach
I'm investigating a break-in last night at the
building next door You notice anyone unusual?
-Just the police
- What about the rest of your family?
It's just me and my son,
Josh, but he wasn't home
- How old is Josh?
- Nineteen
I'm gonna need to talk to him
Have him give me a call
That's my number if you
think of something else
Should I be worried?
That was a lot of commotion
for a break-in
Uh,just make sure you lock up
when you're not at home
Thank you
Uh, excuse me!
Smooth's smarter
than we gave him credit for.
He registered his cathouse
in Cocoa's name
Summer classes
at Pimp U paid off
Well, she's so brainwashed, she'll never roll
on him without a drug charge to hold over her
What are you saying? Everyone
but King Shithead gets busted?
Looks like it's time
for you to catch that bus
I didn't do this
so he could walk
And I didn't do this to settle
some personal grudge of yours
We got his house, his bottom
bitch, most of his girls
It was a good day
No. Use me if you have to.
That cocksucker turned out my 1 3-year-old
sister when she came to visit me
Got her shooting up
Next thing, she's hooking
- Then she gets sick.
- AI DS?
I haven't seen her in two months
Who knows who she's
sucking off for pocket change
Don't let him keep doing this
What do you think?
- Of her half-assed sob story?
- No
Using her to get to Smooth
Could get her killed But if she
doesn't care, why should we?
We send her out of town
when it's done
I say we move on to the next thing
Get her out of our lives
The reason pimp cases are impossible
is because girls won't cooperate
She's willing
I say we go with it
- Saddle someone else with it
- I'm saddling you
Look You want Smooth?
I want my clubhouse back
This isn't a barter
It's an assignment
Everyone's saying
Mrs Nelson was raped
Ma'am, we don't
discuss ongoing cases
Look I'm alone a lot
when my son's out
and I asked you
if I should be worried
Paul Fets
Have you talked with him?
- He's raped before.
- Paul Fets?
He's a registered sex offender.
Lives across the street from Mrs. Nelson.
Why am I the one checking on this?
Ma'am, there are 34 registered sex offenders
in a five-block area around that apartment
including 1 2 high-risk felons
Fets followed me
into my apartment once
Said he wanted to help
with my groceries
If my son hadn't come home
right then, it would've been me
- Well, we will talk to him
- He was looking in her window
Mrs Nelson's
About a week ago I caught him
Why didn't you tell me
that this morning?
Because you didn't tell me
you were looking for a rapist
Did you hear there was a woman
raped in the building next to yours?
No
Somebody crawled into her window
Raped her when she came home
Sounds a lot like that trouble
you got into before
Sorry I'm late Hello
Mandy Trujillo She was a paraplegic
girl in a wheelchair
You forced her side door open...
went into her bedroom,
put your penis in her mouth, didn't you?
I don't think that way anymore
Maybe you can explain why somebody saw
you looking into Mrs. Nelson's window.
- The same window the rapist went in.
- That wasn't me
Was she home, or did you decide
to come back when she was gone?
I didn't look through her window
And you didn't follow Wanda Ledda
into her apartment either, did you?
I was-- I was trying to help her
with the groceries
She-- She didn't have to tell
the neighbors about me
I-- I don't like that pressure
Be here by 1 0:;00 in the morning.
We'll take a run at your pimp.
Why can't we do it tonight?
'Cause you're not the only woman
in my life who needs attention
Well, where am I
supposed to stay?
Where'd you stay last night?
My place
But it's not safe there
Just give me some money
for a motel.
I already gave you a bus ticket
Feel free to use it anytime
Just call me
and tell me you're okay
Could you do that, please?
Great goddamn day
First Mara, then I gotta share
a locker with Pigpen
- They'll be gone soon
- Yeah, or we will
They made 1 5 arrests
last night Vice!
- So what's with Mara?
- These pimps have it figured out.
If you treat 'em like shit,
they stick to you like flies.
If only swatting
'em away was as easy.
I just don't want
to swat this one away
This is the first gal I've ever been with
that's better than me, you know?
She's not better than you
She's probably
just blowing off steam
Yeah
Just, uh, give her some space
She'll call ya
You goin' out?
Yeah I got my daughter tonight
Mini-putt and ice cream
That's good, man
Yeah Be nice to get away
from all the drama
Mom!
I'm sorry I don't know
what happened
She kept screaming
to come home.
- Go to your room and get ready for bed
- I want Daddy to tuck me in
- Go to your room!
- No!
Listen to your mother
I'll make it up to you I promise
- No, Daddy! Please stay!
- Cassidy, stop this right now!
Hold on. Hold on. Maybe I should stay,
just for an hour.
Cassidy, come here right now
Get over here Listen to me
I know what you're doing,
and it's not going to work, okay?
Your father's going to leave now
If you want to spend time with him,you
will behave when it's his turn to see you.
- Now, let's go
- No, Daddy Please don't go
- Please, Daddy, don't go!
- Go!
- Dad, don't! Please! Dad, please don't!
- As you can imagine, I deal
with rape and death every day
- I'm sorry
- As you can imagine, I deal
with rape and death every day
- I'm sorry
I don't mind.
I feel like I'm helping.
Like I'm taking bad people away
before they can hurt somebody else
That's not me
In my experience, people
who would rape an old woman
or a crippled lady,
they always do it again
You do know that, right?
You know what a moral compass is?
It's-It's a thing in people that tells them
what's right and what's wrong
They know because this
moral compass guides them
Only it gets broken
in some people. Smashed.
So they do these horrible things,
but it's not their fault
Their compass is just broken
Can I-- Can I go to the bathroom?
Sure
- This is for girls
- The men's is broken
It's all right
Everybody uses this one
I did things
I know
What-- All right What if
your moral compass is broken?
How-How--
How do you fix it?
You can't
Isabel, that old woman--
This is the last sexual
experience she's gonna have
Can you even imagine that?
A grandmother!
Imagine if it
were your grandmother
I don't think you want
to hurt anybody again
But you gotta help me
make sure that doesn't happen
I don't wanna be broken
Okay Okay
-Javier send you?
- What are we going to do?
I don't think there's much
we can do,Jorge
- Sanchez is a friend
- Of yours
He's been supportive of you
Letting him go without processing him while
I look into things is supportive.
He told me it was
entrapment Is it possible?
I plan on talking
to the arresting officer
I remember when a reporter was
asking questions about you once...
about the rape at USC.
I didn't rape anyone
She was an unstable woman
But I supported you. And I never
asked you if it was true or not.
Um, tell me
about the Sanchez arrest.
He pulled up to the curb--
- Did you flag him?
- I smiled at him
- I do have a nice smile
- Then what?
I engaged him. He said
the magic words,;I gave the signal.
- Be more specific
- He's into pegging
He said he wanted to do me
with his favorite dildo
then have me strap one on
and return the favor
Offered me 1 50 bucks, the cheap bastard.
I've had men go as high as five.
He's claiming it was entrapment
Did you see his bag?
Bondage is more like it
I'm still looking into this case
Don't discuss it with anyone
Hey,you guys took a call
at L.A. Sound Design last week?
- Yeah The one on Sixth Street?
- Yeah. I just took one at the store on Olympic.
I asked the owner
for a surveillance tape.
He goes in the back for two minutes.
Comes out. The tape is ruined.
Ours didn't have a camera
Two in two weeks Hey, can I get a copy
of the serial numbers you guys took?
Isn't that for the insurance
company to worry about?
Yeah, but the detectives
are short-staffed This is low priority
I was thinking, you know, maybe
we can sniff around on our own
Just 'cause you've been icing on the sidelines
doesn't mean you have to play Wonder Woman.
I might be able to dig up
the outfit if you're interested
- The call didn't seem right to me
- We filed our paperwork
Yeah There was nothing weird
that I can remember about the call
Fine Sorry
to interrupt your dinner
Hey, Danny Give me half an hour,
and I'll pull it all together for you
Thanks
Keep it simple Turn around
You tell him you want back into his stable,
and you'll do whatever it takes to do it
- I asked him before
- Most ofhis girls are in lockup.
Chances are he'll need temps
Can't wait to see his face
when we bust him
Well, if he gets rough,
I'll stop him
I can handle a beating
You won't have to
Bury it
- Don't touch me
- Come on
Like you never took a free suck
from Connie We can help each other
-Just put on the goddamn wire
- She said you were nice
All you ever been to me
is an asshole
Place the wire
and follow me
Dutch got a confession
from the rapist.
- Oh, that's great news
- Hey,just curious
We arrested 1 5 johns yesterday
but only booked 1 4
- I released one
- Now I'm even more curious
Javier Sanchez is
the superintendent of schools.
I'm just double-checking
the facts before proceeding
His facts couldn't
be checked from the cage?
I'm extending him a courtesy
What qualifies as the special
treatment club this week?
As soon as he's processed,
he'll be publicly humiliated.
His career effectively will be over
I was under the impression we were showing
people that things were changing around here
- We are
- Smells like the same cookin' to me
You made all these
arrests in the last hour?
Finish the handoff,
then get back out there
We keep haulin' in this many fish,
we might need to find you new digs
- We set?
- YeahJust waitin' for your okay
Yeah Where have you been?
Look You understand that once you go
in there personally, your life's at stake?
Yes
- You're gonna have to get on the bus
- I will
- Look I gotta go
- We're in the middle of something here
I'm sorry Look
I need a personal day
Not a problem
Look who
crawled out from under its rock.
- Can we talk?
- You got nothin' to say, bitch
I'll work twice as hard.
I'll be your best earner.
- I said you have nothin' to say!
- Gotta go
Whoa, whoa. Hold on.
You go out, hit it hard enough
tonight, maybe we'll talk
You freak on me again,
I'll kill you
- It's good
We got it on tape
Good job
These turn into bruises,
get some Polaroids
Yeah.
Can I get your opinion
on something?
I'd stick
with the fishnets
French maid's outfit
might be too much
I got stuck between Claudette
and Aceveda on something
- Uh, what exactly are the politics around here?
- Tell me more
- That john I brought in with the goody bag?
- Mm-hmm
Seems like Aceveda wants it to go away
Important guy, I guess
And Claudette has another idea
So, push comes to shove,
which pony would you ride?
Aceveda's still the boss
After that, city council
If he asks for somethin',
do him the favor
Thanks
- You like Chinese?
- Sometimes
I'll take you to Chinese
sometime, pay you back
- Fets didn't cuddle
- What?
In his statement he says
he raped her, then he left
He also can't tell me
anything about the jewelry
Thinks he dumped it someplace
but doesn't remember where
We've got a confession
We've got a witness
who saw him at the window
He is slow
This is a guy who raped a woman,
didn't leave a single hair fiber
No. Not only have I been chasing
the wrong guy, I caught him.
Give Smooth the money
Be very clear you earned it hooking
That's like $600
It's not enough
You've only been at it
a couple of hours It'll be enough
He won't take this
It's an insult
Make it work
It's all we have
He'll kill me
if I give him this little
We're not gonna
let him hurt you
- No I'll just go to him and explain
- You won't explain anything!
I'll tell him I was working with you,
but I changed my mind
- You tell him that, he will kill you
- Let go of me!
You don't give a shit
about me! You're an asshole!
- He'll take care of me if I tell him the truth
- Don't do it!
I'm not doing this
You think you can just
walk away from me?
Get off of me!
You made me a promise
You told me you wanted this
I don't wanna do this anymore
- 'Cause you're scared?
- He'll kill me
You need to be scared of me
- Vic--
- Back off
Let me just go talk to him
Take it! Now!
Smooth's my bitch
which makes you
my bottom bitch
You're gonna go out there,
you're gonna do what I told you
or I swear to God I will hurt you like
you've never been goddamn hurt before
- You understand?
- Say it!
- Okay
Good
You wanna make me happy, huh?
- Yes
- Sure, you do
Okay
Now, do what I told you
Good girl Go ahead
- What the hell was that?
- I just saved her life You watch
Rolled some tricks for you, baby.
Slow your roll, ho.
Po-po's been cracking down. Come here.
A'ight. Give up the skrilla.
- I can't see her
- We're fine
I see petty cash.
Where's the cheddar?
Sucked a lot
of dicks for that
- You comin' crooked on me, skank?
- That's all the money I got
- You can shove it up your ass.
- What's she doin'?
- She's baiting him Let's go
- That's how it's gonna be?
- Punk-ass bitch You're nothin'
- Oh, yeah?
You don't scare me.
Let go of me!
I said let go of me!
Asshole!
Get back!
Stay still!
Don't fight me!
I got marks You and I can say he hit me
Get him put away longer
I'm not lying for you
We got him for what we got him on
It'll be a long time before another pimp
thinks about laying a hand on me
You forgettin' about
that bus to San Jose?
I don't need it anymore
You're protecting me
No, I'm not
We're done now Finished
Why are you such a shithead?
I chose you over Smooth
I stopped you
from killing yourself
- You stuck a gun in my mouth
- No, I did not
- Now you're not gonna protect me?
- Shut up right now.
You're a bigger
asshole than Smooth!
Even bigger than the one who
turned out your 1 3-year-old sister?
- That's right
- 'Cause I found out the only
sister you have is seven
You're just pissed off that Smooth
stopped you from earning
Is that what you did
to Connie too? Used her?
She trusted you,
and you got her killed
- It's time to go
- You dared that guy to shoot her
Her little boy doesn't have a mother,
and that's your fault!
Wouldn't want you to miss your bus
You didn't give a shit about Connie!
I tolerated her to the extent
she could help me make cases
She's dead because of you
No You all find ways
of killing yourselves
Go find yours
Asshole!
You call for backup?
Yeah We got a hit
on a stolen stereo
A Sun Yun Do at this residence
registered online to get the warranty
You sure you didn't want to call SWAT?
You guys were so helpful
breaking this thing
I thought you'd want to
be here for the arrest
- What the hell are these?
Uh, I went to see Isabel
One of them's Fets
You showed a 73-year-old
rape victim a penis lineup?
She wants the guy caught
All she saw was the penis
Plus, she picked the wrong one
So whose did she choose?
I couldn't get
anyone else to volunteer
- Ah, Dutch!
- Well, I didn't ask you to look at 'em
It's not like it's anything
you haven't seen before
The important thing is Isabel
confirms that Fets isn't our guy.
- We're sending you home.
- Why?
- Because you didn't rape Mrs Nelson
But I think about it with other
women,just like you said
Still, you didn't do it
No My moral compass is broken
Um look
That was just
an interrogation technique
I needed you to believe it
because I wanted you to confess
M-Mandy Trujillo
was seven years ago
You've been good
since then, right?
- I tried real hard
- Well, and it's working
There's a Dr Lakeman who's gonna come
talk to you about staying good
I can't go home
She told everybody about me
and about Mandy
Everybody hates me And now she's gonna
tell 'em that I did it to that old woman
I'll talk to your neighbors, and we're
gonna catch the guy who really did this
Here's my card You call me
if you need anything
Anything
You said you weren't
gonna be here
I wanted to see you for myself
I'm just gonna get the rest
of my things, and I'm leaving
What is your problem?
Why are you acting
like such a psycho bitch?
Just leave me alone
All right Fine Fine You wanna leave?
Then pack your shit
Get out! Here
Better yet, let me help you
What are you sulking for?
You're the one who turned on me
- That's not true
- So what was the plan, huh?
You couldn't afford a car,
so you give up a little ass
play house till you
can make your getaway?
- You're such an asshole
- How is the Lexus driving?
- Keep your goddamn car!
- You keep it You earned it
Hope the next guy enjoys it Oh, please
What, are you gonna start crying now?
Come on Let's see it
Let's see the floodgates open, Mara
-Just let me go
- No I wanna see you cry first
- Let me leave
- No I wanna see how you leaving me
- tearing me--
I wanna see
how it makes you cry
I'm pregnant
Bullshit
I am
It was an accident
Sorry, okay? I'm sorry!
- Well, we'll get married
- Oh, no! Oh, God
Hey Look at me
Hey
Marry me
And I had some more ideas
on your transition team.
So did Aurora. Maybe we could
get together this week--
Just thought you should know Carlos Izturis
from the Daily News is downstairs
- Ah Hello
- What does he want?
He is coming to ask
aboutJavier Sanchez...
being arrested for solicitation
I know Carlos
I can talk to him
Good Then you can tell him
I'm moving forward with the arrest
- Give us a minute
- Take a month.
Nothing's gonna change
Send some unis to pick him up
Nice seeing you again
She leaked this
She brought Izturis in
The important thing is we cut bait
beforeJavier drags us down.
- Dutch
- Hey Congrats on your job back
- Thanks
Hey, thanks for talking
to Aceveda for me
This is that case that
I left the message about
Yeah. Insurance thing, right?
Yeah Guy was robbing from himself,
then making the claims
Sure makes it easier when officers
just hand me closed cases
-Just trying to help
- Detective, call for you on three
Detective Wagenbach
- I tried real hard
- Hello?
- Her son just left She's alone
- Paul?
- I finally got that bitch alone
- Now you can stop me
- Paul? Don't go anywhere, all right?
- Let me, uh-- Let me talk to you
- You have to stop me
Rape in progress
Call it in
Paul, what are you
feeling right now?
How do you change
what you want?
It isn't what you want
I-I promise you
You've done so well
No, I haven't I'll try
not to hurt her too bad
- Paul? Paul--
- Police! Open up!
Police!
Stop! Get on the floor
Let me see your hands.
School and sex crimes
That story's gonna hit big
- He brought it on himself.
- Oh, you helped a little
I know I didn't call Carlos
- Why would I call him?
- We're sending a message.
We're assuring people
that we are cracking down
and no one's safe in Farmington
And you did it in a way
that didn't squash you and Machado
You always were my best detective
- You looking for a date?
- I want her
- She's not for sale
- That's Nasty's new girl
- How much to talk for two minutes?
-Just wanna talk?
- I see you missed that bus
I figured I'd stay
I know Nasty He's good
at what he does
You angling for him
this whole time?
No After you kicked me,
I had to survive
Told Nasty I'd help him
get Smooth's girls
So it's all my fault, huh?
Thanks for helping make me queen
Enjoy your kingdom
That's 20 bucks
I mean, I'm through the door,
and all I see is a black blur flying by me
- You're gettin' slow
All I know is the rapist asshole
got a double dip of vanilla and chocolate
Hey,Julien,you walking out?
Not yet
All right
I'll see you tomorrow
I mean,you really knocked
the wind out ofhim.
We got back here--
he's still out ofbreath.
- Congrats, man
- Thank you, man
Thank you, buddy
Oh, thank you, buddy
Mmm
- Hey, man, where's Vic?
- Don't know, man
- I'm gonna step outside for a second
- Okay
- Bye
- But it was a lot cleaner
Hey, Wayne, the beer's
inside, buddy
- Hey!
- Thank you
- You know where Vic is, man?
No clue
Is this the foster home
for Brian Reisler?
Yeah Is there a--
Is there a problem?
- Can I see him?
- Sure
What's going on?
He wants to see Brian
- How is he?
- What do you mean?
Is he talking yet? Making
friends? What's he like to do?
He plays with the other children
How many foster children
you have here?
Five
Five hundred a head That's--
That's 2,500 you're pulling in a month
Where's it all going?
You're saying we're skimping?
They get what they need
Three hots and a cot?
You bank the rest?
What do you know
about raising kids?
- They're better offhere
than they were out there.
- How do you know that?
His mother was a crack whore
- I knew her
- Then you know what I'm talking about.
At least we're there for them
I'm gonna be checking in
on him from time to time
I better like what I see