- Daddy.
- Okay, honey. Okay.
It's okay. I'm here.
Let me see.
Oh, my God!
What happened?
I was in the bathroom,
and they had some soup on the stove
Matthew got ahold of
some cooking spray and--
- Where is he?
- My mom took him and Megan
He didn't know
what he was doing
Uh, hey Uh, listen
- Thanks for all your help
- Close call.
If your wife hadn't grabbed
that fire extinguisher
- this whole place could have burnt up
- Uh-huh
Yeah, you know what?
I, uh--
I left the stove on too high,
and the grease just went whoosh
Why don't you get some stuff together?
You and the kids are coming to my place
- Vic
- You can't stay here
Help your mom pack up, please
Listen, I, uh-- I think we both know
that this wasn't a grease fire
- Yeah. I just need to determine
if it was set intentionally.
- It wasn't.
I have a young boy
who has developmental problems
His mom is worried sick about him
He was just playing where he shouldn't be
He's only seven years old
I'm sure I can write
this up as an accident
I appreciate it
Thank your boys for me, okay?
Oh, uh
You ever need a favor
Hey, hear you're talking now
You're that new nurse here for my
sponge bath, right?
We lost you to the twilight zone
there for a few weeks, man
Doctor says you can
start rehab pretty soon
I'll be back riding
with you guys in a minute
Everybody misses you
You remember much?
The last thing I can see is
getting into it with Shane
You remember that?
I just remember
fighting with him
We got our first good hit
off the AGC surveillance
We've been monitoring the bugs
and cameras planted in four cars
Mainly just blunts and blow jobs
But, uh, some pretty good prelim intel
Chiefs been asking why we've sunk a ton into
this sting and haven't come up with anything.
Well, this ought to cure
his blue balls Check it out
What's up?
All right
Here's half the money
You're gonna get the rest after
After tomorrow night,
you guys will be long gone.
Hey, man
The Horde's good for it
That's Jantell Davis He's a player
with the Spookstreet Souljahs
Jesse Ventura here
is with The Horde.
The biker gang?
- What are the Aryans doing with
a black banger in Farmington?
- It's no Rainbow Coalition
Horde rolls into town to do a job
They grease the natives
Nobody's feathers get ruffled
Deal was probably
brokered in the joint
- What's the job?
- Uh, we don't know what the target is
Just that it's going down tonight,
and Jantell's providing getaway and layoff cars.
-The Horde's got a pretty violent history
-Yeah, no joke
They dropped two bank guards
last week in Sacramento
- So this is all we have?
- At the moment
So how do we find out the when and where
without exposing to them and the other marks
that we're bugging
A.G.C. 's cars?
It's gonna be a balancing act
- Someone miss the drive-through?
- Came up stolen
We were in pursuit
Driver tried to take a shortcut
- How bad?
- He dove out of the way just in time
Driver fled on foot,
and we lost him.
- Owners They been open less than a week
- I'll talk to them
Did you see the man
who was driving the car?
Scotch
- No tax sticker
- That's a lot of stolen booze
Yeah, 30-year-old booze
This stuff is worth
like 1 20 a fifth
- I'm a light beer man myself.
- This is single malt
- You don't know what you're missing
- You could school me sometime
No insurance. It'll come out of their pocket
if we don't find the guy who did this.
Yeah, well, even if we catch our rabbit,
I doubt he could cover these damages
- Who we looking for?
- Bootlegger
I thought we were gonna keep
this operation under wraps
This AGC sting could
go on for months, a year even
I'm gonna be moving on
Claudette's gonna be moving in
Might as well get her
up to speed now.
Jantell made a call after the meet
to a cloned cell phone
Reported in he got half
the payoff, 1 0 G's
It's gotta be something big
for the Horde to drop 20 grand.
Armored car schedules for today, plus personnel
info for banks and check-cashing joints
Do you want me
to alert these places?
No, let's do our homework first before
we get these people all worked up
We're also clamping down on Spookstreet
We'll bust one of their bangers on something
sweat him until he gives us this heist--
that'll keep AGC in the clear
If you need anything from this end,
run it through Claudette
Let's not make this
a contest, okay?
You work together.
You, uh-- You running
the Strike Team again?
Aceveda's just
keeping me in the loop
- Yeah? And?
- I'm in the loop
Yeah I've got my own things too
I'm very hush-hush
Tavon's up and talking
You spoke to him?
- He's groggy, but he's making sense
- Sweet
- Really?
- What did he say to you?
The good news is
he's recovering
The bad news is he remembers
getting in a fight with Shane
before Mara clocked him
over the head with an iron.
What?
- Tavon told you that?
- No, Vic did
- But Tavon remembers everything up to that
- Wait a minute.
- What happened?
- Shane put Tavon in the hospital
and then lied to us about it
- He came into my home.
- Yeah?
- He threw down first
- Why didn't you tell us instead
of making up some bullshit?
It was my call not to tell you guys, not
Shane's. I was just trying to protect the team.
- You think this is still a team?
- I'd do the same goddamn thing
for you or Ronnie.
- You know what? You won't need to with me
- There's dirt on your hands
Look, we can toss around blame,
or we can fix it
If this thing gets hung on Shane,
we're all gonna be under the microscope.
If they look hard enough,
they'll find our money train cash
- So what do we do about Tavon?
- He's only gonna remember more, not less.
Goddamn it
Shit
Jantell and his boys are hopping today.
Look, all the crap
we've been through lately
Trust me, we're a team.
Wejust gotta get through this.
We never should've
taken that money
God
- Hey, take a walk
- You take a walk We're on the eye here
Walon? What the hell
are you doing here?
- You're gonna tip these assholes off
- Me?
Why don't you just paint ''Five-O''
on the side of the van?
You're sitting on the Spookstreet crew?
What for?
What do you you care?
You're compromising everyone.
Trish is in the store.
Annie over there.
- You're stepping on our case
- We were here first
- Get lost
- You get lost!
Aw,Jesus Christ
Ripped by:
Hound
- A little tight in here, isn't it?
- Why you sitting on Spookstreet?
We're gathering intel on some goober named
Durwin He's making kid-on-kid sex tapes
That's pretty vile,
even for them.
Durwin's running this on the side.
Rest of the gang seems to be in the dark.
- Where does he get the kids?
- He's got a social worker in his pocket
Most of her caseloads
are crack moms
She inserts herself into their
lives, gets to know them
and after a while she offers it
as a way to earn
- Lovely
- We're putting things together
We should be rounding everybody
up by the end of the week
We don't have till
the end of the week
We gotta bring your banger in now
- What for?
- To corroborate a tip
- We can't say
For reasons I'd like to share,
but I can't
So I show you mine,
but you don't show me yours?
Just like when I had your team
streaking through this place.
- You think this is funny?
- We need to fold your case into ours
- We're not even assigned to Farmington
- I've spoken to your captain.
We need to grab your porn guy now.
I'll decoy as a social worker...
Trish as the crack mom.
As soon as the money's exchanged,
we can use the guy for our thing.
Whoa, slow down You go in,
the real social worker walks
She's arranging for kids
to 69 each other, for Christ's sake.
Look, I don't like the wicked witch flying
away scot-free any more than you do
But believe me,
our thing is real
I'm not working for her again
You're already inside.
I'll just be helping
any way I can
Fine
- Hello
- Hey Ready for your seminar?
Yeah, I just got my schedule
You're still driving down, right?
You kidding me? How could I miss
''Groundwater impact on decomposition rate''?
Maybe you'd be
more interested in
''Rewards used to help motivate a dog
to perform special tasks''
- Hi
I got us adjoining rooms.
Ocean view.
And yours is under the name
Jackson Benjamin
Ah, imaginative
Should I wear a disguise?
You laugh, but a lot of my colleagues are
going to be there, and they know Hunter
Relax I don't plan on
leaving the room much
- Neil O'Brien's missing?
- That's right Looks like
the Armenians paid him a visit
-Jesus Are you sure it wasn't just an angry maid?
- Turkish cigarettes
You can only get these
in Little Armenia
I thought your people had
O'Brien under surveillance 2 4-7
Last night someone logged into
our system with security clearance
from an agent who retired
five months ago
He pulled surveil off O'Brien
So are we thinking
he was snatched?
Unless he smelled
trouble and ducked out somehow
There's no blood.
Car's not in the garage.
In any case, the Armenians
have someone inside Treasury
Half the ROC is former KGB
with deep US ties
The Armenians work with the Russians
They got vodka buddies in very high places
- How do we handle this?
- It's been your case from the start.
Until I find this leak,
it's best if it stays local
I'll let you know
if I find anything on my end
Bring in Vic He's dealt with
the Armenians more than anyone
As a resource, right?
I'm still running this
Yes, Dutch
You're in charge
Okay, Durwin Gethers
Grew up in South Gate
In and out of custody
since he was 1 6
Anything else I need
to know about this guy?
Hey, I'm just a crack ho today.
I can't tell you how long it's been
since I've been undercover
Back in those days, there were hardly any
women on the job, let alone a black one
Those bad guys
never saw me coming
You'll be fine
Just like riding a bike
I've been a social worker
for 1 5 years
Hated it for the last 1 0
My ex-husband
gambled away our savings
so I earn on the side
from the crackheads...
who I can't help anyway
even if I wanted to
And you've been one of my cases
for the last 1 0 months
You'll be fine
If I could take back
what you went through
- You can't
- I'd take it on myself
We're cops.
Shit happens.
- Is everything all right?
- No I, uh--
Hunter was mugged
He's hurt
- Is he at the hospital?
- He's at home
- Are the police there?
- No, he called me
He didn't report it?
What happened?
I'm going home to find out, but,
uh, I have to cancel San Diego
I gotta go I'll call you
Hey,Julien
That wagon was jacked
from a school two blocks away
Customs reported 1 1 cases
of Glencallan scotch
stolen from a freight container
in San Pedro last week
Yeah, but there were only
seven in the wagon.
- That means there's still four unaccounted for
- Hey
- You guys busy?
- A little What's up?
- Uh, I got a mugging incident needs checking out
- What happened?
This guy got injured,
but he didn't report it
If you guys got an opening, maybe you
can go over, see what happened
- Who's the victim?
- Uh
Boyfriend of Lauren Riley
She's, uh, the dog handler, helped us
with the meth lab case She's a friend
- We can try
- All right Here's the address Thanks
Sure
Vic, our main suspect in the Armenian
money train robbery, Neil O'Brien
just disappeared
from his apartment
- Huh?
- We alerted airport security.
Posted unis at bus
and train stations.
- Any help you could provide
- Oh, if the Armenian Might got to him
- he won't be walking out of town
- I talked to his landlord
Neil has a taste
for Mexican hookers
What is it about Irish guys
and Latin tail?
Aceveda said I could
use your team
Well, I sort of got my hands full
with this other thing
- Which is what, by the way?
- Uh
Can't talk about it,
but nice try.
In any case, the captain's
pulling you off it...
to see if you can help
with anything on O'Brien
I'll canvass his neighbors, check the bar
where he said he ''found''the marked money.
All right I'll check out the dick dolls,
see what the street knows
Anything you find,
run it by me?
- Sure, Dutch-boy
- You have a problem with that?
Let's connect after you
get back from the Smogjumper.
- Talk to you later
- Yeah
- All right So what's up?
- We got a problem
That Irish hump we dropped the money off on's
gone missing The Armenians are on his tail
-Jesus. How'd they find out about him?
- There's a leak in Treasury
- If they get him, they'll kill him.
- They can't trace him to us
If O'Brien's dead, the feds will plant
themselves here, keep digging
If he's a fugitive, they'll keep busy
until his case collects dust
What about the fact
that the guy's innocent?
That guy's an asshole with a rap sheet
as long as your sad little face
- What, Tavon wasn't enough for you? Huh?
-Jesus Christ! Cut the shit
Look, you don't want this thing to
blow up, you better keep your head
Lem's right We dropped the money off
on O'Brien to divert the feds
- not to set him up for an Armenian hit
- What are we supposed to do now?
Get to him before
the feet choppers do
Get his ass
on a Greyhound to Akron
There's no Armenian
power base there
God.
Get your ass in the van Start checking
the screw shacks in Byz Lats turf
We'll talk to Diagur, see if any of his
girlfriends are spreading for a gringo
- Yeah
- Go
Diagur
- Who'd you lose, man?
- My cousin Aramis in Chino, man.
Some Armenian chopped off his fingers,
and then he stabbed him in the neck
- You know why?
- No, man We ain't got no beef with no Armenians
- You think it's about the marked
cash the feds found on us?
- Could be
The Armenians got a guy inside Treasury
feeding them intel about the marked bills
Man, those cats do
some sick shit to people
This guy's number one on their most
wanted list His name's Neil O'Brien
We think he's behind the robbery.
I got to find him, prove it...
stop the Armenians from finding
the next pair of size tens
- What do you need then?
- He's a gambler He likes to hit cheap Mexican ass
If he's in the hood,
believe me, we'll find him
He hangs at Smogjumpers Have one
of your boys camp out on a stool there
Call us ifhe shows.
You're lucky
we needed a favor, Felicia
because throwing your ass
in prison was my first choice
I understand
You wave,
keep your mouth shut
- What's up?
- Durwin, you and me need to talk some business
- Who the hell are you?
- Felicia's supervisor
I don't know no Felicia
Who's that?
I'm also her business partner.
We split everything fifty-fifty
You paid her $ 1,200 last week for that
little movie star she hooked you up with.
Can I come in?
So what's this business
you tryin' to speak on?
- Felicia shorted me 300
- How's that my problem?
It's not
Just as long as we can deal
directly with each other from now on
All right, whatever
I just need to find me those two little
honeys she been lookin' into
- Tell me what you need
- It's like I told Felicia
They need to be dark-skinned,
no older than 1 1 , and ready to freak
I got two girls, eight and 1 0
- How much?
- Two thousand Mama's gotta get 500 off the top
These little breezies
gonna do whatever I say?
- 'Cause they gonna be gettin' into some hard shit
- It's no problem
Just tell me when you need them
I didn't file a report.
Why are you--
I mentioned it to a couple
of people at the station
- Where were you attacked?
- In the parking lot of my restaurant
He's a sous-chef
at Le Malpeste
I was going to my car,
and I got jumped
They-They wanted my money.
They? More than one?
- Three, I think.
- Did you get a look at them?
- No.
- Were there any weapons?
- No, they went for my watch
That's when I started swinging
- Hunter
Situations like this, it's usually best
to give them what they're after.
You gave me this watch
I wasn't just gonna let them take it
He came in a couple times a week...
- watch the game, place a few bets
- Who'd he bet with?
I promise I'm not out to hassle anybody for
making book I just need to find him
He's in danger
The bookie's name is, uh--
Damn He's got like
a dog's name Sparky?
Scout? Something like that.
I think he owns a furniture store,
upholstery place around here
- Faces I know, names--
- Okay.
If O'Brien or the bookie
come in, give me a call
Hey, any other cops come in,
meet with or ask about O'Brien?
Mackey? Shaved head,
redneck partner?
Don't think so
Okay.
All right, man I hear you
Thanks for the heads-up
Diagur found O'Brien in a motel
He's with a brown patch
- Let's go then.
- He also said that Dutch is looking into us.
Dutch? Why?
I slipped up
Mentioned the name of the bar,
Smogjumpers, to him
- Dutch knows I shouldn't know about that place.
- Dutch is looking into us.
Dutch would look into his own mother
if he thought he could catch a case
He's got nothing.
Let's just get O'Brien out of town.
I can't do this alone
-Señorita.
- Tome.
Come on, get up
- Hey
- Wash your hands
- What?
You just took a piss, man.
Wash your hands.
What? That's disgusting
- There's a lot of people
looking for you.
- Looking to kill me
I came home last night, saw those
Armenian freaks turning over my place
You gonna put me
in protective custody?
Not exactly Sit down
All right, look.
We're with Special Teams.
There's a leak in Treasury and our department
That's how the Armenians found you
Holy shit
The fact of the matter is there's not
a safe place we can offer you in this state.
- I got no dough to split
- What about the money
you took from the Armenians?
- I didn't do that
- Right
- What about the money you
found in front of Smogjumpers?
- Feds froze most of it
That's what I get for putting it
in a goddamn bank
The other 1 6 grand
I lost on a sure thing
- Smart
- I got three large on the Lakers tonight
- I make that, I can move
- You listen to the game
while you drive out of town
My guy Rex already has my bet
Look, we'll front you
the travel money
The Lakers come through, we'll make
sure Rex wires you the winnings
- Where am I supposed to go?
- Akron.
Where's that?
Where the kids at?
With my baby daddy
They'll be here in a minute
Where my money at?
When I see the kids
- Okay That's a nice touch
- Real nice
That's them over there
Eight hundred for the both of them
The deal was five.
- Man.
- Which one's the youngest?
Tayquanna.
She the one on the left.
She ever suck a dick before?
I had a boyfriend They got
'bout it a couple times
- Hey, Vic Followed up on that mugging for you
- Oh.
Things didn't really add up. Although
the girlfriend's buying the story.
She's fawning all over that guy
like he's some superhero
Well, they've been
together for a while
- It's probably complicated
- Or not.
Some women just have
a thing for assholes
- Any luck finding O'Brien?
- Uh, not yet
Hey, a while back
you asked me to keep Vic out
of the loop with the Armenians
Why was that?
He was working
on a quota mandate
I didn't want to distract him
with anything gang related Why?
-Just, you know, being nosy
- Sir, I need to talk to you.
- Is he being cooperative?
- Sir.
- Very
- Okay.
- Sir, they just found a body
behind Manzana Groceria
- The feet are missing
- Okay
Cigarette burns
You think Diagur bitched us out
to the Armenians?
He didn't know
we were involved
He knew we were looking
for O'Brien
And that we kept asking
about the marked money
Diagur Leyva
Ran the Byz Lats
Any luck with the hookers?
Me and my boys got laid,
but no O'Brien
Listen, uh, I gotta ask you
How is it you knew the name of the bar
when I didn't mention it
or you didn't read the report?
I-I saw O'Brien's rap sheet
Knew he'd been picked up on a bunch of
gambling stings, liked Mexican hookers
There's only one place in town
you can do both and be white
- Right Smogjumpers
- Right
You find anything there?
No
I think you're gonna be very
happy with the final product
- Good
- That's my babies
- A'ight Let's let the nasty begin
- You gonna let 'em in?
- Not till I get paid, black.
- Mama gotta get low
Look, I'm gonna
give you half now
half when we finish
I'm gonna let your homegirl hold
the cheese for safekeeping
- Police.
- Stay down
- You're under arrest
- Come on Hell, no
- Hell, yeah
Okay Let Mommy
put the lid on first
- Matthew's not helping
- Matthew, put the, uh--
put the napkins on the table
like I told you
- He just threw the napkins on the floor
- Hello. Hey, sweetheart.
- How does chicken, roasted
potatoes and salad sound?
- Perfect.
- Did you get ice cream?
- Oh.Just chocolate and strawberry.
Hey, little man.
Come here,you.
Come here, little man.
Let me give you a kiss.
- And one for you
- Cassidy, finish setting the table, okay
- Matthew
- Okay, okay Let me help you
Take the napkin just like this
Remember how I showed you?
How long will we be
staying here?
Well, uh, we'll see
The kitchen still needs fixing.
There's gonna be painters in the house...
if you want to change
the color of your room
Hey, that's it
That's the stuff, little man
Very good.
Now you gotta put
the silverware on top of it. Okay?
- Ah, there she is
- You here on business or pleasure?
Always pleasure to see you.
McCoy Tyner at the Blues Project.
- That's a sold-out show These tickets are hot
- Sizzling
No, stolen
Come on Would I take you to
a show with jacked tickets?
You're a fence.
Isn't that what you do?
Come on, blue. I've been waiting
for like an hour to see you.
- Did I say you could come in?
- Okay, why you gotta step on
a brother's goodwill like that?
- Come on, Taylor I'm busy
- Look We got a lot of paperwork
'cause some idiot crashed
while running stolen merch.
Did somebody say ''stolen''?
Did I hear ''stolen''?
Huh, huh?
How can I help?
Okay, we're looking for a guy
who's selling stolen scotch Glencallan
I don't know a lot of
hoodjoints that's pouring 3.0.
However, there are a couple of
possibilities that we can investigate
- We?
- Yeah, look I need a police escort
All right, I got a contractor coming over to
the house tomorrow to work up an estimate
I need to know what it's really gonna cost,
so the insurance people don't try to lowball us
Thanks for tonight
It was nice
What if one of the kids got hurt?
That aerosol can could've
blown up in Matthew's face.
We've got the new therapist
starting this week, but you need--
I need to what? Matthew doesn't
even think he did anything wrong
- How am I supposed to reason with him?
- Somehow
I can't spend every second with him
You can't take him
What are we supposed to do,
put him in a home?
You're serious
No I don't know
We are not gonna put him away
- I don't want to
- Then don't bring it up again
Megan has a shot at a normal life.
Is this fair to her?
Of course not But that doesn't mean
we commit our son
I am doing everything I can
Well, then I'm gonna
have to step in
Maybe you got me on an obscenity beef,
or maybe you don't
'Cause the constitution says
that titty
coochie and ''bedunkadunk''
is erotic expression
- So that shit is protected
- You're a pedophile, Durwin
I don't have to tell you what the life expectancy
is on the inside when you mess with kids
Someone has a chance to take out
a ''shorteyes''and doesn't, catches a shank...
in the back themselves.
Those mamas didn't have no problem
with their kids getting dirty.
Let's see how you get dirty in prison.
You ever suck a dick?
You cooperate,
and maybe we can file on you
in a way that keeps you
from getting your throat cut
Now, Spookstreet's got
its fingers in a lot of pies
What's happening with your boys?
Usual shit.
Can't help you unless
you got something unusual.
There's Primo
He just got out of the pen and he passing
around bad checks to get his pockets tight
- If he could've given us anything else
- don't you think he would've by now?
- He's a foot soldier
We just swapped a social worker who tricks out
kids for a guy passing bad checks That sucks
Let's see if this check kiter, Primo,
is any more plugged in than he is.
All right, but do it fast
Captain. I just got a call from
the bartender at Smogjumpers.
He says the bookie
was in the bar collecting bets
Apparently he needed the cash
to cover a large payout to O'Brien.
- O'Brien's still alive
- The bookie owns a furniture shop
nearby I'm tracking him
Ask Vic
I'm sure he knows
all the bookmakers.
I'll do that
- Everything all right?
- Yeah.
I'm really sorry about this weekend
I was looking forward to it
The week you're going out of town this guy
gets mugged by three guys he can't identify
and he manages
to fight them off?
I bet you didn't know you were
shacked up with the man of steel
- You sent those officers over to see if he was lying
- He is lying
- He faked getting attacked
- Why is that such a stretch?
- Because it's pathological
- So is saying that he'll slit his throat
if you leave him
- I mean, are you ever gonna end it with this guy?
- It's not that easy
- It's not
Hey, Vic.
Just a minute
Did you find the bookie
Dutch was looking for?
- I'm sorry What?
- O'Brien's collecting on a bet
Dutch is trying to track down the bookie
He was gonna check with you
We must have missed each other
- Who won the Laker game?
- LA, by six
Hey The bookie, Rex,
where's his shop?
- Flores
- Let's go
- What's up?
- O'Brien stayed in town to collect his winnings
- Oh, what an asshole
- Dutch-boy's onto him We gotta get to him first
- You ready?
- Yeah
- Captain okay your extracurricular police work?
No OT, but he said
he's buying the first round
Hey, why are you still here?
They couldn't leave until they boarded up
their café I told them I'd stick around
- Any luck finding the driver?
- No, not so far
All right, man
Where are we going?
There's only four joints
that serve top-shelf scotch
And one of them,
the Bling Bling Room...
this hole hasn't served a legal shot
since the day it opened
- Okay, let's party
- Okay.
- Detective Wyms, can I ask you about something?
- What?
This couple back here trying to ID
the guy who ran into their café
I heard about them
What do you need?
Well, Dutch said you were dating
a guy who's a contractor
Their café needs
a lot of work, new windows.
So I was wondering if your boyfriend might
be able to get the materials wholesale
- That would help them out a lot
- I'll ask around
Glad to see you're
making the effort
No effort, really
They're good people
Rex?
- Oh, shit! No feet.
- Oh, man
Shit Goddamn it
- Hey, Vic! Vic!
- Vic!
- Oh, for Christ's sake
- It's O'Brien
They burned him
and dumped him in turpentine
Jesus. How long
do you think they tortured him?
He couldn't tell them anything if he didn't even
know what he was doing in the middle of this
- Goddamn it! Shit!
- Listen, listen to me
Dutch could be here any minute.
We gotta make
O'Brien disappear
- What?
- He's gotta stay a fugitive
Ifhe's dead, Dutch, Treasury--
they'll turn over every rock.
Eventually, we'll be under one of them
He's their prime suspect!
Ifhe's alive and missing,
he stays that way.
All right All right
So h-how do we get rid of him?
- We need something close, simple
- Okay, uh--
- Goddamn it.
- What?
I-I know where to do it
- So, Primo, you're fresh out
- Ten days
Long enough to get
the prison smell off of me
- What you been up to?
- Getting my drink on
my poke on, keepin' it G'd up
from the feet up
- Passing bad checks again?
- No, dog I paid my debt
That is a major
probation violation
You had three and a half years left on
your sentence when you got paroled, right?
Time to pay in full
I was just trying to get me
some ends, so I can start fresh
In an election year, there's
zero tolerance for serial offenders.
But, you know, this check
is yours to rip up
if you give us something to make us
look good to our bosses
In the joint, I heard about
this credit card ring
Federal beef Guy in a suit
will get all the love
I got a line on this ese cat
flippin' hot Sprewells
Give me something sexier My mom
wants to see my picture in the paper
I know a ring of''T'' girls out on
Santa Monica be rolling their johns
Johns got it coming.
Nice try, Primo.
Sorry, we can't do business
Hold on. Hold on.
What if I told you the Horde's
pulling a job tonight?
The Horde is in town?
Ronnie, make sure
his feet aren't in there.
- Shit
- I got it
Oh, shit
They're not here
They must have taken them
as trophies Let's go
Let's get him
in the couch Quick
One, two, three
- Okay,you ready?
- Yeah.
- All right
-
Primo gave it up The Horde's going
after the LA Motor Club on Treadwell
Holiday weekend, they're
probably flush with cash
- Make sure the place is empty
Set up a perimeter
- I'm on it
The Horde's involved? They
can get pretty violent, right?
- I'm seeing if SWAT's available.
- Why don't you pull in the Strike Team too?
Aren't they working
O'Brien with you?
They haven't been able to turn up this
bookie either I'm working my own lead
They're all yours
- Heads up, heads up
Okay, hold it Hold it
Yeah
When?
Okay, we'll be there
in 1 0 minutes
That robbery's going down
Aceveda wants us at the takedown
- What, now?
- Yeah
Okay Park the van
in front of your place
People are used to seeing it They know it
belongs to a cop No one will screw with it
- Yeah, okay
- Okay We'll grab the gear
pick you up at your place
on the way to the takedown
We'll drop the body off late tonight
when things quiet down Let's go
All right
Let's do it
- That was quick.
- Yeah, Mr Bling Bling was very cooperative
when we discovered only two bottles
behind his bar that weren't stolen
When I'm right,
I'm all right
I told him we wouldn't
look into his supply room
if he gave up the name of the guy
who sold him the scotch
We'll pick him up
- Four inside. Driver's still in the van.
- Hold until they come out.
- Roger that.
No idea that they're about
to go tojail for a long time.
If it's our turn someday,
you think we'll see it coming?
It's time we turned our cash
over to the real estate guy
- Stop worrying about it.
- Yeah
I'll get it in motion
- They're coming out.
Everybody move.
- Welcome to Hollywood, asshole
- Lay down right now, right now
- Get your weapons down!
Get on your knees right now!
- Drop it!
Put your weapons on the ground!
Put your hands on your head!
- Drop it!
- Hands on your head!
Down on your knees!
- Go! Down on your knees!
- On your knees, now!
- Hands on your head!
- You right there, drop the gun!
You, goddamn it,
put your hands up!
- Drop it!
- Get down right now!
They'll assume
Spookstreet gave them up.
So the AGC operation wasn't compromised,
keeps a dozen big cases viable Excellent work
I'm just part of the team
We're headin' out
- Thanks for the help
- Would've liked that social worker, but--
We'll stay on her, make sure she's
out of business You have my word
- Not a bad bust
- Not bad at all
Like riding a bicycle, huh?
A little stiff,
but at least I didn't fall off.
- Of course you didn't
- See you
This isn'tjust Margos
calling the shots. He's in town.
He's got a thing for feet,
and he's taking them off himself
- They get O'Brien?
- Luck of the Irish He slipped away again
The Armenian Might's
out of control.
I don't know who amped up these psychos,
but killing Diagur, this guy
They ain't stopping
till they get their money back
You think you can do something?
I make them, this Margos creep,
my number one priority
You give me the word
to hit back hard...
I'll unravel them foot by foot
I'll get Phillips
to sign off on it
You know how hard those people worked to
build that restaurant that you crashed into?
You need to loosen up, homes
Pretty soon, we're gonna
have to deputize you.
So, uh, tell the truth, blue. You had
fun clubbin'with me, didn't you?
That was business
Okay, better than
getting shot at
Okay, so what do you say
next time we do it for real?
All right I see where it is
You have my number,
if you change your mind
Might fool Dutch and the feds,
but the Armenians know the truth