Vic! Come on, dude!
- Tell me you're leaving!
- That which doesn't kill me...
Come on! Come on! Let go!
Vic!
Hi.
David Aceveda.
Vote for me. Appreciate it.
Hi. David Aceveda.
Vote for me.
That's an arm.
Went to Armadillo's place
to talk to him about Tio's murder.
- What'd he say?
- He wasn't there.
Signs of a struggle though.
Bloodstains, seared flesh on the stove.
- Pretty ugly stuff.
- That sounds like Armadillo's M.O.
Checked Tio's phone records.
You were the last call he made
last night on his cell before he died.
Yeah. He sounded kind of agitated.
- We got cut off.
- Too bad.
What are you asking me?
Look, I don't like these questions
any more than you do.
I was with my guys all last night
while Tio was being killed.
Feel free to ask 'em.
Okay, then.
Single blow, a heavy blade.
- An ax, maybe a machete.
- How long ago?
Based on core temp,
I'd say recently.
- Three to four hours.
- So she's been dead since around 6:00.
Didn't say she was dead.
Skin lividity and clotting...
indicate she was alive
when this happened.
- Sadomasochistic torture ritual.
- Okay.
If someone were trying to keep her
alive, how long could she survive?
With a tourniquet and basic
medical knowledge, indefinitely.
Until he tired of his domination and
control Dr. Mengele experiments...
and decided to squeeze the last breath
out of her so he could watch.
See, this is why you and me can't date.
Run these prints.
Get me an I.D. Now.
I spoke to Shane.
He said you weren't with him
for about an hour last night.
Yeah. That's right.
I was with a private eye
named, uh, Gordie Liman.
- What's he got to do with Tio and Armadillo?
- Nothing.
It's a private matter.
I'd rather it stay that way.
I'm happy to help you
if you're helping me.
- Are you?
- I have been.
But I'm just about through.
I guess I'll have to
figure this out on my own.
What the hell was that all about?
Nothing.
Why didn't you just
leave it here and call 911?
- This dog was sniffing around it.
- So?
It's a bone.
The arm probably fell out of the
Dumpster when the truck picked it up.
Call city services. Remand the truck.
Have some unis search it.
The rest of her might still be
in that truck. Alive, even.
Lowe, did we I.D.
the fingerprints yet?
- There's a backlog.
- Backlog? I cant find her if I can't I.D. her.
Give me that. Have your guys
do door knocks. Talk to every neighbor.
Tell everyone if they find anything,
give me a call.
This is Detective Wagenbach.
I told you I needed
a rush on those prints.
We don't know she's dead.
She could still be alive.
And if she is, I'd hate to see
your backlog cost her her life.
- You told Claudette I was gone for an hour?
- You were gone for an hour.
Jesus! She's all over my ass
about this Tio connection.
She said she'd talk to you.
I figured the truth was the safest bet.
- Now it looks like I'm lying to her.
- You are lying to her.
- What, are you trying to be a wiseass?
- No, I'm just...
Just shut the hell up!
- Christ!
- Where are we headed?
I got things to do. I gave you guys
to Aceveda for the day.
- What?
- Apparently, a group of male hustlers...
is hangin' out on the same block
as Aceveda's campaign headquarters.
He's setting up a sting operation.
I volunteered you guys.
- You can't be serious.
- Your shirt's gay enough for the job.
- What do you mean
you gave us to Aceveda? What...
Great. I've got your assignments.
Briefing room, five minutes.
Is everything okay with Kayla?
When was the last time
you saw your roommate?
- Last night around 6:00.
- She didn't come home all night?
I don't know.
I slept at my boyfriend's.
Any idea where she might have gone?
There's two million single men in L.A.
Take your pick.
We found her car in the garage, but not her
purse or keys. Is there someone close?
Somewhere she
might have walked to?
Wait a minute.
Is Kayla dead?
We have every reason to believe
that she's still alive.
'Cause I don't wanna be a bitch...
but our rent's due next week.
- Vic. I got great news.
- What?
Just be glad you hired me and not
the brain-dead idiot your wife did.
Jerk off privately.
What do you got?
Corrine's P.I., they're making
nonsecure calls from his cell phone.
I caught one.
Found where she's at.
- Beauty. You got the address?
- Yeah, sure.
- Oh, geez.
- Corrine... Don't run away.
Just hear me out
for two seconds.
Look, this running has to stop.
How much time
could you possibly need?
This isn't about me, Vic. It's about
our kids, about them being safe.
Do you honestly think
I'd put my children in danger?
Not intentionally,
but the things going on in your life...
Something told me to run.
School's back in session.
Matthew needs to be at Glenridge.
He needs his routine.
Cassidy needs to see her friends.
This isn't gonna
change things between us.
Don't punish them
because of me.
I'll move out if I have to,
if that's what it takes.
But I need to know that they're
at home where they can be safe.
I don't... I don't know, okay?
I'll think about it.
Hey, how'd your meeting
with I.A.D. go last night?
Good. Good.
You ran out of here so quick.
They told me not
to discuss it with anyone.
But it went fine.
Anything yet?
- Hi. I'm Detective Wagenbach.
- All right. Just a second.
- Bob, the police are here.
- Police? Open it.
I saw you all coming in.
What's going on?
I'm investigating
your neighbor's disappearance.
You hear or see anything
suspicious last night?
- Which neighbor?
- Kayla LeSeur.
Oh, man. We heard her arguing
last night out on the balcony.
Yeah, around midnight. I saw her
through the window with a guy.
- You recognize him?
- Yeah. Marcy had me come take a look.
I've seen him around a few times.
Come down, give a description?
Uh, sure. Let me
just grab my jacket.
Great.
- Alvarez?
- All right. Let's take Union.
Hey, how's my favorite hillbilly?
Joe, what in the hell
you doin' here?
I'm here to meet
the big guy for lunch.
- Hey, you still crackin' skulls?
- Yeah, man. How's retirement?
- I'm shavin' a few strokes off my golf game.
- You look good.
- You I don't know.
- Ronnie Gardocki.
Joe Clarke. Taught your boss
everything he knows.
Yeah, but you didn't teach me
everything you know, right?
That's right.
I'm saving some.
- We're gonna grab a bite. Wanna go?
- They're busy.
When I miss tee time at Riviera
for this, you better be buying.
Riviera? Since when do they let
hacks like you play at Riviera?
You guys still here?
Come on!
Hey, who was that with Vic?
- Joe Clarke, his old partner.
- They kicked him off the force.
- Why is that?
- Some punk took a swing at his last partner.
Joe knocked out like half
of his teeth in front of this crowd.
Total railroad job.
Don't worry. It's nothing like
what you're going through.
So it's been a year
since you called me up.
You drag my ass down here.
What's going on?
Can't I buy you lunch?
Vic, come on.
It's, uh...
been a pretty rough ride lately...
Enough I'm thinking about
gettin' off the train.
You wanna give up your badge?
I'm lookin' for a sign.
Seen any around?
You don't wanna give it up.
- Retirement's been pretty good to you.
- A forced retirement.
Believe me. I still miss it.
We can hit the links
together every day.
What's bothering you now?
When, uh...
When we were ridin'...
you ever feel like
you went too far?
Yeah. Couple times, maybe.
Probably.
Definitely.
Hell, you can't always
land just right.
Goin' too far will get you fired. Not
goin' far enough will get you killed.
I never lost any sleep
over it though.
Anyway, we always did
more good than bad, right?
Right.
That's the key.
- Yeah. That's him, all right.
- Yeah.
- Good.
- Anything else we can do?
She was such a nice girl.
She still is.
Roommate I.D.'d the photo
as a Jordan Arnold.
Run the D.M.V.
Get me an address now.
We're running out of time.
Snitch's Tavern.
Your first arrest.
That guy had to be 6'6" easy.
- Still, that bust was when I knew.
- Knew?
That maybe you wouldn't be
a complete screwup after all.
- Take a right up here.
I wanna show you something.
- No, I can't.
I gotta get back to the barn.
I got some stuff I gotta check up.
Bullshit. This is your
training officer, all right?
Take the afternoon off. Humor an old man.
Take a right. Come on.
All right.
Yes?
I've got a problem
on this Tio murder.
What's that?
The more I look into it,
the more Vic Mackey's name pops up.
Well, Tio was Vic's C.I.
He was also a drug dealer.
Vic's name is all over
his phone records.
But Vic told me he hadn't
talked to him in months.
- He lied.
- Well, what do you wanna do about it?
I went through Tio's place.
I found his business ledger detailing
payments made to a landlord.
I wanna check them against Vic's
cash deposits in his bank accounts.
I need your authorization.
Claudette, Vic's one of us.
I got a dead drug dealer.
I got a suspect who's
probably skipped town...
and the only person who
can shed some light on it...
is an uncooperative cop
with a bad rep.
You want me to let this case
just slip away, son?
I.A.D. on Danny's shooting.
Draw up the authorization form.
I'll take a look at it.
Everything looking good
for my officer?
- Getting all the cooperation you need?
- Pardon?
'Cause if anybody's giving you
any interference, I can help.
Ah. Thanks.
Claudette, witness brought in
a freshly amputated arm.
I'm thinking sadomasochist,
probably keeping her alive.
- I've got a suspect named Jordan Arnold.
- Let me help you with that.
Thanks. I can use a sounding board.
Know who lives there?
Cocksucker who cost me my job.
- Fleetwood.
- Yeah.
City paid off the lawsuit: 1.2 mil.
He moved back
just a couple months ago.
- Son of a bitch.
- Hey.
How'd you like to help me do some good,
serve up a little karmic justice?
- Joe...
- Hey, 20 bucks says we bust him
on a felony before nightfall.
These assholes could win a lottery
and still not keep their noses clean.
See that little prick?
He got one over on me, man.
- You know that ain't right.
- Yes, I know it's not right.
- Then here we go.
- Lookee here!
- Jesus Christ.
- Bitch that made me rich!
You thought it'd be fun to beat on me
like a punk nigga now, huh?
- Who's the nigga now?
- Hey! Step back!
Yeah. Here. Go get yourself
some new gear on me.
Go back to your party, burn out
whatever brain cells you got left.
Come on, bitch. Hit me!
I could use another couple million.
- Put the camera down.
- Come on. Show's just startin'.
Hey, let go of him!
Let go!
- Back off!
- That's all right. I'll just buy me a new one.
Hey, what's this?
That's a Palm. Keep it.
Got ten more on order.
Why don't you
crawl on back to your crib?
Hey, you need a beer,
keg's always on tap.
Yeah. This ain't right.
What's the verdict?
Well, other than a few hiccups,
it's looking good.
What hiccups?
According to Julien's statement,
he didn't see the shooting.
What do you mean?
He was right there!
He says he was
in the woman's apartment.
But I wouldn't
worry about it though.
It's gonna be a good shoot.
- Dutch.
- Jordan's alibi checked out.
I ran a records check on
everyone in Kayla's building.
- Any hits?
- Two: A woman passing bad checks
and a Bob Lindhoff.
Bob Lindhoff?
I just had him down here.
Nine years ago, an attempted
kidnapping charge, later dropped.
She's coming to again. Get in the car.
Hey! Hey, I tried to call,
but there was no answer.
We went out to grab a bite to eat.
What's up?
I've got a suspect down at the station
I was hoping you could I.D.
You mind coming back?
- Uh, is it really necessary?
- Yeah, do you mind?
- No, not at all.
- Great. Follow me.
Hey. Fleetwood's been checkin' in
with his parole officer...
doin' community service
and scrubbin' graffiti.
Sumbitch is totally clean. You?
I ran some of the names
he had in his Palm Pilot.
He had four two-strikers
in his address book.
You need a new C.I.?
- Doesn't everyone?
- I'm gonna hit the head.
Then we can go do
some arm twistin', huh?
- Vic, we need to talk.
- What's up?
Claudette's got Tio's ledger.
He was supposed to burn that.
Well, apparently,
Armadillo burned him first.
Claudette wants to run
your financials against Tio's records.
Fine. Let her.
- You sure?
- Trust me. She's not gonna find anything.
- What's Joe Clarke doing here?
- You know Joe?
I remember his picture
in the papers. He can't be here.
Hey, he's a friend of mine.
And he's also an embarrassment
to this department.
So unless he's here
to report a crime...
I can't allow him
in this building.
I don't know.
Makes you think.
Vic says the guy was
a real crackerjack cop.
Somebody like him can get booted,
man, none of us are safe.
Come on. The guy's old.
Probably lost his edge.
- Nothing's gonna happen to us.
- How are you so sure?
Because we're careful.
Because Joe got sloppy and stupid.
Stupid, huh?
- Vic, I...
- What's stupid is Joe's
twice the cop you'll ever be.
You're too sloppy
to even know it.
- Here we go again.
- I guess so.
You know, I'm gettin'
a little tired of this bullshit.
I'm gettin' tired of constantly having
to clean up after your bullshit!
Every time something goes to shit in
your life, I become your whipping boy.
Why don't you find someone else?
- Maybe that's exactly what I'll do.
- You want my transfer request?
Say the word, Vic! It'll be on Aceveda's
desk first thing in the morning!
- Fine. Write it up.
- Fine!
Asshole.
- What'd you call me?
- Hey, hey! Everything all right?
Yeah. Just a little spring cleaning.
Let's ride.
I thought this was about
I.D.'ing somebody.
Actually, we're more interested
in the kidnapping charge...
that was filed
against you in 1993.
That was a misunderstanding.
- You were 35 at the time, right?
- Correct.
- And your girlfriend was in high school?
- She was 18.
And you took her away on vacation for
two weeks and never told her parents.
I know. In hindsight,
it was just a bad judgment call.
But Amanda was an adult.
You're 17 years older
than Marcy too.
You like 'em young, Bob?
Yeah. They just...
feel right.
Did Kayla feel right?
I wouldn't know.
- I know how you feel.
- Excuse me?
What'd your partner do?
He's not backing me up
on the shooting.
- If that guy costs me a promotion...
- He's not backing you up?
- After all I've covered for him.
- You covered for him?
- What did he do?
- Nothin'.
Hey, it's cool.
You can tell me.
No. It doesn't matter.
I gotta get back.
Seeing the way you stiffed your partner,
I figure you're just one big hard-on today.
- Excuse me?
- You know what
an officer-involved shooting means?
It means that we're all involved.
- I told the truth.
- When it comes to your partner's career...
the truth is like grits.
You don't serve it up plain.
You put a little salt on it.
You goddamn rookies.
$20 apiece.
I'll let 'em both go for 35.
That's real... That's like chiffon.
And this look good with your eyes.
And this is silk right here.
This will look real good with...
Drop the clothes, ladies.
Although, you have got to have that one.
- She's keeping that one for free.
- Wait... Whoa!
- I got receipts for all this, man!
- Oh, yeah? That's funny.
I got a police report for it
from Dress For Less.
Dealin' stolen merchandise,
Taylor.
That's your third strike...
before you're 25 years old.
That makes you the goddamn
rookie of the year.
I got a little baby at home.
She need milk and books, man.
Only thing you got at home...
is a wide-screen TV
you haven't paid for yet!
- Ow!
- Here's your statement. Sign it.
Whoa, man. What the hell is this, man?
This is all filled out.
You don't wanna sign? I'll throw you in
County right now on that third strike.
And if I sign this
bullshit confession?
Play ball with us,
we'll let you play extra innings.
We know you've been selling
stolen goods to Fleetwood Walker.
Give us a hand, we'll lose this
statement. We'll forget we ever saw you.
Man!
Oh, my God.
Why would someone
do this to her?
Most likely trying to fill
a twisted sadomasochistic fantasy.
Why would someone fantasize
about cutting a woman's arm off?
Some people derive
sexual pleasure...
through inflicting
physical, emotional abuse.
That's horrible.
Yes, it is.
How old were you
when you met Bob?
- Is he your first boyfriend?
- How did you know?
He made you
feel powerful, right?
Did he tell you about the attempted
kidnapping charges filed against him?
Yes. Why?
Bob went to medical school
for two years.
So?
So...
So if a woman had her arm cut off,
he'd know how to keep her alive.
Oh, God, no.
No. I swear to you.
Bob didn't do anything like that.
What'd we get back on the river basins
and the state parks check?
Nothing. We're still waiting
for regional and county.
Call 'em back.
Don't wait on 'em.
Bob's cold, manipulative. Always been
with women he could control.
Marcy accepts this
'cause she knows no better.
She's been force-fed his opinions to the
point she's incapable of having her own.
Sounds like a surface diagnosis to me.
Believe me, if you'd grown up
in my family for 20 years...
you'd recognize it
right away too.
I'm gonna, uh,
go it on my own on this.
Marcy only knows how to
take orders from men like Bob.
I-I can handle this.
Bob is innocent.
I understand.
You're afraid of him.
- I'm not afraid of him.
- It's okay.
I can protect you, but only
if you tell me what he's doing.
- He's not doing anything.
- Don't lie to me, Marcy!
- I'm not lying!
- Yes, you are!
Bob tells you how to think,
how to feel, how to act.
- Without him, you're worthless. Nothing.
- It's not like that!
And you won't leave him because you're
afraid no one else will ever love you...
that you'll learn Bob
was right about you all along.
- No!
- Oh, damn it, Marcy!
- Don't lie to me!
- Why are you doing this?
Because there's a girl out there
who may still be alive...
and I won't let you kill her!
Now, goddamn it!
Tell me right now! Where is she?
I don't know!
Really! I don't!
I played the daddy.
I broke her.
If she knew Bob was involved,
she would've confessed...
or at least given me
a nondenial.
- You think?
- I don't know.
Maybe Bob's not
a sadomasochistic thrill killer.
Maybe he's just an asshole.
Problem is, he's the only
asshole we've got.
- Well, what do you got for me?
- What you got for me?
Come on.
Embrace the relationship.
Fleetwood is fencin' again.
He's so goddamn predictable.
- What's he movin'?
- Just, you know, warehouse electronics, man.
CDs, TVs, DVDs.
Same stuff as before.
Where's he keeping his stash?
Are you gonna hold this third strike
over me for the rest of my life?
I could lie to you, but I have far too
much respect for you as a person.
Yes, I am.
Here is your authorization to check
Mackey's financial records.
Thanks.
Hope we don't find anything.
I just hope
you find the truth.
Hey, Joe. It's Vic.
Can you believe
I walked out on them?
When they left,
I thought it'd be easier.
I thought they'd miss me more than I'd
miss them. Guess I'm the shithead, huh?
- Stacy still on the swim team?
- Yeah, I think so. Yeah.
Yeah, she, uh...
Damn it!
I didn't want you
to see me like this.
- Broke, with nothing.
- What about your pension?
Damn lawyers for
the civil suit ate it up.
- What about the stuff
you took on the side?
- I guess I didn't take enough.
Always so careful.
Never wanted to get caught.
- Joe, you can't live like this.
- Oh, sure I can.
The truth is, the people we save
from the worst day of their lives...
never gotta see us
when we have to face ours.
Hell, and why should they?
We took the job, not them.
- No, that's not right.
- What you gonna do, man?
I'll tell you
what we're gonna do.
- Fleetwood's got a warehouse
full of stolen merch.
- No.
I say we nail him.
Sell half the stash to my new C.I.
- We get you some new digs.
- I can't let you do that, all right?
Hey, I'm just... I'm just
trying to do some good.
You know, and deliver
some karmic justice.
Now are you in,
or are you out?
Easy. Don't suck
on his tailpipe.
One second.
- Yeah.
- It's me.
- Where are you?
- Home.
- What, our home?
- Yeah. The keys still work.
- Are the kids with you?
- Yeah. We're all here.
Oh, thank you.
- This doesn't change things.
- I know.
- When can I see them?
- Now?
I got to finish up somethin' first.
I'll be right there.
- Okay.
Looks like he's making a deposit.
Yeah, you gotta love good intel.
Stay here.
Watch my back.
This is for my boy down the street.
Fully automatic. You know
what I get for those on the street?
Drop it! Drop it! Drop it!
Fingers interlaced!
Palms on the back
of your head. Now, asshole!
Come on, man! Let's move! Let's move!
- Vic!
- Stay back!
- Vic! You been hit?
- I'm all right. Get out of here.
- I'm gonna kill that son of a bitch.
- Just get out of here.
- No, no, I'm not ditching you, man.
- You're not ditching me.
I can't explain
you being here to Aceveda.
Now, go! Just call an ambulance
and call my family!
I'm gonna kill
that sumbitch!
No. No. Don't.
Goddamn it!
Christ. I hate playing this with you.
This game's sucking.
- You could stop.
- Shut up.
It's Vic.
Hey, what's up, boss?
Jesus Christ.
Are you okay?
- What?
- Vic got shot.
- Can we leave?
- Shouldn't be much longer.
Oh, please.
Don't walk out on me again.
Just please don't leave me alone.
Look, um...
I believe you.
Maybe Bob did this
without you knowing.
I was with him all night.
If I thought he did this,
I would tell you. I would.
I know you would.
- Who did this to you?
- Fleetwood.
That prick that got Joe
kicked off the force?
Yeah. Joe's goin' after him.
You gotta stop him.
Okay.
- Come on, guys. We're losing blood.
- Just hang in there.
- Gotta go.
Detective Wyms,
Carlson just called.
There's a homeless guy with a bloody
machete saying he killed somebody.
- Where?
- Just south of Bell on Vine.
That's a block from Kayla's apartment.
Where's Dutch?
I don't know. Maybe he's checking
in on Vic. Have you heard anything?
Not yet. Find Dutch.
Tell him to meet me there.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
They got the guy?
- Sir, put the knife down, please.
- I'll kill again!
- Drop your weapon!
- I killed them all!
J.F.K., R.F.K., M.L.K.
- Carlson, got bean bags?
- Locked and loaded.
Run D.M.C.!
That's the guy?
He's a nut.
- I was told he had a bloody machete.
- I called in a kitchen knife.
- Oh, for Christ's sakes.
- I was told to call if I found anything.
End this!
Come on.
- Oh, my God!
- Just a bean bag, ma'am.
- Let's get back to Bob and Marcy.
- I released them.
- You what?
- I thought we had the guy here.
Bob didn't do it.
Marcy would've told me.
Stay still for me, sir. That's it.
- I'm his boss. How is he?
- He's gonna live, but we need him in surgery.
- Not until I see my kids.
- Vic, don't be stupid.
They're on their way here.
They're gonna be here any second.
- Vic.
- Where are they?
- They're in the waiting room.
- I gotta see 'em.
- I won't let you. Not like this.
- Corrine...
- I don't want them to be scared.
- They won't be.
Vic.
Daddy!
- Hi.
- Daddy.
I missed you so much.
Kiss.
Hey, Matty.
Give Daddy a kiss.
Hey, Vic, I really
need you in here now.
- Dad, don't go again.
- Oh, honey, I'm sorry. I have to.
Listen, someone was
hurt really bad...
and I have to stay here
until he feels better.
But as soon as I can, I'm gonna come
and see you again, okay? I promise.
I love you.
- Where is he?
- Who?
Fleetwood. You're packing his goddamn
suitcase. Now, where is he?
- I forget.
- Where's your boyfriend at?
- I don't even hear you.
- He just shot my partner.
- Hey, where is he? Where is he?
- What are you gonna do, hit me?
- I don't see any witnesses here.
- Yeah? Let my bruises do the talking.
Don't make me do something
that we both don't want me to do.
- Yeah? Go ahead.
- Just tell me where he is!
Please. Just tell me where he is.
Go ahead and whack me, you cracker
prick. I'll make my own million.
- Is that what you want?
- Mm-hmm.
- Is that what you really want?
- Mmm.
- All right, let's go. Let's go.
- What? What are you...
- Come here!
- No! Let go of me!
- Leave me alone!
- Open up!
What's goin'on in there?
Shane, come on!
You and me, we're about to get real
acquainted if you don't start remembering.
- Don't touch me!
- Where is he?
- Open up!
- Let go of me!
You don't wanna tell me?
- Damn it! Open the door!
- Just let go of me!
Well, maybe I should just let my dick
do the talking. How about that, huh?
- Huh?
- Open the goddamn door!
- Shane, come on!
- Where is he? Where is he?
Okay!
He told me to meet him
at the stash house.
- Where?
- Open up! Come on!
Near the bridge.
Come on!
You're freaking me out!
You have no idea
what you just missed, darlin'.
- Come on!
- Asshole!
Couldn't split town before you
picked up the merchandise, huh?
You were always
such an idiot, Fleetwood.
Weren't you?
- You can't arrest me.
- I'm not here to arrest you, asshole.
- Drop it! Put that on the ground!
- You heard him, asshole!
Now! Turn around!
Turn around!
Your girlfriend gave you up, man.
She couldn't resist my charms.
- You found something?
- Yeah. Over here.
While I was checking
the bathroom, this tile fell off.
It looks directly into
Kayla's bathroom.
Oh, God. Oh, God. We got
to get an A.P.B. out on their car.
Jesus.
- You okay?
- Better than you.
Looks like I taught you
my last lesson, huh?
Don't end up like me.
I shouldn't have
dragged you into this.
Going after that guy
was the right thing to do.
- Hell, I got you shot.
- I always knew there was
a bullet with my name on it.
And guess what?
I'm still here.
So are you.
Hey, you really ought
to get in there and see him.
Yeah. Me and Vic aren't
really talkin' right now.
He'd want to see you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Hey, what the hell
is going on?
We found the peephole, Bob.
- What are you talking about?
This is ridiculous.
- Step away!
- It's clean.
- Pop it.
She's dead.
She didn't like the way
I looked at Kayla.
And the arm was her idea.
She was in the trunk...
the whole time?
Marcy, why didn't you tell me?
Marcy.
Sorry, Daddy.
Oh, Shane.
- Hey.
- When we retire...
we're gonna play golf
together every day.
I never played golf.
I'll teach you.
I'd really like that.