Wheelchair to Admitting.
- Cop's on the second floor
- I'm on it. I'm on it.
- Five-seven. Short hair--
- Christ!
- Are you okay?
- You didn't have to come
- What happened?
- I was patching up this Asian guy
and I saw he had
a gunshot wound to the arm.
When I went to call it in,
he freaked out.
- Damn it
- Nothing's broken. I'll be okay.
I got all the details.
- Any gang tats?
- NoJust track marks
He's either on something
or off his meds
I told you this place was a zoo
Come on I'll take you home
I can get a ride
Uh no lectures I promise
- He's still working with Matt?
- Not now
- What happened?
- I'm okay
Some guy just went off
at the hospital
-Jesus!
- Calm down
- You're gonna get Matt all worked up.
- Matt can handle big feelings
- You an expert on my son?
- Yes, I am
- Vic
- Mommy
Mommy had an accident,
and I'll be okay
Cassidy, get your homework out.
I'll help you in a minute.
- I can handle things here
- Because you're an expert
on my whole family now?
No--
You should come down to the Barn,
look at the mug books
Wha-- Is that a good idea?
I mean, he knows where you work
What's to stop him from coming
back and hurting you again?
I'm what's stopping him
She picks him out
I find him, make sure he knows
going back isn't an option
It's not worth it
I mean,just leave it alone
You know I wouldn't ask you
to do this if I didn't think it was safe
I'll call you
We'll figure it out
- Fine You let me know
- Mm
- Sir, Aurora's on the phone
- Tell her I'm in a meeting
Are you? Because
I don't like lying to people
I'm in a meeting
Whatever you say
Oh, there they are!
- We heard dudes fighting or somethin'
- Yeah?
Saw the gate
Merril always locks it
- You guys did good calling us
- Thanks
Hey, hey, hey Wait here
Wait here, all right?
- I'll go right
- All right I'll flank left
No Danny!
Ripped by:
Hound
This is MerrilJindrich
Runs the community center
Says the name of the victim
is KleeJones Local kid
- Banger?
- Kid had no ink
No gang tags anywhere
He painted this He's got
others around the neighborhood
- It's beautiful stuff
- I always wondered who the artist was
Maybe we could get the Strike Team and
the Decoy Squad to help us run down leads
We don't know if it's
gang or drug related
I want to give Walon
some more cooling off time
Right now, all we have is a homicide
This boy wasn't just murdered
He was lynched You better
know there's a difference
I know
You two can handle it
- How's the stomach?
Ah-- Doc's got me on scrips
Listen I can understand you not wanting
to say anything in front of the others
- But if you took our missing
cash for any reason
- Vic.
I promise we'll make it all right
Look I didn't take it
Okay I just had to ask
Well, you know what, man?
Ask someone else
Where's your mom and dad?
Dead Me and Klee
pretty much raised each other
You know of anyone who
would want to hurt your brother?
People barely notice him
He's so quiet
Everybody loved his paintings
- We saw They're amazing
Ask Gitana I bet she's
got somethin' to do with this
- Who's that?
- This Mexicali girl Klee hooked up with
Her ex-boyfriend, all his friends
are straight-up gangsters
Los Profetas.
Klee was different Not all
about getting at my ass and tits
We'd talk about stuff--
art, love, you know, life shit
Just made me realize,you know,
I could do better for myself.
- Better than Neron?
- We understand your ex-boyfriend
was a member of Los Profetas.
Neron's a Cristo boy
- Didn't work out, huh?
- He wanted me to go to church and shit.
Meanwhile, he's
on the street thuggin'
Klee's sister thinks your gang affiliations
might have to do with Klee's death
A lot of the gangs was pissed
about him painting over their tags
Maybe Neron got jealous--
you dating a black guy
I'm fine, but I ain't killin' fine
I gotta ask you something
I counted right the first time
I counted right the last time
And I didn't take the money
Lem said you asked
You ask Shane yet?
Sir, I have Aurora.
No I have her here
Any leads on the lynching?
Claudette and Dutch are on it
Anyone in custody?
Just witnesses Why?
People are terrified
The black leadership's convening a rally
at the Hope Center You need to go
It's a crime scene, not a photo op
This isn't for the cameras You have to tell
them that you have everyone protected
- You make it sound like I'm checked out
- The last thing we need
is for a dark horse black
candidate to capitalize on this
run as an independent
Crazier things
have happened in this state
Well, I'm not worried
I've given you space
to get through whatever this is.
If you don't want to tell me what
the problem is, I'll find out another way
Sir, uh, you need to take this call
We heard some of the gangs were upset
because his murals covered their tags
He got some threats
Talk mostly
I think some of the gangs
actually dug his stuff
-Just wasn't cool to say so
- Now what?
Do I really want to know?
Father Zavala
Stabbed five times
Must have come out of the sacristy
Wounds are to the back and neck
- Any witnesses?
-Just the calling card
- One-niner payback for KleeJones
- Klee wasn't a banger.
- This is bigger than gang beefs
- He was a black boy hanging from a tree.
The One-niners must think
Los Profetas are responsible
Zavala was their spiritual counsel
Bring in the Strike Team. Track down
the Decoy Squad and use them too.
Now that we know it's gang related?
- Vic, we got trouble
- What's up?
That's the money train fed He was
asking me where Aceveda and Dutch are
- What does he want?
- Nothing we do
They told him to wait upstairs
Detective, your team's
needed right away
Any inside info on Los Profetas?
Killers with a conscience
Got their little piece of the street
- Usually keep to themselves
- It's biblical with these cats
Which means
eye-for-an-eye time
You cover the priest
Dutch and I will stay with the hanging
Hey, look In this hood,
black kid ends up dead
it's 'cause a deal went bad
and someone's pissed off
Guilty until proven white?
Yeah Maybe we should get
the ACLU to solve it
We'll look under our rocks
You look under yours
These guys can't hear
anything right now
Let's check out the Niners first
That's a good decision,
should take care of you guys.
What's up, Tob? What's this?
Bring Your Daddy To Work Day?
Community outreach
Neighborhood's in mourning
I see that
Take the Shriners outside
All right
Let's go, pops Let's go
- Let's talk
Give up the booth, Twizzy
Where's Kern at?
- I think he's in Prague
- Touring
19 Playaz, huh?
One-niners funding that tour?
- We're creative partners.
- Kern's put a lot of faith in you guys
I bet he's gonna be pretty disappointed
when he finds out you knifed a priest
Oh, you gonna be disappointed
when you find out we didn't
No? Then who wrote
''1 -9'' across his face?
He was tagged, asshole.
What kind of crew
are you runnin'here, Tob?
One hand don't know
who the other hand's stabbing?
Look If one of mine did it,
I'll find out
Make sure you give him
a medal for it
Look, man. People loved
that kid's murals, all right?
But I didn't order no hit
on no priest
At least now the Prophets know
what it's like to lose a local hero.
You wanna tell me why you were
breaking bread with the thugs?
Like he said,
community outreach
You went to them for protection?
Don't make me dig deeper.
You see that billboard?
Can you read it? I can't
Decade ago, this whole block
was black owned.
Now me, Perry--
all that's left
Latin gangs hit my liquor store
1 9 times in the past year.
You think paying out
to the One-niners isn't robbery?
Banger gets shot in a drive-by,
that's one thing.
You put on the colors,
you live and die the life
But that boy, the painter,
he was just trying to do good
You know, we got grandsons
coming up in this neighborhood
One-niners might be the only thing
keeping them away from the noose
If you wanna feel safe,
you come to me.
I heard that for the first time
40 years ago, after Watts
Been hearing it ever since
from you boys, every few years.
Los Profetas didn't rope that guy
Is that what the Niners think?
Is that why they killed Father Zavala?
Your ex-girlfriend
had nothing to do with it?
Gitana?
Gitana was just a hit,
like nothing real
You think going to confession
once a week exempts you from
being a shitbag lowlife, Neron?
KleeJones saw an ugly world,
tried to make it a little more beautiful.
He gave back
What did you give?
What's everybody gettin' so torn up about?
There's dudes gettin' dead every day
This dude was lynched
- I thought he was hung
- Lynching is being hung.
- You ever read a history book?
- I tried not to
Lynching's what they used
to terrorize the ex-slaves
That's how the Klan
dealt with race mixes
Well, if I'm gonna do somebody, I ain't gonna
waste time looking for no tree and a rope
when there's a million
guns lyin' around
David, you're gonna shut down
all their street trade and lock them up?
How are you gonna follow up
on that threat?
We got a rally in two hours,
and I don't want bloodshed
Using that guy as your errand boy
is a short-term fix
That's all we got time for
Now get him out of here,
so he can pass on the message
Look what crawled
out of the gutter
I thought you guys were neck-deep in
that homeless torching thing
Six days of undercover
setup gone to shit
- Why? What happened?
- Claudette brought us out
for this lynching.
Why? It's pure gangland
It's not a Decoy thing
Oh, I'm sure she's got a plan
Why the hell did you pull us off?
I want Trish and Annie
inside this community rally
You want my team pressin'a crowd?
We've had two homicides that
have created enough racial tension--
And three homeless dead, and a fourth one's
gonna be toast because you can't keep your--
- Stop that right there!
- Last week, you tanked a major case
and now you want to turn us
into mall security!
- It's bullshit
- I made a mistake.
I start digging into your jacket,
I won't find a few?
None that almost killed a cop.
If you can't find it within
yourself to work with me, fine.
You're docked
Catch up on paperwork
You signing off on this?
The job gets done when we trust
the decisions of our superiors
- If he's out, we're all out
- There's a chair!
There's six weeks of FI's to file
Mr Rabinowitz?
I thought you were a doctor
I've been waiting here 40 minutes
- You were mugged?
- Corman Street.
This man-- Hejumps from out of nowhere
with a pipe,yells, ''Give me your money!''
- And you did?
- Yes
And then he smashed my knee,
took my streimel
- He didn't have to hit you!
- What did I say?
When these things happen,
we must be strong
Can you, uh,
give us a description?
Asian. Black hair.
Had a bandage on his arm.
Bandage?
Our arrest percentages are down
30% since we've been here
- We never had this kind
of interference at Wilshire
- Yeah, it's not right.
We gotta get free again
This team is the assistant chief s baby
Phillips'll listen to me
I just need a witness
Look I don't want to be the one
responsible for letting you slip away
It'll all be off the record. Phillips just
needs to know that I'm not, uh, overreacting.
- He does that sometimes
- I can relate.
You can count me in as a witness
Hold on Hold on
You really want out?
Okay I'll back you up
But you gotta do the right thing.
I need Trish and Annie to work the rally.
My guys are the wrong
shade of black
- Hey, Vic, you got a sec?
- They're all yours
We just took a mugging call
at Mission Cross
- Sounds like the same guy who attacked your wife
- Any leads?
I'm tracking
the stolen credit cards.
- Let me know
- Okay
This guy hurt Corrine
He can't come in feeling good about that
What's the favor?
He turns up--before you
bring him in,you call me.
Okay
- Ready?
- You bet
We appreciate your support
and your concern Um--
Our purpose
for being here today
is notjust to talk about this
travesty thatjust happened...
but to create a forum...
for our awareness, answers--
- Stand over here.
- Now I'd like to turn over
the mic to Reverend Leeman
Would you all be kind enough
to join hands, please
Lord Jesus, we ask you to guide
our hearts and our minds.
Renew our faith, O Lord,
and open our eyes--
I hear you're responsible for having
Trish and Annie change their minds
Walon was way out of line
Thanks
No problem
...for your care is the prayer of God.
- What do you guys got?
- Not much conversation
but I spotted six
sporting One-nine ink
- Couple of baby bangers
- Four of them with unnatural bulges
Okay Point 'em out to my guys They'll be
the first ones we jump if this goes ugly
- Okay
- It's all stirred up, ain't it?
- Yeah
Hey, Vic!
Sorry, boys
Crusade's been canceled
Ain't no holy war, homes
Just come to listen
You're too smart for this, Suvuto You guys
get in your cars and bounce on out of here
Ladies and gentlemen,
please stay where you are
- Let the police officers do their job
- Captain Aceveda is right--
Hey, you got balls tryin' to come here
and break up our rally
They're not lookin' for a fight,
and neither are you!
NahJust lookin'
for a priest killer, homes
- Get against the fence!
- Get down!
- Anybody hurt?
Everyone clear this area now!
Leave or you will be arrested!
Clear the area now!
- Hey, what's up with that?
- You got a name for me?
- Yeah, I got a lot of names for you
- Keep that sense of humor
Man, why you lockin' me up, man?
We was there like anybody else
No one else was jamming clips
into semi-nines, asshole
What you talkin' about, man? It was the
thorn heads who came lookin' for blood and shit
Why don't you guys
talk through the fence
Maybe some racial harmony
will break out
What's up? What's up?
We found firecracker scraps
That's what incited the shootings
Pol Com and the archbishop
have riot fears
They're pressuring us
to bring in the FBI
Put the National Guard on standby
That's a bad move.
Sends a message we've lost control.
- Oh, so we haven't?
We'll solve these
Calm the waters
How much time
before the feds show up?
The chief wants me reporting in
from here the next 2 4 hours
That buys us some time.
Let's see where we are by then.
I sense some disharmony
between you and Tobar
- Kern keeps us civilized
- Kern's in Europe.
I should've gone to you first
Come to me about what?
I gave Tobar the chance to give up
the Niner who offed the priest
He blew it I'm making
you the same offer
Okay, where's my upside?
You give up the killer,
with some proof..
I'll get you your boys
out of lockup
let you do business rent-free
Come on, Mackey. Everybody knows
you've been shut down.
You're not on the street
enough to landlord
I'm getting the keys
to the city back
Spoke to Lem and Ronnie When are you
gonna ask me about the cash?
Don't have to None of us took it
None of us spent it
Trail won't lead back to us
Yeah, I believe
Lem and Ronnie too
But that seven grand didn't
just spontaneously combust
And now Aceveda's pulling his
marked money list from the safe
He's hooking the Treasury guy
up with Rodriguez
Nothing's gonna lead back to us
Okay But if those flagged bills have
anything to do with our missing cash
I'd sure like to know
who the hell's spending it
Rodriguez, I thought you were pulling
those like-crime stats for me.
Sorry Wagenbach's
working the hanging
I got stuck working
this Armenian mob thing
I'll be in the car
We'd better hurry
It's a long trip
Place closes at 4:00
- Where you headed?
- Some bank in Indio
- Where the hell's that?
- Palm Desert
- Sounds hot
How the hell did our cash
end up in the goddamn desert?
It's not from the 20 grand Diagur took
Those marked bills were all scooped up
What gang's running meth
through that part of the state?
I don't know Aceveda and the chief have had
us out of the loop the last few months
Street sweeps and dime-bag bust
quotas have let us lay low
Laying low has kept us in the dark.
We gotta get back to basics...
plug back into the street intel...
make ourselves indispensable
to the department again
Best defense is a good offense.
How are we gonna get Aceveda
and the chief to unleash us?
We won't have to
Walon's gonna do it for us
In the meantime, as long
as there's no paper trail
leading from the marked bills
in Indio to us, we're golden
Can you tell us how long
Klee was painting that mural?
About two weeks
Did you ever see anyone
harass him, complain about it?
- No
- You ever talk to him at all?
- He was right across the street for two weeks
You never spoke to him?
He didn't come in? Buy a soda?
Didn't pay the boy
that much attention
Not an art lover, huh?
Oh, his painting's good and all that
Just sends the wrong message
And what message is that, sir?
You know, in this neighborhood,
you gotta choose a side
I'm black That's my side
Should've been his side too, hmm?
Hey, Vic We pulled
a match from the books
Tung Yung?
I wish I felt like laughing
The other victim's in synagogue.
We're gonna need your wife
to make a positive ID
Okay Circulate this
There's a steak dinner in it for the first one
who gets me a face-to-face with this prick
The Squad is being wasted here.
Aceveda twisted the chief s
arm to get you guys
He's got us reporting to Wyms,
burying us in an extra layer of command
- It's not workin'
- I got my problems with Wyms too
But Aceveda threw her in the deep end
It's not her fault she's drowning
You want me to unplug you, I'm gonna need
a better argument than a personality clash
Providing for the homeless
is one of the mayor's pet projects, right?
Yeah
Might have a hard time
explaining to City Hall
why your crack Decoy Squad was
pulled off the homeless torching case
to file month-old robbery reports
- I'll need details
That's my case
- We were embedded six
goddamn days. Perfect cover--
- What?
- I figured out why Tobar was
flaking on giving up the knifer
- Why is that?
- It was his boy, Link
You'll find the blade
and the bloody wear at his crib
Good work
Next thing I know, me and my
team are ear-deep in Barn shit.
Hey, we got a break
Murder weapon
Blood-stained Yankee jacket
- It's a slam dunk
- Great
This job's still only half done
Where are we on the hanging?
Uh, well, all of the likely
suspects have come up clean
He doesn't circulate in the usual world
We're hitting dead ends
Decoy Squad hit a dead end too?
Father Zavala was killed by gang violence
That's the Strike Team
I know what
the Strike Team does
You have the Decoy Squad in your
house also Why not put them on this?
Because they were docked
for insubordination.
- You docked them?
- I did.
I'm trying to keep the lid
on a racial pressure cooker
- I know that
- You put an entire special unit
on a dead Latino priest
and docked the team that could
be solving the lynching of a black man?
- That's not the truth
- The truth is whatever it looks like
and this looks like racial
prioritizing, Councilman
Come on
- 'Bout time you let us outta here
-Just long enough to do this
Elias Linkletter, you're under arrest
for the murder of Father Oleos Zavala
- This is shit!
- No This is proof
Oh, Tob, man, I didn't kill him
I didn't kill no priest, Tob!
You can let this half go
Except for that one
Aiding and abetting
Hey, man, you hurt us,
you hurt Kern!
Kern's licking caviar
off a Czech whore's nipple
He won't be too hurt
I want you
to tell me what's wrong.
- Aurora, I--
- I went to Rigoberto Spoke to him
Whatever your secret is,
he's keeping it.
There's no secret
You tell your cousin
but not your wife?
A less secure woman might think
there's someone else
- Babe, I'm not screwing around
- You're hiding something.
- Please let this go
- What is it?
Act like a husband
- Please,just trust me
- Trust me!
Aurora!
I'm very scared, David
Hmm
Those guys I fought--
One of them assaulted me
But you're okay now
They tied my hands
and they made me get on my knees
They made you... suck?
- Both of them?
-Just one of them
You didn't.
Oh!
Wait You're a cop
You're trained in--
I-I was alone
I was in-- I was--
No, David
How-- How could you
let that happen?
Because I wanted to live
For you
I wanted to live
for you and Sophia
I can't talk about this here
I never saw that knife, and
I'd never be wearing no Yankee rag
I was born in Boston, man I'd rather
take a knife than wear an ''NY''
I'm not sure if I'd use the Red Sox
defense in a Dodger town
That was a horrible thing
they did to KleeJones.
Lynching a brother's some wrong shit
Maybe you wanted
to send them a message
make sure it didn't ever happen again
You got the right message
but the wrong messenger
No, we don't You stabbed Father Zavala
five times this morning
No!
This morning?
I was at my group
- Group?
- Anger therapy.
Kern's shrink Been learnin'
to keep my emotions in check
He's probably lying about the therapy
session At least when he got there
The parish raised bail for the Prophets.
One murder still unsolved, and now
all the players are back in action
Put Walon's team into the mix.
Let them spend the night on the street.
- You said you'd back me on that decision
-Just do it already!
Hey, whatever's been eating at you
lately, don't take it out on her
She's the main thing keeping
this place glued together
- That's enough, Dutch
- No You've got her juggling
a full detective load
plus this supervisory post, and
then you hang her out to dry
- That's not leadership
- How's your detective load, Wagenbach?
Anything new on the sick
bastard raping grandmothers?
No
Hey, Cobalt How's business?
We're looking for a friend of yours--
an Asian guy trying
to score painkillers
- Aren't we all?
- Mind if we take a look inside?
Mind letting me see a warrant?
That's okay
We'll just wait for him here
- Greet your customers
Who you lookin' for?
He was around.
Junkie tried to give me a ton
of Sudafed for a few dozen Percocet
- This is a cash-only slot
- Where'd you send him?
This Thai cat sells scrips
out of a clinic on Hanover.
Should be there in the morning
Thanks
His anger management alibi
checks out
He's got a shrink and eight fellow
hotheads who can account for his time
How did the knife and bloody sweatshirt
get in his place?
I'll follow up on that
I need a minute
- What is it?
- I bet on the wrong scumbag
- How did you do that?
- You and Wyms have had me buried with bullshit
- I'm outta touch
- Oh, what? So it's my fault?
- I'll bring in the right guy
- Good
But I'm never gonna
let this happen again
I'm no good half in, half out
You gotta make a choice
You either let me do what I do,
or I'll pull the plug on the Strike Team
Take my boys
to another part of town
Lose the hardware!
Lose it!
- Get on the table! Get on the table!
- On the table! Drop it!
- What the hell's goin' on, Mackey?
- Closing time
My first task as the new landlord:
get rid of the old tenants
This was not a part
of our transaction.
That deal went south the second
you screwed everyone else in this room
Screwed who? Oh, shit.
Seems you fingered a man
with an airtight alibi
- Pig's tryin' to turn us against each other, Tobar
- Shut up, bitch
I can see I'm in the way
What are you talkin' about?
You can't leave me with them
I can't take you with me
You're an innocent man
Unless you got somethin'
to confess, Twizzy
- I didn't do nothin'
- Okay. Take care.
Vic, where you--
All right! All right, Vic! All right!
How'd the knife and the Yankee rag
end up under Link's bed?
Not so sure if I remember
all the details now
Let me refresh you on the math
You framed number two,
which implicated number one
which bounced you from number
three to the new number one
And that gets you... zero.
All right, asshole Let's let Tobar
and Link finish the interrogation
Let's go clubbing
Hey, man, look what
we found at Twizzy's place
It's the same rope
Klee was hangin' from
Oh, shit
Shit Damn it
Ain't no one gonna
save your ass, Twizzy
That camera
hasn't worked in months
Now, you talk to us, or you can talk
to your boys between beatings
I strung him
You're damn right I did!
Someone's got to be
the martyr here
It might as well be me
Why?
'Cause that Rainbow Coalition
shit was crushin' us
Kern and Tobar caved on me.
They punked out.
Wanted to strike deals
with the Lats.
So you decided to set off
the racial bomb
The priest?
I wanted to see the Prophets cry
- Fuel the war
- Get the black back
Farmtown,Jack Uzis,
the local businessmen--
I got them all sitting down,
talkin' about working together
I did
Black-on-black lynching
Is that better or worse?
Worse
Hi What's up?
Open it
Locked
It's funny, you know
I never really lock my lockbox
Okay
The reason I never lock it
is because I can never remember
where I put the goddamn key
But somebody locked it.
I-I was looking
for some old photos
Some stuff I don't know
anything about your family I--
You know, I really know a lot
about your family
I called your mom in Indio.
She told me about the $7,000
care package that you sent
You'd disappear at night
I saw you take the key
a couple of times
So you decided
that you would steal from me?
I found a receipt
for a storage facility
with your handwriting
and a fake name
You've been lying to me.
What did you expect me to do?
Jesus Christ! You have no idea
what kind of trouble this is
You know what trouble
I've been going through?
- Why are you hiding money from me?
- You stole from me!
You stole from me!
That trunk was filled with cash!
I just took
what I needed! For us!
Us! What happened to us?
- You gonna lie to your child too?
- Hey, don't turn this around
My mother's a goddamn cancer
She was being evicted She would've
showed up on our doorstep
I didn't want her to ruin this.
You shouldn't have looked
into those trunks
Is there money in all those trunks?
- Is it drug money?
- You don't get to ask that question
- But it's from your job, right?
-Just stop asking
Should I ask Vic instead?
Is it Vic's money?
- Did you steal it from him?
- No
- Then where did it come from?
-Just forget that you saw it
How am I supposed to do that?
You just do it
- Hey
Look You don't take
any more cash
Don't breathe a word
about this to anybody
We gotta figure out what to have your mother
say in case people start asking her questions
Wh-- Who's gonna
ask her questions?
The money wasn't
supposed to be spent
When it comes to money,
we can't trust her
Then we're gonna have to find
a way to control her
Because if this money
gets traced back to me
this is life and death shit
For all of us
Is this the man who attacked you?
- Yeah, that's him
- Great.
The old Jew he mugged
has been in temple lockdown
Now we can finally
arrest this prick
I say something wrong?
I'm sorry Are you Jewish?
Someone keyed Owen's car
They scratched ''stay away''
across the trunk
- You think I did it?
- It had to have been done
last night before I left here
If I wanted you to stay away,
I wouldn't scratch it in your little Volvo
- What? You'd scratch it across my face?
- What are you tellin' this guy?
Nothin'that I can't see for myself.
- You keep your mouth shut in front of my kids!
- Don't yell at him!
Stop it! I wrote it.
- Cassidy.
- I'll do it
I don't want him here
Owen makes your mommy
happy, honey
Why can't you make Mommy happy?
I'd be hurt if I were you too
I will always be your dad
and your mommy'll
always be your mommy
That's never gonna change
Everything is changing
Yes?
The Decoy Squad's being
transferred to South Central
- When?
- Tomorrow
- Who--
- It was the assistant chiefs call.
I didn't fight it
It wasn't gonna work
We can still get done what
we need to with the Strike Team
Vic and his guys are going back
to full-time anti-gang and vice status
You're putting them back on the street
I'm no longer running the team
I had no time to consult with you.
It all went down pretty quickly
You, uh-- You'll resume
your regular detective rotation.
So strike one and I'm out
It was my fault
I had you half in, half out
- I should've just let--
- You're the boss
You don't have to explain
your decision
Charges against your boys
have been dropped
I heard
You also hear that
we know who did it?
Tell Los Profetas
no more retribution
That's God's decision
God's decided to put me
back in business
My streets, my rules
- Niners ain't playin' by the rules
- Twizzy was a rogue
Kern, Tobar-- never
would've let that happen
We still got pain
Twizzy will be in County
till his hearing.
That'll give you a few weeks
to get someone inside
stop the pain
Anything after that--
commit any sins--
I'll be nailing you to a cross
Thank God you caught the guy
Yeah People are relieved
The election should be
smooth sailing
Good
I just came home to change
Okay
He's early
- Tung Yung?
Stay down!
What's the target?
Blue house Russians
Fresh from the Kremlin
Movin' in Movin' weight
China white
I got some bad news, Boris
The air just tastes better
today, doesn't it?
Yeah
Vic, I, uh--
What?
It's good to be back
- Where do you want him?
- Put him in two
Knock, knock
- On the ground right now!
- Down! Now!
Welcome to the neighborhood