Here's our enforcer. Right on time.
Lem's snitch wasn't bullshittin'us.
- We waitin'till the money changes hands?
Or till he hits 'im. Let's go.
Strike Team's
back in business, asshole.
- Where is he?
In the back! He's goin'out the back!
I got him! Get the car!
He's in the house
Let's go
- Hey! Hands up Hands in the air
- Hands in the air.
On the ground!
- I'm a cop!
- Shots!
Don't move!
- Shit, man Are you all right?
- Shit!
- Bitch
- Get up!
Hey, man I swear I didn't know
he was a cop He said it too late
- Here's so you won't forget
- You like takin' shots at cops, huh?
What do I look like now,
you prick?
You didn't look like no cop!
That's good.
That's good
That's good!
- Great news
- Our cuddler rapist wants to talk.
- I thought he was refusing to be interviewed
- Apparently, a week and a half
in solitary
made him very lonely
I sent him a note with the DNA evidence
tying him to two of the bodies
He knows the jig is up; he probably
wants to brag about his exploits
- Good. What about the wife?
- She still won't talk.
- We don't know what she knew
- She seems harmless
We'll find out
for sure tomorrow
We rarely talk to someone
who's taken a shot at us
Usually it's the next of kin
Look, man I swear I didn't know
you guys was cops
Look I see white boys bust in my house,
man, instincts kick in
- What's your name, shithead?
- Trick
We heard about someone shakin'
down store owners We catch this
guy handing out a beat-down
Why's he running to your house?
He workin' for you?
Nah It's the everyday stuff
Macy's open up
a drug prescription department?
- Check this shit out, man
Percocet, Oxy, Valium
Looks like thejackrabbit
led us to Dr. Feelgood.
- What you run here for, Luddy?
- So you two are on a first-name basis
- Vic, a car is pullin' up
- Who is it?
- Let's get out of here Finish it
Hey, hey, hey, hey! It's gotta be
my runner picking up that delivery
This just keeps
gettin' better and better
I'm gonna open the door
Play it cool You try to jet,
I'm gonna sic him on you
It's one of my mules
Ronnie
This mule may be strapped, so be careful.
Freeze!
Ripped by:
Hound
The girl next door says
you got quite the racket goin'
Dealin' illegal pharmaceuticals
on top of tryin' to kill me?
You can get the bends
goin' down in shit that deep
Look, man I'd never shoot
a cop It was an accident
- You got about 50 years coming to figure it out!
- I'll make it up to you, okay?
Give you everything
Look. I ain't the one distributing.
It's my boss, Lewis
Lewis Sperling, man He owns AGC
- Custom car outfit?
- Yeah, man.
- He runs the scrips, man
I recruit the runners for him
- From where? The PTA?
Hey No one ever got pulled over
for driving while being a soccer mom
So what? Dealin' to the burbs doesn't
get you time off an attempted cop killing!
Dealin' is a small thing that helps
with this big thing, man-- washin' money
- Who's got the dirty laundry?
- Bangers, gambling outfits
captains of industry, man--
who knows?
Lewis takes your dirty cash,
puts it in A.G.C....
calls you a solid partner
and cuts you a share of the profits
Yeah,yeah. Hey, look. You make sure a D.A.
don't come after me for cop shootin..
I'll get you in
- Sounds interesting
- This asshole tried to kill me
He didn't know we were cops
Meanwhile, you got him so scared
we're gettin' a tip
we'd never get another way
I won't work with him
Aren't you supposed to be
riding shotgun with Mara's mom
preppin' her for
the big phone call tomorrow?
- Yeah
- Then you focus on that
Make sure it goes right
What's the problem? Do you want me
to lose my Realtor's license?
I don't like this Lying to the US Government,
with the Homeland ''Securities'' and all?
Uh-uh
Ma, this is important
If they find out that I failed to
report this bonus, I could be in serious trouble
- How serious?
- Look, Stella
If there's one thing the government
does right, it's collect taxes.
I hate askin' you to do this-- we both do--
but it'll cost us, kill our careers
I mean, even if we had to split the rest
of the bonus with you--
- How much is that? Few grand?
- Yeah Yeah Three or four
I'll do it for Mara
- Mrs Faulks
- You're bringing in my husband, isn't that right?
- He's agreed to make a statement
- I need to talk to him first
- That's not possible
- Why not?
- You can make arrangements
to visit him at CountyJail
- You don't think I've tried?
I've already tried He won't
see me He won't talk to me
You have an innocent
and scared man in prison
- His DNA matched semen
recovered from the victims
- I've heard about DNA labs
in Los Angeles,
and that means nothing
- If you'd agree to an interview with me--
- Why? So you can frame me?
- So I can clear you of any involvement
- In rapes and murders?
- When's a good time for us to speak?
- I need to talk to him first
- I need to talk to you
- Well, I already said no
Then there's not much reason
for you to be here Buzz me
Gimme some money
I know you got some
Pasty-ass bitch-ass!
I'll be rulin' with an iron rod
as the vessels of a potter
shall be broken to shards
Just take it.
Hey! Drop the pipe!
- Where's the black man's justice?
- Turn around. Turn around.
Put your hands
behind your head Let's go
Verily I say unto you,
be holy, for I am holy
Ain't no half-steppin'
Take a bath lately?
- Let's go.
- I see you been blinkin'at me.
Blink, blink, blink, blink, blink
This will be recorded in writing
and turned over to a directorate,
and then we'll see who's laughing
- Get in
Investors in the AGC
custom car outfit
Colón runs the Farmtown Mijos.
Del Rubio owns a piece of the racetrack
And AGC is the clearinghouse
for all their dirty profits?
Them and who knows what other bad guys
Their drug running just helps 'em clean the cash
Without hard evidence, we can't
target people for owning part of a business
If we can sting this Lewis Sperling
on a drug distribution
we'll get him to roll
on everybody else
You net the octopus,
follow the tentacles, get the ink
- What do you need?
- Well, Lewis interviews all the mules personally
and since we lost the Decoy Squad,
I'm gonna need a female to meet him
- I was thinkin' Sofer
- Danny?
- She's never gone under
-She can fit the bill. And if
this Trick doesn't pop up soon...
Lewis is gonna get suspicious
I don't like cutting a deal
with some prick who fired on an officer
Me either
But if this breaks right
it'll be the biggest case
you and me'll ever see
It'll set crime in Farmington
back 20 years
Okay Send her in
Let me tell you somethin', black
The only difference between you and me
is I was baptized in dirty water
- Yeah.
- Priors for vagrancy.
In and out of psych wards.
- We should turn this guy over
to MEU for evaluation
- They're blinkin' at me
The son of man has eyes of fire
- When do I see the judge?
- Be patient.
- He is A mental patient
-Just send him downtown
He's their problem, not ours
- Bustin' Cardboard Willies, huh?
- That's always fun.
- It's a job
This guy smells like dirty ass
I had something a little more sexy
in mind for ya, but, uh
what did you do
to piss off Aceveda?
- What do you mean?
- Well, I need a female undercover
- I thought you'd be perfect, but--
- But what?
I had to twist his arm
You'd better make me look good
Thanks Wait a minute
What's the gig?
AGC Car Company
is doing a bunch of scams
We need you to go after the owner
as Harriet Homemaker
All right I took home ec Let me know
when I can ditch the uniform
Sure will
Vic
- Hi
- One of your puppies make a bust?
- Yeah Koto
Found five pounds of pot
in a locker at Farmington South.
Smokin' in the boys' room
How you doin'?
Ups and downs I've really wanted
to see you, but Hunter's
- You don't have to explain
- always had issues with depression
but lately he's been talking
about killing himself if I ever leave
Are you safe there?
Oh, yeah
He'd never-- Yeah
I wanna see you though
- Sooner or later, this guy's
gonna need a clean break
- I can't do that right now
But I don't wanna wait either
You name the place
Will?
Will? Will?
Why won't you talk to me?
Upstairs
Interrogation room two
Will!
Will! Will! Goddamn it!
Look at me!
Will, you didn't do this!
Will, let me help you.
I can help you!
- I have one condition before we start.
- You don't get conditions
I want a grilled cheese
on sourdough
a few strips ofbacon on the side,
not on the sandwich...
some fries and a Pepsi
- Okay
- Thanks.
I've never seen Joanna
that upset
She can't understand why you
won't take her phone calls or see her
This doesn't need
to touch her any more than it has to
If she's involved,
you can't protect her forever.
- You think she's involved?
- I don't know what to think
She won't talk to us
until she talks to you
Bring her up here I'll get her to cooperate
Then you and I don't have to worry about it
Matthew bit another classmate
this morning
- Another one? When--
- I was gonna tell you Is the other child okay?
He broke the skin
It required tetanus shots
The last couple of weeks,
Matthew's been a serious problem
- It's starting to influence the other students
- You know what?
That's about the time we lost his in-house
therapist. We're still looking for a replacement.
We've decided
to increase his one-on-one...
then reevaluate whether to
bring him back into the fold
- Wait You're isolating him?
- For the safety of the other children
How's he supposed to learn to socialize
if you won't let him near other kids?
- Maybe the one-on-one's gonna help
- We're payin' 'em 25 grand
a year so he won't get stuck
in a public school broom closet
We'll continue to work
with Matthew as best we can
But if he injures another child, we're going
to have to ask you to find another school
- Please don't do that
- What school is gonna take an autistic kid
that you've branded
as being violent?
- Bring back Owen
- He took a job in Phoenix
We had a fight I couldn't
bring him back now even if I wanted to
and, uh, there's a waiting list
at the service
for qualified therapists
I'll come by tonight, talk to Matt
about the biting
- I'll set him straight
- I'd like to talk to him alone
- I'm sorry I can't allow that
- Why not?
- It's against policy.
- Change the goddamn policy
- Jo, stop it. This won't take that long.
Did you tell them
you didn't do this?
- I hate that you got dragged into it
- It's all right It's a mistake
All we have to do now is figure out
how to get you back home
Any questions he asks,just answer
You're not involved, so just tell the truth
- Neither one of us is involved
- I did it,Jo.
I raped those women
I killed them
I brought you things
from their houses.
- They making you say that?
- Joanna, I did it.
- No
- Best-case scenario is I'm going to prison for life
so you need to move on
with yours
We're never gonna see each other
again after today, understand?
I won't ever agree to see you
People are staring at me like I--
The school has told me not to show up
until this is all settled
There's cameras
There's helicopters flying over our house
People are throwing trash
on our lawn What do I do, Will?
- What am I supposed to tell people?
- She needs to leave
- My mother said I was a bad wife
to you. Was I a bad wife?
- Take her away, or I won't talk
Tell me Was I supposed to know?
Was I supposed to know this, that you were--
All right. Let's go.
Look No gun No wire
We'll be out front
but basically,
you're on your own
- What's goin' on?
- Danny's interviewing with Lewis
- You're kiddin' me
- You and Lem back her up
We'll be with knucklehead
I always thought when I finally
went undercover, it'd be as a hooker
Don't lose that dream Ronnie,
hook up Danny with a fake ID
And toss Shane's buddy here
in the cage for safekeeping.
Get up
A case this big is good for us
in a hundred different ways
- How'd it go with Mara's mom?
- Okay, I think
The feds want her to stop in
when she gets back to Indio
What? I'm gone a couple hours, all
of a sudden we're in bed with a cop killer?
- Aceveda signed off.
- As long as you and Aceveda are cool with it
- What are you pouting for?
- He took a shot at me, and
no one seems to give a shit!
- He's gonna do time for that.
- Not enough!
Look, what are we doing to prep Mara's mom
for her face-to-face with the feds?
Maybe next raid, I'll catch that bullet, and
you won't have to worry about a connection
You can just
lay it all at my door
Man.
You're under arrest
for three murders and seven rapes.
I'm guilty of all those crimes.
Are there any other crimes
you'd like to confess to at this time?
No. I just did the three murders
and the seven rapes.
What about your wife? How could Joanna
not know what you were doing?
I was good She didn't
You were out all day scoping your victims,
out all night raping them
Did she ever wonder
where you were?
I told her I was working
or writing
- She never called to check up on you?
- She never had reason to
She didn't see that side of me
You were married for eight years
She didn't wanna see it
Being married doesn't mean
you know what's in a person's heart.
- You married?
- No.
Ever or anymore?
- Anymore
- You leave her or she leave you?
When you were married to her,
did you know what she wanted?
What was really in her heart then?
Or did you only find out later
when she was gone?
- We're deaf and blind here Be ready for anything
Yeah. Copy.
- Dude, what was that
back in the clubhouse?
-Just 'cause
we're on this team doesn't mean
we can't become a problem
If there's one thing Vic's good at,
it's solving problems
Dude, Vic's never
gonna kick you off the team.
If Vic ever thought me and Mara were becoming
a problem, you'd let me know, wouldn't ya?
A regular customer.
Strictly recreational. Got some smarts.
- You hit it?
- No, it's too white, man
It's all pink, nigga
Yo, give me your license
- Got any kids?
- No.
Buy yourself a car seat on your own dime
I don't supply start-up costs
Spill something on it--some crumbs,
couple of toys. Kids are messy.
- You take a nice picture, Danielle
- Thanks.
I'll hold onto this, make sure
you're the real Danielle Spencer
- Come back when you're fitted out.
- All right
What's the status of that homeless guy
that you and Danny brought in?
I tried sending him to County
on a 5 1 50 for observation. No beds.
- You called around?
- Call around where?
There's private facilities
There's that shelter on Bonnie Brae
You know if he's in the military?
He could go to Veterans
- Hmm I'll check
- Throwin'that guy to the gladiators...
in the city lockup
oughta be the last resort, don't you think?
I said I'd check
He's indicated to me
you're not involved You're cleared
- I'm cleared?
- You should go home
Oh, because I'm innocent? People think
I'm guilty of living with him
and of not telling them
he was a monster.
- You're not guilty
- How does a wife not know?
How does she live with somebody
and love him and not know that he's--
Ask him that
Ask him where my life goes now
and then
tell me what his answer is
You got the directions. Give the bag
to Weston. Wait on the porch.
- He'll give you something to bring back
- Okay
Five miles over the speed limit. No more,
no less. You get popped,you own the shit.
Gets back to me,
I'll make sure you never have kids
You guys follow,
make sure the drop goes smooth
- Hey!
- Shit Go, go, go
- Go, go!
Stay put, asshole
- You okay?
- Yeah God
- Goddamn it! He got the drugs!
- You sure you're all right?
- Yeah I didn't wanna blow my cover
Vic
- Oh, shit!
- Goddamn it! Goddamn it!
Cheap piece of shit!
- Hey
- No sign?
Glad we partnered up
with this asshole
If I don't make the delivery, we can't
sting Lewis Aceveda's head's gonna explode
We gotta make this right.
You want your first undercover gig...
to go south before
it got off the ground?
I'm gonna go back in there, make it right
with Lewis, tell him what happened
- No, man Trick could've already phoned you in
- Lem's right. No way.
But the guy's only been running
for five minutes He'll be running 20 more
before he stops to make a phone call.
- I gotta go back in now
- Hey
Okay We're giving you three minutes
Then we'll come and get you
So some nigga just walks up to you
and grabs my shit, huh?
- I didn't know what to do
- What you do is not hand it over, you stupid ho
- The guy had a gun
- Like this? Huh?
- Is that what he did?
Huh?
Whoo! You just
passed the test, bitch.
Whoo! They were my guys,
making sure you were honest
Whoo You're good in the fire
Came straight to me
- Where'd Trick find you?
- Around
Yeah? What? You borrow too much money
from that shark?
How much you into him for?
Enough that I need this job
Well, get to work
- What's your sex life with Joanna like?
- Good
Yeah? Just like
anyone else, huh?
She's never been big on blow jobs--
thinks they're demeaning
- Other than that--
- You'd say you have a normal sex life?
Yeah. Why?
You still thinking I'm impotent?
You shouldn't have gone on TV
and told people
I was something I wasn't.
It's just the profile of the kind of man
who rapes elderly women--
- There's usually a sexual dysfunction at work
- ''Profile''?
You think I'm a chapter in a book?
I just think you're
exaggerating your prowess
Yeah? Why don't you ask
my goddamned wife that? She'll tell you.
You're talking to me about profiles
I'm trying to tell you the truth here
- You raped seven elderly women...
- Nothing to do with Joanna
and cuddled with them for hours
- Why old ladies, Will?
- You think I resented my mother or something?
- You're digging the wrong hole
- Point me to the right one
Maybe I picked 'em because they were old,
and they couldn't fight back
You ever think
about that?
What went through your head
as you were waiting for them to come home?
Did you plan exactly
how you were gonna rape them?
I didn't go there to rape them
I went there to kill them
- The first four, you just raped
- To set the table
The cuddling was just
to keep them calm...
while I decided
whether to go through with it or not
- If not, I just left
- Bullshit
Killing somebody is
about the most selfish thing you can do
Taking away all the moments they've got left
just so you can feel that thing for one moment
The victims I chose
didn't have much life left anyway
It just seemed less selfish
on my part
- Everything on track?
Yeah. We'rejust
swappin'out scrips for dummy dope.
I'm on my way to Lancaster to make the drop,
see who's on the other side
I filled in the assistant chief
He's pretty excited
- Yeah We all are
- And no problems?
No
I talked to Ronnie
Trick hasn't been home or to his mom's
- That means he's gotta collect some cash
to get outta Dodge
- Yeah
Hey You were
Trick's shakedown muscle
- Who owed him money?
- Bunch of people
Yeah? What people?
Huh? What people?
- Huh?
- Dude works out of some burger joint
- Couple of Lithuanian taxi humps
- Who's the smallest and who owes the most?
Thought we had a D.B.,
but the guy's still alive.
Our panhandler?
I thought you found him a shelter?
He got into a beef with one
of the counselors, and he bailed
- Someone tried to suffocate him with these
- Bag that up.
- Hey No trespassin' No No
- We did the canvassing
- No one's talking
- Who called them?
- I did.
- You think they're gonna cooperate now?
Here he comes
Looks like Trick
chose the path ofleast resistance.
- Pussy
Over here Over here Go on
Let go, man! Come on, man!
- Hey! Come on, man
- Shut your face
I'll take one
with everything on it, huh?
Let's go back to when
you first moved to Los Angeles
- Why?
- There are a few open cases from
then I'd like to talk about
- I didn't do anything back then.
- Serial offenders start earlier than 39
- It's more book stuff
- You're just telling me the truth
about the crimes
I've already got you on
- Why would I lie?
Why would you rape?
Why would you kill?
I came here so you could tell me
Do you know what it's like to have
a passion--a thing that drives you...
that consumes your thoughts--but never
to be able to say a word about it...
to your parents, to your best friend,
to your wife?
I came here to talk about this thing,
to finally be able to talk about it
to share it with someone--
to have you tell me why I do it
- Can you help me or not?
- Yes
Then tell me why--
why do I do it? Am I just sick?
No. You're an organized sociopath
with tendencies toward--
No. That's just labels.
Just tell me why I do it.
- To dominate To feel that--
- No That's not right
- To exert your power over--
- No.
- You're compelled to
- By what?
- Organized sociopaths tend to--
- Is that who you think you were
chasing this whole time?
A type?
Some answer on an exam?
Who would you be chasing right now if
you hadn't stumbled over my parking tickets?
But I did find your parking tickets
What happens if the next guy
reads the street signs?
Over here Here you go
Tell 'em your name
- Where's Shane?
- Booking a suspect. I'll have him give you a call.
I need to talk to him about Treasury
I can't talk about it on the phone
You sure as hell can't
talk about it here
They left another message
for my mother to meet them tomorrow
- What does that mean?
- Shane's coachin' her She'll be just fine
No Everything's not fine
We need to get to--
Look You've done
what you were supposed to do Now, leave
Not until I know
what the plan is
Would you stop talking
like you're a part of my goddamn team?
You sucked us
into this shit storm and I'll get us out
but not with you chirping
in my face!
I want you to do something, I'll have Shane
let you know You have questions
you keep 'em to yourself,
you sit at home and keep your mouth shut
- Look at y'all
- You got nothin' real
- Bitch, we got Trick downstairs
you distributing illegal pharmaceuticals,
possession and intent to sell
- Those scrips you moved
came from across state lines
- We're talkin' RICO
That's at least 1 0 years With the feds,
you won't be out in less than eight
Tell us who's doin'what at A.G.C.
We'll let you stay open...
customize cars,
with one small addition
- What's that?
- Bugs Cameras
- Bug my partners? You're crazy
- We catch 'em on tape
They hang themselves. End of the day,
you can play ignorant, blame your mechanics.
All you got's Trick Who's gonna believe
a homeboy with a rap sheet long as my dick?
Trust me That's long
- Meet our star witness
- Hey, boss
- Callan a friend of yours?
- He didn't have friends. He, uh--
- He had issues
- So who tried to suffocate him?
I don't know
This was found
in your shopping cart
This is the same kind of rope found tied
around a bag over Callan's head
He was always stirrin' things up,
pickin' fights, stealin' stuff
babblin' his blackJesus shit
- But I didn't put no bag on his head.
- So someone else got your rope.
- Must have
- Come on.
No one gets near your cart
without a fight, isn't that right?
I need a drink
I'll give you what you want,
but I'm not doin' any time
- Out of the question
- I'm talkin' 'bout handin' you gangstas, brokers
producers, businessmen, dealers--
even throw in a few Republicans
- But like I said-- no time
- Not a day under 1 0
- Okay Ten
- Good
As long as you subtract a year
for every conviction I get you
End of the day,
you gonna owe me time
Thank you
I need a name.
Crazy Eight
No That was just
to get you even
Now, let's talk...
about taking a shot
at pulling yourself up
Artie Cabravansky
- Who's that?
- Artie likes bringin' hardware into South Central
- Who else?
- Rob Kenneally
- Who?
- Runs the Wilshire branch, LA Savings
Floats off-the-book loans
to his buddies
What about this Alison Harden?
What's she into?
Moves underage girls.
Wanna bust some tweener slit,
she's your hookup.
Keep going
Hey You should hear the names
Lewis is spewin' up there
- What did you say to Mara?
- I told her we were taking care of it and not her
- She was just tryin'to help.
- We don't need her help
She's in this too Deep
In waters we know how to swim. She starts
drownin: she's gonna take us all down.
- You could show her a little more respect
- Why? She stole money from you.
Look, man.
You've known us for years.
She's gonna be gone
in a couple of months.
We all see itJust because
you can't doesn't mean I'm gonna let her
be the thing
that splits us apart.
Ayear from now,
you're gonna be thankin' me
- You talked about a ''thing''
- What?
Twice now...
talked about a ''thing''
at the moment when--
- Yeah
- Explain that to me
- Have you ever killed something before?
- Ants.
Bigger
When I was a kid, I found a bird
on the ground, barely moving
I felt bad, so I stepped on it
What did you feel the moment
your foot came down?
I was scared
No Listen
When I was a kid,
I brought a puppy home one day
My father told me never
to bring home a stray
so he made me go down
to the stream and drown it
He gave me a bag and some rope,
and I walked down a hill
to this stream,
got ready to drown this puppy
but it didn't seem right
to kill it
just because
my dad said so
So I took it out of the bag,
and I started petting it
Just kept on petting it
until I kind of found myself choking it.
There's a look
in a thing's eyes--
people too--
right before they die
They're on the edge of this great big hole,
and they'll do anything not to fall in
And at that last moment,
looking into their eyes--
You see the face of God
No
Well, yes, but that's not
what the ''thing'' is
The thing's not in their eyes
It's in here
It's feeling this--
- Power?
- No
- Intimacy?
Compassion?
I'd like to go back
to my cell now
- What?
- You can't help me
I heard you were still here
I'm sorry I--
I wanted to get the names and addresses
of the victims'families...
because I-- I wanted to write them
to tell them how sorry I am
Um, that's probably
not a good idea right now Maybe later
Oh, because obviously
there must be something I can do
A charity or something
Just tell me what it is
Just tell me
what I should be doing
I can't help you
You know, Mara taking the money
and her mom involved--
- Shane feels pretty bad about it all.
- It's not his fault
- Will you tell him that?
- He knows
Hejust wants to feel like we're not
turning our backs on him.
- We're not
- He wants to feel safe
He is
He's part of this team
Well, Terry was part
of this team too
- And?
- And he got killed.
The way Shane was talkin'today, it's like he
thinks we didn't do everything we could've to--
And you believe that?
Shane bother tellin' you
about his latest mistake?
- Sendin' Tavon flyin'through a windshield?
- What?
Yeah. Tavon and Shane, they were
mixin'it up. Mara cracked him...
in the back of the head
with an iron
He got back in the van,
swerved himself into critical condition
Shane tell you about that,
that he came to me lookin'for help?
And I put my neck on the line,
cleanin' it up for them?
You need to stop questioning me
and start helping me
to put a lid
on Shane's queen bee and her mom...
if you wanna
keep this team together
- Let's get married
- We're going to.
I don't wanna wait anymore
You mean,
you just wanna go now?
Right now
We can be in Vegas in a few hours
But my mom and--
- Well, should we call someone--
someone to meet us?
- No.Just us.
Just us
Uh, I'll-- I'll pack
I just wanna look--
You do You do
You're beautiful
- Now?
- Yeah
Where's Matt?
What's the matter?
- He was fighting with Megan.
- Are they okay?
- Everyone's just great
- All right I'll go talk to him
He didn't start it She did
Bit him in the arm
- She's just copying him.
- Have you seen her artwork?
All right
I'll get a painter to go over it
She just keeps drawing lines
until I take the marker out of her hand
And then she keeps drawing as if
I never took it away in the first place
There's something wrong with her
- She's a baby
- She's almost two. She barely speaks.
She doesn't make eye contact
Just like Matthew
She just likes to play by herself
She's autistic, Vic,just like him
She's autistic
- We don't know
- We are going to take her to the doctor...
and he is gonna tell us
that it's autism
- Megan!
- Oh, God
- Matt?
- You locking him in his room?
- To stop them from fighting To keep him calm
Stop Stop Matt, stop it
Mommy's gonna give you a squeeze
I'm gonna give you a big squeeze
- Mommy loves you Calm down
Mommy loves you
Calm down
Mommy loves you.
Calm down.
Mommy loves you. Calm down.
Mommy loves you. Calm--
- Is that our would-be murderer?
- Yeah.
He was afraid if Callan kept smashin' up cars,
the police would crack down on the block
- Caused the thing he was worried about
- Yeah.
Have you ever thought about
joining the Black Officers Association?
- Look No disrespect, but why are you all over me?
- I wanna help
I wasn't aware
I needed any help
You're becoming one of those cops
who's content to let things slide by.
- I made P2 I pull my weight
- Going on blue runs with Mackey?
Excessive force charge
in that church a couple months back?
All I see is you taking shortcuts
You need a new mentor
- Anything else?
- I don't wanna bore you
with what it was like for me...
coming up in this department
25 years ago
There was only a handful of black cops,
but we pushed each other
We looked out for each other
We made each other better cops
You opened the door for a lot of us,
and we are all very grateful
Yeah Opened it wide enough so that when
a black officer flushes out, no one notices
I am not flushin' out
Well, in a couple of months,
Aceveda'll be out
and I'll be
makin' that decision
Hey, sweetie Yeah
Yeah I'm, uh--
I'm just wrappin' up a crime scene
Mm-hmm.
It was good
Yeah Oh, yeah?
Oh, really? Yeah
What did he say?
No I already ate Yeah
Yeah No
Well, don't wait for me. Why don't you
go ahead and eat without me?
- Shh