The mole is a local from Glendale.
He worked a kibbutz in Israel for two years
He was enjoying the nightlife in Tel Aviv
when some connected Russian émigrés
got their claws into him
- What's his connection to O'Brien?
- None
He provided the Armenians with
classified intelligence in return for cash.
Had a few girlfriends
with expensive tastes.
Sounds like you've got things handled
Why am I here?
We set up a trap
on our computer system.
He signed on, accessed information
on four of your men.
Which officers?
You gave the Armenian mob
information on my men?
They called. Asked for intel
on the Farmington Strike Team.
- How much information did you pass on?
-J-Just names and photos
Did they ask for anything else?
Home addresses? Relatives?
They wanted everything The system here
shut down before I could get the rest
The Armenian mob
is on a killing spree
If my men are in danger,
I need to know
If they ask for information,
I get it to them
But in your experience,
what does that mean?
It probably isn't good
- Hey, what's with the uniform?
I spoke to Heather
about cutting back my hours
I'm, uh, working
part-time days now
I thought you were quitting
I'm only gonna work when the kids
are at school or with the therapist
I'm not going to give up
every other aspect of my life
Heather said that
I could choose my own hours.
Listen, uh, as soon
as the house is livable again
I'd like for Cassidy
to stay here with me for a while
It'll give you a chance
to focus on Megan and Matthew
I'm not splitting up my family
They'll still be together, on weekends, holidays.
I'm just talking day to day.
- A trial basis
- How can you even handle her on a day to day?
I'll do whatever I have to do.
I'll hire people,just like you.
Now,you're doing your best.
But Matthew almost burnt the house down
It's not working
Sojust this once,
I'm gonna try it my way.
Hey
Brought you some contraband
Don't let the nurses see it
When we get you outta here, we're gonna
rustle you up some live ones
I bet
Um, they're, uh, sending someone
over from the station to talk to you
- They come by yet?
- Uh, tomorrow, I think
Oh, good Last thing you need
is IAD crawling up your ass
H-How do you mean?
Well, if they found out you started
the fight with Shane, hit Mara--
You could lose yourjob,
your pension.
Maybe even your health benefits
Lem said you don't remember
much about what happened
I-I don't,
but I wouldn't hit a woman
Mara's pregnant Remember?
The department could
come down pretty hard
Look You know,
I'll tell my side of the story
Let him tell his,
and then they can just sort it out
- Tavon didn't bite
What if I come forward?
I take responsibility for hitting him?
That's smart.
Just walk into a police station...
and admit the three of us
have been covering it up for two months
- I'm just trying to do what's best
- I gave you the chance to--
Hey, look I made the call
I mean, can't you just talk to him again?
He's not listening to me
Well, Tavon's always had
a soft spot for Lem
Maybe the both of you
can work on him
All right, it's time to go
bitch-slap the Armenian mob.
We'll talk about it on the way
Try not to land the three of us
in jail while we're gone
- What are you looking at?
What's this?
Something for me?
Euro Rug Imports
Is that your business?
- I do work for them
- What kind of work?
Euro Rug Imports
Right
Show and tell, kids Show us what
you're doing We'll tell you why it's a crime
- Hey!
- Oh, shit
That's Armenian for ''Oh, shit''
Ripped by:
Hound
That was some serious bookkeeping
you had going on down there
Wanna tell me what
all the accounting was for?
- What, did you open up a branch of H&R Blochian?
- I'm in the rug business
There are only a half dozen rugs
in that place
The numbers your girl
was crunching went into the six digits
My guess, we'll have to sweat her.
- No, she doesn't--
- She doesn't what?
We're all just in
the rug business
Three months ago,you're in a duplex in
Kirovakan, running your family's tile business.
You're educated,
no criminal record
How'd you end up
in the asshole of LA
cooking the books
for the Armenian Might?
What do they have on you?
My-- father
uh, lost money to them
He got sick, couldn't pay
And now you're covering the debt
He died two weeks after I left
Then why do you stay here?
My sister, Sosi.
He has her here.
He will kill her
if I do not keep helping
- Who has her?
- Don't know name
They fear him
Long hair
Margos
- Is he here in Los Angeles?
- Yes Not know where
He tells Petrosh nothing.
Treats him like dog
Uh, tell me
about the accounting
They steal gas,
sell it, pay no taxes
Sosi
she doesn't even know
our father is dead
The DA asked me to come down
- A public defender was shot?
- Lisa Kensit
She was a good lawyer
She tried a bunch of cases of mine
Made me look like a fool
a couple times on the stand
I know.
It's hard to believe.
She's at Mission Cross.
Don't think she's gonna make it.
- We know what happened?
- She'djust come from sentencing for her client.
A gang member in the One-niners
He got 1 0 in Chino,
no chance of parole
- You think this is payback for a guilty verdict?
- No one likes lawyers
Having a thankless job
is bad enough.
Getting shot for it is just insulting
Hey! Hey, pull over!
Right here! Pull over!
Put your hands
where I can see 'em
License and registration
Get your ass
down here right now
- I-- Did I do something wrong?
- Sit down
What were you doing at Gas 5 5?
-Just making a delivery
- Tanker's at 92% capacity
Just making a delivery, huh?
You were delivering for 20 minutes
- Your tanks are almost full
- I just started my run
- Maybe you're filling up and not dropping off?
- Let's go, gas man
- Right?
- Protection for fuel--
Is that the deal the Armenian Might
cut with the local pumps?
Once a week-- Once a week,
I hit about three or four places
I fill up the truck, and then
I unload the gas at our stations
We closed down your stations.
Confiscated your tankers
You're outta gas, Petrosh
We got no problem with the Armenians
trying to do business
We just can't have some psycho
chopping off people's feet
- and leaving the dead stumps in our backyard
- Margos
He's a problem
Your bookkeeper
confirmed his Interpol mug shot
We know he's in town
Come on. I know you hate
this guy as much as I do.
You need to--
You need to stop Margos for good
He'll be stopped
When our money laundering
operation took a hit
the bosses back home got angry
They sent Margos to stabilize,
get us back to the basics
- Basics? What, drugs?
- Heroin.
From his connections in Peru
Margos has organized
weekly shipments
- Where is he?
- He doesn't tell us.
But Kail Saffian
he sets up deliveries,
distributes
All right,you and Ronnie take
the first watch on Margos's distributor, Kail.
- Lem and I will go see Tavon.
- Okay
Hey, thanks for
helping me out on that
There's some bad blood between
old-world and new-school Armenians.
Margos Dezirian's stateside,
looking to revitalize the heroin trade
- How do we get to him?
- Gonna sit on his distributor.
You guys find Margos
before he finds you
- What's that mean?
- A mole inside Treasury...
passed on your names and photos
to the Armenian mob.
- Anything else?
- Your personnel files weren't breached.
But if you want
department protection--
The Armenians
need protection, not us
They could be looking to retaliate
I take it as a compliment
Means we're making a dent
All right Let me know
if you change your minds
The Armenians think we know
something about the money train.
- Diagur or O'Brien told them
- They have our names and pictures.
We're walking bull's-eyes, man.
We've been turning over Little Armenia
for days now It's payback for the raids
Margos is in town.
He's here about the money, not the raids.
Look. In the next few days, that money
will be turned into untraceable real estate.
In the meantime, we get
to this Margos prick before he gets to us.
I just heard from Nell Why didn't
you tell me Treasury found their mole?
Because a public defender was shot
I needed you working on that
- So, what'd they tell us?
- They caught the guy
trying to access information
on the Strike Team
-Just the Strike Team?
- You sound disappointed
I'm not
It's just we were all looking
into O'Brien, including you and me
Vic and his guys have been tossing
Little Armenia all week
Yeah
The question is why
What?
Well
Vic knew the name
of the bar
that O'Brien says he found
the marked money in
And you and I were the only ones
who saw the case file
You-- You think Vic's involved?
Here's a guy who can overturn
the Armenian mob in a week
but hasn't been able to find anything
on the money train in three months?
If he's that good, how does
a multimillion-dollar laundering ring
get ripped off in his backyard
without him knowing anything about it?
Maybe he found out who did it,
is protecting him
Keeping the money safe,
in return for a cut of the action
No, he came begging
to me for some OT
He's worked three security details
in the last two weeks
This is not somebody
who is flush with cash
I'm not saying
he'd be stupid about it
Stick with Claudette
I'll look into it
All right Vic says this distributor
is supposed to be short
How short?
That short.
- Kail's got kids
- What, bad guys aren't allowed?
I just think a guy with kids,you know,you'd
think he'd pull his act together. That's all.
Oh, Christ.
Well, he can call them
collect from prison.
Report to Labor and Delivery.
- He's sleeping
- Come on
Let's go
Hey, man, you ready
for that sponge bath?
I thought I asked
for the nurse without the hairy knuckles.
Vic says you don't remember
hitting Mara
Yeah, 'cause I didn't
Okay?
Shane called me down
after the fight
You hit her right above the eye
and in the side
- No
- I treated the cut.
I saw the bruise
The reason we didn't take her to the hospital
is so you wouldn't get implicated
Mara just got you
worked up, man
Believe me, I've wanted to
crack her a few times myself
Look.
You can't let one stupid mistake cost you.
Jesus.
Did I--
Did I hurt the baby?
No, no, the-- the baby's fine
Though Mara did have some bleeding
for a couple of days
Um--
What do you--
What do you want me-- What do I--
What do I say to the investigators?
Just keep it simple
You were tired,
fell asleep at the wheel
Next thing you know,
you--you woke up here
Okay
Can you, uh--
Do you think you can ask Mara to come--
Mara to come down here
and see me?
- I just want to tell her how sorry I am
- Yeah
Sure
Don't sweat it, man
We got you backed up
Parking attendant gave us your license plate
number You were in court today?
I just finished as a juror
in a tax fraud case
Six weeks of trial,
two more in the jury room
I was the only one who graduated
from high school It was a little slice of hell
She said you were in a rush
to leave the parking garage
I just did my civic duty
for two months
Wasn't really looking to get involved
as a witness in a murder trial
I never mentioned anything
about murder Dutch?
Give us a place to start We'll try to
keep you off the witness stand
Let's just say
I heard a story once
about a black guy
who shot a woman
Ran down a stairwell after that
and took off in a green Toyota.
She came in
heavily anesthetized
Doctors are afraid if they operate,
she could go into cardiac arrest
- What was she on?
- Opiate levels in her blood...
are typical ofhigh doses
of OxyContin.
- How big a dose?
- Enough to kill a normal person
She's apparently developed
a high resistance
Uh, she's a junkie?
Doctors say she could have dosed
as early as this morning.
She was in court this morning
Shane, Shane, where you at, man?
You copy?
Yeah, man, I'm here
- Where's Kail?
- He's the midget into his third stack of hotcakes
Hey, man, how did everything
go at the hospital?
Good Everything's fine
Thank you
- He's moving
Okay, he's, uh--
He's-- He's moving
He's in the silver Expedition
On a booster seat
Okay, we got 'im.
You already got me bugging cars
in my garage What else you want, man?
Tell me more about
how your operation launders cash
What, you plan on
jacking a bank, Captain?
It's an additional part
of our investigation
Didn't Detective Mackey
go over this with you?
He never said shit
Well, let's say you've got
two, three million dollars in cash
What would somebody do with it?
Not everyone's as smart
as I am about this
- Let's pretend they were
- First thing you do is nothing
You hold on to it
until the heat goes away
- Hold it where?
- Not home, not work
Someplace close
in case you need to access it quickly
Low profile
Untraceable
Me? I prefer shell corporations
Mere mortals, they use warehouses,
storage lockers
And you're tapped into
other money launderers, yeah?
- I gave everything I'm giving you, man
- I want you to spread word
that the feds are onto the crew that ripped off
the Armenian mob six months ago
- For real?
- Yeah
And if whoever's facilitating
the cash claim comes forward now
reveals who's got it,
they're looking at a free pass
We're north on Kenmore
He's driving with purpose
Yeah, we got him.
West on Fountain
- Shit!
He's evading. He's driving smart.
Don't tip him off.
We got him. We're smarter.
He's driving this careful, he's going
somewhere he doesn't wanna see us
We're circling back around to you.
- Shit! What's he doing?
- He just made a U-turn
He's heading back your way
- Ah, he's by us
- Goddamn it
I need an APB
on a silver Ford Expedition
The reason you're here is Lisa Kensit
paged you eight times last month
- Twice last night
- She's my lawyer
- Trial was three years ago.
What'd you talk about?
- It's privileged.
- The office said your name
wasn't on the sign-in sheet
We met outside
She liked the fresh air
We checked her cell phone records
You were the last person she spoke to
- before she was shot
- I didn't shoot her.
Maybe you slipped off the wagon
She threatened to tell your PO
- I've been clean a long time
- Why don't you just tell me why you paged her...
and I'll let you go home
She had a habit
So, how'd you
come into that?
I told her I'd report her
if she didn't get me out of trouble
And she got you probation?
Pulled every favor she had
at the D.A. 's office.
So,you needed help
keeping out ofjail.
She needed help finding fixes?
How long you have
this arrangement?
If, uh, you delivered the drugs,
who was her dealer?
No, no, no, in a minute
How long did you have this arrangement?
All we want is the dealer
- What are you doing?
- You're shifting focus
We need to find the shooter, not get
the down and dirty on Kensit's social life
Maybe her social life
got her shot in the first place
- But that's not why you're asking
- What are you afraid of?
If you establish a timeline
for her addiction
any lawyer worth their salt's
gonna push to retry her cases
If she were high in court,
they should
She defended Bob Lindhoff
He cut off Kayla LeSeur's arm
and left her in a trunk to die
You wanna roll the dice
on a retrial for him?
You're worried
about your conviction rate
Witnesses get lost, change their story
Criminals will go free
If we know she was high, that's one thing.
I'm just saying...
we don't have to work
so hard to find out
Let's find the shooter
David Aceveda for city council.
He's cleaned up Farmington
He's gonna clean up LA
David Aceveda for city council
and a better future
Ma'am, management
wants you to move
Of course they want me to move
They're big business
- Ma'am, we're gonna have to make you leave
- David Aceveda
For everyday people
I-Is David aware of this?
- He's a police captain
- Yeah, we know
- He's our boss
- Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey! Wh-What's with that?
What are you doing?
- Okay, come on
- Yeah No, no, no, no
- Why are you harassing his supporters? Huh?
- Ma'am--
- Is it because he fights police corruption?
- It's time to go
- Come on
- I'm not moving
Watch your step.
David It's him David!
- Quiet down.
- Someone call for me?
Your biggest fan. She's been campaigning
outside of supermarkets...
harassing customers for days.
David
You're gonna win
You'll be mayor one day
No, governor
I'll talk to her
No reason to put her
through the system
Uh, so, what's your name?
- Carol
- Well, tell me, Carol
Are you involved in my campaign
in a-- in an official capacity?
No I do this all by myself
Well, I appreciate your support,
but all I really need is your vote
So, I'm-- I'm gonna let you out, but I trust
you're not gonna break the law again. Okay?
That's it?
I'm out there 1 2 hours a day,
and-- and that's how he thanks me?
6-Paul-1 1,
we have a visual on your Ford Expedition.
- Should we pull him over?
- Negative
Gimme his location
Keep tailing and stay outta sight
I got you now, you jerk bastard
- Who's Kensit's dealer?
- I can't tell you
Can't or won't?
The dealer, Mary
Is it cold in here?
No Why?
I noticed the goose bumps
Show me your eyes
I told you I'm clean
How long did you deliver
Oxy to Kensit?
- You're under arrest
- On what charges?
Obstruction of justice
being under the influence
of a controlled substance
The only thing I'm on
is allergy medicine
I don't think so
- You can't hold her
- Sure I can
Besides, she won't
be in here for long
Another hour or two, she'll be jonesing
Tell us everything we want
Kail's outside the warehouse
with three other guys
- Armenian swap meet.
- Can I interest you in a little smack, anyone?
- A rug?
- Yeah, with horse rolled up inside of it
Yeah? What if it's not?
We blow this chance to get Margos...
we might not get another
I hope the rug fits in his cell
Hands on your head!
Do it now! Hands on your head!
Get on your knees, fatty! Get down!
Right there
Let's go Right there
Up against the car, man
Let's go Up against the car
Stay right there
Right there
Clear
Oh, I want the rest of the day off.
- Where's Margos?
- Who?
- Hold 'em off
- We're good
Margos, where is he?
You do have the right to remain silent,
but I wouldn't recommend it
Jesus Christ, Vic.
Shit!
Where you meeting Margos?
Where are you meeting Margos?
Jesus, I'm seeing
a lot of windows here, goddamn it
You heard Aceveda
These assholes didn't get our names
and our pictures to send us Christmas cards
- We're getting Margos
- Shit.
Before he finds us
You still thirsty?
- Help!
- Huh? You still thirsty?
- Maybe I should top you off
- Goddamn it Shit That's enough, Vic
- Get off me!
- Come on, bro!
He's talking or he's drowning
Now that can't taste good
In the car
Address in the car
- Where?
- On the visor
- Check it out
On your knees
Shit That's a block away
Jesus Christ
Is he watching us?
Sosi
You see?
Let's go!
Go, go, go, go, go!
- Ram it!
Something's blocking it
- Oh, goddamn it Lem!
- Oh, shit!
- Shit, shit, shit, shit
- Find him!
She's alive!
- Clear. Not here.
- He stabbed her in the back of the neck.
He saw the whole goddamn thing
- She needs an ambulance.
- There's not enough time. Get her in the car.
No Margos
- Call the hospital Tell them we're coming
- Get the sister down there
- Hurry up!
- What about Margos?
- Keep looking for him
- We got it. We got it.
- Hurry up, man. Hurry up!
- Come on, faster She's going white
- Is she conscious?
- No! No, man
I hear you wanna talk
Looks like you'rejonesing
for more than allergy medication.
His name's Marlon Gault
- That wasn't so hard
- He's my boyfriend
- He took care of me
- I can see that. Did he shoot her?
I don't know
He just told me to arrange a meet
at the garage so they could talk
How long have you been delivering
OxyContin to Lisa Kensit?
Three years
Do you have any proof, uh, paperwork,
receipts You could verify it?
No I just arranged the meets
Marlon always took
the money himself
She's gone
We won't stand
for his gestapo tactics
He doesn't care about working families
Just himself Huh?
- Uh-oh
Here come
his storm troopers now
Okay
Would you please
turn around, ma'am?
Your girlfriend flipped
on you, Marlon
She puts you at the crime scene.
She'll be saying something else
the trial comes around
If Kensit dies, you've got no chance
of helping yourself
- I didn't shoot the bitch
Amazing what a junkie will tell you
if you threaten to put them in detox
Lisa Kensit owed you $ 1 5,000.
Sounds like motive
That's a lot of money
for a pissant drug dealer like you.
She couldn't pay you back,
so word hit the street you were soft
- Can I chime in here?
- I'll talk to the D.A.
But he'll need something
on the drugs you sold to Kensit
How's dealing to her for three years
gonna give me time off this shooting?
Depends
If you can provide us with any proof
that she was using during that time
Shit, I got proof
I need years off
Make it quick
I'm hunting someone down
We're gonna have to hold off
on this real estate transaction right now
It's-- Something about
the Armenian mob being ripped off
Treasury's onto
the guys who did it.
- Who told you this?
- Well, the word spreads.
Bottom line is a big transaction like yours
is gonna be too dangerous right now
- I don't know what you mean
- The money.
- Cleaning it
- You got the wrong guy
What, you think
I'm wired or something?
I don't know who you are, man,
or why you called me down here
I thought you could give me a heads-up
when the heat's off, and it's safe to do business
Hey, listen, pal, I'm a cop
You're talking about doing something illegal
You keep pushing, I'll haul you in
Now get the hell lost
Tavon changed his story
We're gonna be fine
Babe?
I've made a decision
- I don't want Vic in our lives anymore
- Excuse me?
- You can transfer to a new team, right?
- No
- I don't want him around us
I don't want him around our child
Mara, he's my best friend
Would a best friend
allow some scumbag to get away
- with taking a shot at you?
- Oh, come on Goddamn it, Mara!
We've already--
That guy is going to jail
Not long enough
You said so
And when you told him
that you didn't take that seven grand
- he didn't believe you, did he?
- That's because you took it
- But he didn't-- he didn't know that then
- You took it!
You told him the truth,
and your best friend still blamed it on you
Vic's in our lives. All right?
He's staying in our lives.
So, you're just gonna have to
find a way to make that work
- All right?
Excuse me
Captain
Hey Everything okay?
Yeah I, uh--
- Hi
- Hey
I've got a house
I gotta get ready to show for tomorrow
- Bye
Uh, what's up?
I talked to a guy who said
he rented out a storage locker to you
He ID'd your photo but said
you used the name Cletus Van Damme
- Why are you--
- I was on something else
- but that is your locker, right?
- Yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah
When, uh, when Mara moved in
she wanted me to get
rid of my old furniture
I didn't know if we'd make it or not,
so I just put it in storage
So why the fake name?
In case they called
and she answered
I don't want her thinking
I might be having second thoughts
I mean-- I mean, you know how chicks are
What's this about?
I don't have a legal right
to search that locker
so I was wondering how you would feel
about showing me what's inside?
What's-- What are you looking for?
Hopefully nothing
Yeah, when Mara and I got married,
I just kinda threw everything away
I had to sign a year lease though
I still got the key
Go see for yourself
- Come in
Our money launderer claims the feds
are onto whoever ripped off the Armenians
- Oh, shit!
- So the feds know it's us?
I didn't ask
He could have been wired
Aceveda was here Wanted to
see the storage locker we cleared out
- What? Well, how long ago?
- Half an hour.
He knew I put it
under the name Cletus Van Damme
- Well, how'd he track you down?
- The manager.
- He ID'd a picture of me
- So Aceveda and the feds are tracking us
- We don't know exactly.
- What ifhis next stop is where
we're really stashing it?
We can't wait to find out
We move the money right now
- Figure it all out later
- Look They'll just keep looking for it
If-- If they catch us
with it now, man, we're done
We're driving it up to Bakersfield
- Well, who decided this?
- Me and Shane
- Really
- There's hundreds of storage units up there
They'll never look
Here Go Up! Up!
Okay All right
- We'll keep in contact by phone
the whole way there
- Okay
All right. Shane and I will take off first.
Get about five miles out
We'll look for tails, eye in the sky,
surveillance teams
You have to evade choppers,
you know what to do
Just drive the speed limit
You'll be fine
Call us when you get
on the road
All right. Check the back. Make sure
the trunks are covered up, all right?
Okay.
Hey, man, my phone's not getting reception
Let me see yours
- Yeah, it's good
- Is it?
Hey, it's locked
What are you doing?
Lem! What are you--
- Lem! Jesus!
Lem!
You made the arrest,
got the shooter
What if she were trying
all her cases high?
How could a public defender be an addict
for three years and no one pick up on it?
Scrips aren't like ''H'' or crack
It's easier to be functional
I sat with one in Interrogation
They had no idea
We checked Kensit's court records
- Her acquittal rate is below average
- Other PDs have worse results?
- Yes, but--
- So, does that mean they're using drugs?
You're talking about reopening cases
that will cost the city millions of dollars
only to reconvict people
that we know are dangerous
The DA will never agree to a deal
that turns the system upside down
Then I'll get an assistant DA
Dutch, give us a moment, please
Sure
Do you know for an absolute fact
this woman was abusing drugs?
- Not yet.
- You have knowledge
that she was using in court?
- She used drugs this morning
- That was a sentencing, not trial.
Oxy is not recreational.
This is an addiction.
- You can't prove that
- I can try.
You have open cases
that need solving?
That's your job
Not this
I wouldn't just be fighting the DA,
would I? I'd be fighting you
Yeah, well, when you're in command,
you'll learn to make these kinds of decisions
- I hope to God not
- Every cop in this house worked
hard to earn those convictions
- You'll be alienating everyone here
- I can't worry about that
You need to if you intend
to be their leader
If you think the D.A. and the chief
are gonna stand and cheer...
while you risk putting these kinds
of people back on the street...
you are seriously
overestimating your support
What if one of the people
she was representing is innocent?
The chief will not promote you
He will look
for the first chance to fire you!
- You understand that, right?
- I understand I can't take a promotion
if the only way to get it is to stick
my conscience in a drawer!
Oh, please
- What happened?
- He just took off
- Which way did he go?
He took a right on Sunset,
then disappeared
- Lem's not answering his cell phone or Ronnie's
- You say anything?
- No!
- Lem ripped us off?
No No way
He was never in it for the cash
He always thought
the money was a problem
- Oh, no No
- What? What?
I know where he's going
Oh, God, no!
Don't, Lem!
Lem, stop it!
Back off Back off
- What are you doing?
- Keeping us safe
Put the goddamn money
down, Lem!
This won't help us.
If there's no money to find,
Aceveda and the feds can't touch us.
Lem, back off.
Back goddamn off right now!
- Back off,man. I mean it.
- Shane
Shane, put down the gun.
Shane!
Please, man
Don't do this, man
Please.
It's gonna be all right
I promise
- Oh, man
- Come on, man Come on
You guys-- You guys are the only family
I got, all right?
I'm not gonna let
any of us go to prison
That's a decision for the four of us to make,
not just you
I've always gone along
with everything you ever wanted.
And all it's done is get us
deeper and deeper into shit
- Stop it!
-Just let me finish this, please
Get off me!
It's over It's over
It's over