Here she is
What's going on? Jesus.
No one's telling us anything.
I talked to Dr Thiel,
and Tavon's condition is grave
Traumatic brain damage
He's got a tough road
- Can we see him?
- He's in I.C.U. It's family only.
- He's on my team
- Ifhe takes a turn either way, I'll let you know.
- Yeah
- Did you get my messages?
No What, uh--
What's going on?
Tavon got into an accident, man
Hit a parked car at full speed
- He might not make it
- Oh, man
Listen, we're at Mission Cross
You gotta get down here
Yeah I, uh--
I kinda had a rough night myself
I mixed it up with this guy
at the Three of Clubs
- I gotta take this other call
- If you can make it, you should come
- Okay
We gotta clean this up
- Hello
- I called you.
What's the problem, ma'am?
I think my ex-boyfriend's in the house
Lyle Dockman
He's been harassing me
My bedroom light was off
when I went to work.
Did you get a restraining order
out on him?
Yes It just made him madder
All right We'll check it out
Police!
Anyone in the house?
I'll check the upstairs
Ma'am, stay back, please.
- Bedroom's clear.
- Oh, my God!
- Danny!
Halt! Police! Halt!
- You okay?
- Yeah
Is he gone?
Yeah
I'm here. What?
Oh Sorry about Tavon
- What do you want?
- I need you to sweep the Alvarado corridor
- Looking for--
- Cruisers, loiterers
There've been complaints
from business owners and citizens
You--
You want me for something real,
I'll be at the hospital
Well, the doctors said they won't know
anything for a couple of days
I'm sorry it happened,
but there's still work to do
I'm a detective, not a janitor
- Get your unis to do your sweeping
- I'm giving you the broom.
The Strike Team's a special unit.
All you've done since your promotion
is jam us up with bullshit gigs
Maybe with Gilroy
you could pick your special cases...
but now it goes Chief Bankston
to Aceveda to me to you.
You don't like that pecking order,
take it up the ladder...
see who's out of a job
- Alvarado corridor, huh?
- Till I tell you otherwise
- You all right?
- Bulb blew out
Ripped by:
Hound
- Shane!
- I got it. Hang on!
- Comin'!
Okay
- Sorry I was on my way
- Forget it Wyms has us on a shit sweep
Alvarado.Jesus!
- Someone clocked you
- Dude, who kicked your ass?
It was this guy
This drunk asshole
was pawing me in the bar...
and Shane told him to get lost
and him and his friends
jumped him in the bathroom
- There was more than one guy?
- No It was mainly one guy
I mean, the other guys
just stood there and watched
How's Tavon doing?
Hey, did he come by here tonight?
Tavon? No. Why would he?
He said he was gonna mend fences
It's just us. Laundry night.
- Everything else all right?
- Yeah I'm good
- I'm taking care ofhim.
- Stay home
I don't want you showing up at work
looking like you got bitch-slapped
Fiesta siesta!
Anybody still here in a minute
gets run in!
You heard the man
Let's pack it up, party people!
- You don't gotta sweat me, man!
- Thought this was a free country
- Got a curfew in this part of town, homes
- Not for me I'm over 21
What do you think?
- About 1 4 coats of high-end enamel?
- Let's see.
Yo, man, I'm gone, man
- Where were you tonight around 1 0:00?
-Jogging
I do three miles every night after work
Sure you weren't doing the 1 00-yard dash
through your ex-girlfriend's backyard?
Elena?
I can't go within 1 ,000 feet of her
Right, or call her But you've been
leaving messages on her machine
Before the restraining order.
It's a crime to want another chance?
She's not giving you another chance
- Not yet
- Not ever
Look, someone was
in her house tonight.
- Is she okay?
- She's fine.
Can anyone verify
you were jogging tonight?
You'd have to ask around
Okay, well, we're watching over Elena
And now we're watching you
Problemo, amigo
This is your 1 0th citation
for cruising in the last four months
I juice up cars
Hummin' out here with my baby's
the only advertisement I got
Try the Yellow Pages
'cause we're bringing the car in
- When do I get it back?
- About a month or two
After you see a judge, pay a fine
We'll take care of her till then, all right?
Every cent I made the last five years
I got wrapped up on her
Really? I would've pegged you
as more of a mutual fund guy
What do I got to do
to keep my wheels?
Flip me someone juicier than you
Oh, here's her ride
Wait, wait This vato, Aramis
I call her twice a month
I always remember her birthday
- Her own son.
- So you're taking her side.
- Seen Claudette?
- She and Dutch just caught one
Another possible elderly rape victim
What do you need?
She's got me working
the Alvarado corridor
- for the next few days
- Right Sweeping duty
Last night I'm tagging this guy
we're about to tow away
his Hot Wheels
he spills about this guy
sneaking contraband
into Chino Prison for his gang buddies
- What kind of contraband?
- Drugs, cigs
cock rings, weapons of mass destruction,
who knows what
- You checking into it?
- I was looking for Claudette
to see if I should stick
with cruiser duty
- Follow up on this for the time being
- Wherever you want me
- Gentlemen, what do we got?
- B-and-E robbery
Fits your rapist profile though
- Elderly woman living alone
- You read my memos?
- Watch CO makes us
- Did the victim call it in?
- No, I didn't.
- I did.
Detective Wyms and Wagenbach.
Patty Klopp. My mother, Luann.
They broke in last night
I stopped by this morning
I noticed some of her Hummels were gone
Couple of tchotchkes So what?
Someone broke into your home, Ma.
- You have to report that.
- And now you have
She's supposed to be watching
her sugar levels
Anything taken from the bedroom?
- Not that I know of
- When did the robbery occur?
Last night I came home around 9:00
from the movies
- You see anybody?
-Just saw my things missing
And you weren't afraid
Honey, I've lived in this neighborhood
for 40 years.
Your daughter says she's trying
to get you to move to Encino.
You'll have to kill me
before I'll retire to the valley
Ooh, you got something special in mind
for the ride back?
Funny The compulsive eating,
the odd, distracted behavior--
I think Luann was raped
Well, yeah, she's a tough old broad,
but I saw it too
- You're agreeing with me?
- I'm agreeing that she loses her dignity...
if she admits she was attacked--
her dignity and her independence
Speaking oflosing your dignity--
The bed was stripped
There was nothing in the clothes hamper
Whatever you find in there's gonna be
too contaminated to test.
That's too bad
Why do you throw out
a perfectly good set of sheets?
To bury the truth
God, I wonder how many other
buried sheets there are out there.
Oh, here's Aramis.
Byz Lats are showing initiative.
Diagur's running them
better than I thought.
Yo, Ronnie,you see him?
Guy with the cigarettes?
Yeah, I got him.
That's good.
Either this guy is sneaking shit into Chino...
or he needs the world's largest patch.
Let's see where he takes us.
We can't provide 2 4-hour protection
to every woman
who has an ex with a temper
Sir, I did some checking up
on this asshole
The last ex who got
a restraining order on him
left a good job in Cleveland
to move to New Hampshire
just to disappear from this guy
She was sure that he would kill her
- This one feels real to me, sir
- Danny's right
This one feels real
Okay We can escort her
to and from work Extra patrols
You've got one week for this guy
to violate the order before I pull the plug
All right Thank you, sir
Don't thank me
She should be thanking you
I got 29 B-and-E's
of elderly women.
- Eleven in the last six months
- I called the hospitals.
They said they'd give us a heads-up
if anyone fits that profile.
What about your new promotion? You sure
you've got time to help me out on this one?
- For this? Yeah I'm all yours
- Yeah?
You ever hear of this guy?
''Mueller's Geographical Profiles. ''
That's the criminologist from Duke?
Doctor of Criminal Logistics
Takes data on serial violent crimes--
victims, nature of the assault--
Generates the most likely location
of where the perpetrator lives or works
Needs three confirmed cases
to work up a preliminary profile
- We've only got one victim confirmed
- Two, if Luann comes clean.
You think Aceveda will spring for it?
It's expensive
Nah Let's go find numbers two and three:
then we'll stick him with a bill
- You already made arrests?
- Caught 'em exchanging
packages of smokes and drugs
along with 7,500 in cash
Guess that's the going
smuggling rate these days
- Good work
- The banger puts together the care packages
The white guy's
a frozen food delivery man
Drops off at Chino twice a week
What are you working on exactly?
I got a tip from a cruiser last night...
about a guy sneaking swag
into the state pen
Shouldn't be too hard to getJoe Trucker
to roll on cholo and vice versa
You moved off the Alvarado corridor?
Yeah I couldn't find you,
so I moved up the ladder
- So I had some cigarettes
- We're not talking about
a couple cartons of Marlboros
We nabbed you handing off
20 thumbs of heroin too
Must be the old man's
'cause I learned in school to just say no
You take the orders, gather the shit...
hand 'em off to Fred,
who sneaks it in with the frozen peas
- Am I right?
- Yeah, we got you dead to rights, man
On all your wrongs Look
I spoke to the DA
If you cooperate
I can make sure that you do your time at
Chino again with all your fellow banditos
Otherwise, who knows?
Maybe you end up someplace chilly like Shasta.
Can I go home now?
Sorry It's gonna be a little while
What's the problem?
Wejust talked to Aramis.
He told us the whole thing.
Twice a week drop-offs you make
at Chino State Correctional Facility.
I'm a deliveryman
That's my job
There was heroin
in this week's care package
I don't look at what's in the packages.
But you knew it was wrong.
Um
I-- I should go home now
My wife's making dinner
Whoa, easy It's all right Easy
Fred. Fred.
You're under arrest,
you understand that?
No. That's not right.
If you can confirm
who receives the stuff on the inside...
- maybe we can make things a little easier on you
- No.
This is-- This is a mistake
This can't happen
I'm not a criminal
The Strike Team just made a bust
that included $7,500 in cash
I need you to run
the serial numbers of the bills...
against the numbers on this list
Again with this?
Let me know if you get any matches,
and then return that list straight to me.
Why do you have me doing
such menial things for you?
Because you're my assistant
I could be so much more to you
With the election and everything
I have a campaign staff for that
They don't know what they're doing
You have no idea the mistakes I fix
before they land on your desk
And I appreciate it,
but for right now, please
just check the numbers on that list
against the money in Evidence
- You okay?
- It's Layla
She reported a robbery
five months ago...
and after a lot of hand-holding
just admitted she was raped
-Jesus This guy is--
- She tell you anything that'll help?
No condoms, no climax,
a lot of cuddling.
That makes two confirmed
I struck out on my end
We need one more
I don't remember
anybody snooping around
Delivery guy?
- Anybody that seemed suspicious?
- This neighborhood?
Try to find someone
who doesn't look suspicious
The reason we ask, Luann,
is because there is a man...
who is breaking into homes
and sexually assaulting women.
- Sexually?
- I'm flattered, Detective
He's targeting women your age
- What are you talking about?
- Did someone hurt you?
Course not
Thank God
- I pulled Tavon's accident report.
- Thanks for doing that
You know, witnesses saw the car
swerving a couple blocks
before he hit that parked car
- Before?
- Yeah.
- Is Tavon a drinker?
- I don't think so
Which direction was the car going in?
Uh, north on Perry
North? Uh, thanks
Hey I thought
you didn't want me coming in
I thought you were gonna come alone
She wasn't sure I was good to drive
- Thoughtful
- Yeah What's up?
Tavon was headed away from your place
Witnesses saw his car swerving
all over the road before he hit the car
- Toxi report shows no drugs or alcohol
- That's weird
What do you think happened?
Don't know yet
Don't have all the facts
There's something missing
Like a coffee table or a painting
Look, he came over
Gave me this backhanded apology
We had some words
He jumped me, and I tagged him back
with a pretty good shot
- How good and where?
- To the back of the head
The back of the--
He has brain trauma.
It was from an accident
that happened miles away from my place
He was swerving all over the road
before the crash
Your blow probably caused it
You could face charges.
- What did you hit him with?
- A paperweight or something
Look, he was all over me
Where were you during all this?
I-- I was doing the laundry
in the basement
Really? Whites or colors?
- I--
- She wasn't there
All right?
This thing was all me
Uh, hold on
- Here's your list back
- Thank you
- Got two matches
- What?
Two of the bills,
their serial numbers were on the list
I wrote which ones down for you
- Where you taking him?
- Interrogation
- I'll meet you upstairs
- Sure thing
We miss a piece of the puzzle
putting together Aramis?
No We just need to talk to him
on an unrelated matter
I'll let you guys get back
to the Alvarado corridor
- Thanks
- Who's the suit?
His ID said Treasury That's the second
''T'' fed in our house in two weeks
What's Treasury want from our collar?
Aramis is one of Diagur's tenientes.
You think that Aceveda knows about
the corners we cut with Diagur
- to get those guns back?
- One way to find out
Don't care about that
Just tell us where you got the 7,500
in cash you gave to the delivery guy
I already made a deal
with the other cop.
I ain't got to rat on my boys
on the outside.
Your crime is now under
federal investigation
- That's why Agent Nell is here
- Which means any previous deal
is now null and void
Bullshit My ticket's punched to Chino
Your ticket's punched
wherever we say it is
Captain Aceveda's been checking
all money confiscated in big arrests
So?
Two of the bills you had
in your possession were marked
It was currency stolen from
an Armenian money laundering ring
- Holy shit
- We've been waiting for it to show up.
Guess what.
It showed up in your hands.
- Our money's marked?
- No way.
Aramis said he got that cash from Diagur
We got our bag back from Diagur
20 grand light
We're starting at square one, Aramis
Who did you get the money from?
- I don't know where I got it from
- Not good enough.
Whoever stole that money
killed two Armenians to get it...
and we're gonna tie someone
to these murders
You want it to be you
or someone else?
I really don't think you want to be facing
the death penalty for something you didn't do
Go! Go!
I got a sick feeling, man
It's all crashing
- Not if we steer it in the right direction
- Our money's marked?
- Some of it? All of it?
- We don't know, man
- Where are we going?
- To find Diagur.
Silence his smoking gun
We're looking for Diagur.
- Who are you faggots?
- Hey, watch your mouth
We're the guys busting you
for possession of an illegal substance
- Where's Diagur?
- Who?
Today's not the day
I just need to talk to him
- Where is he?
Yeah You give me a message,
I'll pass it on to him
How long you been
out ofTerminal Island?
Not long enough
You don't tell me where your boss is at,
you're gonna bejumping back.
Home is where the heart is
Huff the pipe, asshole
Take a hit
- Take it
Take it, goddamn it!
Join the party, sweetheart
Come on
He's at Yolanda's
One street over
Brown house with the Madonna
- Diagur?
- Si.
- Donde?
- En el quarto.
-Jesus Christ
- Get out!
- It's okay I know 'em
- How old are you?
Old enough
Glad Mom has such a firm grasp on things
Wait outside
- Come on, let's go
- I need my clothes
Whatcha doin',
breaking into my freak, yo?
You got a Byz Lats lawyer
on your speed dial?
Yeah One of my boys has an uncle
Call him Get him down to
the Farmington station house right now
- What's there?
- Your prison delivery boy, Aramis
If he's done anything,
it's without me knowing about it
I'm all over your Chino game.
And unless you want
my boss all over you
you get your lawyer down there
and make sure he zips it now
Someone left a rose
in Elena's mailbox this afternoon
Don't you have
more important things to do?
Actually, unlawful use of a mailbox
is a federal offense
We just got done talking to your boss
Technically, you were on the clock
- You were supposed to be making business calls
- You got proof it was me?
For future proof,your boss has agreed to
monitor all your calls and online activity at work.
- You can't do that
- No, but she can.
You can either spend your 9 to 5
stalking or spend it working.
- Can't do both
- Listen, lady, this is my job
Not for long
if you don't leave Elena alone
Have a nice day
I'll talk to you later
- Lawyer's on his way
- Good
You said before you didn't have my back
Why you helping me now?
Feds are buzzing around
the money you gave to Aramis
It's tied to a robbery
Somebody ripped off
the Armenian mob
Come on, man
I ain't suicidal
The Armenians find out
that you guys are suspects
the Byz Lats will be up to their necks
in severed feet
I'm just trying to prevent a war
Where'd you get the cash?
Who knows?
It comes in a dozen ways
Anybody asks, that's your best answer
You give Aramis anything
besides the 7,500?
Yeah
Fifteen grand
- You handed it to him personally?
- You think I'm gonna trust that
kind of cash with some flunky?
So your fingerprints could still be on it
- Any idea where he might've stashed it?
- Yeah
- In his freezer My idea
- Original
Get somebody down to his place
to pick it up
And you disappear
for a couple of weeks
Oh, shit
- He's back in the cage
- He talked
He goddamn talked
- Sarge
Cold hard cash
I'll run the serial numbers
against the master list
I get this to the lab before 5:00
I can get fingerprint results
by morning
You coming?
He gave us permission
to search his place
I'm curious what else
we might find here
I'll call some unis for a ride
Diana Peabo.
She came into the E.R. last month.
Injuries sustained during a home robbery.
Her kids just brought her in again
Allergic reaction
Mixed up two of her meds
They said that she's been
kind of out of it since the attack
One of the other nurses
saw your bulletin
- Thank her for us
- It's a him, actually
They're in consultation
- How's Tavon?
- He's the same
Excuse me
Could I talk with you a moment?
Detective Wyms
Detective Wagenbach
How's your mother?
She'll be just fine
What's this all about?
We were wondering if we could talk to her
about that robbery last month
- Why now?
- We think your mother might be able to help us
find the person who did it
It's not here.
Police! Don't move!
Keep your hands in the open!
Hey! Don't move!
Don't make me do it, man
Stop right there
Put your hands in the air
Don't make it worse for yourself
Turn around
On your knees, man
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Hey, man
Hey, don't make this mistake
I'm a police officer
So you a cop, huh?
That mean you can do
whatever the hell you want?
Hey,you can still get out of this.
Oh, now you telling me
what to do, huh?
Hey, man, you need
to calm your friend down
Tie him up
Tie him up with something
Your hands, man
- Hurry up
Hey, man
Don't throw your life away
I ain't afraid of prison,
but you should be
You ever, uh
suck a dick like a cell bitch, cop-man?
- Huh?
- Don't do this
It's your turn to gag on something
Huh?
No
- Open up, sweetheart
- No!
You wanna die instead? Huh?
- No
Captain!
Great
Probably had a limo
come pick him up
Can I get confirmation
on that pickup address?
There's no one here
at our current location
Negative, 1 -Tango-1 6 Unable to confirm
Let's head out
They're gone
Let's see that mouth
- El Presidente around?
- Captain Aceveda? No
- Where is he?
- Conducting a search at a suspect's house
Could you raise him on the horn for me?
I got an important question for him
I'll try, but I've left two messages for him
in the last 1 0 minutes
His cell phone coverage
is bad sometimes
No
Thanks
Put your groove into it
Suck it!
Little bigger than you're used to?
Uh, uh, uh, uh, uh
Yeah,just like that
Get your phone, man
- What?
- Your phone
I wanna get a Kodak of this
Yeah, that's the way.
Mm-hmm, okay.
- You ready?
- Yeah
- I got it
You don't remember anything else?
Nothing about his face?
His height?
I'm gonna tell you something you're
not gonna like hearing very much, Vince
I know, as a son,
it's the last thing I'd want to hear.
What's going on?
Um, we--
We think your mother wasn't just
knocked down by that guy last month
We believe he may have
sexually assaulted her
- Sexually?
- It would account for why
she's so distracted lately
That's a lot of pain to push down
We hope we're wrong.
Why don't you start by telling us
what happened that day?
I found her lying on the kitchen floor
She couldn't stop crying
- What else?
- Back window was broken
She said a guy came in, knocked her down,
grabbed a few things, then ran
She would've told me if--
Maybe she needed more time
- Yo, man, ifhe tells his boys, we're done.
- You gonna say anything?
- No
You can't believe that shit.
- What, you want to kill him?
- You do it
- You want it done, you do it
Hey, man, I have a little girl
I-- I have a wife
Mother
Yo, man, you gotta do it
I'll watch
You been wantin' the juice, man
- Do it
If your mother were here,
what would she tell you to do?
Not this kind of juice, bro
Not this kind of juice
It's that other cop Let's go
- I'm in here!
- Bust the door!
- Try it again.
- I got it.
- He's here!
- Sweep it
- You all right?
- Yeah
- Clear!
- They got my gun
- They?
Yeah Two of them
- Are you hurt?
- No
I was able to fight 'em off
Mom
I need you to tell me
what happened during the robbery
I told you everything I remember
Have you?
What else did he do to you?
Where are those police people?
He hurt you?
Stop it, Vincent.
- Raped you?
- Don't you say that!
Mom, did he?
Don't say that!
Why didn't you tell me?
Mama, why?
- Hold it
- You see something?
- Maybe.
- Let's go
- Yep
- You can't keep me here
- That's true
You'll probably make bail
sometime tomorrow
Trial won't be for another six months,
but in between
every time you roll a stop sign,
I'm gonna be handing you a ticket
Every lunch break you take, I'm gonna be
sitting right there at the next table.
- Yeah, that's harassment
- No, Lyle, that's stalking
Hey,you okay?
Yeah, I had a little run-in
No harm done
Let's not waste any time on it
- Hey, what happened?
- He fended off a couple of bad guys
Miracle he hasn't called
a press conference yet
She's in there alone
with her husband's service weapon
My key wasn't working
in the new lock
- She shot at me when I opened the door
- You okay?
Ma'am, come on
I told you to stay in the car
Luann!
Luann?
Luann
- Can you drop the gun?
- Put the gun down, Luann.
It's okay, sweetheart
I know what happened to you
That's our wedding
You were very beautiful
I was a size four
Can you tell me
what happened to you?
He robbed me
I didn't want to get robbed again
Hey, Cassie
Hello, Mr Mackey
Cassidy, Owen said hello to you
Hey
I'm sorry
She's struggling with this whole thing
It's okay
- Hey, little man
- I'm drawing a zoo
Wow Hey, that's great, Matty
Corrine's in with Megan
Hey
- How'd she do at Dr Franks?
- You know shrinks
You ask them one question,
they give you five back
She's being quiet and a little stubborn
He wants you and I to do sessions too
- One-on-one
- Look, I want her to get all the help she needs
But me laying down on a couch?
It's not gonna happen
Stubborn and incommunicative
Wonder where she gets that from
How's Tavon doing?
The last surgery gave them some hope
The brain tissue bruising
isn't as bad as they thought
- That's good
- The next 48 hours should tell.
Good
Oh, um, if he recovers
would he be able to remember
anything that happened?
I got him working on
this undercover assignment
Well, he could remember every detail
or he could wake up
and barely recognize his own reflection
IfTavon lives, he could remember
everything that happened
If he dies, an autopsy could reveal the blow
to the back of the head before the crash
We'll figure it out, baby
Chew on this, baby
We just found out the feds
marked some of our money train cash
- What?
- Part of a sting they're doing on the Armenians
- Oh, shit
- Deep
And if that's not enough,
this accident leads back to you
without us getting self-defense
on the books
I.A.D. could be all over you...
right at the time we're gonna
cash in on the money train.
- So what do we do?
- Oh Now it's ''we''
- Tell me the truth.
- I did
You had a fight One of you hit him
It was self-defense
If you both tell your story right now,
this could all go away
Look, we gotta make a decision
Right now
Which road are we going down?
Look, everybody knew
Tavon and I had bad blood
No We gotta make this disappear
We think this cuddler rapist
has been around for a while.
We've looked at like-crimes...
we've interviewed dozens of women.
We've confirmed three victims...
which is required for his analysis
Mueller's results have been proven accurate
down to the square block
We match this with known offenders
we narrow our search dramatically.
Well, if this Mueller can help,
then let him
Mueller isn't free
- His fee's $5,000
- Right
- Then it can't happen
- We're really at a standstill on this.
A stranger perpetrator
The victims could just pile up
until he makes a mistake
and so far, he hasn't made one.
- Captain
- No I said no
We don't have the money
All right, roll up that rug
Hit some yard sales.
Pick up a new rug and a table.
Picture too. Use cash.
I'll drop by this weekend
and help you patch that wall.
What'd you hit him with?
Nice paperweight.
Put that in the truck with the rug.
It's a brand-new iron
I washed it It's clean
We'll get a new one.
Put the broken table in my truck.
I'll dump that too.
This is dangerous
You know that, don't you?
It's not my fault that he crashed
You mean it's not Shane's fault
He must really love you
- He's doing what he thinks is right
- What do you think is right?
I trust him.
We're gonna cover our tracks
the best we can
But if push comes to shove,
you gotta step up, tell the truth
The DA-- never gonna pursue
the conviction of a pregnant woman
trying to protect the father of her child
That's not how Shane wants to do it
He'll do it however you tell him to do it
- Is everything okay?
- Sure.
Sweetheart, let me get that
I got it
Hey, hey, hey Luminol
Spray it all around. Use the light.
Blood traces will glow
Here I--
Fumes could be dangerous to the baby
Cleanup's on you
- Thank you
- Yeah
Sir, we caught that stalker lurking
behind the victim's house last night.
- Good
-Just thought you'd like to know, sir
- Captain
- I need your signature.
- You ready for the monthly reports?
- Not yet