One-Tango-13 in pursuit
of car jackers...
eastbound on Campo,
approaching Melrose.
Oh, shit. They're bailing.
One-tango-13. My partner's on foot pursuit.
- 1300 block of Pico.
Additional backup requested.
Suspects are armed.
I've got 'im. Go.
One-Tango-13.
We have the child. He's unharmed.
Stop!
He's in there.
Freeze!
Stop!
Stay down.
Hands behind your back.
You're under arrest.
They took the skin from his ass.
Left cheek and upper thigh.
Those jokes just write themselves.
I'm ready to come back.
- You should take some more time.
- All I can think about...
is ripping off these Armenians.
- You up to work and the money train?
- I need this.
He's come up
with a new way inside.
It's a little late
for changes in the game plan.
I went two nights ago,
scoped out the whole location again.
The one thing we've never been able
to figure out is the bottleneck problem.
All four of us going in together...
if just one of those Armenians
isn't where we expect him to be...
- Yeah, we're toast.
- Ronnie noticed this
garbage pickup at the site.
It's Armenian.
They just wave it in.
We get ahold of the garbage truck,
deposit two of us on the inside...
a few hours before
the money train arrives.
Me and Shane,
we climb inside a Dumpster...
- Why am I in the garbage?
- Two inside, two outside.
We triangulate.
Sounds like a real possibility.
Have to figure out how to get our hands
on one of those garbage trucks.
We're already on it.
We only have two weeks
to master a new plan.
Let me think about it.
Goddamn it.
You're not talking about me, I hope.
- What do you want?
- Everything okay?
The Times is gonna endorse
Karen Mitchell for city council primary.
- So? Don't you have some big lead?
- Not anymore.
And with Lanie's official report due
a week before the election...
Yeah, well...
I was thinking about some ways
to take the sting out of that report.
Enlighten me.
One big, high-profile bust...
something the chief...
not even Lanie... can deny us.
- And I suppose you have a candidate.
- Fresh off the Teletype.
Dante Fell. He was a major gangbanger
when I was in the blues.
He went national,
went off my radar.
F.B.I., D.E.A., State, County,
they all want him bad.
How sweet would it be
if we dragged his ass in?
Scored one for the home team?
Federal authorities
believe Dante Fell...
may be on his way to Farmington
or already here.
Dante is a founding member
of the Compton Crowns street gang.
He spent the last four years of his life
franchising his gang to other places...
like Wichita, San Antonio
and Oklahoma City...
supplying them
with drugs and weapons.
Pick up a flyer
and be on the lookout for him.
- Think you can get him before the feds?
- Absolutely.
- Listen, I gotta bring Ronnie back.
- Sure he's ready?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
- I'm not.
Tavon's still learning.
I need a full team.
This guy Dante isn't
gonna be an easy catch.
Fine. I don't want you
to have any excuses.
I won't need any.
What are you doing here?
Read about that civilian
auditor's report.
- It was pretty rough.
- What's up?
- When you had me running
that protective detail on Corrine?
- Yeah?
I saw my guy's surveillance notes,
and he followed her...
to some law firm on Ventura,
so I looked into it.
She went to see
a divorce lawyer. Twice.
- And you're just telling me this now?
- I didn't confirm it until now.
Divorce lawyer.
- We're not anywhere near that.
- I'm just telling you, Vic.
It's a mistake I'll always regret,
not seeing the writing on the wall.
We're supposed to be
in a holding pattern
till we figure things out.
She's already seen
this lawyer twice.
She's scheduled to see him again
Tuesday, 4 p.m.
- She wouldn't do this to me, not right now.
- I bet you didn't think...
she was capable of packing up and running out
with your kids, and she did.
Listen, please, just do me a favor.
- Talk to this guy of mine.
- Divorce guy?
He's one of the best.
I really appreciate the heads-up
on this, but it's unnecessary.
- Tavon Garris, right?
- That's me.
I'm Lanie Kellis.
Oh, sure, your, uh...
Your report's causing quite a stir
around here.
That was a mistake.
Someone leaked my notes.
My official report
comes out next week.
Being new, I'm probably the only person in the
building not sweating it, huh?
Well, I know everybody here
sees me as the bogeyman...
but if you ask me,
I'm misunderstood.
I've been meaning
to talk to you actually.
- Yeah? What about?
- Vic Mackey.
Mmm, look at the patch man.
Back in the saddle, baby.
Listen, you get ahold of that thing
we were talking about?
I'm open to the new plan.
- Get going, then.
- All right.
Call in with updates
and keep 'em open.
Hey. You seen Tavon around?
Not in the last half hour. Why?
I saw him chatting up with Lanie
in the kitchen earlier.
- What were they saying?
- I couldn't hear...
but they looked awful cozy.
Now, the last thing we need
is another guy we can't trust.
Yo.
Hey, I saw you talking
to our civilian auditor.
Yeah.
What's up with her?
She's a bitch.
What were you two talking about?
- Nothing, really.
- Keep it that way.
Let's get started on finding
this Dante prick.
Come on.
It's a needle in a haystack.
I mean, according to the Teletype,
the guy might be in town?
For reasons either the feds don't know
or don't want to reveal, it's a jerk-off.
What?
You giving up already?
Actually, we do have a bona fide tip
that the feds don't have.
- Yeah, what's that?
- One of Dante's old homies is Kern Little.
- The hip-hop guy?
- Yeah, they got picked up
a few times together.
Knowing Kern,
he stays in touch.
What makes you think
Kern's gonna help us?
Kern's a friend.
Grab your shit.
You're riding with us today.
Looks like I'm moving up
in the world.
Hey.
A'ight. I see you're adding
a little color to the team.
- Tavon, man. It's good to meet you.
- We're here for a favor.
- Funny. I need one from you.
- Mine first. Dante Fell.
I hear he's in town.
What can you tell me?
Man, I ain't seen
Dante in, like, forever.
- But you know who he hangs with, right?
- When we getting to my favor?
Soon.
All right. If he's in L.A. ...
you want to be
talking to Frogger.
Real name Freddy Germaine,
Dante's quarter brother.
Quarter brother? That some
kind of new ghetto math?
Nah, man. It means Dante's moms was
shacked up with Froggy's pops.
Pops took off.
Dante's moms kept Froggy.
- So you know, they're not
blood brothers, they're...
- Quarter brothers.
Exactly. So, what's up
with my favor?
- You like that studio stuff, huh?
- It's hot, man.
Why don't you give him
a tour of the place, baby?
Sure. Let me
show you around.
So here's the deal, man.
I'm trying to get back into the drug game.
I need y'all on my team, though.
Same deal you had
with Rondell and Tio.
That wasn't working out for us
the way we'd hoped. I can't help you.
Being kind of cold
for someone who owes me.
- Owe you for what?
- I was getting a cut from Rondell.
Y'all wanted him out.
I went along with it.
Y'all was supposed to
be protecting Tio.
He goes up in smoke.
Suddenly, my cut dries up.
Look, I didn't come to y'all for lost wages,
but y'all know I could've.
Well, it looks like
you're scraping by.
Well, I'm not.
Man, I got lawsuits...
cheating accountants,
hungry crew.
You're broke?
Not if I could fill the powder void
in Farmington. I need y'all, though.
We got pressures
of our own right now.
It'd make it impossible
for us to do what you ask.
I appreciate
the Frogger tip...
but I'm gonna have to figure out
another way to make it up to you.
- That's it?
- That's it. Tavon!
Good work.
Keep it up.
Two for one, man.
Unbelievable.
Yeah. Store owner says
we're gonna lose Julien to the NFL.
Julien, isn't that your...
Yeah. I got it.
What are you doing here?
I'm out on parole.
I wanted to see you as soon as I...
Now is not a great time.
Okay, well, when would
be a good time then?
Things have changed, Tomas.
Everything has changed.
You've gotta leave.
Look, I really need your help right now.
I got no one else...
Look, I cannot
do this right now.
Maybe later.
Oh, goddamn it.
We've got a tail.
Don't look.
- You sure?
- Green sedan about three cars back.
Saw it on the way to Kern's.
He's still on our ass.
- Who'd stick a tail on us?
- That's what you're gonna find out.
All right.
Get ready to bail.
Go, go.
- May I help you?
- My daughter Evette, she was raped.
I'm sorry.
Has she seen a doctor yet?
No. Uh, it happened a couple of days ago.
I just found out about it.
Her boss had her close the store late with him,
so he could get her alone.
- You get the tag?
- Yeah.
- Write it down.
- It's cool, man. I got it right here.
Unless you're the world
concentration champion...
just write down the damn tag number,
man, it's important.
Whoever he is,
he's still back there.
Why do I have
to have these tests?
Well, it may still give us a chance
to get a sample of his D.N.A.
He wore a condom.
Well, it also proves
that intercourse took place.
Won't take long.
You're a brave girl to come forward.
What is it?
I have a boyfriend...
and we...
- You had intercourse with your boyfriend?
- Mama doesn't know.
When was the last time
you had sex?
A few days ago.
Will that show up on the test?
Let's just wait for the results.
It's gonna be okay.
I'm the manager.
Hey, darling.
Uh, we're looking for Freddy.
- Frogger?
- Yeah. Can you help us?
Ain't seen him today.
Why? Did he do something?
Well, have you seen this guy
hanging around lately?
- No.
- Is there anything you can
tell us about Frogger?
Always pays his rent late.
Not late enough to kick him out...
but late enough to make me take
an extra trip to the bank every month.
- Has he paid up this month?
- Not yet. Four days late.
- I hope he's okay in there.
- What do you mean?
Well, maybe he's sick
in there or something.
Can't get to the phone.
And as the manager, you could let us in,
just to see if he's okay.
I mean, if you're worried
about him or anything.
Should I be?
Let me get my keys.
- Leo wants to take a few shots for
the paper, then get a short interview.
- Great.
- Actually, he just wants Julien.
- Sure.
- Here we go, smile.
- Julien, I really need to talk to you.
- I'm busy right now.
- It'll just take a second.
Um, this is Tomas.
He's a friend.
Heard about our hero, huh?
Oh, yeah.
I knew him when.
- Um, this is Vanessa, my wife.
- Hi.
- Ah. Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Please?
Make it quick.
- What are you doing?
- You said talk to you later. It's later.
- Your wife looks incredible.
- What?
Almost fooled me. Wait a minute.
You really married a woman?
Watch your mouth.
Wait, look, look. Julien.
I got no place to stay, all right.
Can you help me out here?
Look, I'm married now.
You can't stay with me.
Married? Julien,
what about what we had?
That's not who I am anymore.
I've said good-bye to that part of my life.
Now I have to say
good-bye to you.
Look, if you don't help me...
you know what I'm gonna
have to do to survive?
Is that what
you want for me?
- Julien, the photographer's ready for you.
- All right.
- You should go.
- I'll be there in a minute.
If you don't want
to see me anymore, fine.
But don't tell me you can't help me out,
because I know you can.
Look!
Get a hotel for
a few nights on me. Here.
What kind of place takes cash?
I need a credit card
if I'm gonna get a room.
Here.
All right, I'll bring
this back when I'm done.
Just go, please.
He's not dead in there, is he?
No, ma'am.
You have one saved message.
Hey, yo, Frogger, this Kern Little.
I'm boys with Dante.
Yo, listen, bro, cops is looking for him.
They think you the key, man.
They on their way over there.
You there?
You better move your ass,
and don't tell 'em I told you.
- So what else was I supposed to do, man?
- Hey, look, I... I...
I don't blame you.
You feel like we screwed you.
- So you screwed us right back.
- Man!
Listen, let's see if we can't
start all over again.
I'm here, listening.
All right. In our earlier conversation,
what I was trying to get at...
is we made a mistake
in our previous business model.
We got in too deep.
Now, I just don't wanna...
make the same mistake
a second time.
We both learning
from our mistakes.
I can't do the same things I did for Rondell,
but I can provide some intel...
eliminate some competition,
do some favors.
- That's all I'm asking.
- I won't have the same room to maneuver...
unless I double my arrest quota.
I gotta get the big fish.
Look, I put my ass on the line with my boss.
I told him I'd get Dante.
We can help each other out,
but it's gotta start with you.
I've always been straight with you,
Kern, every time.
Yeah, I know.
All right, man.
I'll make some calls.
I'll find out what pad
the Frogger landed on.
I appreciate it.
Why do you think
she'd accuse you?
I don't know.
I had to put Evette on notice last week.
It was her second warning.
- About what?
- Well, take your pick.
She's late all the time.
She, uh, could give...
a rat's ass about
customer service.
Not exactly employee
of the month.
It's these girls. They take the job for the
discount and leave after six weeks.
As God is my witness,
I didn't touch her.
She says you told her she had to stay late
the other night.
Yeah, to... to help close up.
It's a two-person job.
So it was just
the two of you, then.
We totaled the receipts and took out the trash
and locked up and left.
I even walked her to her car.
So, got any dish
on Lanie's report?
No. What have you heard?
Nothing.
Just major cuts are coming.
Don't have to be psychic
to know that.
You'll, uh, put in a good word
for me, right?
- With who?
- Lanie.
You better
put that one in yourself.
- Come on. I've seen you two talking.
- Who's that?
Can I help you?
Uh, yes.
Um, an officer called me...
about my husband,
asked me to come down here.
- And your husband is...
- Bruce Rosen. What's going on?
I'm Detective Wagenbach.
This is Detective Wyms.
Why don't you take a seat?
- No. Just tell me, is my husband all right?
- Mrs. Rosen...
your husband's been accused of
allegedly raping one of his employees.
What? That's ridiculous.
There been accusations
like that in the past?
Of what, rape?
Of course not. He's never
been arrested in his life.
- Do you have a daughter?
- Yes.
- How old is she?
- Fourteen.
- We're gonna need to talk to her.
- Why?
The alleged victim's 16. If your husband did
have forcible sex with her...
- sometimes there's a pattern
that extends to the family.
- That's sick.
- It's procedure in these cases.
- Yeah, what's procedure?
To lock up an innocent man
and attack his family?
I want to see Bruce now.
Okay. Little man's asleep.
What's that?
Uh, from Matthew's teacher.
Progress report.
He's struggling.
- He seems the same to me.
- Yeah, that's the problem.
Oh, the roofer's coming Tuesday afternoon.
He's gonna give us a bid.
Um, Tuesday's not good.
I have a school thing for Cassidy.
School thing?
Yeah, um, room mother meeting.
Okay. I'll reschedule.
She said she had a school meeting
on Tuesday. She lied.
That's not the only thing
she's lying about.
If you file first, then the settlement
proceeds on your terms.
You get a much better shot
at more time with your kids...
maybe joint custody...
makes you look like
the wronged party.
- Wronged party?
- I gave him some of your details.
She took your kids without telling
you where she was going.
- She was scared.
- You call it scared. I call it kidnapping.
Gordon Jr. was 20 months
when my wife split.
You know what he calls
the asshole she married? Daddy.
- That's not gonna happen.
- Oh, really?
You don't move fast in this business,
you're gonna get run over.
- I don't know.
- In California, there's
a six-month holding period...
before a divorce becomes legal.
You two patch things up
before then...
you can withdraw the petition.
If you want to protect yourself,
you gotta move now.
Detective...
your kit's back.
Shouldn't you be out
doing something heroic?
Figured I'd give
someone else a chance.
Well, there was
bruising on her breast...
slight tearing
around the vagina.
- Consistent with her statement.
- Try not to look so happy...
- when reading rape kit results.
- Huh.
There's a lot of semen.
- She said Rosen wore a condom.
- Exactly.
Not only that,
most of the sperm was still alive.
Means it was less
than 24 hours old...
which means she had sex
the day after her rape.
That's not what she told me.
All right, I checked the plates
of those dudes following us.
The car belongs
to Trent's Auto Body.
T.A.B.
Tommy Aaron Bankston.
- The chief?
- It's code for the dummy shop...
North Hollywood created
to cover surveillance.
It means the guys tailing us
aren't Justice. They're us.
There's a department
budget code.
- Listed as I.A.
- I.A.D.?
You're way off.
I.A.D. only runs out of downtown.
It's gotta be another part
of the department.
Independent auditor.
Shit, those clowns
are on loan to Lanie Kellis.
She's had her little goons
up our asses.
Well, if she wants
to waste her time, let her.
Wait until she sees us bring in Dante.
- What up?
- Yo, Vic, I got a bead on Frog.
- Where at?
- Collin Greens.
I need a warrant fast.
You got a location on Dante?
No. Buddy of his named Frogger.
We think he knows where Dante is though.
Well, Dante's wanted federally.
If this guy's a material witness...
the fastest way is to get
a warrant from the feds.
If we want all the credit on this,
we gotta do the heavy lifting.
Where's this Frogger hiding?
- Collin Greens.
- That place is a zoo.
- We'll have to go in heavy.
- Can't.
Frogger's just a guy
who can lead us to Dante.
We go in full force,
Dante'll hightail it across 13 states.
- It's gotta be just me and my guys.
- This lead's solid?
Because if it's not
and this blows up in our faces...
- Lanie's got even more ammo.
- It's solid.
All right.
I'll call Judge Arias right now.
All right, listen. This place is the
tribal council for the Compton Crowns.
Best way up's gonna be the first stairwell
on the right. It's unmarked.
- They all are.
- Crowns making it hard for us to do our job?
Always. Only the people who live here
know which place is which.
- Well, how'd you find out?
- I got contacts here.
- Decent folks who hate living in a cell block.
- When did you talk to 'em?
4 a.m. I've been sitting on this place all night,
making sure Frogger didn't hop away.
That's great work.
Everybody ready?
Detective Mackey!
- Who the hell are you?
- Special Agent Vulpio, F.B.I.
We understand you're executing
a warrant involving Dante Fell.
- Who told you that?
- He's a federal fugitive.
We have jurisdiction in this case.
We're gonna go get our guy nice and quiet.
Then we can figure out who he belongs to.
You don't understand, Detective!
- You're not making any arrest
without us present!
- Shut up!
- Five-oh!
- Goddamn it, we gotta go right now!
- Which one is he in?
- It's that one! There!
All right, grab cover.
Goddamn it, grab some cover
and watch our backs.
Shane, let's go!
Shots fired! Shots fired!
- Where the hell is it coming from?
- I don't know!
Somebody call for backup!
On the ground!
On your knees right now!
Hands on your head right now!
- Are we clear?
- Clear!
All right, which one of you
is Frogger?
Huh? Which one?
Better question:
How the hell are we getting out of here?
We're having a problem
making this case.
Your daughter said that
Mr. Rosen wore a condom...
but the rape kit shows
the presence of semen.
My daughter was a virgin
before she was raped.
Well, the results also prove that she had
intercourse after the rape.
Did you know she was sexually active
with her boyfriend Miguel?
- That's not true.
- Maybe she thought you'd
find out she was having sex...
and made up a story
about her boss raping her.
No. It's not a story.
It's the truth.
I had sex with Miguel
two nights ago.
Girls who get raped on Friday night
don't usually have sex on Saturday.
He didn't rape you, did he?
What was it, Evette?
He...
He threatened to fire you,
so you fired back?
He raped me.
You say you fought him
to get away.
No bruises on your arms.
No skin under your nails.
Your story doesn't wash.
I don't believe you.
- You're lying.
- No, I'm not.
Mr. Rosen's bigger than you.
It seems odd he wouldn't leave a mark.
He did leave a mark.
Here... and here.
Why can't you believe that?
What? I saw you looking.
- You're mistaken.
- Where are you going?
I think we know what happened
in that store. Nothing.
This case is over.
No, it's not! He raped me!
He needs to pay.
If you don't help me,
I'll tell people that you just grabbed me.
You just did.
Now the whole world knows
you're a liar.
Let's go! Let's go!
All right, that's the room right up there, okay?
Secure the perimeter.
- Somebody already took
a couple of potshots at us.
- I ain't going out there!
- Don't worry. We got you covered.
Somebody takes a shot at you,
they might hit me by mistake!
Then tell me where Dante is.
- Let's go.
- Let's go. On your feet.
Get him in.
You take your own car.
Bring him upstairs to two.
What happened?
Is everyone okay?
Someone tipped off the feds about our bust.
One guess who.
- This is a federal case.
They had every right to know.
- They blew our covert entry...
put each one of my men in extreme danger,
you sanctimonious little bitch.
- I'll be sure to include that quote in my report.
- Include whatever you like.
Tell those amateurs you got following me
they might as well take the rest of the day off!
What are you,
about a buck thirty soaking wet, Froggy?
- Buck sixty.
- Hardly Compton Crown material.
Thank God your quarter bro
pushed through your membership.
- I earned my rep.
- Oh, yeah?
We'll see. Where's Dante?
- Don't know.
- Why's he in town?
- Oh, so he is in town?
Didn't say that.
Christ, this is gonna be easy.
Yes, it is.
Yeah?
You were right about Mackey.
He's not on the level.
You wanted me
to find some dirt on him.
I may have found something.
You have my word
your name will not be mentioned.
Today I saw him
committing a 225-02VC.
What is that?
He parked more than
six inches away from the curb.
- Excuse me?
- Look, if you want something
more than that, lady...
you're gonna have
to do it on your own.
- We've got proof.
- What proof?
It's what he used.
I'm gonna sue that man
and his store for everything.
- How'd you get that?
- I went through the trash
at the back of the store.
You went through three days
of store garbage to find this?
It was the only way
to make you believe me.
I was a virgin before he raped me.
What the hell's this?
Stop showing me those.
You know what really
makes me sick about these?
It's that your quarter bro
is responsible for all these deaths.
They're Crown casualties
from all his franchised cities.
And these are
just the innocents!
- What?
- These are three cops from San Antonio.
Where's Dante?
You're obstructing justice.
One of you's going to jail for this,
and you're not built for it.
But he is.
- I swear to God, if I see one more...
- He's at Mission Cross!
One of his girls is having a baby.
He's here for the birth
of his child?
It's his first son.
He kept it secret from everyone
except me he was a dad.
Ursula went into labor
last night.
Of course she did.
I'll let the chief know.
You can let him know after we
bring the suspect into custody.
We earned this, and no one
is beating us to this arrest.
- Ursula Hayes. What's her room number?
- Room 607.
Okay, you guys go through here.
- Mm-hmm.
You.
What are you doing?
Dante, put the baby down.
You need to put the baby down
right now and come with us.
Don't give us any trouble.
I won't.
Just give me a minute.
He's my boy.
Hey. It's okay, boy.
- I thought this was all over?
- Yeah, um...
they brought in
a used condom...
- and we have to handle it as evidence.
- A condom?
- She fished it out of the trash
in the back of the store.
- She what?
So how do we get this
cleared up?
We do a D.N.A. test
to rule you out.
- Great.
- We can have the nurse draw
blood within the hour...
- if we get your permission.
- Great.
What if I don't give
my permission?
Well, uh...
with probable cause,
we can get a warrant to draw the blood.
Bruce?
What did you do?
Did you...
It wasn't rape.
What do you mean?
She came on to me,
and I couldn't, uh, help myself.
The next day, um,
they blackmailed me.
She and her mom came,
said if I didn't pay 'em $5,000...
they'd go to the head office
and... and report me.
We don't have that kind of money.
I di...
I-I didn't rape her.
It was consensual.
I mean, I-I...
I even walked her
to her car afterwards.
You slept with a child!
Okay. All right.
You will never see
our daughter again!
- Okay.
- Never!
Another win for me
right before the final bell.
Maybe I won't need
your help to keep my job.
Listen.
I put in a good word for you.
- Thank you.
- Not because you're my partner.
Because you're a good detective.
And because you don't want to see
the partnership broken up, right?
Come with me, miss.
Yo, wassup?
How do this sound to you?
- Great.
- Great?
Man, she gonna knock
Lauryn Hill on her ass.
Couple of more scores,
bring in some more players...
get on tour,
build up the hype.
But, yo, I got word
on a couple of operations.
Think it might be
our best way back in.
Listen, Kern, uh,
we're not gonna be getting back in.
- What do you mean?
- I lied.
- What?
- I had to.
To get Dante.
It was important.
Lied to me?
Listen, me and my guys aren't
going down that road again.
We're out of the drug trade.
If you're smart,
you'll stay out too.
Otherwise, I'm gonna have to
come after you just like anybody else.
Stay out?
I called in my old crew.
I borrowed off
future transactions.
I don't got no more money coming in!
I came here to tell you straight up
what the deal was.
I owed you at least that much.
Man, you owe me
a shitload more than that!
I risked my ass on the line
to get you Frogger! You promised...
Hey, he broke his promise, all right?
So just get over it.
We can let this stand,
get past it.
I can make it up to you in some other way or...
you can start something.
- This is wrong, man.
- I know.
But you came up from nothing once before.
You can do it again.
- Can you drive it or not?
- Yeah.
Jesus!
- Dude, what are you doing?
- Nothing... I got it. I got it.
- You guys all right?
- Yeah, why?
Well, I heard a garbage truck
sideswiped two parked cars.
- You heard about that?
- It was all over the police radio.
- Well, it took a little while
to figure out the controls.
- Jesus, come on!
This is supposed to be
a quiet operation.
We fumble like this during the actual
money train, we'll all end up in jail!
Sorry.
How long do we get to
keep the truck here?
- Property sweeps aren't
for another three weeks.
- Good.
Yeah.
We're really doing this,
aren't we?
Yeah, looks that way.
I want my credit card back.
Somebody canceled it anyway.
You're taking this stuff back.
No. I'm gonna sell it.
I need the money.
You're taking it back.
Take me back.
Keep away from me.
Keep away from my wife.
- I'm leaving.
- Good-bye.
When my report
comes out next week...
it will hit like an earthquake.
- So we'll all be buried in the rubble?
- Not you.
I'm recommending that you be
elevated to captain, take over here...
and run things the way
they should be.
You have integrity.
You tell the truth.
The truth is your report
is only gonna cause a few tremors.
You're not the first civilian auditor
this department has had...
and in the end,
cops will protect cops.
Outrage will turn to apathy...
turn to, "Didn't something
happen there once?"
And it all goes back
to the way it was.
Maybe with someone like you in charge,
things might change.
I wouldn't want the job.
One officer saves a kid
from some car jackers.
My team hauls in a guy
the feds have been after for two years.
I really hope you got a plan
to fix things up around here.
I talked to the guy at the desk.
I know you're in here.
Vic!
Vic, I know you're in here!
Open the door!
Come on!
You have some stranger come
to the house at night and give me this?
- You're walking out on us?
- I'm not walking out on my kids.
- I'm protecting myself from you.
- From me?
From divorcing me.
From keeping them from me.
- You think I'm divorcing you?
- You're seeing a lawyer.
A friend of mine made me talk to him.
It doesn't mean that I'm filing.
Oh, that's bullshit.
You're seeing him again on Tuesday.
Jesus Christ, I have to sign some papers
to get my deposit back.
You said that we were trying to figure
things out. That... That's what you said.
You're just buying time...
to spring this on me.
N-No.
Don't touch me!
I can make you miserable too.