Oh, God.
Well, I can't say the content of
this report comes as a surprise.
The changes around here
can't just be cosmetic.
I agree.
On top of this mess, we have
a budget cut. No more O. T.
- What about a pay freeze?
- Done. Even the pension is taking a hit.
- Ayear longer to qualify, less in benefits.
- Jesus.
You think I like doing this
my first month on the job?
This squad is going to have to
cut its work force by 20%.
20%? How are we supposed to maintain our
arrest numbers with a depleted force?
We have to find a way.
Start with the disciplinary cases
and the retirement phase-outs.
Then fire whoever
you have to to get to 20%.
- You want me to choose who goes?
- You're the C.O. You know them best.
You want the blood on my hands,
not yours. I won't do it.
- Yes, you will.
- Why should I?
I'm on borrowed time here as it is.
You can't afford to lose your job...
the day before a close election.
For the moment,
you are still my employee.
I want the list of who's gone
by this evening.
- Tomas.
- Julien. Thanks for coming.
- This is Gary, my sponsor.
- I help with Julien's reorientation therapy.
Look, I came to tell you
to stop calling me.
There's no room
in my life for you.
You gotta be kidding me. And you brought
him along as muscle?
Look, Julien's made his intent
with you very clear.
Any further contact
is only gonna damage you both.
Listen, I got no place to stay.
I got no money.
- Shelters can help you.
- Stop trying to keep yourself
connected. It's over.
- You stay out of this!
- Tomas, I am married now. I have a son.
My life has to be
about them and God.
You fags can hide
behind Jesus all you want...
but you're not
fooling anybody.
That's enough.
You've been warned.
Gary!
- My eye!
- What's going on over there?
Look up, look, up, look up.
Oh, God.
All right, all right, all right.
There's a full five paragraphs
in the report...
on the Bob and Marcy case.
Well, it wasn't our finest hour.
I appreciate you
including yourself...
but everybody knows it was me who let the
suspects go with the victim in their trunk.
Jeffrey Cole, 14. Been missing since
as late as last night.
- Are you the parents?
- He's the father, but I'm the parent.
- Don't be like that.
- This wouldn't have happened
if he was still with me.
- When was the last time you saw Jeffrey?
- Last night when I left for work.
When I got back, I didn't want to wake
him. I shoulda checked on him earlier.
I live in Venice. I called everyone
we know there. Nothing!
We'll need a recent picture so the officers
can pass it around to everyone in the area.
- Maybe someone's seen him.
- There you go.
Oh, God. If anything's
happened to him...
I'll never forgive myself.
- The money train's moving up?
- We don't know...
but the ship the Armenians use to get the
money out of the country hits port tonight.
- It's not due for two weeks.
- According to the manifest...
it's scheduled to
ship out in two days.
The Armenians can't be onto us.
We've been careful.
Maybe they're just
changing things up...
- just trying to avoid a routine.
- Goddamn it.
There's no room for last-minute
surprises. This kills us.
- We can't just walk away
from the money train.
- Look, I know you need this.
- We all do!
- But I'm not takin' any chances.
At least let Ronnie and me try
to find out where they might be
moving the money train to.
Let's not give up yet.
All right.
But if this thing's
not rock solid, we're bailin'.
- What's your name?
- Kandle. You can light me
up at both ends.
Have you seen this boy
in the past 24 hours?
- Sorry, sister.
- Thanks.
I haven't read the report yet, but I
hear there's a whole paragraph...
on Armadillo getting stabbed
to death in the cage.
I saw you frisk him.
He got that knife some other way.
Yeah. Tell that
to the bosses. Sir.
Excuse me, sir. Have you
seen this boy recently?
Last night. Walking around.
He seemed a little lost.
- Sure it was him?
- He stood out from the sickos.
- Did you see which way he went?
- He got into a car.
On his own, or was he forced in?
I was running somebody's credit card,
and I looked up...
and the car drove off
with him in it.
What kind of car was it, sir?
Jeffrey attended school in Venice.
Dad lives here, wanted to take
his son in for a year.
Mom reluctantly agreed. Kid's only been
in Farmington for two months.
Hasn't really made
too many friends.
- What's that got to do
with him hitching a ride?
- Fits the profile.
Isolated, alienated, vulnerable. He's the perfect
candidate to be taken by an adult aggressor.
Two kids were snatched in that area
three months ago.
Both taken at different times,
bodies found weeks apart.
These are the two kids who were
duct-taped and shot in the face?
Yeah. One 12, the other 13.
Both sexually assaulted and tortured.
That's Brent's case. Talk to him. See if
there's anything else pertinent in his file.
We may only have a couple of hours.
Kid may already be dead.
I hate to say it, but our best
hope is that this deviant's...
got the boy chained up to a fence
somewhere, loves his ass so much...
- can't give it up for a few days.
- That's my son, asshole!
Hey, hey, hey! Get off him!
Get off him!
That's my son he's talking about!
He's talking about Jeffrey!
Goddamn it, stop it! It was a stupid
thing to say. Now calm down!
We're the ones that are
trying to help you, okay?
The only thing that's important right
now is finding your boy, right? Right?
Come on.
Let's go talk about it.
The idea of some monster and my boy.
We don't know yet
if that's what's happened.
Well, that's what that
goddamn detective said.
Look, Dutch-boy's people skills might not be
first-rate, but his detective work is.
He doesn't want to know my son.
Jeffrey's a good kid.
He's been through a lot of things,
but he's a good kid.
We're gonna do everything
we can to get him back to you.
- You too?
- Yeah. Me too.
How's the dad doing?
He'd be a lot better
if we found his kid.
- Look, this pedophilia
thing's not my strong suit.
- I can run with it.
Nah. If it's all the same
to you, I'd like to lend a hand.
Just tell me how to help.
Okay. Well, um, the first two victims
suffered sadistic torture ritual.
That stuff usually starts
at the fantasy level.
What, fantasy, as in kid flicks?
All three abductions took place
in the same neighborhood.
If the guy gets his victims there...
maybe he gets
his porn there too.
Vic and I'll run the smut shops, get names of
the K.Y. cowboys who prefer to ride ponies.
It won't be easy getting names from
a sex shop. Uh, privacy issues involved.
Maybe we can get around it.
Learn anything new?
I, uh, checked Brent's
files, ran the names...
of all the sex offenders who live in the
neighborhood where the boys were abducted.
- So did Brent. He didn't find anything.
- He didn't follow up.
A convicted child molester
lives in the neighborhood.
He just didn't register until after the
investigation. Our guys talked to him.
They didn't know
the connection.
Get Brent's files,
consolidate the two cases...
- and the two of you take the point.
- You got it.
Detective Wyms.
A pleasure to meet you.
I'm Chief Bankston.
Yes, I know.
My tour is done.
Would you mind walking me out?
Sure.
I read Ms. Kellis's report.
I haven't had a chance yet.
Well, she thinks you're
the best candidate to run this place.
That's a bit of an exaggeration.
- How do you think things are here?
- The barn has problems...
as deep as the report
indicates, but not as wide.
- Meaning?
- I'd rather not elaborate.
- So, about the job, then.
- I'm a detective, not a leader.
I do my work.
I go home. I like that.
Hey. We got
a missing kid, huh?
Yeah. Shane and I are running the
skin shops. I want you over in Venice.
- All right. What's there?
- The mom.
Find out who the kid's hangin' with.
See what they know about him.
Me and Ronnie'll
stay on the money tr...
Money what?
- Money, uh... Money trail, right?
- Yeah, right.
Yeah.
That's what the, uh...
Find out if the kid was using the dad's
credit or check cards, right?
- Yeah.
- All right. Let's get going. Come on.
Let's go, Ronnie.
Hi.
All right, man. See ya.
- "Me and Ronnie'll look
after the money train"?
- I stopped before I said it.
- Not before Tavon smelled it.
- I forgot. Tavon feels like one of us.
Yeah, well, he isn't one of us.
- We don't know who this guy
is yet, you understand?
- All right. I'm sorry.
You two are on edge about this
entire thing, and you pull that shit.
You know what? I screwed up.
Like it's never happened to you before?
I'm sorry, all right?
I'm sorry.
Hey, Julien, man, we just responded to
an assault victim at Mission Cross.
- Gary. I dropped him off.
- Poor guy's vision's blurry.
They say it may be permanent.
- Really?
- Yeah. And he said the guy who did it...
was wearing a ring or something and screwed
up his eye, and he didn't see who did it.
- Um, I... I saw him.
- What?
Who hit him.
His name is Tomas Motyashik.
- He's on parole.
- Okay. We'll pick him up.
Thanks.
What did Tomas do this time?
He went too far.
- Get out.
- Hey, hey, hey. You got a warrant?
I just busted a couple of guys cruising, asked
them where they got their jerk-off material.
- Well, it's still legal to sell pornography.
- They said you got a back room.
- How many back doors you got around here?
- I see one.
I want to see the warrant.
I'm not goin' anywhere
your regular customers don't go.
- Hey. What's in here?
- This is all legal.
- Child bondage films.
- No minors were used.
The faces were just digitally morphed
to make 'em look like kids.
- Yeah, hooray for Hollywood.
- Well, you may not like it...
but the Supreme Court says it's cool,
'cause no real kids got hurt.
Until some asshole watches this
and gets some ideas.
Technically, you're out of luck.
Yeah, well, technically, I see about
a dozen fire-code violations in here.
I'm gonna need a list
of your more deviant clients.
- Want me to call and get the
fire marshal on the horn?
- No, that won't be necessary.
Will it?
He looks very sweet.
We have a witness who saw Jeffrey get
into your car around 9:30 last night.
- How do you explain that?
- You better get yourself a better eyewitness.
- Why is that?
- I was at dinner at 9:30.
- With whom?
- A group of, uh...
like-minded individuals.
We talked about boys...
but we didn't have any for dessert.
You're not funny.
You're a monster.
Men who kill and torture
are monsters.
Not me.
You're a registered sex offender.
You molest children.
I have never molested a child.
I have only shared experiences
with those that give consent...
with those that yearn
to experience life.
These boys are flowers
looking to bloom.
I am their sun and their water.
Right.
This guy didn't do it. Makes my
stomach crawl, but he didn't do it.
I know. A 15-year-old named
Lydell Crouch was just abducted
from the same neighborhood.
Oh, Jesus.
Anyone see who did it?
No. It was in his house.
Window was broken.
- Kid's just missing.
- Wait a minute.
Maybe our predator's pathology...
is to abduct multiple boys
simultaneously.
- I don't want to hear this.
- In Brent's case, the first two
were killed at the same time.
Maybe our predator needs a voyeuristic
component to fulfill his fantasy...
forces them to interact sexually
or maybe molests one while
forcing the other one to watch.
The point is, if he needs
them both alive to get off...
there's a good chance
he hasn't killed Jeffrey yet.
Okay, thanks. Keep working
on the other friends.
- I'll run this freak list
against the D.M.V. records.
- Good.
You found anything yet?
- We're working on some good leads.
- What does that mean?
It means you're gonna have to trust me.
I'm doing everything I can.
Okay.
Um, one of my men spoke to one of
Jeffrey's friends over in Venice.
He said that Jeff's been depressed
lately. Is that true?
I guess.
I just thought he was
going through a phase.
I mean, he's a teenager. I missed
so much of his life after the divorce.
I just thought he was
acting out, you know?
You think he ran away and got in a car
with somebody he shouldn't have?
If he did run away, you have any idea
where he may have gone?
To his mom's.
I mean, she's the only one
that's really been there for him.
Julien, Julien! Come here.
Don't turn your back on me.
Not after all we've had together.
Oh, you got laid. Now you want to
just ignore me? Huh?
- That's right. I was his lover!
- Shut up! Now!
You loved me. Every night for a month.
You still love me!
You know what?
You can cool off upstairs.
- We did everything. Everything!
- Stop it!
- And now you won't help me?
- You got yourself in trouble.
- I didn't have anything to do with it.
- You can't admit who you are!
- Leave him alone!
- Your dick in my ass means you're gay.
- Shut up!
- My dick in your mouth
means you're really gay!
You okay?
Corrine subpoenaed your police jacket
and financial records...
froze your joint savings,
emptied your checking account.
Now, in my experience, no one goes
straight to DEFCON 5 the way she did...
without a reason.
The other night
when you served her the papers...
she came over
to my apartment.
You weren't alone?
You know this makes my job
a lot tougher, right?
Look, you gotta protect
my rights with my kids.
- That's the only thing that matters.
- I'll do the best I can...
but screwing some broad
and getting caught isn't going to help.
Look, I'm supposed to go over and see Cassidy
and help her with a science project.
If you had a predetermined
time to be with your kid, honor that.
Corrine?
Aw, come on, Corrine!
I know you're home!
You're such a good girl.
Corrine!
Matthew! Matthew!
You know what? Wait here
and keep an eye on your sister, okay?
Shit!
Corrine, what's the code?
- What are you doing here?
- Matthew was screaming.
Great!
- God. You broke the window?
- You changed the goddamn locks!
- To keep you out!
- It's my house!
- Not anymore.
I came here to see Cassidy.
You'll have to go through my lawyer
to set up a time from now on!
I'm not gonna schedule time with
your lawyer to see my children!
Then you're not gonna see them!
Megan!
- I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
- It's okay, Cassidy. Is she all right?
- No. It's scalding water!
- Let me see. Let me see.
She just got splashed.
She just got a little scared.
Just go!
Now!
Hello? Yeah, uh, the code?
"Little man"?
Yeah. No, we're okay. Thank you.
Matt?
You okay, little man?
Come on.
Okay. Okay.
Come here. Come here.
- Yes?
- Chief offer you my job?
Yes. I wasn't interested.
- Why not?
- Because I really don't
want to be you right now.
Hey, we think we've found a poss...
Where have you been the last hour?
- Taking care of some personal stuff.
- Do it on your own time.
You're either on this case
or you're not.
Shane cross-checked the kiddie porn
client list with the D.M.V.
We might have found
a possible match to the car.
- Might have?
- The same general description.
And his X-rated interests
are a match for our predator.
- That's not enough to satisfy a judge.
- It satisfies me.
Look, one of us better start getting creative
while this kid's still breathing.
Which won't be much longer if he follows
the same M.O. as his previous victims.
He killed both kids
within 30 hours of abduction.
Go around the warrant for now.
Pick him up on the street...
just for questioning.
I'll use kid gloves.
- That's okay, Adam. We'll drive.
- What'd I do?
- Two 14 year olds.
- Where'd you get the shiner?
One of'em fight back,
you sick prick?
- I didn't do anything.
- This used to be a church, man.
- If you lie in here, you're
going straight to hell.
- He's going there anyway.
Is that the guy?
Is that the one who...
Hey, hey. That's what
we're gonna find out.
I'm on this for you.
You stay here. You stay calm.
It's okay. Just go in there
and sit down.
We have a witness who saw Jeffrey Cole
getting into your car yesterday on Doverson.
I've never seen him before. Sorry.
- He barely looked. He's lying.
- You didn't even bother to look at the photo.
What about Lydell?
Did he fight back?
He give you that black eye
when you abducted him?
- I didn't abduct anyone.
- So they went along willingly.
Okay, that's not kidnapping.
That might help you.
We're dusting your car
for their prints.
If either of theirs turn up,
we'll know you're lying.
You know, I was told that you just
wanted to ask some questions.
Now, if you want to start treating me like
a suspect, I want to talk to my lawyer.
- You don't have a thing on him.
- Lawyering up this fast, we know he's lying.
Captain, patrol just found a body.
Looks like one of our kids.
- Over there.
- Mark it. Make sure
they pick it up later.
It's Lydell, our second missing kid.
Looks like two shots,
back of the head.
Be a while before the M.E.
Can determine sexual abuse.
Maybe Adam had Jeffrey
shoot Lydell...
his own twisted snuff film,
only without the film.
- Where do you get this stuff from?
- Hey, it happens.
- At least we got the creep in custody.
- For the moment.
- I don't like talking about this now.
- This is important.
- What?
- They cleared out the money
location, moved everything out.
That's it, then. We're out.
- Hold on.
- I hacked into the port computer.
The Armenians reserved a container with
a bigger break point than before.
- That means more money.
This thing is a gold mine.
- I just said we're out.
The company they're running the
shipment through filed for Chapter 11.
After this shipment, they're closing the
money train, moving it someplace else.
- Seattle, Frisco, who knows?
- And we're only gonna get one shot at this.
So we gotta take it. We have to
come up with a new plan right now.
Look, I'm done
talking about this.
I set up a series
of important rallies for you.
- You were supposed to be there.
- I'm sorry. I sent Aurora.
I am financing you
in this election, David.
Not your wife!
I have a very important case here.
I can't get away.
I need you to get
out on the streets...
and try to win every vote you can get,
especially now.
I have three dead children
and a missing one.
I'm overseeing
the investigation.
That takes precedent...
over scrambling
for a few hundred votes.
A few hundred votes will make
the difference, David.
- Well, right now
I have a job to do here.
- A job?
The chief is going to
take your job away. He told you so.
This primary is all you have,
and it's tomorrow.
You need to be out there.
I have a lot of important decisions
to make. I can't spare the time.
Sofer, what the hell's up
with your partner?
- What do you mean?
- This gay thing. You know about that?
I know that guy in the cage
is a total player.
- Sounded convincing to me.
- Yeah, and why would he lie about that?
Who knows?
That Arab widow came after me
for no reason.
- You killed her old man.
- You know, I think the question here is...
if Julien's lyin' about this,
then what else is Julien lying about?
And how could
we trust him now?
You know what?
Julien's a good cop.
- Most of the time, better than
the two of you combined.
- So it's true, then?
Grow up.
We need prints from his car.
Without prints, there's no warrant.
The lab says
three hours minimum.
His lawyer's gonna
be here in 20 minutes.
Now you give me five minutes
alone with him...
- And you'll what?
- Once he lawyers up, things get
much more difficult for us.
Okay.
How about this?
- Let him go. You wait for
the warrant. I'll follow him.
- Yeah.
- What could go wrong with that?
- What could go right is,
he leads us right to Jeffrey.
He might not be able
to resist the thrill.
Look, once his lawyer gets here,
he's gonna walk anyway.
All right.
- My lawyer here?
- Uh, no, not yet.
But, uh, there's been a mistake.
We were able to clear you as a suspect.
You're free to go.
I'm-I'm sorry for the inconvenience.
Shit.
- Damn it.
- Went straight home.
The one place we can't
bust in without a warrant.
- Well, what if Jeffrey's in there?
- Jesus.
Look, maybe we just tell a judge we
heard the kid screamin', had to go in.
If Jeffrey isn't in there, we've ruined
any shot we have at a legit arrest.
All right, so what do we do?
- Aw, man!
- Mmm-mm!
Hey, hey, Julien, what are...
It makes it awfully hard
to defend this place to the chief...
when I see crap like this.
Anyone who knows who did this
has an obligation to tell me.
Let's start acting like adults.
Okay, here they are.
- That's the son of a bitch's house.
- Yeah.
Once we're finally
able to go inside...
I'm gonna need you to identify
anything that belongs to your son.
- What are we waiting for?
- A search warrant.
The judge we pulled
is just left of Karl Marx.
- Our captain is trying to soften him up now.
- How long do you have to wait?
A while.
Maybe the rest of the day.
Wait a minute, man. My son is in there.
He could be doin'...
The law only allows us
so much latitude.
These guys have rights too.
I'm a cop.
I have to honor that.
Well, I'm not a cop.
That's true. Just a father
lookin' out for his son.
- You check this guy for a weapon?
- Yeah, I patted him down.
Good. This guy'd kill for his kid,
so let's be ready.
Ooh, that's a felony
in progress. Let's go.
Where is he?
Where's my son?
Where's my son? Where's Jeffrey?
- He was in my car, but I did not
kidnap him. I swear!
- That's enough!
- Stop! Right now!
- Where's Jeffrey?
Hey, he was in your car,
and you didn't kidnap him?
- Try again, you bastard!
- Where is he?
I just picked him up,
and I offered him $20 for a blow job.
Keep goin'!
We went behind a grocery, and then he pulled
a knife, stole my wallet and hit me.
- I did not kidnap him.
- You liar!
- Your son attacked me!
Let me get him!
Let me get him! Let me get him!
Hey, hold on.
Vic, where's Adam?
He's not our guy.
- How do you know?
- Ruled him out.
Doesn't have the kid.
Checked his house and everything.
I asked where's Adam.
He's at his house.
What did you do?
William...
you told me
Jeffrey was a good kid.
That's not what I'm hearin' now.
I never said he was a saint,
but he's got a good heart.
My guy in Venice talked to
some more of Jeffrey's friends.
He's been sellin' drugs. He's been
gettin' in fights, carrying a knife...
- No. No, not Jeffrey.
- We know he's been rollin'
queens with that knife.
Why, 'cause some baby-raper says so?
Look, another kid is dead.
I don't know how Jeffrey's involved in that.
He's not.
I'm sorry. I... I...
I know this is hard...
but you don't know Jeffrey as well as
you've been lettin' on, do ya?
- I need to leave.
- You need to help me find him.
I don't wanna hear this.
There's another boy dead.
His name is Lydell Crouch.
- Now, you need to think
about how his parents feel.
- I know how they feel.
I been helpin' you all day.
Now you're gonna help me.
Help you arrest my son?
No. I'm leavin'.
You can't arrest me.
Hey! Hey, what's the charge?
- Assault.
- Well, you had me do that!
No, I didn't.
I told you the facts.
You decided what to do with 'em.
Look, believe it or not,
I'm trying to help you.
Safest place you could be
right now is in here.
- What are you doing?
- I'm trying to salvage what's left of my job.
David, please, you can't.
It'll cost you the election.
Hey, at least I can do
the right thing here then.
- What do you gain by it?
- Nothing.
- Then why?
- Because I can't fire people arbitrarily...
or in between campaign stops.
You'll have no job
and no political career.
I won't do it.
You're gonna be
throwin' both away.
You don't think
I've thought of that?
Hey.
Okay.
Police!
- What happened?
- Nothin'.
I just wanna be left alone.
I saw Adam.
William went after him. Good thing
we were there in time to break it up.
So how did he know
where his house was?
Probably heard
somethin' around here.
You allowed an innocent man
to get the shit kicked out of him.
He's not innocent.
He's a pedophile.
But he's innocent
of this crime.
Ah, I'm sure he'll think twice before cruisin'
the school yard and committing his next crime.
But he's innocent now!
You just don't get that, do ya?
Boss!
Kyle Hutton.
He's a 15-year-old piece of work.
Jeffrey's friends in Venice say that he's
the only one that Jeffrey talks to anymore.
Cool.
I already told that monkey cop.
I don't know where he is.
What'd you just say?
- Nothin'.
- "Monkey cop."
You said it for a reason.
Come on. You got special
insights in life. Let's hear it.
80% of the world
doesn't look like you.
I'll bet that drives
you crazy, huh?
- Let's see how hard-core you really are.
- Don't touch me, faggot!
Nice.
Where'd you pick up
that party line?
The Internet?
Some angry short-order cook...
a couple of credits
short on his G.E.D.?
- I been reading.
- Jeffrey read those books in school?
No way.
That school's all Negro.
Jeffrey can't even walk
to class without gettin'jumped.
- He have any trouble with Lydell Crouch?
- Him and his homies. Yeah.
- So Jeffrey took out Lydell.
- I didn't say that.
What's Jeffrey's beef with the gay guys
over on Doverson?
No beef. Just for fun.
When we need cash, we pull a knife,
take their wallets.
They're not gonna
talk to the cops...
say they're tryin'to
fudge-pack some teenagers.
What'd Jeffrey
need money for last night?
A gun to kill Lydell with?
Is that what he was plannin'to do
with the rest of Lydell's buddies?
Come here!
You see that?
If there's one thing this country's good
at, it's incarcerating black males.
That's where they belong.
Yeah? Well, guess what?
It's one thing to chant "Heil Hitler"
in your buddy's rec room.
It's another thing entirely
to say it loud and proud...
in the exercise yard
at Pelican Bay.
You do the math and tell me exactly how it is
you think you're gonna survive down there.
With help
from the brotherhood.
I don't get it.
You got the attitude.
You got the tats.
Why would you help a nigger?
- I'd never do that.
- Well, you are right now.
- Jeff's father's a black guy.
- I've met his mom. She's pure.
His dad's not.
Look. See that guy right there?
That's Jeffrey's dad.
- No, it's not.
- Yes, it is.
Jeffrey never told you, did he?
Come on.
I'll go introduce you to him.
Then you'll tell me
where I can find Jeffrey.
- Jeffrey's a nigger?
- The worst kind.
Shane!
- Shane!
- Oh, God. Shane!
He's hit! Oh, God! Shane!
Drop it!
Everyone all right?
Shane took one in the vest.
Luckily the door slowed the bullet down first.
It's just a bruise.
Found this in Jeffrey's pocket.
It's a hit list and a map of
his victims' houses circled.
You got him before
his spree really started.
Lem got him.
- What's goin' on?
- Somebody called my house.
- They told Vanessa?
- They told Randall.
A 10-year-old boy.
They just threw it in his face.
- Oh, man, that's horrible.
- I made those choices.
- I can live with the consequences.
- Julien...
But why punish a little boy?
Keys.
Jeffrey was armed.
He was planning
on hurting other kids.
He shot another police officer
in the chest. We had no choice but to...
I really tried
to get him back to you.
I've got a ton of work to do.
Whoever killed those other
two boys is still out there.
Gotta comb through the rest of Brent's files,
make sure nothing else was missed...
probably re-interview witnesses.
Can't let the trail get too cold.
Probably not
gonna get much sleep.
I'll see ya in the morning.
Pitching him not to cut it so deeply
on the supplemental...
and that pencil-neck
deputy of his...
- uh, what's that... that guy Kelly...
- Kelly.
Pipes in and says,
"What about the supplemental?"
- And the...
- Excuse me.
I'm sorry to disturb your dinner.
It's quite all right.
What can I help you with?
If you offered me
that job, I'd take it.
- So now you want it?
- No, but I'd take it.
You always communicate in riddles?
I've kept
my head down long enough.
I don't like
what I'm seeing lately...
so it's either do something about it
or quit.
And I'm way too young to retire.
Enjoy your meal.
Look, I know you don't
wanna talk about this...
but me, Lem and Ronnie really think
that there might be...
- Money train's back on.
- What?
Look, I don't know
how we're gonna do it, but we are.
We have to make it work...
because we do need it
to get past all this.
The money train's our safety net.
The way things are changin'...
we're gonna need one soon.
Well.
I see you've been
doing your homework.
You have those names?
- Is this a joke?
- No.
I told you to cut
the work force by 20%.
- There are five names on this list.
- Those are the real problems.
The others are good, hardworking people
who deserve to keep their jobs.
- Vic Mackey?
- It all starts with him.
Shane Vendrell,
Ronald Gardocki...
Curtis Lemansky...
David Aceveda.
They couldn't
have done it without me.
That's all right.
I sent the same list to the Times
and a few of the news stations.
What?
The election is tomorrow.
This'll kill you.
I know.
It's the only way to pressure you into
doing something about the strike team...
once and for all.
Julien.
Listen, it's just a couple of guys.
They're assholes.
It's not the whole barn.
I need to get home
to my wife and son.
- Detective Vic Mackey?
- Yeah?
- You're wanted for questioning, sir.
- Excuse me?
Your ex-wife filed a domestic dispute
complaint, says you broke into her home.
First of all, it's my wife,
and it's my home.
I don't know the facts.
We're just here to affect the arrest.
- Jesus Christ. It's just a misunderstanding.
- I'm sorry.
I work here.
I know these people.
Please, can these wait
until we get outside?
You know I can't do that.
We need your gun.
Can you block the way, at least?
Gun.
Here.
- What in the hell is this?
- Corrine.
- We had an argument. It's a mistake.
- Jesus Christ.
- Ah, come on. Guys, it's bullshit.
- I'm sorry.
Hold on a second.
- I got him.
- Thanks.