Hello. You've reached the police
department's main switchboard.
Please listen carefully
to the following options
To be connected to a supervisor because one
of ourjackbooted thugs mistreated you...
and you want his goddamn badge,
press one.
- A cop I know sent it to me
- If you've committed a crime...
you think you can bullshit
your way out of,press two.
- It's great, isn't it?
- If you'd shut up and let us listen.
If you're shirtless and threatening
your girlfriend with a knife...
but don't want one of our officers
interfering with true love...
- press three.
- Priceless
To report an incident
of racial profiling...
- put down your crack pipe--
If you can't locate one of
your seven, unsupervised...
- fatherless children, press five.
- I need you
All right.
Let's all get back to work.
What's the status
on the custom car sting?
AGC? Ronnie's running
down the warrants
- I can see that
- As soon as the judge signs off
we'll start placing cameras and bugs
in all the high-end rides
- Prospects?
- Money laundering, drug running
There's even a studio guy who's selling
bootleg DVDs of his own movies
- How's your surveillance equipment?
- It's on loan from the feds
State of the art Ronnie's like
a kid with his first titty magazine
Good
- What's going on?
- Rodriguez has been working
with the chief s task force
to reduce violent crime
in Koreatown
I need your team to serve
a high-risk warrant
That's Charlie Kim
He's an enforcer for the K-town Killers
Oh, the prick who firebombed
a motel last year
when the manager started
hassling their hookers
Three people burned to death
Task force also thinks
that Kim is the triggerman
in four other homicides
They caught a break when
the owner of the motel agreed to testify
I want to show the Korean
community that helping us works
Just 'cause they call you ''the sheriff'
doesn't mean they think you're the law.
Convicting him with
a Korean eyewitness is a start
But I need this asshole
brought in alive
I'll do my best
Where is he now?
- He was spotted in an apartment
complex on Alexandria.
- Can we trust the tip?
Yes, but he doesn't stay in one spot
for long, so we gotta move now.
- You're late.
- I was at the hospital
- Tavon keeps getting better
- Oh, that's great.
He's got some body movement
Opens his eyes
- That's good news
- Yeah
Wait-- Is that--
Is that a wedding ring?
Yeah Yeah, viva Las Vegas
We, uh,just did it Sunday,
you know
- Wejust figured why wait?
Congratulations
Any more surprises?
Okay, then let's hand out one
or two of our own
Two original Thaeron-designed chairs were stolen
from a moving truck yesterday near Echo Park
Sara Dagit bought the chairs
at an estate auction
Her husband, Nick,
sits on the police commission
- Ten thousand dollars for a chair
- It's a felony
And my detectives are busy
Can you track them down?
Dagit's got friends
on the budget committee.
The last thing we need
are more cuts around here
A lot of these robberies
are inside jobs
Just find them
He's in Apartment 6 Kim rides
a riceburner, so watch the garage
Somebody get these kids on
the other side of the street right now!
- Go, go, go
- Across the street, honey, right now
Hurry Run
Go Come on Inside
Go!
- Go!
- Get down! Get down on the ground right now!
- You, down!
It's not him
Where's Charlie Kim?
Knock on some doors in case
he's in another apartment! Let's go!
Quick! Move!
Hey Hey, he's running!
Let's go!
- How'd he get behind us?
- Son of a bitch
- Hey, call it in.
Get a chopper on this guy.
- Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- Let's go. Come on.
She's breathing
She's still breathing
- Hey, let's get an ambulance in here!
- You kill him!
- He was the only one shooting--
- Shane
- Get these people back!
Come on
Ripped by:
Hound
Jesus Christ, Vic.
What the hell happened here?
Kim was in an apartment
in the building next door
He had a perfect sight line
into the unit that we stormed
- Who screwed up?
- I just saw two kids get shot
- Who didn't screw up?
- Who was in Kim's apartment?
Tourists A Korean couple
on their honeymoon
Do you at least know
who owned the building?
John Cho We're running
him down right now
Are you talking
to these people?
Yes, but they're not
talking back
If you're gonna get murdered,
it might as well be by your own kind
Hey, Vic
- Hey. We're looking for Charlie Kim.
- He just shot two kids
in front of one of your buildings
English, asshole.
We know you're American.
Why was he staying in one
of your apartments rent free?
These kids were seven and eight
One of'em's dead That matter to you?
It matters to me, asshole
Let's go Get your ass in the car
- What?
- Um, you're smiling
- I try it occasionally
- You had another date with James
- Detective Wagenbach
- That's what, like, three times this week?
- You look tired
That cat still
keeping you up all night?
No
Uh, yeah, give it to me
Thanks
- Armed robbery, 87 Cents Store
- Is there a profit in that?
- Eighty-seven cents here,
eighty-seven cents there
Pretty soon you're talking
about real money
- So is this getting serious?
- Oh,just stick to the case
Oh, it's serious
You can't even hide it
She wasn't your typical
stickup gal
- How's that?
- I've been robbed before
She was real nervous
Like it was her first time
You know how a woman is
her first time
- Not as well as I'd like to
I never thought she'd really shoot me,
but who wants to take the chance?
- Was she working alone?
- It was just her
She walked right up
and put a snub-nose in my face
- You get a good look at her?
- She was white, with a baseball cap
and sunglasses, so I didn't
see much of her face
- You're sure she was a woman?
- Oh
Surveillance cameras
caught the action
Could I get a copy of that?
I got robbed at gunpoint.
I'd like to show my wife
I heard Moses got promoted
over atJustice again
Yeah Not bad for a few guys
who couldn't even get into a frat, huh?
- So this is about the shootings
- We're looking for Charlie Kim
- People are blaming the department
for what happened
- Kim fired those shots
- I hope you catch him
- If he wasn't being protected, we would have
- What am I supposed to do?
- The people in the apartment
complex aren't cooperating.
Neither is the owner
I need to get through
There's a dead boy and a girl
in critical condition.
Come on, David.
You know Korean customs.
You don't trust the police
You don't trust anybody but your own kind
- Including the gangs?
- They serve a purpose
They create order, and they keep the black
and Latino bangers out
- Can your department do that?
- That is the old way of thinking It's gotta change
My advice to you
is to let things settle
Pick Kim up later, without
the threat of more violence
If the community blames us and we don't
handle this now, things will only get worse.
I need Kim I need your help
- I need a contact
- Okay, look I got life shit going on Okay?
I can't be
at y'all disposal 2 4-7
I drop this confession of
your third strike to the D.A....
and your schedule
clears up real fast
- You do business with Koreans?
- Yeah, if the yellows can bring the green--
I need a name-- someone who's
into something I can lean on
But they have to be tapped
into that community
There is this slant I do business with.
The chick is into I.D. theft.
- Where?
- She got a shop up off of Western
Look, do you feel like taking
your hand outta my ass now?
No And if this tip is a washout,
I'm gonna make a fist
Hey, listen, Aceveda's got us
tracking down these stolen chairs
We're running out of options You guys know
anybody plugged into the street trade?
- Meet Taylor
- How y'all doing?
- Married, huh?
- Yeah
Yeah, I can hardly
believe it myself
I'm sorry I missed that
Look, you sure you know
what you're doing?
I know what I want
Just--
Just don't make
the same mistakes I made.
You'll be fine
- People buy this shit?
- I'll believe that when I see it
- Can I help you?
- Tracy Pak?
- Yeah
- I understand you applied for a
confidential informant position
- No
- Yeah
- We're here for the interview
- Are you the cops?
- We'll talk in your office
- You can't go back there!
The Bank of Tracy.
- Nice setup.
- Pretty good interest rate on these?
- What is this?
- Let me run down the rules for you
There's no set number of tips
you have to provide us
but trust me,
I know if someone's sliding
You start sliding,
you get shut down
become the feds' problem
I judge my CIs by the quality
of their work, not the quantity
- Yeah, but quantity's good too
- If things don't get violent,
I'll let this operation slide
I'll even provide tips of police activity
that might be bad for business
Yeah, but you gotta
earn your way in first.
What?
- Charlie Kim
- I only know about 1 5 Charlie Kims
- You know the one I'm looking for
- I'm the wrong girl!
Really?
Are you the Tracy Pak that's about
to spend the next eight years
in federal prison
for credit card fraud?
Yeah, you're the right girl
So you got a knack
for finding things, huh?
Yes, I do And we can start
by finding your smile
- How about we find these?
- Damn, these some ugly-ass chairs!
They were stolen from a truck
in front of Burrito Castle on 6th.
They're worth about
$1 0,000 apiece
- Not to no black people, they're not
- I gotta agree
Looks like the 87 Cents Store
paid that much for their video camera
- Crosby Nell called
- The Treasury guy?
They picked up a suspect in the Armenian
money train robbery depositing marked bills
Looks like I still might solve
that double murder.
- Let's focus on our double robbery first
- Double?
A woman fitting our description
did a grab-and-dash...
at a nearby convenience store
this morning
Witness saw the suspect
get into a blue Civic
- Got a partial plate
- DMV's running it now
So she wasn't a virgin,
criminally speaking
We're already on a list
for an OT for Matthew
Now with Megan diagnosed,
we're in trouble
Sorry Thanks for waiting
We already assigned Matthew a therapist,
and he left because--
He had to take
a job out of town.
I wish I had
more therapists available
- But you do have some, right?
- A few.
We try to steer them to situations
with a high likelihood of success.
Megan's autism
isn't as bad as Matthew's
Her doctor said that treatment at
an early age can be quite effective
- You're separated?
- I spend as much time with the children as I can
You work full time
She's doing 30 hours a week
Private therapists
are expensive
Our workshops are designed for after-session
exercises with the children.
If you're both working, who's there
to do them with the children?
- We have several different babysitters
- We can't rely on babysitters
We'll take care of things at home
We'll figure out how to pay for it
Just find us someone, okay?
Later Hmm?
Okay
- ThatJames?
- Is that the partial plates?
You know,
if this is getting serious...
I can provide valuable insight
into the male psyche
- Pony up the DMV reports
- You'll let me know if I can help?
Three registered possibilities
in the area-- Donna Talic
Carl Grossey,
Henry and Angie Deitze
- Angie fits
- I ran them through N.C.I.C.
She's clean
But Hank is a whole
different animal
Looks like he's turning wife beating
into an Olympic sport
Multiple assault and batteries,
spousal abuse...
a couple of misdemeanor thefts
in his teens.
- Interesting
- I also ran a firearms background check
- He owns a 38 snub-nose
- Very interesting
- Got any insights on his psyche?
- I'd say he's just an asshole
- You got your boy helping you, huh?
- He wants what we want.
Well, all I want is another shot
at this Kim prick
- Detective, meet Neil O'Brien.
- A pleasure Right in here
Guess who Dutch-boy and his
Treasury bitch just brought in?
- O'Brien?
- No way
- Way
- Yes!
Those marked bills that we dropped on him
must've hit the banks.
Which means that
we're free and clear.
It feels good
Neil O'Brien Career criminal
Not associated with the Irish mob
or any other organization we know of
Last week, O'Brien deposited
$1 7,000 cash
into three LA bank accounts
all on the same day
- Some of that cash was on our marked bill list?
- All of it was on the list.
O'Brien's family is also from Indio,
where the money first got flagged.
Tie him to the two murders
and find out who his accomplices were
So this guy steals from the mob,
kills two of'em
just to get away with
a bunch of marked money?
I thought the Irish
were supposed to be lucky.
So Cho is afraid of Kim
He's afraid of what he might do to his tenants
So he pays him every month, and then lets Kim
move around to his different buildings
- How much contact did he have with Kim?
- Minimal
These are the addresses of other apartments
that Kim has access to
- He might be at one of them
- Stay sharp
- This is weird
- All the curtains are closed
- A setup?
- Watch our backs
This is it
- Go!
Shit
- Clear
Clear Shit
- It's cold
- Kim's probably on an underground
rickshaw to Seoul by now.
Damn it All right Knock on some doors,
not that it'll do any good
- Yeah, this is Detective Mackey Get me Aceveda
- Vic! Vic!
Get over here Our car, man
Our car Shit!
You better flag down
that rickshaw
Somebody wants us out ofhere.
Come on. Julien and I were already here.
The owner said
he never saw the chairs
Well, membership
has its privileges.
- Hey, Leroy! What's up? What's up?
Hey, no, no. They're cool, man.
They'rejust my ride.
Listen, did, uh-- Did anybody
come in here trying to flip these?
Skinny-ass, yeah He popped in
this morning, around 1 1 :00
So you lied to us?
Right pawnshop You just came
with the wrong brother
The clown wanted $200 for 'em.
I sent him packin
- You have any idea where he
might try to sell them next?
- Somebody looking for firewood
- Two hundred dollars
- They's some ugly-ass chairs, ain't they?
Thanks for the lift
- You all right?
- Yeah The car's a little overheated though
- So what do we have?
- If this was any other gang, I'd have him already
So we just sit and wait
for a break? No
- Can you think of anything we're missing?
- Sorry
Don't worry.
I'm not letting Kim win this.
You made some rather large
cash deposits recently, didn't you, Neil?
If you know,
why are you asking?
Seventeen thousand
to three different banks
- Where'd you get the money?
- I pinched my pennies
- That's a pretty big piggy bank
- Yeah, it's huge
- You're going to have to do better than that
- A friend owed it to me.
- Paid it back in a lump sum
- A good friend What's his name?
We'll need it
to verify your story
All right
I won it in Vegas
- I got hot What can I say?
- Which casino?
- A few different ones
- They have to report winnings to the IRS
- I never won that much at any one place
- They all have cameras.
Tell us which casinos,
we'll check it out.
- I forgot.
- You remember a pyramid? A pirate ship, maybe?
We've got time.
Think about it.
- Ronnie, we clear in here?
- Yeah, I swept it.
So, what's up?
Uh, Megan
was diagnosed with autism
It's not as severe as Matthew's,
but the quicker she gets care...
the better off she'll be
Okay
To get a therapist
for her and Matthew...
Corrine's gonna need
to stay home
I have to pick up
the financial slack.
I figured since the feds
are onto O'Brien
and off of Mara and Stella,
I could dip into the money train cash
Not a lot.Just enough to supplement
the weekly payments...
get them the help they need.
- What about the plan?
- That's why I'm asking
You guys discuss it
Whatever you decide,
I'll respect it
- All right
- All right?
Well, Vic needs this
Well, I say no.
Jesus, Lem. Come on.
These are his kids.
How good's it gonna be
for his kids if Vic's in jail?
- The feds are with O'Brien
right now They're off of us
- We don't know that for sure
He had the rest of the marked money.
We're in the clear.
Look, every time we spend a dime of that money,
some new shit storm smacks us in the face.
- I'm not going down on this
- Vic knows the score
He'll play it smart
Look, if we can't use the money
for something like this
then why the hell did we
steal it in the first place?
We said we wouldn't make the same
mistakes as the dumbasses we catch
We're not. We're not.
Vic's not thinking about
the big picture, all right?
He needs us to do it for him
- Well, what about you?
- I don't know
That 1 7 thou you stole?
It was marked by the U.S. Treasury.
- So?
- We were investigating the Armenian mob.
- That's who you stole it from
- They were marked so they could be traced
and the footprints
led right back to you, Neil.
There were at least three
other men involved in that robbery
You give us their names,
you get the best deal of the bunch
You're serious
I found the money on the street
- I did.
- Where? On the Yellow Brick Road?
Outside a bar off Pico.
I walked out to the parking lot.
It was in a bank bag on the ground,
so I took it I didn't steal it
- I swear to God.
- I've seen your sheet.
I've heard about a half dozen lies
come out of your mouth already.
You're in some serious shit
He was here Wanted a hundred bucks
for these torture racks
- He's lowering his prices
- You have any idea where he went?
Try the S&M club
Can you find my smile now?
I'm gonna talk to the other store owners
around here, see if they know anything.
He did leave a number,
just in case I change my mind.
I think I tossed it.
Uh, my man, my man, my man, is--
is she hooked up with anybody?
- I don't know
- Huh You know, man, I never,
ever hit a cop before
You think she takes charge in bed, or you figure
I'll have to break her down a little bit?
- She's my partner Shut up
- So what you saying? I'm not good enough?
- That's exactly what I'm saying
- Huh Okay
Well, we'll see
what she says, okay?
- Fine
- Yeah
Here it is It's one of these
Thank you
I thought you
had today off
Uh, yeah, I decided to catch up
on my paperwork
Computer systems down
over at Wilshire?
- The scenery's nicer over here
- You know, we keep meeting this way
one of these detectives might think
that we actually like each other
I'm speaking at a dog training seminar
next weekend in San Diego
and Hunter has to stay here
Do you feel like
going out of town?
We won't have to
look over our shoulders
I might be able
to free up my schedule
- Don't leave without saying good-bye
- Okay
- Mackey
- It's Tracy
There's a PC arcade
down on Vermont
One of those places where
the geeks play all day
- I know what it is
- A girl I know says Kim's there playing online
- I really don't like doing this
- Don't worry It gets easier
Kim's at a PC arcade
on Vermont
- There might be more children there
- We'll be careful
- Get down!
- Sir, don't move.
- Hands up!
- Hands up right now! Nobody move!
- Get your hands up. Get 'em up!
- Don't see him.
Not here
Ronnie
You see the guy
who was sitting here?
Was it Charlie Kim?
Hey, man, I'm talking to you
Left in a hurry.
Didn't even log out.
- How long ago?
- Six minutes.
- This is bullshit, man.
- I'm getting sick of this game
- Yeah, me too.
- You told Kim we were coming!
- No, I didn't!
- Nobody else knew we were on his ass!
- I told you where he was
- It's not my fault if you didn't find him
- Back room Grab everything
- It's evidence I'm throwing
someone's ass in jail today
- Oh, no! Please don't!
- Shut your face! I can't trust you
- I'm telling you the truth!
I saw a kid get killed today
That means no more second chances
I did what you told me
Look, I haven't had to pay
any protection money yet
but the K-town Killers will
get around to me
You're a better deal than
I'll ever get with Kim's boys
You got me
What are you doing?
She's right
She's not the only one who knew
- Sit down, Hank
- Slipped disk
Hurts like a bitch to stand back up
Besides, I can't stay long
- Where's your gun?
- At my house. Why?
- You sure it's not with your wife?
- She knows not to touch it
Then why was she sticking it
in a store clerk's face this morning?
You put a gun in her hand, she'd shake
too much to point it at anyone.
- Where is she now then?
- Temping
- Where?
- I don't know That's why they call it temping
Call me when you get things
straightened out
- We're not done here yet
My back!
Jesus Christ!
I want my lawyer
Now!
- Come here, school chum!
- Vic!
- He'll call you back
- Get in here
You want to make another call?
Have Kim come down here and meet us?
Huh? Come here!
- Vic! Vic, what are you doing?
- I found out why Kim's always
one step ahead of us
- Your friend here's been tipping him off
- He just assaulted me
- You're a witness
- Kim murdered a child, and you're protecting him?
- I can check your phone records
- I've discussed the situation
with community leaders
If they've chosen to warn him,
there's nothing I can do
- So they make the call for you instead!
- That's conspiracy
We don't want cops like him
intruding into our lives
- Look,just give us Kim
- I won't do that.
Then you'll get more cops,
not less
Grab every uni you can.
Turn their shops upside down.
I want every inch
of Koreatown smothered
Like white on rice
Gear up Time to tear
Koreatown a new one
What?
Oh, you voted
- Look, it's not that we don't wanna help you--
- It's okay.
It's probably the smart thing
Let's go We got a job to do
- Let's go!
All right We're looking
for Charlie Kim
He's a banger
with the K-town Killers
That makes today
''meet your local cop''day.
You see any violations,you write a ticket.
You see anything illegal,you bust it.
Anyone smarts off, you pop 'em
Any questions?
Then let's protect and serve
How'd it go with O'Brien?
The guy just set the world
record for speed-lying
The unis are passing out these photos
of Angie to all the local stores
- Hank's lawyer here yet?
-Just arrived Guess which bozo it is
- Who?
- Arreyo Gonzalez
The ambulance chaser
who's on all the city buses?
Mmm Greed knows no racial
nor ethnic boundaries
Can you say ''accidentes''?
Hey, y-you saw that I just
barely touched that guy, right?
Is that the officer
that assaulted you?
- That's him.
- We'll see you in civil court.
We'll see him
in criminal court.
The question we're trying
to answer is why a quiet...
mild-mannered housewife is
holding up convenience stores
- She's not.
- That's your forte, not your wife's
I was a kid. I lifted
a couple cases of suds.
Your landlord says you're three months
past due with the rent
- My disability ran out.
- So, you get stressed when you owe money?
No It makes me feel like I'm
lying on the beach drinking mai tais
- Next question
- You know the old joke,
''Do you still beat your wife?''
Well, do you?
- Next question.
- You've been bullying Angie for years
She's running around
knocking off stores in your car
- with your gun, and you
don't know nothing about it?
- No
You bought three boxes
of.38 slugs at Big Five last week.
- Why'd you buy the bullets?
- My neighborhood's turned to shit
I got a right to protect myself
We've got unis
outside your house
When Angie comes home, she's gonna
tell us that you put her up to it
She won't say it,
'cause I didn't do it.
She's afraid
of another beating
so he scares her into committing robberies
to put food on the table
She could be acting alone
Joanna Faulks had no idea her husband
was a rapist and a murderer
She's a battered woman
She's living under a bully's thumb
Everything we know
about this woman's thirdhand
Come on Everything we know tells us
that armed robbery isn't in her nature
We don't know what's in
her heart or mind
If I told you the worst five things I've done
in my life, I'll bet a few'd surprise you
- Something you want to confess?
- No Is there anything you want to tell me?
- I'm just saying, who knows
what secrets Angie's keeping?
Right?
- Surprise inspection
- We can find the kitchen.
- You ever heard of a refrigerator?
- Is clean
- Very safe We get ''A''
- So I see.
We know the wink-wink deal your
councilman has with the inspectors
No more grade fixing
Tell your customers to go home
You're shut down
You wanna keep us
out of your backyard?
You give us Charlie Kim
And tell your friends
I'll take this one
So, uh--
So you into music?
It's just that you look like
a woman that appreciates a live show
'Cause I'm the guy who can get you
anywhere you want Front row, dead center
So close you'd be able to lick
the sweat off the tip of Snoop's nose
- You know what I mean?
- Yeah, I don't think so
What is it? You don't date
black guys, is that it?
I dated a black guy once
I wasn't that impressed
Then you need to give me
that bitch's number
so I can go kick his ass for
killing it for the rest of us
I'm not joking
Put a stop to this,
before you can't fix the damage
- Give me Kim
- This is who we are.
- It's not perfect Are you?
- You used to rebel against that culture
I'm a businessman now
I'm going to be a leader someday
-Just like you, I have to make choices
- You made the wrong one
You say that now But when you're on city council
and you have to answer to your people--
- You lied to me
- Are you gonna tear your culture down then?
If they protected
a child killer,yes, I would.
What if they want to
speak Spanish in school?
What if they want
a driver's license?
Are you gonna be the same poli sci major
who used to talk about changing things?
My people are not gonna leave
Koreatown without Charlie Kim
You want us out,
you know what you need to do.
Yeah?
I think we have something
628 Bennet Street
A local businessman
is hiding Kim in his house.
Hey, drop it
We're on the move
Hey! Option one is
we take him alive
But feel free
to consider option two
Lemon, rush it! Rush it!
Go this way!
Get 'em up!
We're clear in here.
Pussy
We got your number
from Angie Deitze's landlord.
He said
you two were friends
Thanks to Hank,
I'm her only friend
- Did that bastard hit her again?
- No Angie's got his gun
She's out there committing
armed robbery
Angie'd never do that.
Even to avoid another beating?
- We think Hank's making her do it
- No
Angie's a good person
She just wanted to--
- What?
- Nothing
She's running around with a gun
You need to tell us
before she hurts someone
She wanted to start a new life
Said if she got $4,000, $5,000,
it might get her away from Hank
- Why 5,000?
- Half for her and the rest for his rent
She didn't want him to get
tossed out on the street.
Angie has a good heart.
You're free to go
I'm still waiting
for an apology
Your wife's out there robbing places
so she can leave you
- You've lost her.
- Okay Yeah
We spoke to her friend, Ginnie
Apparently she'd rather
risk a lifetime in jail...
than spend another
single day with you
- And who can blame her?
- Not me
- Shut up!
- Your, uh-- Your back feeling better?
Sit down.
Don't aggravate your injury.
Sit somewhere else.
I want you out of my house.
I don't see it. It's not on the--
It's right here It's to the left I'm sorry
It's right there, right there, right there
- Afternoon
- Ain't no trouble out here
Except you forgot
your bishop was pinned
- Your bitch is mine
- Are these your chairs, gentlemen?
- Why? You wanna buy them?
- They're stolen property.
- You wanna tell us where you got 'em?
- We get our 1 0 bucks back?
Yeah, we can get you
your 1 0 bucks back
Damn
She finally
got away from Hank.
I saw that police flyer. I recognized
the bitch the second she walked in.
She started pulling out her gun.
I guess mine was a little faster.
We're gonna need to
take an official statement.
Okay. How long to
wheel her out ofhere?
- Excuse me?
- So I can reopen my store
Make yourself at home
- Not a scratch on him
- Against my better judgment
Now we can get our trial, and Koreatown
can see what we're trying to do
Might've lost
a few votes there today
I can afford to lose a few
Hey, listen
I'm gonna need some OT
About 1 5, 20 hours a week
I don't have any to give
Certainly not that much
My little one
has autism too
My boy and her are gonna
need private therapists
It's expensive
- I'm not sure what I can do
- If things come up--
security details, film jobs,
after-hours clubs--
If these things come up,
if you can think of me first?
You'll be spreading yourself
pretty thin
Look, this AGC sting operation's
important to me, the chief
- You can't afford to get sloppy once--
- I'm not gonna get sloppy
I'll see what I can do
- You're releasing him?
- He's sticking with his
''I found it on the street''story.
We'll look into his finances,
tap his phones, see who he calls
He's scared Stir things up,
see what drifts to the top
Are you okay?
You were quiet in there.
Yeah
- Work?
What happened today?
Nothing I'm fine
You told me not to leave
without saying good-bye.
That was four hours ago.
Let me see if I can make it
worth your while
This is so high school
I can get my sleeping bag
Meet me underneath
the grandstands later
- How's the schedule?
- You know what?
I'm gonna be in San Diego
next weekend
- Mm-hmm
- I'll call you when I can
- Okay
Sorry
That wasn't too unpleasant, huh?
Thanks for your help
And look-- look, I was--
I was serious about the concert, you know?
What kind of music
are you into?
Come on Listen-- Listen,
I get it, okay?
You're scared of getting
hooked up with a player, right?
But I'm not like that
I'd just-- No, listen
I would just like a chance
to get to know you
Are you serious,
or is this all part of the act?
I can't even believe
you'd ask me that I can't
Thanks again for your help
Okay
Come in
I'll buy you a drink
I didn't know there was
a reason to celebrate
To Matt and Megan
getting a therapist
Larry called They can have
someone here as soon as two weeks
That's great news
One of us is gonna need
to be here a lot more though
So, what are we gonna do?
How soon can you give notice?
Go ahead, say it
You expect it to be me
One of us
has to pay the bills
With overtime, I make plenty.
So why aren't you quitting?
Look, we gotta
get together on this
How does it feel
to get to be selfish?
Or don't you know because you're
''with the children as much as you can be''?
We both know you're
the best person to do this
Yeah
I know
Hey, man, where'd you go?
Took care of
some personal stuff
Uh, Vic, we just wanna explain
why we voted the way we did
- There's no need
- It's not like your kids aren't worth it. It's just--
I told you I'd respect
anything you guys decided
Besides, I've made other plans
Uh, hey, how about we grab
a beer then? I'm buying.
- Yeah? With your own money?
- Yeah, with my own money
I'm sorry I got some paperwork
I've gotta finish on Kim
See you tomorrow
How about you guys?
I got a wife
I gotta get back to
I hope you two are happy
We did the right thing