What,you didn't hear, dude?
Shane's getting married!
Smokes for everyone
Get 'em while they're hot
- Dutch.
- This mean you're coming off the market?
He's a family man now
He's gonna be stuck at home with a rug rat
- You're having a kid?
I didn't know you were married
- I'm not.
Must've been
an immaculate conception.
Congratulations. Who is she?
- She your cousin?
- Vic.
- Amazing thing is she's not a stripper.
- How's Mara feeling?
- She's got morning sickness already
It's crazy, isn't it, man?
I'm gonna be a daddy
- Yeah
Listen, we haven't talked plans
I don't know We may just elope
But whatever we do,
I want you there
Absolutely
- Someone call for a detective?
- That was me
Mrs Mackey? I didn't
know you worked here
- I just started Corrine Mackey
- Oh.
- Dutch Wagenbach You're Vic's wife, right?
- Yeah, technically
Dr. Genty asked me to call you.
- Hi
- Doctor
Patient came in with
a bad case of food poisoning
- It's his third time this month
- Fast food'll kill ya
- Especially when it's laced with thallium.
- Thallium. What's that?
Poison-- odorless, colorless,
almost impossible to detect.
Maybe someone's messing
with things at my grocery store
We'll look into that
We can check with the other hospitals
See if they have people
with similar symptoms
We'll need to go through your house, make
sure none of the packages were tampered with
Maybe it's a mix-up at the lab?
I mean, I feel better now
- We ran two different samples
- We have to ask, uh, but
did you try to poison yourself?
- God, no
- No cell phones here, please
- Okay
- Where did you eat today?
- Hello.
Home.
My brother stopped by. We had breakfast.
What about the other times
you got sick?
- Home, I think
- Your brother stop by then too?
Yeah He feels awful I give him shit
for being such a terrible cook
That was Aceveda.
You're on your own.
What's up?
I'm thinkin'
of transferring off the team
Why?
It's not as much fun
as I thought it'd be
- I'm not fitting in the way that I wanted
- You're wanted
- I know we're a tight bunch--
- There's no hard feelings
You're cool, but, uh--
Shane
- I need to be somewhere
where I can be the go-to guy
- Detective?
Just sit tight, okay?
I've got plans for you Trust me
Captain Aceveda and Detective Wyms
need to see you right away.
- 10-4, Mary-Queen 31--
Victim's Karen Rivas,
the homeless advocate.
She and her child were
apparently carjacked after a robbery
Fortunately, the baby's fine.
The owner and his son-- that's
three dead, including a public figure.
This is Claudette's case
Both teams will take her lead
Why both? We've knocked down
cases like this before
- So have they
- Don't worry, Mac-man
You can back us up at the arrest
We'll huddle in five.
You'll get your marching orders.
Random crime. No video.
Media attention.
- Lucky we're here
- Look, the boss ma'am's waiting
What do you say we, uh,
put down a few notes on this?
- First team to bring in the shooter wins
- Who needs money?
Why don't we put up something
that really counts, like your pride
All right, you guys lose,
Sasquatch here has to take a bath
- Better yet, how 'bout this?
- The losing team streaks through the Barn
- Very 1 97 4 of you
- You okay with that, Daddy?
- What sort ofbet is that?
- Put some money up
- Yeah, be a man
- Yeah.
- Real man puts his dignity on the line
What, afraid your boys
will fall short?
Look,you guys have ladies.
I got to be a gentleman, offer you an out.
Only ladies I see
are you pussies afraid to take this bet.
- Ooh!
- All right You're on
- Oh, and yours are gonna be off
- Yeah, we'll see
Ripped by:
Hound
Rivas was driving a 1 999
white Mercedes S-420
Vic, put your guys on finding it
Get the license plate and VI N number
Put out an APB
- You got it
- Unis combed the crowd.
Of course, no one seems to have seen anything
Walon, you find somebody who has
Annie, hit this crowd up again
Trish, across the street
- Eddie, hit the neighboring stores
- Male Hispanic.
Two of the cases inside were cleared out
Maybe the shooter was
looking for something special
Or maybe he couldn't get into the cash
register, took something so it wasn't a bust.
- Check the records See if something's missing
- Ronnie, you play bookworm
I know a fence who'll buy anything
Maybe the stuffll end up there
Good Find out what's missing
and then take Shane
Better yet, I'll get out there right now,
start hitting the fences
- Ronnie, call me with the info
- I'll come with you Let us know
Good luck
If the killer dumped the car,
it'll turn up.
Since he didn't get the till,
maybe he flipped it for a few bucks
- Let's hit the chop shops, see what breaks
- Good Report anything to me
- 'Kay.
Already got a witness
It was horrible
I-I heard shots
and then I saw this white guy
and this black girl run out
And they jacked this lady's car, shot her
dead, and threw her baby to the curb
And all I could do was scream
for somebody to call 9 1 1.
How come you didn't report
what you saw to us immediately?
I went home to change first,
put some makeup on
- Why?
- I saw all the cameras I need the tape
I been out here for six months
with nothing to show for it
- You can't land a gig without tape
- You're an actress?
You have any idea how tough it is?
Aren't you worried these killers
now know you can identify them?
- They don't know my name
- It's on the news, right?
- But they won't know where I live
- Are you in the phone book?
Y'all are gonna
protect me, right?
- Edixon?
- All right
Yo, Ronnie says the Decoy Squad
brought in some other witnesses
Aceveda's definitely
auditioning them to replace us
- Yeah, won't let it happen, man
- Damn straight Edixon!
Hey!
Edixon!
Hey, it's getting harder
to find you.
Took me all of two phone calls
today to track you down
- No lo visto.
- ¿No lo visto?
- No
- No Mercedes, huh?
- No, no Mercedes, no
- Nada
¿Nada?
Awww!
Not another chop shop, Edixon
Who's stealing for you?
Evil churro vendor?
- Policia! Now!
- Now
Hey, hey, bro.
- If I find Mercedes, I call, okay?
- Not good enough
You're gonna tell everyone that
you're looking to buy Pay top dollar
- ¿Claro?
- Yo
- Tavon, yo
- This is my partner, Shane
- What up?
Listen,
we're looking for some things
- They were taken from Ling's over on Fifth
- Mm, saw it on the news
Can't say I'm sorry
Those rat slants always did outbid me
Still, that's a rough way
to go out ofbusiness.
- Haven't seen any of it
- You sure?
'Cause if you already shelled out cash
for it, maybe you wouldn't want to say
Yeah, I'm sure
- What you doing back there?
- Like my partner says
just looking for a little
stolen bling-bling--
- stuff involved in a triple murder
- And I don't have it
- Yeah, what do you have?
- Yo, man, what's up with partner-boy?
Hey, Shane, Meaty's cool
If he says it ain't here, it ain't
- Shit!
- Got a license to sell these?
Serial numbers filed off
There's four in the box
Look, asshole,
I said I didn't see your shit.
- Now, leave mine alone
- Oh,yeah? You're under arrest.
- Turn around, skinny Let's go
- Hey, hey, Shane Come on What are you doing?
- Being an asshole
- Come on If it turns up, he'll call
- Not anymore
- See?
You gonna stand there?
Can I get a help, please?
Your cuffs, man
One pair just isn't doing it for this cat
Don't worry. There's thousands more.
Can we finish this later?
My 1 5 minutes are ticking away
- Sit down
- The truth is, I saw the sister good
But the white guy with her, they all
sort of-- It's hard to differentiate
- You know what I'm saying?
- Keep looking
- City just posted a $5,000 reward
- Reward?
We got a few chop shops
paying top dollar for '99 Benzes
If our shooters dump it,
my CI's will call
What about
the missing pawn items?
Ronnie just went through
the robbery victim's ledger
Turns out all the missing
items were jewelry
pawned by the same guy--
Dean Warrison
Maybe he came back for his stuff
Yeah, we went by his place,
but he moved out months ago.
Trying to track down his new crib.
We're also trying to figure out
who the Bonnie is to his Clyde
Robbery, breaking and entering,
drug possession
- That the man?
- Mmm
He's white Could be
He feels good I'm going to release the make
and model of the car to the press
let them know
we have two suspects
How's the Decoy Squad doing?
Rivas's AmEx card was used
about an hour ago at a gas station
Walon's talking
to the station clerk now
Kevin, you're here because
someone's trying to kill your brother.
We found traces of a deadly poison,
thallium, in Robert's stomach
Uh, that doesn't sound right
Especially since this is the third time
this month he's been hospitalized for it
Y-You-You think
he's trying to kill himself?
That's an interesting theory
Let's think it through
Robert's got a decent-paying job
He's been there for 1 2 years
He owns his house: seems to have
a lot of friends: no trouble dating:
- healthy--
- Besides the food poisoning
Besides the food poisoning
So
why would a guy like that
try to kill himself?
Depression?
Let's consider my theory
You're unemployed: been to rehab:
you're broke--
You really don't have a lot going on
But Robert made you
his insurance beneficiary
Then he suffers a rash of poisonings...
all after you come over
to cook food for him.
- A-A guy can't cook his brother breakfast
- Look at the facts, Kevin
You cook He gets poisoned
It's a little perspicuous,
don't you think?
You don't know what
''perspicuous'' means, do you?
You think you're smart enough to lie to me?
You think you're smart enough to convince
me you had nothing to do with this?
''Perspicuous'' means obvious
Oh, well, it's obvious you're a dick.
Talked to one of Dean Warrison's
drug buddies
Hadn't seen him for a while but
heard he moved in with some black girl
- Our Bonnie? What's the address?
- Still working on it
Well, work harder.
Our killer's running around out there...
and I don't wanna be running
around in here buck naked
Hell, I got nothin'
to be embarrassed about
- If I'd known, I'd have waxed my back
- I've seen you in the shower
- It's not your back you need to be worried about
- We gotta ID the girl
His jacket said that he was in rehab
- Run that down Maybe they met there
- All right
I've been fielding calls from chop shops all day
Nothing so far
Take the mug shot around to local motels
See if he's holed up somewhere
- Yeah, that's a good idea Whose mug shot?
- Nobody
- Oh, that's cold
- Not as cold as you're gonna be
I'm gonna crank up the AC
in the clubhouse so your sac shrinks
I'll shrink your sac
Detective? You know Carlos
Ah, Daily News?
Carlos is going to be covering our investigation
for a piece in the Sunday magazine
He's to have unlimited access
- How'd you get that assignment?
- It was your captain's idea
Sir, chief of police is on the phone.
Tell him I'll call him back
Have a seat
We'll get you started in a minute.
- I know you like the limelight--
- It's not about me
A Good Samaritan gets killed
while running errands?
It feeds into everyone's
bad perceptions about Farmington
And how's his piece gonna read
if this case doesn't get solved?
- We have a suspect We're going to solve this
- It's never a slam dunk
You said you have everything
you need to crack this
So let's turn
this press coverage into a positive.
See about getting you three square meals
- Vic.
- What's up?
Shane arrested my CI
He ruined a five-year relationship
- and he's trying to make me look like a punk
- All right, all right, all right
- What's goin' on?
- Caught Fatboy Slim here
filing serial numbers
off a few handguns
- What's this have to do with our triple homicide?
- Nothing!
He's got his head up his ass,
and I told him-- back off
Hey,you don't tell me anything. I tell you.
- When Vic's not around, I am in charge
- My lead My guy
You believe this?
- Kick him
- Kick him?
I don't have time for bullshit! We're trying
to catch a killer before the Decoy Squad does.
- Sorry, brother.
- No need You ain't the bitch
Hey, I just did you a favor!
You open your mouth one more time,
you'll be begging me to only lock you up
Now get out! Get out!
Take your shit!
- What was that about?
- Passionate people having a difference of opinion
Trust me, it works
Can I speak to you?
Guess I'll take advantage
of that unlimited access
I, uh-- I went a little too far
with the poisoning victim's brother
- How'd you do that?
- Because you were down here
with your photo shoot
- and I was up there by myself
- Oh, so it's my fault?
Well, I-- I was trying something new.
Tryin' a, you know,
a curve ball to my fastball
Don't tell me you played bad cop
- You weren't up there to stop me!
- I knew you could handle this
Ninety percent of the time,yes.
But 1 0 percent, there's a connection
We-- It's like you--
Please, don't say I complete you
Go up there and give it
one more shot
- You go to a doctor!
- You coming?
- Yeah
- It's Julien's house
We got a call about a disturbance
Can we come in?
Sure
- Hey,Julien
- How you doin'?
- Maybe we should go?
- No! No, it's okay.
It was just verbal
I didn't realize it had gotten that loud
- Actually, the call came from this address
- What?
- Randall
- Ra--
Randall? Randall
Did you call 9 1 1, honey?
Baby, I'm sorry!
We didn't mean to scare you.
Mind if I speak to the boy, ma'am?
- Go ahead.
- I'm gonna have to talk to Vanessa
- Everything okay?
- Yes.
Are you feeling
threatened or unsafe?
Lord, no No
Look, everything is fine.
He has been through so much,
and it's hard on him.
The shame, the stress,
the surgery just--
- Surgery?
- For-For his back, after the beating.
He's already had one,
and it still hurts him.
He might need another one.
- I didn't know
Randall just got scared That's all
We're all right
The Decoy Squad got a call
from a motel clerk who saw the car
- They're talking with him now
- I got one better
Got an ID on Dean Warrison's
roommate The black female?
- Her name is Danielle Riggs
- You show the picture to the witness?
Positively ID'd her
as one of the carjackers
- Nice work
- Thanks More to do
- What was that before? Tavon and Shane?
- It's just two dogs humping
Well, if you can't pry them loose,
I can get my hose out
- I can handle it
- Because the Decoy Squad is working very well
I don't want any worries
with your team
Who's there? What, man, what?
You know they ain't in there!
I saw 'em both leave early
this morning
Check it out
Is this Danielle?
That her?
Yeah, that's her
She left with the white boy
- Damn it!
- All clear.
Here you go
Robert's gonna stay
in the hospital overnight
Just for observation,
it's nothing to worry about
So, uh, listen
I spoke to him again
He, uh--
He really cares about you
Practically threw me out ofhis room
when he found out we were talking to you.
- Hmm
- I can see there's a real bond there.
He says, uh, you've really
been trying hard lately
- Is that what he said?
- Yeah.
- You've blown a few opportunities in the past.
He's needed to bail you out.
He says it's added up
to 1 5 grand over the years
It's only 1 4 If the other investors
hadn't gotten cold feet
and pulled out, then, you know--
So you're, what,
one of these guys who, uh
it doesn't work out,
you just blame someone else?
And you're one of these guys who's always
just a dick?
I saw you and Lucas responded
to a domestic atJulien's
- How did you know about that?
- New policy
Any 91 1 call at an officer's
home address is flagged
- Everything all right?
- Yeah, it was nothing
Then why didn't you
put in the report?
I brought you back
to be straight with me
I thought our deal
was if I saw anything
All I saw was
a husband-wife argument
and a kid who got scared
and called 91 1
No special treatment
There's a complaint againstJulien
for excessive force and now this
- Should I be worried for him?
- I'll talk to him I'll let you know
Lem and Tavon
are sitting on the apartment.
Shane and Ronnie are
running down the girl's family
- If they're still in town, we're gonna nail 'em
- You won't have to look far
- We got him.
- Interrogation one
- You brought in our guy?
- Looks that way
- How'd you find him?
- Claudette gave us his sheet
I saw the drug possessions bust
We followed up, discovered
a treatment program he attended
We sat on
a few methadone clinics and bingo
- You busted him based on my tip
- Yeah
Oh, speaking of tips, uh,
give us a little preview-- cut or uncut?
Heard about the shooting
at the pawnshop, Dean?
Not really, no
Three people dead, shooter runs out
with a bunch of jewelry--
chains, rings, bracelets
All stuff you hocked
Just put him at the scene already
Got a witness
who saw you run out the store
- I wasn't there
- Sure you were
You and Danielle
I didn't go in that shop
It was Danielle
and my friend, Crazyhouse
- ''Crazyhouse''
- Danielle's boyfriend.
Got out of prison a couple months ago
He shot those people
Not me
Make me believe.
- I drove them there,
but I stayed in the car.
- He's not the shooter
Yeah, I believe him
Start stripping
I been staying with Danielle
Haven't been hitting her though
Needed some cash,
so I hocked a few things
- She didn't even miss 'em
- Get to it
Crazyhouse gets out, starts asking
about the jewelry he gave her
I fessed up He freaked out
Made me drive them to the shop
I stayed in the car
- When I heard shots, I jumped, man
- Damn!
Man, he must've jacked
that car after I split
And I didn't know
he was gonna kill no one.
- He's not the shooter.
- He's an accomplice.
- We said the shooter
- I don't know what the hell you're talking about.
We've got the killer's
name and his girl Find them
- You're welshing?
- The bet was who'd find the shooter first
That guy's the driver
Are you welshing?
- Okay Bet's still on
Yeah
Oh, got a little tip
about the missing car See ya
Eddie, it's half now,
halflater. That's always been our deal.
Police Hands up Up
Lookin' for someone?
I hear you're
lookin' to ditch a '99 Benz
Uh-- Uh, sorry
Can't help you Right, Eddie?
Don't shoot.
Who are you?
Oh, God.
Cut the crap. You set me up.
You're making an awful mistake
I don't think so.
I know who you are.
Long-lost friend
Tryin' to dump off Rivas's car
She might be able to lead
us to the shooters
How come you never called?
Hey, Vic.
- Thought you forgot my name.
- Welcome back
- Yeah
- How's it goin'?
- It's good
I hear you're mentoring
Julien, sort of
- What's going on?
- Nothin'
- You looking out for him?
- I just told Julien to stand up for himself
You mean like with Carlson
and his broken arm
I don't know how
Carlson broke his arm
I just know that no one's
gonna be giving Julien
another blanket party anytime soon
So, I hear you're going
to the city council
I just won the primary
The general election
isn't for a few months
Oh, yeah, but you're
running unopposed, right?
You can wait till all the votes are in before
making me the second Mrs Aceveda
Well, I'm sure the first Mrs. Aceveda
will have an objection or two.
Are your suspects usually so flirty?
- No Who are you?
- We're looking for two killers,
the same people that...
jacked that car
you were trying to sell
They left three people dead
Where are they?
I understand there's a reward?
- For information leading to their arrest
- I don't know where they are.
I mean,
I just work for a car broker
They called, said they were looking
to dump a '99 Benz
I heard Edixon was buying--
I mean, I didn't know it was the ride
you were looking for till I was arrested
So you never spoke to these people?
No
But I can tell you
where the car is
I was careful. You know, all that pristine
evidence,just sitting there.
- And what will it cost me?
-Just the reward, up front.
And my boss and I walk
Hasn't talked to our shooters? Please
She knows more than she's saying
We've got to find that car
- I'm going to give her immunity
- Then kick her
Let me follow her
See what angle she's playing
Heard you got a lead on the vehicle
Need us to run it down?
Sure. Car thiefjust
gave up the car. Give me a sec...
I'll give you the exact location
- Where have you been?
- Working a triple murder
- Can't get anywhere with the brother
He hates me
- What about the evidence?
- Did you go through the house?
- There's no trace of thallium anywhere
If he doesn't confess, he's gonna
walk out of here and do it again
Robert totally trusts him He can't
believe his brother poses any threat
What do you want me to do?
Let's recapitulate
Your brother is the success
You are not.
Your brother has lots of money
You're in the negative
Your brother is a well-adjusted,
caring individual
You are fratricidal
Which means
you're goin'tojail.
Is that perspicuous enough for you?
''Perspicuous'' You remember,
or should I get a dictionary?
- What the hell's going on?
- I'm interrogating a suspect
What is this shit?
Would you step outside?
Sorry. He's got an uncle
higher up on the force.
- We can't get rid of him
- She's just playing him I got here on merit
I've been doing this job
a lot longer than he has.
And he's always trying to teach me something,
like I don't know what I'm doin'
Sorry. I get worked up
just thinkin'about it.
- I get it
- Oh,yeah?
- I know someone like that
- No offense
he can't possibly be this bad
So what are you gonna do
about Tavon?
Booting the one black guy
we have on the team
isn't going to win us any
favors with a Hispanic captain...
a black chief
or a black nanny
- Besides, we need him.
- For what?
He's an outsider.
He keeps us sharp about the money train.
Bullshit.
We never needed him before.
It's my call.
Live with it.
- All right now, this could be it
Man, she's fast
All right
Move in, boys Move in
- Copy that.
- Get out. Hands up!
- Get outta the car!
- Outta the car!
- Get out!
Against the car!
Man, twice in one day!
Damn! It's a good thing
we're friends, huh?
- Is that your car?
- No, but I have immunity
- No, not on this one, you don't
- Vic!
You talked to the shooter
Now save the snow jobs for Aceveda
because I will press charges on this
They sold us the stolen Mercedes.
They need a new car to get out of town.
Hon,just let me
handle this, okay?
Look, we were gonna do the deal,
and then we were gonna turn them in I swear
So they were gonna pay you
for stolen wheels...
- and you were gonna get the reward?
- Somethin' like that
I got a new plan
- Man, I hope these two idiots don't blow it
- I'd worry about Chucklehead
- The future Mrs Aceveda'll do just fine
Gimme a second
- Yeah
- Vic, Cassidy's missing!
- What?
- She's missing
The babysitter thought
she was in her bedroom
- but when I got home, she's gone
- Did she run away?
- I think so
- Call the police
They're on their way over
I'll be right there
Cassidy's missing
- Shit, man. What do we do?
-Just get these guys!
Hey, wait a second, man
Who's-- Who's in charge?
We're a team
Just get it done
- Any word?
- I called all her friends No one's seen her
- Did you set up a perimeter?
- We have six units on it
Juvenile detectives have been notified
They're en route to set up a command center
Good Okay
- Her bike's missing
- Oh, good Probably means she left on her own
- Where would she go?
- I don't know
- Think!
- I'm thinking
- Were you here?
- Yes
- Did you hear anything?
- No
- Nothing? What were you doing?
- No.
- Vic!
- I was workin' with Matthew
- Let's go find her
What are you doing here?
Aceveda called in extra units
until those killers are in custody
Hey,Julien. You think maybe
you came back too early?
What?
Maybe you should've
stayed on disability some more.
Vanessa worries too much
Look, things are good for me now.
Better than they've ever been--
- here, at home
- I was at your home.
Come on,Julien
You're not yourself
I am
Yeah? Well, what happened
to Carlson then?
He got hurt
Yo, Ronnie. That's them.
- Gun!
- Shit! He blew it!
Everybody out of the way!
Everybody down!
We know she's your girlfriend, man.
Just let her go.
- I'll still kill her
- Okay
You got a car, man
Just go Go, man
- Ohh!
- Don't move!
- Get on your stomach! On your stomach!
- Hands out! Palms up!
- Bring 'em around! I got him.
- Get your ass up
- Yeah, let's go
- Was she upset or something?
- I told her she couldn't go
to Piper's for a sleepover
She lost it But I told her that
we were gonna talk about it tonight
- after I got home from work
- I thought you were taking night shifts?
- This was OT
- And then this happens
- Camilla was there.
And Owen was with Matthew.
- I don't even know Owen
And-And-And who the hell is Camilla?
Jesus Christ, Corrine--
We're getting a divorce!
I need to work! This is not my fault!
- Whose is it then?
- Vic, shut up
Just shut up!
- I didn't do it
Wha-- Wh-Wh-What is it?
It's a qua--
drophenia report
Positive traces of thallium
were found in your kitchen.
I didn't have any thallium
in my kitchen
Then how do you explain that?
Yeah, what--
What happens now?
Dutch gets his name in the papers
Egomaniac roped in a reporter
to do a story on him
- He's in the building
- So everybody'll know he busted me?
He was assigned the case.
He gets credit.
Well, uh--
What if I tell you what happened?
I guess that I'd get the credit
Well, it's not like you think.
I mean, I knew I could never pay
Robert back all that money
And the thallium, it just-- it--
it just seemed easier
than disappointing him again
- There! There!
- Stop Stop!
- Cass! Are you okay?
- Yep
Cass?
All right
Come on Let's go
Cassidy
Let's go!
Right now!
I decided to partner you up again
I thought Tommy and I
were doing well together, sir
You two have a history. This made more sense
for me. Do you have a problem with this?
Not ifJulien doesn't
Trust me. This'll work.
You'll start
riding together tomorrow.
Yes, sir
- How's Cass, man?
- She's good
Looks like you guys
didjust fine without me.
- Oh,yeah!
- That's right.
Lookee what we got
Now you can get
the chief on the phone
- The shooter's in custody?
- Oh! It's chilly in here
Somebody turn up
the air conditioning?
- How'd you find 'em?
- By runnin' my ass off
Wyms had us going over
the stolen car looking for nose hairs.
So, how 'bout a preview,
bikini or Brazilian?
- Hey
It's good stuff out there today
Avoided a shoot-out at the swap meet
- Could've got real ugly
- It's no biggie
Yes, it was.
It was great work.
Hey, you don't
have to go overboard
I do when I'm about
to ask someone a big favor.
- I need you to work it out with Shane
- Tell him
You could be the bigger man here
I dig what you do
- And Shane--
- He's a cracker with 'tude
He's just acting out,
'cause you're good
Help me make him feel secure
- Send him to a shrink
- I'm gonna talk to him too
But I'm asking you--
Take one for the team here, for me
Shit
Babe, what are we doing?
Maybe it's God's plan for us
just to have Randall
I want my own child too
- With you
- Randall is your child.
A man like Shane Vendrell can get
his woman pregnant without even trying
-Jesus!
- We're trying
- We'll just-- We'll keep trying
- You know what I mean
You're not comfortable I don't want
to start another fight about this
No fight I will go to the doctor,
and I will see what I can do
Two cases in one day
You're on a roll
You're the one who solved the poisoning
I was just your pawn
That's one way oflooking at it, I guess.
So, what's your story?
You running your two teams,
or are you
still a measly detective with me?
- I'm whatever you need me to be
- What if I need you to complete me?
Please don't say that
- Hey.
- What's goin' on?
- Your baby, man
Congratulations
I can't feel anything
Looks like
you're feeling somethin'
Look, man, um
- I was hoping we could talk
- Yeah, what about?
Figured we could, uh, work some shit out
How you feelin'?
As long as I have ginger ale
and crackers, I'm fine.
- Yeah
- So, you want anything?
- Just to clear the air
I'm gonna go check on the laundry
- Bye
- Thanks
All right Look
The Strike Team, that's your gig, okay?
You and Vic,you established it.
Everyone knows that.
- I just want to add what I can to the mix
- I appreciate that
But I don't wanna be along
for the ride if I'm not wanted
I wasn't tryin' to be a dick
But me and Vic built this thing
and I don't want somebody
coming in and screwing it up
I won't
You comin' here and apologizin',
I get that
Just as long as you know your place,
we'll be all right.
My place, huh?
What, like the back of the bus?
What, you think
you're driving the bus?
Damn it, Shane, you know what? He-He
doesn't want to hurt your little feelings
- But Vic has plans for me
- He's my best friend
He's been my best best friend
for seven years
You really think he's gonna
push me aside for some darkie?
- Get off
- Stop!
- Where you going?
- No! No! No!
- Where you going? Come here
- No No
- No No Stop!
- Come here! Come here!
- Let go of me!
- Baby, please!
- Let go of me! Let go of me! Let go of me!
- No No
Please Oh, my God
I wanted you to know.
That little problem before?
- All taken care of
- Good
My guys did good today
Just as long as they keep
their clothes on
Oh, you heard about that, huh?
Little wager--
good incentive for a great job
- Lucky you didn't lose
- I wasn't worried
No Lucky for us you didn't lose
Call 91 1 , man
Somebody
Get on there
This way, please
Let's go
Keep moving
- Cage is clear Give 'em a two-minute warning
- Hello?
- I spoke to Cassidy's teacher.
You know, the usual
''this is normal in a divorce kind of stuff''
- Well, what do we do now?
- We all need to sit down together
and work it out with a counselor
Listen, uh,
this wasn't your fault
- I was just-- I was out of my mind
- I know
- Okay Um--
- I'm just glad she's home
- Me too
- Okay
God
What's up with that?
- Yeah!
- Work it, Walon! Work it!
Work that mother, man!
I cannot believe that Shane
and Tavon just missed that