- Previously on The Shield-
- Ever killed something before?
There's a look in a thing's eyes.
They're on the edge of this great big hole...
and they'll do anything
not to fall in.
And at that last moment,
looking into their eyes-
You see the face of God.
[Hisses, Yowls]
[Claudette's Voice] Kleavon Gardner-
questioned in four homicides.
Maybe you, uh, happened by
this crime scene too?
Yeah. I didn't kill her.
He didn't even blink
at those photos.
Classic sociopathic
nonreaction.
- [Claudette] He's innocent.
- Guy's still a stone-cold killer.
Got a suspect and no victim.
That's new.
You ever suck a dick
like a cell bitch, cop?
- Suck it!
- [Coughing]
- I worked with Rich Nelson.
- How's he doin'?
Passed three years ago.
He was always talkin' about
how he was gonna piss on my grave.
[Snickering]
Rich Nelson and his task force
had a rough time nailing you...
- but they did.
- Took 13 years of my life.
Just found a crack in
Antwon Mitchell's family seal.
His oldest son, Donald ///'s been
moving fake /.D. 's out ofhis van.
I got an idea how to get him back
for all those sad Christmas mornings.
I don't like the dude, but I ain't gonna help
the white occupation take him down either.
They busted my son. They're comin'
to get me through my blood, man.
- Is this part of Antwon's operation?
- This block? Yeah, it's gotta be.
This is the little ho
that gave up my block.
- [Gunshots]
- Her body shows up...
with bullets in it
from your two gats...
you'll be doin' time
for a long, long time.
From now on,
I say, "Suck my dick,"
you say, " You want me
to lick your balls, Daddy?"
Pressure on the seizure program
is only gonna get more intense...
and when it does, that shit is gonna rise
straight to the surface.
- Find the leak.
- This surveillance tape's
from Shane's car last night.
How would you like to get that
little girl's body back? Body for a body.
- Who?
- Vic Mackey.
His body for hers.
Let me know when it's done.
- What's the matter with you?
- Bugged your car.
/t's you or me, right?
Antwon killed Angie right in front
of me and Army. He did it with our guns.
He's squeezing us.
Will you help me?
You had a gun to his head.
He's gonna tell you anything you want.
He was never comin' after me.
Trust me.
Be advised. We have two officers
unaccounted for. Requesting a tac alert.
- Captain- I mean, Councilman.
- It's just officer tonight.
- Oh, Jesus!
- Somebody's certainly making his point.
Antwon Mitchell's
hit the hardest.
Once we have the girl's body,
Antwon doesn't have any more leverage.
We dig her up,
extract our bullets-
- [Groaning]
- Pitarrio, you did something
for Mitchell. What was it?
- Antwon told me to move a body.
- Cops?
- I think it was a girl.
- Where?
Griffith Park, man-
by the horses.
Captain's arranged
a welcome wagon for Antwon.
How long you think it's gonna take him
to point a finger at me and Army?
I'll make sure it takes long enough
for us to get our leverage back.
- So what's your captain
gonna sweat me on, huh?
- I'll be in the room.
I'll steer the questioning
away from anything sensitive-
that is, if we're workin' together.
- We can only hold him 12 hours.
- She's buried in Griffith Park, near the horses...
- in three holes.
- Christ.
- Don't know what we're gonna throw at him yet.
- I have a couple aces.
Thanks for coming in, Antwon.
- [Footsteps Approaching]
- [Owl Hooting /n Distance]
[Curtis] So, how big's this rock
we're looking for anyway?
[Shane] /t's big, man.
/t's landmark-like.
- [Ronnie Grunts] Nothing.
- [Army] Me either.
Are we sure that's
the stables back there?
/ got the horseshit
on my shoes to prove it.
[Shane] Pitarrio said the girl's body's buried
200 yards south of the horses.
- [Army] Which way's south?
- [Ronnie] We are south.
This is supposed
to be the place.
[Shane] / don't know.
This doesn't feel right.
- [Curtis]Jesus Christ. This is bullshit.
- You got something to say?
No, I'm just looking for a dead girl's body
to keep your ass clean.
- You don't want to be here. Don't be.
- /'m not here for you.
- I'm here for her.
- [Horse Whinnies /n Distance]
Couldn't pass up a police escort.
I felt like the mayor of Crackertown.
Enjoy it now. Your next police escort
might not be a round-trip.
- [Door Opens]
- / thought we were being friendly.
Times like this, a community needs
to come together.
Here's the waiver. Says you agree to talk to us
without the presence of an attorney.
Waive my constitutional rights?
Let it be said that Antwon Mitchell
is all about the help.
Who killed our cops?
Way people feeling about y'all these days,
could've been anybody.
You've been speaking out
against the seizures.
Our dead cops were found
in a seized house.
You sure that wasn't
your idea of a protest song?
This may come as a big surprise
to you, but, uh...
there's a lot of shit that goes on
out there I ain't privy to.
That house is in Niner territory.
You're king of the One-niners.
You're telling me
you didn't order the hit.
Hear about it afterwards?
I just got off a plane.
I ain't even been back to the castle yet.
Yeah, that was convenient. Out of town just
long enough for two cops to get murdered.
You know what happens now,
don't you?
Investigation never ends. Ever.
Did you hear about Antwon's son...
Donald III?
- He's in County, isn't he?
- [Murmurs]
Turns out Don's been
a bad boy in lockup.
The surveillance camera caught him
in the bathroom with another inmate.
Guards say that he
wasn't forced.
Did you know that your son
was gay, Antwon?
Ooh, / didn't know your crew was
so friendly with the Mexicans.
Makes me got to wonder what would happen
if I pulled a few strings...
- and had him transferred to Folsom.
- Little Tijuana?
[Chuckles] He'd have
a line of boyfriends outside his cell.
/ want to know
who killed our cops.
When / come back,
you help me with that-
we'll talk about
how I can help your son.
I'll take care of that.
- I didn't know about the kid. There's cameras-
- You goddamn busted him.
- Check yourself.
- No.
You better check her.
Don't forget...
I got cards to play here too.
[Door Closes]
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Ends]
If you've got any more bombs to drop,
give me a heads-up now.
- You're doing great.
- I'd do better if you'd let me in on your intel.
No time. We've only got him for 12 hours.
/ want to get back in there.
I don't think that going after
Antwon's family is the best way to-
Somebody killed two of ours.
He knows who.
[Door Opens]
[Sighs]
Who killed our cops?
[Scoffs]
More yearbook photos?
These are the Mexi O.G. 's...
who are running, uh, gen pop at Folsom.
They all have one thing in common.
They want you dead.
Now they've got something else.
[Scoffs]
You some kind of special, lady.
Guess he's gonna have to learn
how to watch his own ass now.
- He ain't my problem.
- [Monica] Oh, / don't believe that.
I bet you're feeling
like a real bad dad...
for not being there
during the wonder years.
I mean, just think, if you
hadn't been away doing time...
maybeJunior wouldn't be
in the pokey doing dick.
I don't want to see anything
happen to your son.
It's bad enough having you
for a father.
So tell me about my cops...
and Donald will stay
right where he is.
You ain't got much regard
for a man's family, do you?
- I don't think much of you.
- I wasn't talking about me.
/ was talking about Rich Nelson.
You used to work together, right?
Way back when.
- This ain't about history, jerk-off.
- It's all about history.
Couldn't have had much respect
for his wife and kids either-
- you screwing him and all.
- I said, shut your face.
She ain't the only one
that went to the library.
Don't you want to hear
my book report?
Say what you gotta say.
When I was away...
I heard that you and Rich had a thing.
But / guess it didn't work out.
He went back home
to his unhappy family...
got the cancer...
and you moved on to take care
of mamas and their babies.
Now look at you.
Threatening to have my son
raped and killed.
How'd your old boyfriend
like the new you, huh?
Oh, he'd like me fine.
He had you put away, remember?
Oh, yeah, but /'m back now...
and he's long dead gone.
Get me a cup of water.
Room temperature.
This ain't it. The body's not here.
The ground was torn up, man.
/ mean, you saw it.
[Army]
By a mountain lion or something.
We're west of the stables.
The body's supposed to be south.
- [Sighs] This is where the rock is.
- Know what? I'm calling Vic.
He's got his hands full keeping
Antwon and Monica under control.
Instead of locking Antwon up. That shit's on you,
like all this other stuff.
- Why'd you bring him into this?
- Vic did that.
Probably wanted someone around
wasn't thinking about killing him.
- I never would have done that.
- We'll never know, 'cause Vic
got the drop on you first.
[Shovel Clatters]
Screw him.
- We can rule this guy out.
- What's the latest?
We're still following up
on the stolen J.P. necklace.
- Pulled these from Gang Central.
- We went all the way back to '98. Slim pickings.
Team's cleared
over 60 people so far.
Tips keep comin'. Two cops dead,
everybody wants a taste of the action.
No one's taking the claim?
Bragging to their buddies in the street?
Not yet.
Your best lead's upstairs.
For now, uh, Billings is gonna take the lead
on, uh, Scooby and Carl.
- [Dutch] You can't take us off this-
- Just temporarily.
Kleavon Gardner...
your possible serial killer from San Antonio-
You know this guy.
- What happened?
- Young female, black...
was grabbed on DuPont and strangled
in the vacant lot in Houseman.
A couple interrupted the attack,
but she died on the way to Mission Cross.
- How'd we get onto my friend?
- He was seen in the area.
A couple gave a description close enough,
so unis are bringing them in.
We close Kleavon, you move us
back to Carl and Scooby?
Maybe I can solve that
while you solve this.
- Looks like we've got him this time.
- Yeah, one victim too late.
You've got Antwon Mitchell upstairs?
What's his connection with
the gun supplier you arrested?
- It's not clear yet.
- But they're both involved
in Carl and Scooby's murders?
Yeah, I'd rather not discuss it
till we know more.
Oh, so you announce
you have your guy...
keep the streets quiet until
you get a lead on the real thing.
Smart call.
- You look terrible.
- Thanks. So do you.
You should go home,
get some sleep.
- So should you.
- [Laughs]
Thanks for your help.
/s Antwon keeping his mouth shut?
[Exhales]
Captain's pushing him pretty hard.
Meaning he's about
to start pushing back?
And all we got is a rock in the middle
of a pretty damn big woods.
Department's got a metal detector.
The girl was buried with, uh,
earrings, a belt buckle-
- It'll pick that up.
- Or Shane's bullets?
I don't know.
Look- Maybe we should just
step away from this thing.
- You mean away from Shane.
- /f / gotta choose...
between taking down Antwon
and covering for Shane-
- We're not there yet.
- You and I have both been living straight...
and now we're in deeper than ever
because of him.
/f we hadn't allowed ourselves to get pulled apart,
stopped looking out for each other...
Shane wouldn't have been in this mess.
/t's time for us to turn that around.
Like it or not, Shane's family.
[Door Closes]
- You goin' home?
- Yeah.
Hey, nice gettin' shot at
with you today.
[Pills Clattering]
Maybe next time two cops get murdered,
we'll be paired up again.
Maybe.
Hey, could be worse. Could be Carl and Scooby
making bad jokes about us.
You found them, huh?
[Whispers]
Yeah.
Did they, um-
- You know, were they-
- I don't think they suffered much.
Really?
/ heard it was pretty bad.
They had each been stabbed
several times.
But they had been moved
from another scene...
so the blood was minimal.
You know what? On second thought,
I don't want to know.
Yeah.
Me either.
- [Zipper Zipping]
- Thanks for riding with me.
- [Locker Door Closes]
- [Sniffs] You're lucky, you know?
You got family at home, waiting for you
to walk through the door.
Take care, Danny.
[Door Opens, Closes]
- About time.
- Who killed our cops?
Donald gets transferred out to Folsom next
Tuesday. I suggest you arrange a visit...
to say good-bye.
And I suggest you come down
out of that tower, ivory.
We all just taking a run at something feels better,
using the power in our hands.
Rich Nelson-
He was using his power.
Screwing you wasn't his only
indiscretion, was it?
He planted that blow in my car
and trumped up those trafficking charges...
becausejust like you all,
he had shit on me.
You had to know it.
Your boyfriend-
He cheated that evidence.
So what does that
make him, huh?
- You, for knowing?
- Do you want to talk about indiscretions?
Secrets in the dark?
How about when you were
a kid- 13, 14-
fat, not very popular...
burying your head under the covers
to drown out the screams of your baby sister?
Your six-year-old sister
that your daddy raped...
night after night.
And you couldn't stop it,
could you?
Too much of a coward to confront
your old man, but not your mama.
She emptied two loads
of buckshot into his gut.
So Daddy's dead, baby sister's
in the psych ward, and your mama?
She's doing life in Chino...
all because you couldn't
come out from under the covers.
But, oh, boy, you're
making up for it now.
Oh, yeah, you're street tough.
You're a gangster...
full of cop-killing rage.
But you're still too much of a coward
to even save your own son.
Cuff him.
End this now, man.
Give us a name,
somewhere we can look.
Maybe you ought
to take this out there...
ask around your own house.
What the hell
does that mean?
Heard a lot of street chatter about
a little girl, got herself killed...
because she was tangled up
with a dirty cop.
/f / heard it, maybe the murdered cops
heard it too...
got dead 'cause of it.
[Mackey]
Bullshit.
For you to figure out.
In the meantime...
I want my lawyer.
Now.
[Scoffs]
Hey, Julien. Watch commander
wants us to cover the cage tonight.
Won't be able
to sleep anyway.
I'll let Vanessa know.
/ saw Carl's wife before.
How's she doin'?
She's upset.
She's thinking about
suing the department.
- You're kidding.
- This didn't have to happen.
She sees that.
She sees that,
or you put it in her head?
It wasn't like that.
Okay, I'll be in the cage.
Take your time gettin' there.
You saw a black male- 30s-
running from the scene?
- He was about six feet, wearing jeans.
- No. He was wearing a tracksuit.
- [Man] Since when's a tracksuit made of denim?
- Don't tell me what I saw.
Can you describe anything else?
Hair? Distinguishing marks?
Just your average
shifty-looking black dude.
- No offense.
- Thank you.
He was clean-cut, the kind
you would bring home to Mom.
- At least from a distance.
- Sounds like you want to bone the guy.
- I don't think she meant it that way.
- Trust me. She meant it.
He thinks it's funny
making me feel like shit.
Think you could pick the man
out of a lineup?
- I could. She's useless.
- He's right. / have a terrible
track record picking out men.
[Man] /t's too bad that psycho
didn't cross your path.
[Woman]
Oh, you are-
- [Man] Arrest her.
- Arrest me?
Okay. Let's just calm down.
- If it was me smacking her around,
you'd lock me up!
- Asshole.
- Bitch!
- [Dutch] Okay. Take her away.
This is bullshit.
- He's the one you should arrest.
- Watch your step.
- He's stealing our cable.
- [Danny] Lady, two officers were killed today.
All right? Boosted cable's
just not a priority.
Lookin'good, Trina.
Lookin'real good.
Sir, step away
from the cage. Come on.
How about the stolen car parts
in our garage?
- You think you could make that a priority?
- She's lying.
Real crime is
how small his dick is.
Afraid that one's
not in the penal code.
Then search our garage.
Get him on grand theft.
/'ll give you permission
to search our house.
Dead victim,
no physical evidence...
two witnesses who failed
to pick Kleavon out of a six-pack-
We got nothin'.
Kleavon's logged more hours
in interrogation than the two of us.
If he's guilty...
he's not gonna crack unless
he's under some serious pressure.
Well, the M.E. 's initial report says
that the girl was strangled face-to-face.
- What are you doin'?
- I only have a hundred. I'm getting change.
I need some cash.
For gas.
If Kleavon thinks that girl is alive...
he'd know she could I.D. him.
He might want a deal.
/f we offer one,
he'll smell weakness.
Then we gotta get him to ask for one.
Let me get a run at it.
- He's got a thing for us black girls.
- [Scoffs]
Young woman was rushed
to Mission Cross for surgery.
They say she's a fighter.
50-50 she makes it.
Glad to hear it.
Sloppy work.
Not by me.
You're jittery.
Afraid of what she'll say
when she comes to?
Why should / be?
/ was home watching the game.
- Ask my sister.
- I will.
Then do it.
Let me out of here.
Last time you were here,
you were so calm 'cause you were innocent.
- What's different about tonight?
- Out of patience.
Seems like every time somebody shits
around here, y'all smell my ass.
Witnesses put you at the scene.
You sure you didn't leave your house?
- I went out for soda.
- You changed your story.
You were watchin' the game,
or you went out-Which is it?
/ never been arrested.
Never tried, never convicted,
never on probation.
Come and go as I please.
Look, /'m sorry that girl
got her neck wrung...
but it ain't my problem.
He wasn't gone long,
not more than five, 10 minutes.
Barely long enough
to get the sodas.
We have two witnesses who saw him
attack this girl. They chased him off.
They're wrong.
He has a habit of being in the vicinity
of murdered black girls.
That's what
the San Antonio police said...
and they've convinced you
of the same thing.
I know it's hard to believe
this of your own brother.
[Woman]
Kleavon is not a killer.
If he was- I'm his sister.
Believe me, I'd know it.
We had a woman in here last year
whose husband was a serial rapist.
She had no idea.
He said he was at work. Even took a job
that, uh, suited his other career.
/ don't think she really even
believed it when he confessed.
Then I'll pray for her.
But Kleavon was home with me.
He left for only a few minutes.
/s that enough time
for him to get the sodas...
stalk some girl
he doesn't even know...
drag her to a lot
and strangle her?
/s it?
[Door Opens]
- [Door Closes]
- [Sara] Nice place.
What are we doing here?
I was driving by. It felt right.
After last time, I think we need
to go over the rules again.
No bruising, no ripping out hair.
When I say stop, stop.
I heard on the news
about those two cops.
Died in the bottom
of some sewer.
Assholes overpowered them.
[Sighs, Chuckles]
Let me make you feel better.
I don't want to feel better.
My client and I need
to speak in private.
/'m surprised your client
can afford your services.
From ex-con to millionaire
rec center owner-That's quite a leap.
Earn your 500 an hour, ass-wipe.
Let me know when they're done.
Will do.
They can only hold you
six more hours.
No reason to say
one word more.
I need you to do me a favor
while I'm stuck here.
- What?
- Cover that camera first.
Our conversations are privileged.
They're not allowed to watch.
Humor me, Tom.
[Antwon]
Call Bobcat.
Tell him it's time to let the police
find that girl.
- [Tom] / don't want to hear anymore.
- [Antwon] Fine.
- [People Laughing]
- Just get him the message.
- What? What now?
- Pitarrio- He screwed us, man.
We've been north, south, east,
west of those damn stables.
What?
Captain's been digging
into Donald III.
Antwon's kid?
Turns out the kid's a come burper,
grabbing his ankles for Mexi inmates.
Sent Antwon over the edge.
He's got his piece-of-shit mouthpiece
setting things into motion.
- He's dropping the body?
- Anonymous tip could come in anytime.
Okay, uh-
Okay, we gotta go back to Pitarrio.
Have him be real damn clear this time
where Angie's body is.
Split up. One to his place,
one to the recycling center.
Uh, recycling center-
It's on Lexington.
- There are four of them.
- Forget it. You take the cut house?
Get some collateral this time,
so we know he's telling the truth.
- Okay.
- Hey.
- We still got time.
- Yeah, all right.
[Door Closes]
[Gasping]
Please! No!
No! No! No.
[Crying]
Please. Don't.
Don't.
[Gasping]
Come here.
Get on your knees.
- Not so hard.
- Huh?
- Open up, sweetheart.
- I said, not so hard.
[Grunting]
[Gasping]
- Let me see that pretty mouth, huh?
- Stop!
Ever suck a dick, huh?
Like a cell bitch?
- Huh?
- I said, stop it!
[Grunts, Gasps]
[Panting]
Did somebody do that to you-
- put a gun at your head?
- Shut up.
Just-
[Gasping]
[Retching]
[Spits, Gasps]
Look, whoever did...
whatever to you-
You didn't know they wouldn't
pull the trigger.
You probably knew they would.
/f you fought it, you'd be dead.
/t's not your fault.
You're not like that.
You're a good person.
A good person wouldn't
be here with you.
I don't want to ever
see you again.
Get out.
/ said, get out.
[Panting]
Leave.
- [Door Opens, Closes]
- [Sighs]
Your sister says you were gone
about half an hour.
No. She knows it was
five, 10 minutes.
Her statement puts
your alibi in jeopardy.
Those Texas boys were good at locking up
their colored folks on bullshit charges.
- Somehow I don't think you two
run the same scam.
- /f you needed soda...
there was a convenience store
two blocks away...
but you went a half a mile further
to a more expensive supermarket?
That convenience store
don't always stock my drink.
I didn't want to miss the game,
so I just went straight to the market.
The same grocery
near the victim's bus stop.
She passes it every Tuesday and Thursday
on her way home from teaching night school.
But you've been stalkin' her for weeks,
haven't you?
No, sir.
Our witnesses are here.
Ready to stand in the lineup?
That's him, Officer.
[Claudette]
Number four...
you're out of luck.
Dutch, you ready with
that second witness?
Four, keep your number up.
[Latin]
Psst. Put your hands up.
- Shh.
- You want Pitarrio?
- Yeah, Pitarrio.
- Good.
- I got too much to do today to get hauled in.
- Shh.
- Put your hands down.
- He's in the other room.
All right. Let's go.
Shut up.
Keep it down.
- [Continues]
- All right. Go on. Get out ofhere.
[Thuds]
Go.
- Mmm. Shit!
- Get up!
- Who are you?
- You met my friends yesterday.
- Asked about a little girl's body you buried.
- I told them.
Directions didn't work out.
Try again. No bullshit this time.
- South of the horses, man.
- You like lying about dead girls...
- as much as you like burying them?
- Screw you- [Grunts]
[Curtis]
Goddamn it! Shit.
Wipe it up.
Look, you tell me where the girl's buried,
and do not say the stables.
- What stables?
- You said the stables.
No. No, horses, man.
That go up and down?
- The m-The merry-go-round?
- Yeah.
The goddamn
merry-go-round! Christ.
- Where's your stash? Where's your stash?
- Ain't got no stash.
How many goddamn teeth
do you want to lose today?
- Where is it?
- It's in there.
Get up. Get your ass up.
- Where?
- It's in there, man.
All right. Don't move.
[Clattering]
We find the dead girl's body,
you get this back.
It's your last chance
to change your story.
200 yards south of the merry-go-round,
by the big rock, man.
Body's by the merry-go-round.
He said horses. He said horses.
So we've been in the wrong spot all night!
- Lem's on the way.
- I'll meet him there.
[Dog Barking /n Distance]
- Good morning.
- You're back.
Hey, sweetie.
- / missed you.
- [Sophia] / missed you too.
Those two officers-
- Did they find out who did it?
- No, not yet.
[Sighs]
It was a long night.
The drywall guy's coming today. Can you
leave a check before you go into the office?
Sure.
Actually I was, uh-
/ was thinking maybe
/ wouldn't go in today.
Maybe we could take Sophia
to the beach.
Oh, I don't want to get her
off her preschool schedule.
I found them.
Stabbed, tortured.
[Gasps]
Jesus, David.
We should try and do something
for their families.
I'm sorry.
For everything.
l- I've made mistakes,
trying to get out of this hole.
Okay, please don't.
Just don't.
Those two men,
lying on that ground-
/ don't want to spend another day
losing you and Sophia.
I spent the whole night worried
something happened to you.
- You didn't even call.
- I know. l-
I'll change things.
I'll get better.
It's over.
I swear.
[Gasps]
- I swear to God.
- [Sniffles]
Oh, shit.
[Chattering On Police Radio]
[Ronnie] There's overturned dirt
about a hundred yards back.
Andjust as we started digging,
the cops rolled up.
Wetback says horses.
We go to the real goddamn horses. [Laughs]
- What do you think, an hour
before they find that body?
- I don't know.
Sorry, man.
We tried our best.
Yeah.
Two witnesses,
two different lineups-
They both went right for ya.
Your witnesses-They're white?
Figured.
You know witness I.D.'s across race lines
don't hold up in court.
- You're a D.A. now, huh?
- Something I read once.
Whitey think we all look the same.
Isn't it true?
Same as us not knowing
one Chinaman from another.
The word of two white people
against one black man-
Isn't that enough for any jury?
Not this time. I wasn't there.
The doctors at Mission Cross called.
- The victim came to.
- She I.D.'d your brother as her assailant.
It's got to be a mistake.
You go to church regularly?
Every Sunday.
Never miss a service.
You said your brother left at 8:00,
came back 10 minutes later.
Five to 10.
Would you be willing to put your hand
on the Bible in court...
and swear to God on it?
Maybe it wasn't exactly 10 minutes...
but it didn't seem like much longer.
My goddamn card is in her pocket.
I mean, how long you think it's gonna take
for the captain to come straight at me?
About five minutes
before she comes at me.
- [Mackey] They haven't found the body yet.
- [Curtis] As far as we know.
- Goddamn it.
- [Shane] Look, man.
/'ve been involved in shootings.
My ballistics are on record.
Yours aren't.
Maybe you swap out your gun.
You can get out of this.
Yeah, they gotta bring the body
to the coroner.
We can't get in there during the day,
but maybe tonight-
Come on, man. Come on.
That's bullshit, and you know it.
Cameras all over the place.
Look, someone say it.
/'m goin'away.
We're gonna think of something.
Me going to jail and Antwon walking
out of here-That's not gonna happen.
I saw him shoot that little girl
four times.
So if /'m gonna go tojail for murder,
it may as well be for his.
- Don't be a dumb shit.
- He killed Angie. Probably our two cops.
This guy- He's evil.
/ put a bullet in his brain,
at least there's somejustice.
- We ain't deep enough?
- [Sighs]
They're gonna find that body
any minute.
I won't have another chance.
- No.
- This is my mess.
[Sighs] You guys did everything
that you could for me...
and / appreciate it, but, uh...
it's time for me to take care
of business myself.
We're not giving up to this guy.
Not to this guy.
- Let him do it.
- Shut up.
Well, Antwon's a problem
Shane can make go away.
Putting himself on the line
to protect us-
Make sure Mitchell
gets what he deserves-
That's the first good thing
he done in a while.
Now's not the time, Lem.
Let it go.
Aw, come on, man.
Lem's right.
I'm the one who got us
mixed up with Antwon.
/ let him back me into a corner
that / didn't know how to get out of.
Well, now I do.
This one's on me.
Yeah.
[/nhales, Exhales]
[Door Opens]
[Door Closes]
[Sighs]
You and me- We're gonna chat.
- I ain't chatting without my lawyer.
- This ain't about lawyers.
This is about you and me.
Stand up. I want
to look you in the eye.
Stand up.
You're not gonna get away
with killing that little girl.
What little girl, Detective?
Oh, you got it all, don't ya?
You got money.
You got power, respect!
[Chuckles] The hillbilly's been
listenin' to my speeches.
It's too bad about your son though.
Tell you what. /f my little boy
turned out to be a fag...
I don't know what I would do.
They say you're born that way.
You doin'his mother up the ass
when you knocked her up?
One time, doin' time
for a long time.
That poor little kid...
is gonna be found facedown
in a shower...
with a back full of shiv
and an ass full of come.
Word hits the street,
what's that gonna make you look like, huh?
I mean, your people don't cotton
to the homo vibe.
- My people ain't your worry.
- Yeah?
But you know what, man?
With all that money, all that power...
at the end of the day,
you're still just a nigger...
with a faggot nigger son!
And where's the respect in that, huh?
Where's the respect in that?
[Breathing Heavily]
[Chuckles]
[Handcuffs Clattering]
Now...
what were you sayin' about
my nigger faggot son?
Talk to you for a minute?
[Panting]
You don't get out of this
by getting dirtier.
You come clean,
to the captain-both of you.
- No. Come on, man. That's not gonna fly.
- We tell her the truth.
Antwon- He grabbed you up,
took your guns- He beat you.
Killed Angie. Used it to blackmail you
into working for him.
And we've got the proof on tape.
- There's a lot of other shit.
- Not on that video.
I can sell it.
- We've got him on tape soliciting
one cop to kill another cop.
- No.
No. Then it implicates you and Ronnie
for not coming clean sooner.
- Army gets dragged into this.
- We do this right, nobody goes down.
Don't underestimate
how much she wants Antwon.
Maybe.
Yeah. Look, I can't ask you to do that.
I'm offering.
But you know how this works.
Captain doesn't buy it, they will drag in
anybody that is close to me.
So we survive it together
or not at all.
[Sighs]
- One more thing.
- [Shane On TV] What?
[Antwon On TV] How would you like
to get that little girl's body back-
your bullets and all?
- Jesus Christ.
- Trade.
- Body for a body.
- [Shane] Who?
[Antwon] Vic Mackey.
His body for hers.
[Clicks]
- Shane and Army killed Angie?
- No. No.
Antwon did it.
Took their weapons,
beat the shit out of'em.
Then he shot Angie
with their guns.
He's had them
on the hook ever since.
How'd you get the tape?
You asked me to find the leak when
the drug warehouse came up empty.
I knew it wasn't Shane,
but I wasn't sure about Army...
so / bugged their
department vehicle.
Without my authorization.
But one word from you that I had
authorization to install that camera-
it's all good.
You told me to find the leak.
And when you did, you kept it from me.
For how long?
Couple of days. That's all.
Ronnie and l-
- We were going-
- Gardocki too? What about Lemansky?
- Are all you guys working things
behind my back?
- No.
We had to go through hours of video
before we found that.
/ confronted Shane.
We've been working it out.
I had to have time
to wrap my brain around it...
find a way to get Shane and Army
out from under Antwon...
- without them losing their careers.
- This isn't about careers.
He put a hit out on a cop.
You didn't come forward.
Carl and Scooby were killed.
I guess I wasn't thinking straight.
Not until we're minutes away from digging up
Angie's body with your guys' bullets in it.
Anonymous tip gives us
the location of that girl...
with Antwon in our house?
You're gonna find Shane's card
in that girl's pocket.
Now, if this wasn't a setup, you think
that Shane would've left that behind?
- Antwon's the bad guy here.
- And you guys are supposed to be the cops.
Shane needed my help.
His back was against the wall.
What would you have done
if it were Rich Nelson?
You goddamn leave him
out of this.
Tell them I want to talk to them.
[Antwon On TV] You've been tellin'me
he's behind all my misery.
You're a regular AutoZone, Morgan.
You're such a bitch.
Takes one to know one, asshole.
[Julien] You- over there.
You- over there.
Move.
Yeah, it sucks to be stuck
with the wrong person, huh?
[Monica]
Sit down.
One whiff of bullshit,
and my next call is I.A.D.
So explain to me
how Antwon got to you.
Uh, when that cul-de-sac
got busted, we, uh-
- Tried to tip him about that?
- No.
But after it went down, Army and /
figured that the girl going missing...
was his way
of sending a message.
So you went after him alone?
Well, there were two of us.
/ thought we had a handle.
I was wrong.
Not coming to me immediately
is a fireable offense.
He said he would hurt my family.
I have a three-month-old son.
I have a wife who shows open houses all day.
What was I supposed to do?
Carl had a wife.
Yeah, Scooby has a mother.
He was her only son.
What did you do for Antwon?
[Sighs]
I tipped him
about the drug warehouse.
/ busted a couple of rival dealers.
But when Mitchell asked me
to put a bullet into Vic...
I knew I had to come clean.
So you went to Mackey.
Well, he came to me
before / had a chance.
You'll take a polygraph.
I'll do whatever you need.
Army?
[Monica]
Take a seat.
- [Knocking On Door]
- Yep.
- Well?
- Uh, they'll take a lie detector.
I'll decide after that.
I was wrong not coming
to you right away...
but don't punish
two good cops because of it.
You think they're good cops-
you're a good cop.
/ get helping friends. /t's just-
[Laughs]
I asked you repeatedly
to find that leak...
and when you did,
you hid it from me.
You can use that tape...
to get Antwon Mitchell off the street
for the rest of his life...
or you can use it to hang me
and the rest of my guys.
Or I can do both.
[Door Opens, Closes]
- Your sister rescinded bail.
- What? Why?
She wasn't too thrilled when she found out
about the stuff you stole...
out of your mother's house
after she died.
- You told them that?
- Wanted the company.
The officers will be by to check out
the items in your attic later.
You can thank him for
giving us permission to search.
You know, he's into kiddie porn.
Hey, Barely Legal is exactly
what it says- legal.
Pretty detailed and reliable
for white folk.
[Scoffs]
- Am I under arrest?
- As soon as the statement's processed.
- We spoke to your sister again.
- / want to talk to her.
Can't let you do that.
You may taint her testimony.
She said you weren't watching the game.
You were watching the news.
- A report on the cop killings?
- Bet that gave you the itch, didn't it?
We were watching the game. They kept
breaking in with bulletins about those dead cops.
Let me ask you something.
- Why would somebody kill them?
- Ask them.
We're-We're really stumped on this.
Hypothetically,
why would somebody kill a cop?
- Why-Why would you?
- I didn't kill no cop.
- Hypothetically.
- Tell you what I think.
I think people are tired
of being treated like criminals-
tired of being hauled
into rooms like this...
asked a million questions
they don't know the answer to.
"Where were you last night? '"
"How'd you know the victim? '"
"Why'd you do it? '"
"What made you kill?"
You don't know nothin' about me.
I know I make you feel small.
- [Door Opens]
- Detectives?
Doctors called from Mission Cross.
Your victim's awake.
- Was that all right?
- Uh, yeah, thanks.
He was responding to you.
- No, I lost him.
- Because you stopped pushing.
I don't see the point in burying myself deeper
in his mind. There's nothing useful there.
What's wrong?
You all right?
- I'm fine.
- Then go in there and close him.
- [Sighs]
- [Tapping]
Van'll be by later.
- Will you make him stop looking at me?
- Back up.
There's a rumor going around that the money
in that donation jar is for a legal fund...
to hire a lawyer
to sue the department.
It is for whatever they need.
Same as when any officer dies.
People are really raw around here,
you know it?
It's not the time to start rubbing salt
into a wound.
Look, I didn't choose the timing.
I was your T.O.
You did not learn this from me.
Screwing the department?
Disobeying the captain?
Look, I understand that you're on edge
because of what happened.
But maybe what's really bothering you
is knowing that if people had listened to me...
Carl and Scooby might be alive.
You may not be a cop killer,
Kleavon...
but you definitely tried
to kill that girl last night.
Lana's talking.
She's /.D. 'd you
as her assailant.
You bought a case of soda
and two packs of Kools.
Grocery clerk said
you were in a hurry to leave.
An opportunity caught your eye.
She got off the M.T.A. bus, walked across
wearing her headphones.
You put your soda in the car,
followed her...
waiting for your moment.
You came at her head-on.
You wore latex gloves
to avoid prints...
but also for a surer grip.
Her neck was, uh, thin, weak.
Her panic excited you.
That's the whole point.
[Scoffs]
All you can think about is finishing.
Her carotid artery pulses...
needs to pump oxygen to the brain.
Her throat pops.
Her urine splashes the ground.
She cries.
All the fight is gone.
Her eyes roll back in her head.
It's over.
You look into those eyes...
and all you can see is darkness.
And almost immediately,
you feel guilty...
- wrong.
- Shut your mouth.
She told us what you did.
You expect me to believe...
that girl got strangled...
then came out of a coma
pointing a finger at me?
Well, that's what happened.
Is she in a coma, or is she
in surgery? It ain't both.
She was in a coma. She went into surgery
to open an airway to fix her crushed trachea.
Nah. I don't think you two
got your stories straight.
/ think /'ll wait...
visit her at the hospital...
and see if she can point me out.
[Sniffs]
[Antwon On TV] How would you like
to get that little girl's body back-
your bullets and all?
- [Shane] How?
- Trade.
Body for a body.
Who?
[Antwon On TV] Vic Mackey.
His body for hers.
- This is entrapment.
- Good luck on selling that one.
- /t's an illegal recording.
- Camera was placed in
a department issue vehicle.
On my authorization.
The Supreme Court says
that we're golden.
Plus our two officers
are willing to testify...
that you shot Angie Stubbs
with their weapons.
That and a murder-for-hire charge.
Next time you arrange a cop killing,
don't do it in a cop car.
[Antwon Grunting]
Let go.
Don't move.
Do you want to tell us
who killed our two men now?
Death penalty's off the table?
/ go back to Lompoc, right?
My son comin'with me?
You think there's anything I get out here
that I don't get on the inside?
Girls, cold brew-
You saw how I was livin'.
Life for me won't change.
Well, it'll be
different enough for us.
Who killed our two cops?
I don't know.
Who has their guns and radios?
Don't know.
This deal is no good
unless you give us everything.
Look, / told you
/ killed the girl.
Bang, bang.
The bitch deserved it.
Put a hit out on Mackey.
But / ain't had nothing to do with two dead cops.
You barking up the wrong tree with that one.
And while we're
on the subject of truth...
you ought to know something.
Vendrell and that burrito boy
he rolls with-
They were dirty way before
I got anything on them.
So you can tell them
I'll see 'em on the inside.
[Chuckling]
It's bullshit. He's just trying to take down
as many of us as he can.
You gonna let him have his way?
If they pass the lie detector,
they'll be fine.
[Door Opens]
We're releasing your brother.
The girl's dead.
Deep down you know we're right.
There's something wrong with him.
You just don't want to see it.
But now that you know,
things will add up.
If I'm living with a killer...
why hasn't he killed me?
He feels safe with you.
You've never suspected him.
So what do I do now?
Just act as if everything's normal.
But be careful.
Fatima.
- She's scared.
- Good.
Her first sleepless night...
- we'll be her first call.
- [Door Closes]
Money jar's gone.
Someone took it.
I guess someone has a problem
with the idea of suing the department.
Excuse us.
We're ready to go.
We worked it all out.
We'd like to drop the charges.
Well, you can just express
your undying affection to thejudge.
- You're not lettin' us go?
- Not till the van shows up
to take you downtown.
- Asshole.
- Bitch.
Captain showed Mitchell
our little home video.
Got him to confess to soliciting my death
and for killing Angie.
- [Exhales]
- Barely put up a fight.
- Hallelujah.
- What about Carl and Scooby?
Didn't give us anything on that one,
but we all get to go home.
Antwon's going tojail.
But what about the lie detector?
[Chuckles] After what we pulled off today,
polygraph's a piece of cake.
Couple of Vicodin, and you'll have 'em
believin'that you don'tjerk off.
- [Men Laughing]
- Rawling'll back you up.
That and all the backslapping
over gettin'Antwon-
- It's over.
- Free and clear.
Couldn't have gone down better
if we'd planned it.
Thank you.
Look, I know you didn't
want to, but-
Maybe this is just who we are.
- Me too.
- No, it isn't.
We had a problem.
We came together.
We solved it.
That's who we are.
From now on,
we got nothin'over us.
We got one thing to do.
Hit the streets, find the bad guys,
show 'em who's in charge.
Strike-Team style.
[Mackey] Starting with the pricks
who stabbed Scooby and Carl.
When the time comes, we'll be there
to see 'em get the needle.
/'ll sweat the baby bangers...
threaten to take away their P.S.P.'s
if they hold out on intel.
Well, anybody
that owes me a favor-
I'll just be real damn clear
that it's way past due.
For one, there's gonna be a lot more talkin'
with Antwon gone.
[Shane] / tell you what, man.
This whole thing is gonna shake up the street.
Bangers won't know which way to turn.
And then- Bam! There we'll be.
Mackey's coming up clean
the past six months.
You've been through
the seizure files?
Sloppy paperwork,
but it all reads fine.
- How about the evidence room?
- Nothing's missing or out of order.
I've been asking around the street
as much as I can without attracting attention.
I thought this would be good news.
Stay on Mackey.
All of his guys.
You sure?
I wish I wasn't.
- [Car Doors Slam]
- Here he comes.
[Mackey]
We got him, fellas.
Guess it's time for you
to lick my balls, Daddy.
Captain's not buying
your tall tales, Antwon.
She bought the one about me
knowing nothing about them dead cops.
You think some shit like that
goes down without my okay?
- Who?
- Who what?
- We're just whispering here.
- Those kind of whispers violate your deal.
Yeah. Not unless
you got 'em on tape.
You'll never find out
who offed them pigs.
I'll go to sleep every night
smiling on that one.
[Laughs] You'll go to sleep every night
in a 6-by-12, asshole.
[Man] Let's go.
In the van.
I'll find out who killed our boys...
- and I'm gonna wipe that smile
off his goddamn face.
- [Engine Starts]
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Continues]
[Ends]