Previously on The Shield...
You ever suck a dick like
a cell bitch, cop man?
I'm just gonna tell the whole
courtroom what went down with us.
Convince Juan
to miss his court date.
Took a 40-pound dumbbell to
the back of the head in County.
So Aceveda meets with
Juan and with Antwon.
Antwon gets a deal
and Juan gets killed.
I get to officially notify
you that Internal Affairs
is investigating your
famous strike team.
I'm representing
all 4 of these detectives.
Vic gave me some cash
in a bag a while ago.
How much?
65,000.
I've got lupus.
I've had it for 15 years.
You guys have a Fatima Gardner
sign in to see you this morning?
Her brother just
reported her missing.
Maybe she started
looking at you funny.
So you killed her
and reported her missing
so you can make yourself
look innocent.
No! Don't talk to me
like that!
I'll talk to you
any way I goddamn can.
You can't arrest me!
And you're not helping me!
I'll find her myself!
Uni says it looks like
rape. His own sister?
It's not Fatima.
You recognize the haircut?
It looks like I got under
Kleavon's skin after all.
Come on! The other division stinks!
Come on, Lem! One to
tie, two to win it, baby!
This guy's pitching is as
bad as his arrest record.
Let's go!
Strike.
This is it!
Here we go, Lem!
Big swing! Big swing!
Way to go!
Down! Down!
Safe!
Hey! There's no
contact allowed.
This is C-plus league softball,
for god's sake!
Oh, I tripped.
Bullshit! You gotta
call him out, Billy.
Will you guys calm down!
That's bullshit!
Cheap shot.
You know what?
You win some, you win some.
This ain't over!
Game's still tied, 6-6.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Back off!
Whoa! Jesus Christ!
If olympic division calls,
you tell them to shove it
up their ass!
Actually, Paul Reyes did
just call from olympic.
Is he still complaining
about the game?
That is a sore loser.
Let's call him back
and tell him
and tell him to shove it
up his ass times two.
Times two.
I think he wants
your help on a case.
Oh, sure. Tell him
I'll get right on it.
You know, Reyes is heading
up that citywide task force.
Maybe you better
give him a call.
All right.
Where's Sofer?
She called in sick...
and I can't do
her job and mine.
Goddammit!
I knew that baby
was gonna screw me.
Gardocki!
Got a minute?
No, he doesn't. I need him
for a special assignment.
I'm sure I can get him
freed up for an hour.
Who should I call?
Why don't you tickle
your balls on your own time?
I'll see you
in my office.
Not until his lawyer
gets down here.
Tell her to hurry.
We'll do that.
I'm gonna feel him out,
then maybe spring
Fatima's visit,
his missing death kit
on him,
look for a crack.
Actually, I'm gonna
go at him alone.
That's not your
decision.
It was his the minute he cut Pauline
Wahler's hair to look like mine.
Ok. Ok. Ok, good. Good.
He knows how I operate.
He thinks he's got
a bead on me.
You'll come at him
from a new angle.
I'm gonna watch on the
monitor, develop a game plan.
If you want me to jump in,
ask him if he wants you to
turn down the air conditioning.
It's a code.
Between San Antonio and here,
you've killed at least
8 women,
including one last night.
Your sister's missing
24 hours.
We think you
killed her, too.
Let's start talking.
If you're looking
for a rematch,
I left my cleats
back at the barn.
He left half his skin
on the dirt.
Unless it's the post-game
activities you're looking to finish.
You guys cheated us fair and
square. We'll get you next year.
Since when are you guys good losers?
Since I got the news my
task force was expanding.
I was thinking of offering
your team the new slot.
I hear the barn's
a sinking ship.
We could have discussed this over
a couple beers just as easily.
I was going to
after the game.
Didn't get the chance.
Figure we'd talk over
a couple bodies,
give me a chance
to see you in action.
I don't know
if you heard, uh...
I.A.D.'s had a wild hair
up their ass about us.
I've tangled with those
bastards a couple times.
It just means you're
getting shit done.
When this case is over,
we'll get those beers.
Hell, I'll even buy.
Let's go.
How old?
She was 2, maybe 3.
House belongs to
Maurizio Ochoa.
The dead woman's his
girlfriend, Jenny Rayball.
Shot 15 times.
We've picked up Ochoa
before. Deals meth.
Little girls name
was Violet.
Didn't Ochoa
get popped once
for busting up
his girlfriend?
Couple times.
Broke her jaw 6 months ago.
That sounds like
the crank talking.
Let me guess.
He took his stash
with him on the way out.
Ochoa hooked up with
a mexican cartel guy in Chino.
Convinced him he had
the chops to handle weight.
We've been set up
on Ochoa for 3 months.
Had our guy in place
to make the buy,
just waiting for
the word.
So, even if Ochoa didn't
do this, his business did.
He could be a rival slanger.
Either way, shot 15
times, it was personal.
We got to track down
Ochoa.
If he sticks his head up,
we'll be there to whack it.
We think he's sitting on a
hundred pounds of meth... to sell.
I looked into
your finances.
You know what I found?
Yeah. Nothing unusual.
How did you manage to hide
your dirty money so well, huh?
The only money that I get
is from my weekly paycheck.
You trying to tell me that you never
took just a little bit off the side?
Why don't you provide
some proof
before you accuse him
of a crime?
Ronnie, you got
an idea
where Mackey came up
with $65,000 in cash?
Don't answer that.
You said
you wanted some proof.
I think you're bullshitting.
Vendrell, he's got money he
can't account for, either,
which means
one of two things.
Either these guys don't
include you in their bounty,
which should
piss you off,
or you're the one guy who's
bright enough not to leave a trail.
Which one is it?
You just said you checked my
records and you didn't find anything.
And I don't keep track of how the
other guys balance their checkbooks.
Hmm. One lawyer
for 4 guys.
Who's looking out
for your interests?
Because from what I see,
she seems to be
more concerned
with steering the
conversation away from Mackey.
Who hired her
in the first place?
Because she's certainly not
looking out for your interests.
Let's go.
My client
is cooperating.
He's willing to answer any questions.
If you have another one,
you let us know.
Come on. Let's go.
Ronnie. Ronnie,
you've been disciplined.
You've been careful.
But not them.
They're gonna
screw this up.
bring you down
for a mistake that you
were too smart to make.
That's it.
Let's go.
We're gonna pick this up
later, ok?
How'd it go
with Kavanaugh?
He asked me if I knew where
you came up with $65,000 cash.
65? Exactly?
Yeah.
They've been going through our
financial records, all of them.
He said this in front of Becca? Yeah.
What did you do with your
share of the money train cash?
I gave it to Corrine
for the kids.
So then she gave you up
to Kavanaugh.
What else could it be?
You said she wasn't
calling you back.
Look, I'll get
into it.
Tell me another way he could
have known the exact number.
That's gonna look
great at trial.
Your ex-wife on the stand
talking about dirty money
we stole from
the armenian mob.
She doesn't know
how we got it,
and she's never testifying
against me in court.
Now let's go find Ochoa before he
dumps these drugs on the street.
MAN INSIDE
Yeah?
We're looking for
Maurizio Ochoa.
What for?
He won the lottery.
We're here to give him
a check.
Face down
like your little girl.
Just sorry I can't put
a bullet in your head.
Get up. Get up!
Fatima came to us.
Brought us this.
Whose blood is that?
It's not my shirt.
She also let my partner
into your house.
He found a death kit,
tape, gloves, a knife...
to control your victims
before strangling, I presume.
Fatima would never
have come to you.
Or maybe you found out
she visited us.
Or maybe she got so nervous,
she showed her hand.
She's known for a while
how you hunt women.
If that girl had
a problem with me,
believe me,
she'd let me know it.
Where are we gonna find
Fatima's body?
Why are you so sure
there's a body?
Detective, you wanted to know
of any hits on a Fatima Gardner.
$2,300 master card purchase at
Hahn's furniture store on Western.
Sounds stolen, but whoever took
it may know what happened to her.
I can't leave here.
Can you...
We'll run it down.
We'll get right back to you.
Thank you.
So, why did you follow
Fatima to L.A.?
So she'd continue
to look out for you?
I thought it was because
those Texas cops
had you pegged
for those murders,
so you decided to swim
to safer waters.
They got the wrong guy... just like you.
Those boys still
living in Jim Crow.
They see a proud
black man,
they're gonna come up with a reason
to put his ass
in jail.
Press him!
What about me?
I just gotta see a proud
black man behind bars, too?
Oh, you're just like
them Texas cops.
Racist white folk.
Don't try to convince me
that you're sitting there
because I'm some kind
of Uncle Tom.
No better than
a house nigger
called up to the master's
room each night.
Ok. This guy's got
a real need
for black women
to be subservient.
Last time you got
in his face,
he lost it
and killed a woman.
We've got him trapped
here, so press him... hard.
Don't take his shit.
Just fling it right
back in his face.
He'll get angry,
lose his balance.
I need some water.
Take him into interrogation,
twist him.
I'll be there in a minute.
When were you gonna tell me
about the $65,000?!
I wasn't.
First, you're being
persecuted,
then you're a prime suspect
in a cop killing,
and now you're just
a cop on the take?
Sometimes things
crossed our path.
Drugs, money.
Sometimes we took
a little to use later
to help with intel
on the street.
And some just ended up
in your pocket.
I gave it to my ex,
actually.
Looks like Kavanaugh
got to her.
I am trying to defend
you, do you get that?
I let you guys answer
Kavanaugh's questions
because I was told there
was nothing to hide.
If you really want me
to help you,
you better mend fences
with your ex...
and me.
We're not going to have
to worry about her.
We need to find out
what side she's on.
Look, I got two
autistic kids.
There's special schools,
doctors.
No, that's bullshit.
I'm not gonna use
my kids as an excuse.
It's bullshit.
It was easy, all right?
No fuss, no victims.
I was clearing twice as
many cases as anyone here.
I worked my ass off.
I knew I was making a
difference, so I took some for me.
Me!
The city got their
money's worth, trust me.
But that was then.
I'm not the same
person now.
Why? Because you got caught?
Because I want
to still be a cop.
Because I don't
want to be smeared
and pushed out of my job
by the same people
who patted me on
the back
every time I brought some
murdering rapist asshole in here!
Because I can do better.
But if I'm gonna have
a second chance at that,
I'm gonna need
your help to get it.
You don't shoot
your lady 15 times.
Not unless you want
the bitch extra-dead.
It wasn't enough
to break Jenny's jaw?
Send her to the hospital
last summer?
I lost it a few times
and messed her up.
But I never hurt Violet.
You had a hundred pounds of
mexican weight you wanted to unload.
What's another 30 pounds
to a little girl?
You knew we'd rip
the place up once we found'em,
so you had a choice.
You move two bloody bodies
or you move the drugs.
Lot easier to hide
your meth stash.
A lot less messy, too.
You shot your girlfriend
15 times,
you killed your daughter,
and then you pulled your product
down from the kitchen ceiling.
Wait. Are you saying the drugs
aren't in the crawl space?
That's what we're saying.
He stole'em.
He killed'em both.
Who? Ted Someshit. Her ex.
He's the guy.
Someshit?
Why are you so sure
it was him?
Some meth head.
And he never
got over the fact
that his woman
left him for me
while he was doing a
year and a half in Folsom.
He just got out
last month.
So he wasn't too happy
when he found out
about the daughter
that she had with you.
She wasn't my kid.
What?
Violet was his,
Someshit's.
He didn't even know.
That's the way
Jenny wanted it.
He's name's
not Someshit.
Shusett. Ted Shusett.
M.E. called. Nothing on
last nights "vic" we can use.
Not even a hair?
He's that good.
He's such a perfectionist.
He killed extemporaneously
without leaving a trace.
He's made the move from
organized killer
to thrill killer
without missing a beat.
But he knows it wasn't
his best work.
He got impatient.
He rushed it.
He's probably on edge about
leaving trace evidence behind.
Hit that hard.
He screwed up.
Didn't take his time.
Didn't plan it.
He knows he left himself
exposed by cutting the hair.
He said too much with that.
He's gotta be kicking
himself for it.
Hey. Don't let up.
See you later.
Well, now I know why you
won't return my calls.
Shouldn't you be at some Lamaze
class or something for your new baby?
Is that what
Kavanaugh told you?
Is it true,
that pregnant cop?
She didn't tell me
I was the father.
But you're a candidate?
Well, you must be
very proud.
So you told Kavanaugh about
the money out of spite?
No.
I gave you the money
for our kids.
You get angry at me
for a second,
and... and you want
to send me to jail?
No, I didn't want that.
He was looking
into our accounts.
We didn't declare
that money.
You want to put me in jail?
He's bluffing.
He wants me.
What kind of a man puts the mother
of his children in this position?
What did you want me to do?
Nothing. I wanted you
to say nothing.
I'm sorry, ok?
I didn't want to hurt you.
I'm sorry.
Ochoa's alibi checks out.
He was at a house party
in Whittier.
We got a lead on
Shusett.
Apartment on Rowena.
Good.
Listen, you guys should know.
I told Becca about some
of our money skimming.
You did what?
I had to explain
the 65 grand.
So you just confessed for all of us?
She's our attorney.
Maybe we need
to talk about that, too.
It's all privileged.
She has to know how best
to protect us.
Vendrell.
Why don't you come on
up here, spin the wheel?
Bring Becca.
I don't want her.
Hey, we can't take
any chances. Trust me.
Counselor.
Get on the ground
right now! Get down!
Get on the ground!
Don't move!
Hands up! Hands up!
Sorry to crash
the party, fellas.
Which one of you
is Ted Shusett?
He ain't here.
Who are you?
Billy Boyd.
That's my brother Jimmy.
You know where he is?
He comes by at night
to crash lately.
I don't know what he does
in the sunlight.
He kills people,
like his ex-girlfriend
and his kid, for example.
Here. You hear from him,
you call that number.
You don't, I'll have you
both arrested
for conspiracy
in their murders.
You must be doing ok.
You bought a $600,000 house
in Atwater 6 months ago.
How do you like
the area?
We don't live there.
That's right. Contractor
said you gutted it.
Everything new from
the ground up.
Do you have a question, lieutenant?
Actually, you pay
as you go.
He gives your wife
the bills,
and she writes
the checks.
And we save every
goddamn receipt,
every invoice,
every cashed check.
Everything
is accounted for.
You wanna see'em?
I already have.
I've seen everything.
As I.A.D., you're only entitled
to look at department pay stubs.
You need a subpoena for
any other financial history.
Every penny
is accounted for,
except for the normal, everyday
expenses of people living.
We scrape by. You wanna jump in here?
You get any help
from anybody?
Your friends? Your
family? Your relatives?
You doing anything to
make a little extra cash?
Don't answer that.
We're done.
Next time, you submit your questions
in writing
to my office.
I just want to know where
you get the extra money from.
Come on! Vendrell!
She's defending me
like we're guilty.
Why don't you just put it up
in big flashing neon lights?
I'm not the one with bags
of cash floating around.
And excuse me if I step
on his questions
to help keep you
out of jail.
This is about
more than that.
It's about keeping
our jobs.
It's about walking
out of here
with our pensions,
our reputations.
Keeping us out of jail is
just one piece of the puzzle.
Until Kavanaugh
charges somebody,
we just have to deflect,
hope he reveals
more than he should.
Not me.
I'm sorry, darlin', but you
don't represent me anymore.
Can you give us
a moment, please?
What the hell
happened up there?
He's looking into
my records.
What me and Mara
bring home,
what we're paying
for the house.
Yeah. I thought
that was all covered.
It is, to the penny.
Problem is,
there's nothing left over
and he knows it.
This isn't good.
No shit!
All right. All right.
Let's just take
a deep breath.
While we still
breathing free air?
Vic, we got
a "shots fired" call
from the address
you guys just left.
All right.
Lemansky.
I need to see you
for a sec.
What happened?
Some kind of shootout.
Dead guy inside.
It's this guy's brother.
Who killed Jimmy?
Was it Shusett?
No. Saw him coming
up the stairs.
Knew some major stuff
was gonna go down,
so I went and got my gun.
By the time I found it,
Jimmy was all shot up.
Did you see
who killed him?
Some cholo dude.
Rolls with Ochoa.
I guess Ochoa's a little more broken
up than we thought about his dead lady.
Or he wanted
his drugs back.
He killed my brother, man.
My street intel says someone's
trying to unload weight.
Mexican meth.
Shusett didn't go to Ochoa's
to kill his ex crank skank.
He went to steal
his drugs.
When those things flood
the barrio, forget it.
So let's
find'em first.
Better yet,
let's buy'em.
Who do we know who could buy from
Shusett without raising flags?
I got a dealer. Street name's Burnout.
I think he got popped with
Shusett once for possession.
All right. Let me check in with my guys.
Let me know if you find them. Good.
My quota's a little
low this week.
Who wants to do
the bracelet dance?
Back up, Burnout.
We need you
to buy some drugs
from an old friend
of yours, Ted Shusett.
You guys got popped
together once.
Once a fellow fiend,
always a fellow fiend.
Partying together
don't make us tight.
Call him. Tell him your looking
for product. He'll listen.
Do I look like
a stupid nigger to you?
Why do you think
we're talking?
Man, this is legit.
When he stole
those drugs,
Shusett killed a 2-year-old
girl and her mother.
So?
We tried to do it
the easy way.
Ok, hold up!
Hold up, man!
Look, a call
like that,
little girl
dead, man,
street's gonna know I'm
the one givin' it up.
That's pretty rough
on my reputation.
What's the going rate
for a reputation these days?
25 grand.
Get him outta here.
That's too much
for the department
to authorize on less
than 24-hours notice.
City council could
rubber stamp a reward, though.
See you guys inside,
all right?
Councilman?
I thought I could
catch you.
You got a minute?
I have a speech to give.
This is really important
for the investigation.
Have you ever heard of a
guy named Antwon Mitchell?
You know I have.
I talked to Lemansky,
and I don't want to push
on Antwon Mitchell
until I heard what you
got to say about him.
I don't know
what I can tell you.
How did Mackey learn that
Crowley was working with justice?
What does this
have to do with Mitchell?
Humor me.
I suspected
it was Gilroy.
Maybe it was you.
You set up Crowley.
You tipped Mackey.
Right. I'm also
the fifth Beatle.
Mrs. Mackey reported that
he gave her 65 grand in cash.
What was your share?
Running a political campaign
gets really expensive.
So's my time, and now
you're wasting it.
I'm just trying to figure out
how Antwon Mitchell
and a guy named Juan Lozano
figure into all of this.
Lozano was the guy...
wasn't that the kid
who assaulted you?
Yes!
Yes.
Who grabbed your gun?
You killed his buddy
during a robbery,
tracked Lozano down
yourself.
That's a pretty impressive
bust for a desk jockey.
And later, you visited
him in County.
Well, he was planning
to appeal his case.
Hmm.
I know that Mackey
and his guys,
they have some connection
with Antwon Mitchell,
and he was in
the same cellblock
when Lozano
was found dead.
There's something big
going on here.
You, Mackey,
Mitchell, Lozano.
You wanna fill me in?
Waste your time with
these conspiracy theories
and you'll find yourself even
more lost than you are now.
Clerk said it was a black
woman who used the credit card.
Wasn't sure if it was
Fatima Gardner.
Is anybody
listening to me?
What? Say again?
I said Terry's the guy
you're looking for.
I'm not talking
to you.
Say again, Julien?
I said we've got
a motel address
where the woman wanted
the purchases delivered.
We're headed there now.
Ok. Good.
You gotta find Terry.
He's the one that needs
to be in here.
Shut up.
Pretty sloppy work you did
last night, killing that girl.
Not your usual work of art.
Why'd you cut off
her hair?
Why did you
cut off yours?
Don't interrupt.
My questions, not yours.
You used to look
a lot different.
How long you been sick?
You're the one
who's sick, Kleavon.
Please, girl, you're wobbolin' more
than a squirrel fall from a tree.
Oh, you may act like
everything's all right,
but your needle's
going back and forth, yeah.
I hear your bones creaking every
time you get out of that chair.
Get in there!
Hey, what am
I doing here?
One of the victims I.D.ed the
guy you sent to kill Shusett,
get your crank back.
We can lure Someshit out
if we make an offer to buy.
The only problem is we
need a 25 grand reward
for our conscientious
dealer first.
Why is this guy so important
you have to pay him?
'Cause he can guarantee putting
us in touch with the guy.
He knows Someshit.
It's the fastest way we can
get our hands on this guy
and the suitcase
full of crank.
All right.
How fast do you need it?
The guy stole
over a hundred pounds.
He's holding a fire sale.
It's only a matter of hours
before he finds a taker.
Or Ochoa's guy
finds him first.
My boys put a lot
of hours into this.
Hate to see it slip away,
end up on the street
after all that.
All right. I can
authorize the reward,
but expediting it's
another question.
A 2-yeard-old girl
was executed.
2-year-old? Hell,
I'll give you some money.
That's ok, pal.
We got it.
You didn't tell me I.A.D.
set up shop in the barn.
Yeah, well, this guy's a
special kind of asshole.
Kavanaugh's case
against you
is a hell of a lot
stronger than you think.
Since when are you
looking out for me?
He's holding back
his trump card
until he can nail
all 4 of you.
It turns out he reports
directly to chief Johnson.
Even the mayor's office
is involved.
The city is committed on getting
it's PR win off you guys.
But, uh...
I could broker a deal,
make sure that jail time's knocked
down to just one year for all of you...
No. Instead of the 7 to
10 you're looking at now.
No way.
Look, all you need to do is give
Kavanaugh something on the others,
something that will
give the city its win.
Give them Vic?
He's dragging you down.
And any of this "all for one, one
for all" pep talk he's feeding you
is a bunch of bullshit.
Fine, but you're gonna
let me know soon.
When are you gonna get
it through your head?
I don't want your help!
Just one year!
Lem, one year
for all of you!
Just one year for
all the shit you guys have done!
But you're too stupid
to take it?
Well, then the 4 of you
deserve everything you get.
Ok. Let me know
when you see him,
but let him get all the
way in the apartment.
All right. Copy.
Stay sharp.
You didn't say you was gonna
be using my house.
I would have
charged you more.
25 grand was
to lure him here.
I said nothing about
protecting you.
Well, shit...
Hold on.
Someone's coming.
I think that's him.
Ok.
Ok, we're ready.
This guy's tweaking,
big time.
Where's he going?
Shit. Vic, he's going
to the wrong door.
Does he got the drugs?
No.
Maybe in his car,
but it's not on him now.
What is he doing? I can't
see past this goddamn fence.
He's arguing with
the woman next door.
She's telling him he's
got the wrong place,
but he's not leaving.
We need him
and the drugs.
Goddammit.
Vic, Reyes and his guys
are moving.
We gotta go, too, man.
There's kids around.
No, goddammit! Stay put!
Goddamn you!
Speak to me in english!
I'm supposed to meet
Burnout here right now!
Do you understand me?
I wanna see Burnout!
Chill out.
Hey! Let her go!
Back! Back!
Let's go!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Go! Get out of here!
Get back!
He's got a hostage.
And a damn good
vantage point!
SWAT's rolling.
15 minutes out.
Back off!
Shithead's on
a mexican high.
We don't have 15.
No.
Hey! I want a plane!
She's toast, man.
Pull back and wait
for SWAT.
Anyone got a better idea?
Department lets you guys
carry C4?
I just finished
my weekend in the guard.
Never hurts to bring home
some supplies from the office.
Whenever you're ready?
Are you sure
about this?
It's this woman's
best shot
at getting out
of there alive.
All right. Let's do it.
Yeah.
It's just him
at the window now.
It's clear. Go now.
Ok.
Ready?
Do it!
You ok? You ok?
Don't move!
Let's get out of
here. Come on.
Come on.
Give me a hand.
You had the drugs.
Why'd you have to kill
that little girl?
It wasn't me.
Drugs were stolen
from Ochoa's house
same time Jenny
and the kid were killed.
I got news for you.
That little girl,
the one you killed this morning,
she was your own blood.
You had a daughter, Ted.
You didn't just kill
an innocent child.
You murdered your own
baby girl.
21/2 years
plus 9 months.
That means you and the ex, what...
Christmas time.
3 years ago.
You do so much meth you forget
how to do a little arithmetic, Ted?
I wouldn't kill
my own girl...
not if I knew.
Hey. What was her name?
What was her name?!
It's good working
with you.
Pretty crazy stunt
blowing that wall.
Yeah. I talked
to my captain.
This I.A.D. thing is really
pretty entrenched, so... -
It means I'm getting
shit done, right?
Yeah.
I would love to work
with you again,
but the boss...
he won't have you
working for me, so...
You know what?
It saves me giving
the bad news.
Me and my guys,
we talked about it.
We're happy
where we are.
All right.
I'll see you on
the diamond, then?
Yeah.
Hey, listen to this.
When I was talking
to Kavanaugh,
I noticed he was wearing
a wedding ring.
But he's been divorced,
like, 2 years.
What's that about?
Hmm.
Maybe this gives us
something
that let's us put our boot
on his neck for a change.
Police! Open up!
Give me your key.
Ms. Gardner!
Fatima, you need to open up, ma'am.
It's all right.
It's ok!
It's ok, ma'am.
You're safe,
we're not here
to hurt you.
It's ok.
We have him in custody.
You have nothing
to worry about.
And what if you can't
arrest him again?
Now he knows
I've talked to you.
He values his
relationship with you.
He was always
our little prince.
A sweet, sensitive boy with
just me, my mom, and auntie.
We just wanted him
to know he was special.
Unfortunately, that
resulted in his narcissism.
So how do you want
to play this?
We found Fatima.
Strangled,
dumped in an alley.
I'd say sorry, but this is
the way you wanted it, isn't it?
It's all you,
your signature.
You're wrong.
You killed her
like you did those other girls.
You're telling me you have
blackouts after you kill them?
You don't remember it?
It's you.
It's your fault.
You should have
found her in time.
You didn't even try.
This was all you.
And now you sit here
blubbering,
expecting mercy
from god's vengeance
when you didn't even
give a damn
about those brothers
and sisters,
the mothers and fathers
of the girls you killed.
How many of them
had to suffer
because you felt you had
the right to kill?
You didn't respect them.
You didn't even
see them as people.
And now your own sister,
the one who took care of you!
Jesus.
He's not gonna
break.
He's cracking.
No, Dutch,
he's not.
His grief over his sister's
death is fueling his rage.
Just one more push.
I can't.
Well, don't pull out now.
Dutch...
I can't do this.
Well, you have to do it.
There's no evidence.
You've accessed this guy better
than anyone else ever has.
That's why it has
to be you, now.
You're... you're so close.
I can't.
Look at me.
You accused me of letting
you being sick get in the way.
Well, now you're letting it.
This guy is a killer,
and I don't
give a shit how tired
or weak or pained
you are.
If he walks today,
he's gonna come after Fatima
or you or some other woman.
So you get back in there
and you close him.
As your lawyer,
it's a mistake,
and a big one.
But you know
I have to do it.
You can't change
the past,
and it only makes
the present harder.
I can't get a fresh start
unless I know she has one.
It's dangerous.
It makes amends.
I'll deal with
the danger later.
Haven't been here in years.
Young and poor.
We actually thought this
was fine dining, remember?
This doesn't feel
too weird.
Listen, I...
You and the kids can't
get caught up with this.
It feels like
it's too late.
No, it's not.
I want you to get
a lawyer.
Make a deal that gets you
clear with Kavanaugh.
Make sure he gets you
IRS immunity, too.
But you...
And I want you to answer
all his questions.
From now on,
complete cooperation.
The whole truth, no matter
what it makes me look like.
I don't want anything
to happen to you.
Let me worry
about me.
You just worry
about our 3.
What do I say
about the money?
Well, when we needed it,
I came up with it.
I said I was gonna take some
overtime to cover the expenses.
As far as you know,
that's what I did.
But that's not gonna go with anything...
Let me worry about me.
The menu hasn't changed.
Some things never do.
Maybe I should just give them some
minor bullshit that won't stick,
get us all out of it.
You're gonna trust
Aceveda now?
Hey.
Why are we having this
conversation without Vic?
Because Vic's listening to his
lawyer more than he's listening to us.
I don't like her
representing all 4 of us.
But I hate to say it,
but we all have different
levels of involvement.
Yeah, they'll get Lem
on possession,
they'll get me and Vic
on tax evasion.
You're the only one
clean so far.
Hey, I'm in this with you,
and so is Vic.
But I don't like this
unified lawyer front.
Kavanaugh cannot handle 4
lawyers poking holes in his case.
I saw we all lawyer up,
get them to throw everything
they can at him.
Keep him off balance.
I mean, what are
we waiting for?
Vic.
The medical examiner
found a hair
of an african-american male
on last night's victim's body.
We're gonna need to draw some
blood and take some hair samples.
I won't agree to that.
It's not your choice anymore.
It's the court's.
Real stupid of you.
You got so pissed at us
asking you questions
about Fatima's disappearance,
you finally got sloppy.
Went out there,
killed in a hurry.
All the other times,
the planning was just perfect.
Why?
You sat here before.
What's different this time?
You had a fight with Fatima?
Did she confront you
about the other girls?
Is that why you finally
killed your own sister?
Or was it just me
you couldn't control?
I didn't kill her.
You must have known
what was happening,
seen her loathing,
her disappointment.
When she came to see us,
she said it was all her fault.
She never came to you.
Said she should have
tried to stop you.
Is that what happened?
She tried to stop you?
You're bleeding.
Let's get some ice.
I'm fine.
Come with me.
No.
Fatima hated you.
Her own brother,
a killer.
She loved me.
And you loved her?
Bullshit.
You killed her.
Over and over.
All those girls,
Texas, here, and god knows where else,
they were all
Fatima to you.
You needed her,
but you hated her,
and you killed them
until you finally
got up the courage
to kill her.
No.
And now with that hair we
found on that woman last night,
we got you,
you son of a bitch!
I got you for her!
And the jury,
if I got one,
we'll put all the others
on you, too,
including your sister.
We have the evidence
this time.
I could never...
You killed Fatima...
and the hair proves you
killed a woman last night.
She was nothin'.
Those others were nothin'.
Fatima...
Fatima was my sister.
So the others,
you killed them?
Pauline Wahler
last night.
Mary Simpson.
Lana Gregory.
They were just... things.
You could hardly
call it killing.
The ones in Texas.
Them, too.
But not Fatima.
Not her.
She was a person.
I didn't kill her.
Fatima?
You did this?
You helped them
make me think you were dead?
Your soul's gonna
burn, Kleavon.
And until it does,
I'll visit you.
You bitch!
You're never going
to see momma or auntie.
They're crying now
over what you've done!
What's wrong with you?!
Why'd you tell'em?!
Move!
Someone get him
outta here!
You traitor!
I'm your blood!
What's wrong with you?!
Put him in there
to cool off!
Claudette!
Oh, my god!
Is she all right?
Claudette?
He pushed her!
What's going on?
No, no! She fainted!
She was out before
she fell! Claudette?
She fell?
Is she bleeding?
Don't move her.
Call the paramedics.
Her neck is...
Call an ambulance.
Claudette?
Hurry! Hurry!
Who is going
to hell now?
Hey... hey, Claudette?
Claudette?
Subtitles:
FRM-xxy & Sapotille
www.1000fr.com
www.theshield-laserie.com