Previously on The Shield...
Sir, what's the problem?
My dick. Please...
You're caught
in a rat trap.
I've got lupus.
I've had it for 15 years.
Don't move her.
Call the paramedics.
Why didn't you tell me Sadie
has a history of mental illness?
I made a life for myself.
You been missing me?
Ex-wife.
I wasn't worth taking care of,
and now I'm not worth shit!
I want to go home!
At least we found
his weak spot.
Shit, go!
You! You're under arrest...
for possession
of heroin
with intent to distribute.
The price is simple. I help you
put away these four fine young men,
you make sure you put
them away right here.
You send Lem to Lompoc,
it's you that's the real murderer.
I had a conversation
with Antwon Mitchell.
You're bluffin'.
You don't have the stomach
to serve Lem up to Antwon.
I didn't used to.
Shit.
Morning.
- You gotta be kiddin' me.
- Welcome home.
- You don't look so good.
- I'm not talking to you.
It's a social call.
You're lucky having
a friend like Mr. Holvis.
Smithen Holvis.
Your good buddy who posted your bail.
- Smitty.
- This is funny.
He doesn't remember you
that well either.
Just get out, man.
You know, when I find out how Vic
and the other two got that bail money,
they're gonna wish that they had
a friend like your friend Smitty.
Jesus! Is that blood?
You need a doctor?
Just get the hell out!
Just get out!
Heard you had
a rough week,
so I told Jon I'd stop
by and check in on you.
The sun will rise
in the west
the day that man cares
whether I live or die.
Well, he did the same
thing for me with my ex.
Did more for her
than he did for me.
Sounds like you guys
are close.
We've been spending a lot
of time together, actually,
On account of the job.
But Jon's kinda tough
to figure out.
Consider yourself fortunate.
He didn't tell me, uh...
you have kids?
Family wasn't on
Jon's "to do"list.
Just as well.
Easier to move on.
You want coffee?
Uh, water's fine.
So how does it work,
you and the ex?
Good and bad.
But I look out for her,
make sure she gets
what she needs.
At least you guys
have a connection.
For better or worse.
You're not what
I expected.
The truth is
I didn't have a clue
what sort of woman
Jon would have married.
Neither did he.
He still doesn't.
Just like him to send
somebody else over
to carry my emotional
baggage.
Tell the prick
I'm great.
Hey, it's tough
to be a cop's wife.
Jon's wife is the job.
It's what keeps him
warm at night.
Is there some other message
you'd like me to give him?
Sure.
Whoa. Whoa.
What about Jon?
When Jon left me,
he made his choice.
I'll make mine.
Hey. Where you been?
I had an ex-wife thing.
What'd you need us here for?
Not her, me.
I'm gonna
take a deal.
Just listen.
If I plead guilty
to the heroin thing,
this all seals off.
Without me, Kavanaugh's
got nothing else.
He's got nothing
on you guys.
We're not feeding you
to Antwon.
Lompoc's an idle threat.
The judge will
most likely place him
in a medium security
facility.
Kavanaugh's not gonna let
you skate with some cush deal.
He's got Emolia's testimony,
man. He wants years!
He's got the brass
behind him.
Not anymore.
O.I.G. and the chief,
they're losing confidence
in Kavanaugh's investigation.
D.A.'s receptive.
I plead guilty to theft
under color of authority,
they'll drop the intent
to distribute charge.
No!
5 years. Up for parole
in 18 months.
If you plead guilty,
it's your badge,
it's your pension.
We're talking prison.
18 months isn't a week.
I know.
Don't do it!
Don't do it, man!
We're fighting this, man!
I don't wanna
fight anymore.
I don't wanna fight
anymore, all right?
If you were in my place,
you'd take the hit...
to protect me,
the team.
I know you would.
OF MICE AND LEM
Look, no matter what we do,
end of the day,
Kavanaugh's still got
a brick of tar.
He's still got
Emolia's word.
You heard Becca.
The chief's losing
faith.
I'm working on
discrediting this guy.
So I.A.D. brings in
someone else.
They still have
the same brick.
I'm doing time
no matter what.
This way,
I got some control.
Look, I'm just so tired of not
knowing what's gonna happen,
worrying about
the rest of you.
I gotta see an end.
Jesus Christ, man!
I gotta get back inside
and talk to Becca.
Let us know
if anything breaks.
All right.
For him to get out
in 18 months,
he's gonna have to be
a model inmate.
That's not gonna happen.
Protective custody's
a joke.
He's gonna be fightin' for
his life the full 5 years.
What the hell
is he thinking?
Between Kavanaugh
spinning doom
and Becca selling him
a rose garden,
the poor guy doesn't
know what end is up.
Or he's taking the deal
because he knows
eventually Kavanaugh's
gonna get him to crack.
I'm off to Lompoc.
I was beginning to think that you
didn't have love for me anymore.
I was getting
a little jealous,
you spending so much
time with another cop.
Oh. Yeah, Kavanaugh's
an intense cat, isn't he?
Shame about Lemansky, man.
But you do know that blondie
will end up in my backyard.
We don't know
anything yet.
And if Lem does do time,
he's not gonna
land here.
I've got a real big backyard.
And wherever he lands,
I decide his quality
of life.
But that's why you're here.
You need something,
same as I do.
Otherwise, you wouldn't
have sent
that little black breezy
to find me.
Truth is Antwon Mitchell's
the answer to all your prayers.
Lemansky's guardian angel.
You see, we have
a relationship, you and me.
That relationship's
had its ups and downs,
but it's still
a relationship.
You make me drive all the way
out here for couple's counseling
or you got something
to say?
The Niners have taken
a serious hit
since my incarceration.
Halpern's been running
them under the radar,
until this black-brown
shitstorm plays itself out.
That cranky black bitch is
afraid of his own goddamn shadow.
I've got some serious
old-school weight coming in.
Kern Little.
I knew Kern's rap career
was in the dollar bin.
I didn't know he was
back in colors.
Eventually,
they all come home.
And Kern, he's eager to help
me with my cash-flow problem.
I've got to hand out a lot
of turkeys at Thanksgiving.
There's a warehouse
on ridge road,
a place where they're storing
what's left of the seized assets.
You want me to rip off
a P.D. warehouse?
Of course not.
Kern's already put
together a team for that.
You just gotta come up with a plan
on how and when to get my guys in.
Walk Kern and his
second, Moses, through it.
That's more than an escort.
That's a hooker
and a hand-job.
Hey. That's the price for my
guarantee that Lemansky stays alive.
Stand back.
Nothing to see here.
Jesus!
His dick's gone.
Somebody find it.
Jogger called it in.
No I.D.
- Gunshot?
- No.
There's a rat trap
in one of the stalls.
I was real careful not
to disturb the crime scene.
Good thinking. You
wanna get that on ice.
Send it with him
to the hospital.
It's not gonna matter if
we don't get him stabilized.
We need to move now.
Let's get
a canvass going.
The same M.O. as that attack
a couple of weeks ago.
The suspect was male,
caucasian, thirties.
Well, let's not rule
anyone out yet.
In a world of men,
the thoughts even
crossed my mind.
Serrated teeth,
Interlocking,
no less.
This is a lot more gothic than
the last glory-hole attack.
Did you talk
to the hospital?
The victim's
still unconscious.
He sustained a head
injury when he passed out.
He's in pretty
rough shape.
So we have no way
of knowing
if and when he'll
be able to communicate.
Canvass turn up
anything?
Nothing so far.
So we got dick...
which is more than I can
say for the victim.
We need to get
the word out.
Bookstores, bathhouses,
bars,
anywhere this sort of
activity goes on.
Uh, we need to re-interview
the victim
of the first
glory-hole attack.
What's his name?
He gave us everything
that he had.
He never talked
to a detective.
It's Alarico Trujillo.
I'll write
his address down.
This Trujillo guy,
he's married, kids.
I told him I'd keep his name
out of it if he cooperated.
He held up his end.
This has escalated way beyond
a twisted prank.
He's our only
conscious witness.
We'll be discreet.
Thank you.
Is this thing even
remotely safe?
We make sure it is,
'cause we got no choice.
Antwon's the devil we know.
What it it's
the other devil?
Kavanaugh laying
a trap.
He's been cutting deals
with Antwon.
Maybe this is his last stab
before Lem seals us off.
No, this place
is wide open.
We can spot a surveillance
unit a mile away.
If Kavanaugh was
planning a sting,
this wouldn't
be the place.
Or he knows we would
think that.
We sniff out
every inch of this thing.
Triple check
every last detail.
We get on bad whiff,
we bail.
Hey, why don't
you crank it up?
Might still be some cops in
long beach who can't hear it.
Why don't you relax, Teeth.
I was hoping I'd never
see you in purple again.
I never took it off.
You know how that goes.
Yeah, I do.
This is my boy Moses.
Check 'em both.
Looking for this?
No. We got a little
bug problem lately.
You think we work
for the white law?
White law, black power,
it's all the same shit.
I just want to make sure
our visit stays anonymous.
They're clean.
No shit, captain cracker.
That's clever.
Can't understand why that
rap career didn't take off.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Easy! Easy! Easy!
Now, what's your
goddamn problem?
Times change, man.
I don't trust you
or your ghost squad.
Well, the lack of love
is mutual.
Yeah, I see that.
You and Antwon?
Nothing like karma.
Hey! The favor
I have to do.
Taking mouth shit from
MC Has-Been, I don't!
Come on.
Come on, fellas.
Now, let's just put
this history on hold
and get this shit done, OK?
Let's go over it.
OK. There's one guard.
He spends most of his shift
at the gatehouse, here.
A guy of ours says the warehouse
is wall-to-wall cameras.
They feed into a bank
of monitors back at the gate.
The seizure locker's here.
Can't miss it,
right past the hummer.
There's antiques, TVs,
and a safe, a big one.
Mitchell was right.
We checked the inventory.
Over 500 grand
in watches and jewelry.
Yeah, and that's all
we go for.
No one drives out of there with
a hummer or a flat screen.
Yeah?
- Where are you?
- Why?
We need to talk.
Kavanaugh's
covering his bets
in case the criminal case
against you doesn't make.
What do you mean
"in case?"
Surprised this clown hasn't
gotten the hook already.
By acknowledging you failed to
clear the room when Terry was shot,
Kavanaugh's to characterize your earlier
statements as false and misleading.
That's bullshit.
I've told the truth
since day one.
Nothing I've said has changed
because the facts haven't.
Then he's doing a good job
of twisting your words.
It's not unconceivable that he
could cost you your retirement.
Where'd you hear that?
Your case was referred to the
police committee for review.
You let him try
to take my pension.
PBA reps will have
his head on a pike.
I wouldn't be so sure.
You know, Kavanaugh
could get this
as a face-saving way
to end his investigation.
Never mind prying a cop with a
sketchy jacket of the taxpayer's tit.
Anyway, we said we'd share.
I thought you'd want
the heads up.
Thanks.
Wait a minute.
Is Kavanaugh making any noise
around here about me?
All's been quiet
as it relates to you.
Undermining him
is a priority.
For both of us.
We'd like to speak
to Alarico Trujillo.
About a car accident he
witnessed a couple weeks back.
Policía.
Policía?
Uh, we have a few more
questions about that accident.
I told you people
everything.
You didn't tell me
about no car accident.
I got nothing
more to say.
There's been another driver
that's been very seriously injured.
It's important
you come with us.
Someplace private.
Look, man...
just leave me alone, OK?
We can do this another way
if we have to.
Pretty soon this is
gonna be a lonely room
filled with
empty lockers, huh?
You and me are the only
ones on the way out.
I just cut a deal
with the D.A.
What deal's that?
Why don't you ask
the chief?
It's sitting on his desk
waiting for his signature.
He'll be out
on parole
before the blood rushes
back to your face.
You don't mind
if I check the facts
before I pack my bags,
do you?
I don't give a shit
what you do.
Yeah. Thanks.
Chief's office hasn't even
seen the Lemansky deal yet.
His mouthpiece's is
feeding him a happy meal
to keep his spirits up.
Speaking of
happy meals,
did Vic bite on that intel
about me going after his pension?
You didn't see the steam
coming off his bald head?
Beautiful, man.
I so want there to be
trust between you two.
I need to use
your office.
Of course.
Anything I can do for you?
No. It's a police
matter.
Mi casa es su casa.
You gave us all a scare,
that spill you took.
Well, if you got
one of these,
there's plenty of...
bounce to the ounce.
Let me get to the point.
I've been made aware that you
have a serious medical condition,
one that could compromise your
ability to perform your duties.
You needed to disclose
a disease like lupus.
You didn't.
Because it was
a personal matter.
Supposed you had taken
that heathout in the field?
You could have put
other officers at risk.
But it didn't happen.
And I'm not here because
of how I knock down doors.
I'm ordering you to see a city
physician for a full medical review.
Until then, you're assigned
to desk duty.
Then let's get it done,
ASAP!
I've got plenty
of cases to clear.
I'm responsible for the health and
welfare of everyone working here.
Then maybe you ought
to do something
about the epidemic
of bullshit in this place.
Claudette, don't let
your frustrations get you in over--
This man Kavanaugh that you've
just given the place over to,
I understand he's got
an investigation to run,
but have you any idea
what he's doing to morale?
She's got
a point there.
I.A.D. is arrogant
and intrusive.
It's nature of the beast.
But this man takes intimidation
to a whole other level.
He's got every officer
in this place spooked.
They spend more time
looking over their shoulders
than they do
doing their jobs.
That's a fair
assessment.
Our last captain had
unpopular policies.
So you stuck us with an interim
jellyfish that won't rock the boat.
Then you cut resources
that we need to do the job.
Talk about putting
people at risk.
Crime stats are down
since I took over.
If you aren't out to lunch,
passing the buck,
or leaving every day at 4:00,
you'd know that our citizens
aren't reporting
half of what's going on
out there
because they know that
we can't or won't do anything.
If you want me to go
and pee in a cup,
I'll be happy
to fill it.
But I'm not
your problem.
Pretty loopy.
Maybe that's why
they call it lupus.
Look, I've been here
too long as it is.
My wife's gonna
get suspicious.
You have a perfectly
plausible cover story.
If you'd like me
to call and explain--
No. Please...
- Dutch.
- I just wanna go home.
Give me a second.
Sit down.
What'd the assistant
chief want?
I'm trying to comprehend
why you felt the need
to inform the department
that I have lupus.
What? I did nothing
of the kind.
The chief's office
is certainly up to speed.
Well, not from me.
You're the only one
who knew.
Obviously not.
Because of you,
I'm riding a desk.
Claudette,
you're not hearing me.
I have not spoken
to anyone about this.
You went to
the D.A.'s office before
To make a separate peace
behind my back, remember?
Oh, come on!
You don't believe me?
If you didn't
tell them that directly,
Then somebody
you told did.
Maybe that little latina wet dream
you've been pushing up against.
Maybe you gave her
a little bit of gossip
so you could show how
plugged in you are!
Hold on--
you've crossed the line
into wholesale character
assassination.
Career assassination
is a lot worse!
This is good.
This helps a lot.
I'll have an officer
give you a ride home.
I'll take a bus.
I don't want to be
getting out of a police car
in my neighborhood.
Captain?
What can I do for you?
Art Gadway, Los Angeles
gay men's initiative.
I'd like to talk
to whoever's in charge
about recent attacks
on members of our community.
Julien, come talk
to this guy
about the rat trap
glory-hole business, will you?
This is officer Lowe. He's been
with this since the beginning.
Um, we've been
interviewing witnesses.
In the meantime,
we're asking anyone
with any information
to contact us.
So basically you're waiting for
this sadist to turn himself in.
That would be
a wrong perception.
Well, your captain couldn't
wait to shuffle me off onto you.
And it's clear that you'd rather
be anywhere else than talking to me.
Instead of playing
the blame game,
why don't you help us get the
word out and distribute these?
I'm sure you people know
where the glory holes are
better than we do.
Are you aware that e there are
at least a half dozen attacks
we know of haven't
been reported?
Maybe those people knew
what they were doing was wrong.
Adults engaging in
consensual sex?
In public...
which is a crime.
Thank you for coming down
and registering your concerns.
I need your name
and badge number.
You need to keep
your hands off me.
Look, you and your buddies in
blue can hate all you want to,
but we're here.
You need to get
used to it.
I did a 5-mile sweep.
No R.F. on infrared
readout anywhere.
Nobody's transmitting
any voice or video.
We've been up and down
the dial. No coded chatter.
Don't move.
You don't fight,
you don't die.
No fighting, man.
Whatever you want.
Shut up! Walk!
Come on!
Don't forget the tools.
What the hell
are you doing?!
Finishing the job.
Antwon's orders.
Holy shit! Turn around!
Against the fence right now!
He's gone.
Shit!
This was not
part of the deal!
Sure it was.
The part Antwon
didn't tell you about.
Kill me and you lose
favor with Antwon.
And your boy ends up
facedown
in a pool of blood
and blowjuice.
Hey! Hey!
Get up!
Get the safe and get out!
You heard him,
let's go! Get up!
What the hell
do we do here?
Goddamn it.
Give me a hand.
Shit.
I don't get it.
Kern was no
backseat banger.
Antwon had him taken out
before Kern took over.
Why not just
whack him when he's in the hood?
Word got out that
Antwon took out Kern,
the street would take it
as a weakness.
A gang without a leader.
Brothers jump to other sets.
Kern goes down in
the line of duty.
Get some Niners
street cred.
Moses takes over,
pushes Antwon's agenda.
Goddam it.
Goddam it, man.
Let's go.
You gotta be shittin' me!
These brothers
can take a bullet.
Oh, God. What now?
Help. Help.
Let's go.
Vic, come on, man!
We can't just--
911 will take 20 minutes
to get here.
He's gonna be dead in 10.
We'll wait. Then we leave,
call it in.
You sure about this?
Kern's dead.
We can still save Lem.
Jesus!
Mackey!
Mackey, please!
Let me outta here!
Police! We're cutting
the lock!
On my command you stand,
hands on your head!
Sorry I spaced
on the combination.
There's glory hole over there
and a couple of rat traps.
The owner said
he put them out.
Tough to prove
whose whose.
Stand slowly!
Hands on your head!
We helped you catch him.
I expect you to hold up
your end.
What do you suppose
would happen
If someone snapped this--
on someone's dick?
You're sick,
you know that?
I didn't make this up.
This one here?
Serrated teeth.
Guy who got caught in this
is gonna pee sitting down...
if he survives.
Aren't you glad
it wasn't you?
That'd be a hell of a secret
you'd have to live with.
Something personal
and embarrassing
that affects your ability
to function.
Not something you'd want
a lot of people top know about.
OK, you want
to do this?
You can talk to him.
I'll come back
later.
So, Jared, what do you got
against gay folks?
That some sort of tactic?
You pretend to pick a fight,
and then you do
the whole tag-team thing?
Just answer the question.
He give you anything?
Nope.
We need to put this guy
in a lineup.
He's all yours.
Tina, we need to bring
Trujillo in again.
I'll tell him to meet you
down the block from his place.
Keep up appearances.
Got it.
Alarico Trujillo
on Lattimer Ave?
Yeah.
Unis just responded
to a domestic
at his address
that got ugly.
You should run with it since
you're dealing with him--
OK. OK.
I got balls in the air on a
big 211 that just got called in.
I'm gonna check in
on it personally.
We got here, he was standing
over her with a baseball bat.
What happened?
We got married,
the priest told her everything
I'd done before with men
was in the past.
I tried to stop, but
she knew what was up.
You people started coming
around asking questions.
She knew why.
What the hell
is he doing here?
Pretending to be a cop.
You guys
called this in?
Yeah. We got a tip the One-Niners
were hitting this place.
We got stuck in
the van on a stakeout.
Couldn't make it
back here in time.
What's the damage?
Looks like the guard
took out one of them
before he got his head
blown off.
Detective Mackey,
do you know him?
It's Kern Kittle.
Old-school One-Niner.
Went back to
the street game
once his hip-hop career
hit the skids.
Why don't you inventory
what's missing,
then we'll start turning over
One-Niner rocks.
Familiar scenario, this.
How so?
Come on.
You don't see it?
A dead cop killed by the
gun of a dead bad guy.
You two,
innocent bystanders.
We were on the other side
of Farmington, asshole.
Anybody see you?
Wouldn't have been much
of a stakeout if they had.
You know what? You should
start eating again, man.
Malnourishment's starting
to screw with your logic.
Lemansky's going
to prison.
You need to protect him.
You reach out
to Antwon Mitchell.
For some reason, he needs
his crew leader dead.
Bad blood, internal
beef, whatever.
So... you kill him.
Your end of the deal.
He keeps Lem alive.
His end of the deal.
How's that logic
sound to you?
Let me remind you of a few
things you seem to have forgotten.
I didn't kill Terry.
You've lost your leverage
with Lem.
And your ex-wife's pussy...
tastes like sweet butter.
What do you want?
Sadie, you gonna
let me in?
I'm in the middle
of something.
I just need to know
if you've seen this guy.
Yeah. He came through.
Are you OK?
What do you care?
Did he hurt you?
You're the only one
who ever hurts me, Jon.
That's not gonna
happen again.
Can you just...
tell me what he did.
Just tell me
what happened.
What did he do?
What did he do? Um...
he made me come.
That's what he did.
No, he didn't.
Oh, yeah.
Twice.
Do you know...
who this guy is, Sadie?
Your friend...
who you sent
to check up on me.
Well, he did.
What did you do?
Huh?
You need to go.
Move your arm
from the door, Jon...
now...
or I will call the police.
What's up?
What are you doing here?
Chief's office just
signed off on the deal.
It's OK, man.
It's over.
Uh...
Thank you, man.
It's all right.
It's OK.
We got your back.
I know.
You're gonna be taken
care of, you understand?
I had nothing
to do with this.
But if you're asking me
if I think
these perverts deserve
to be punished,
look what they're doing
to our country.
Yeah, it's seducing our
kids, spreading AIDS.
You gave us your schpiel.
A moment of your time?
So where are we
with this freak?
He's guilty, just not
prosecutable.
The problem is the
evidence is circumstantial
and threadbare
at best.
He matches
the witness description.
There's no way the D.A.'s gonna
indict off a wife beater's say so.
Let's put him
on the tour.
Lose him in the system for a
couple of days, bye some time.
With I.A.D. bivouacked
to my colon?
Are you out of your mind?
If you can't close him,
lose him.
Oh. Uh, Claudette,
the chief's here.
He wants to see you.
Hey, I tried to keep it
copasetic for you and Phillips.
I got a preliminary report
back from the city physician.
Your medically fit
to resume your duties.
I could have told you that.
You'll be required
to have quarterly checkups.
Your nickel.
I understand
you unloaded
with both barrels
on my number two here.
Sometimes happens
I see red.
Changes have to be made.
For starters, I've decided
to appoint you captain.
What makes you think
I want that revolving door?
You know this place better
than anybody in the department.
Which is why you don't
see my jumping at the offer.
My predecessor
made a mistake
slapping you down
with that D.A. nonsense.
But you and I can find a
way to work together, right?
For starters, I would need a
guarantee that I would run the Barn.
Not in theory,
in fact.
No one can do the job
with...
Sorry to interrupt,
but...
can I just confirm some
very disturbing news?
Did you...
did you sigh off
on a deal with Lemansky?
I did.
I thought we agreed
no deals.
The only way to get Mackey
is to leverage his guys.
We're in the middle of
something here, lieutenant.
So am I! And it just got derailed
because you guys backed down!
It's over, Jon.
Sending Lemansky to jail
sends a message.
We all move on now.
And Mackey
skates clean.
This guy--
This guy is just pissing...
just pissing
all over us...
and we just smile
and lick it up?
That's enough.
Vic Mackey kills cops!
He--
He deals drugs!
He beats suspects!
You know what
he did yesterday?
He--
He screwed my ex-wife
with the sole purpose...
of making this investigation
seem like a personal vendetta.
He may have assassinated
a gang leader.
And that's just
all in one day.
I wonder what
he's gonna do today?
I wonder what he's gonna
do tomorrow?
This guy--
This guy's just pissing--
He's pissing
all over us!
He's pissing on you!
What does it taste like?
Chief, what does
it taste like?
'Cause you know what?
It tastes like
piss to me!
You have 48 hours
to tie up the lose ends.
And find someplace else
to do the paperwork.
Captain Wyms
needs her office.
We'll sneak the whole cow
into you, man.
Hey, Lem, I'm sorry.
Glad it's over,
though.
That's OK. Thanks.
Thank you.
Man, you're gonna be a little
thinner next time I see you.
Yeah.
Thanks. Hey, I gotta
get some things in order.
I'll see you guys
at the party, all right?
Here you go.
What's that?
That's the paperwork for the
211 you called in last night.
EMT found a ton of jewelry in
the pocket of the dead banger.
Shitheads shot
an innocent guy
and walked away with
almost nothing.
Which means...
the goddamn safe
was empty?
Holy shit. I gotta
talk to Antwon.
These fags. They choose
a life of sin and suffering,
get what they deserve.
But I'm the one
in handcuffs.
Hey.
Stand up.
Does his family deserve
to have their lives ruined
because of what
you did to him?
Men's room on Alvarado.
I've never seen
that guy before.
But if he's being punished
for his wickedness,
then it's God's will.
You're His
spokesman now?
It's right there
in the book.
"You shall not lie with the
male as one lies with a female."
It's an abomination.
I mean, come on.
Hey! Hey!
Leviticus 18, I know.
Where do you go to church?
Christ Bethany.
What is this?
So then you know that Jesus
lived a perfect life of truth,
and he was
crucified for it.
What do you suppose happens
to someone who lies in his name,
who passes judgment
on other people in his name?
Psalm 71, verse 4.
- Hey! Stop!
- "Deliver me, o my God,
"Out of the hand
of the wicked.
"Out of the hand of the
unrighteous and the cruel man."
Stop!
You wanted to look
at a man down there.
You wanted to touch it!
Thought about it
for a long time.
Maybe all of your life.
You just never did it
'cause you knew
that it was wrong.
No! No!
So you convinced yourself
that you were doing God's will,
gave yourself
an excuse to find out
what another man's
penis feels like?
No! I would never do something
so repulsive and disgusting!
You're no different than
the men you prey on.
You're a homosexual.
No! No! No!
Homosexual!
No.
You're just too weak
and afraid to admit it.
That's a lie!
That is a lie!
I am a christian!
They are vermin!
I did it because
they are vermin!
Why would any man wanna to
touch another man down there?
I did it to punish them!
What, no muffins?
You shouldn't have taken
the deal, Curtis.
You weren't supposed to
get the worst of this.
That's all you did from the minute you
picked me up is threaten me with jail.
That's all it was.
It was just a threat.
Well, you threw me
in country.
You arrested me.
I'd knew you'd make
bail, just not so soon.
It was just
a strategy, man,
a wedge to get you
to turn.
Cops will always give it
up with the threat of jail.
Always.
But not you,
not Curtis Lemansky.
I can't believe
you're doing this.
You're gonna take the
hit for him, for them?
Well, believe it.
I'm sorry that
I didn't...
that we didn't become
friends sooner.
Maybe, uh...
pulled this in
another direction.
If I'd just made a...
any man'd be lucky to
have you in his corner.
Good luck, Curtis.
Hey. Hey.
It's over.
I know.
Take care of yourself,
all right?
Things went south.
Dirty south.
Alabama south.
If I had all the information
going in,
We wouldn't be
sitting here.
But here we are right now.
Big blue and his
little black puppet.
What the hell
are you talking about?
Kavanaugh dimed me, man.
Told me you'd been braggin' about
how you were playing me against him,
How you manipulated me
into protecting Lemansky
To shit all over
his leverage.
That's bullshit!
He's jerkin' us off.
What do you care?
He can't get to you
in here.
No, but he can touch
everyone around me.
That crazy-ass nigger,
he initiated a full-scale D.O.C.
investigation of this place.
The heat's is on.
And soon, I won't be feeling
all the comforts of home.
Look, I'll figure out a way
to get you your cash.
I'll look into
this d.O.C. thing.
You've done enough.
The deal and this
conversation are over.
Jesus Christ! I took care of
that "little" thing for you!
Now, you're to tell me that
doesn't buy Lem some time?
Oh, that buys you
one more dead cop.
I got Niners in every
pen in the state.
So wherever he touches
down, it will happen.
And you can set your watch
to that inevitability.
If one of your crew
so much as hard looks my guy,
my reach will
get you shaved.
You got reach like that?
So why are you sitting down here
talking to me, grey boy, huh?
It's OK.
It's all right.
That's just detective Mackey's
way of saying good-bye.
I cut you a break for that
meltdown in front of Phillips
on account of your
medical problems and so forth,
and then I find out it's part
of your campaign to steal my job?
I didn't go after this.
Why did you do me like this?
I thought you and me
were good.
We are good,
and I didn't do you.
Letting Kavanaugh loose
in this place,
they set you up
to fail.
It's not your fault.
I didn't fail.
Is that what people
are saying?
I'll need you to help me
pick up the pieces.
I'm supposed to stick around after
getting shagged in the back like this?
No. I got some pride,
you know?
Why don't you give it
a few days?
When you're ready
to talk, my door's open.
I gotta get
a good look.
Hey.
Your entertainment
just showed up.
I figured it was time
for me to leave.
Right.
This is not
the safest 'hood.
I'll get you
to your car.
Oh, my.
I'm taking him to the
courthouse, 9:00 tomorrow morning.
Officially surrender.
You doing OK?
Yeah.
We did the right thing, Vic.
Thank you for
helping him.
You're a good friend.
He's lucky to have you.
Hey. What's going on?
Listen, I gotta
tell you something.
What?
I hear we got a confession
out of trapper John.
He and Julien
reasoned together.
Congratulations
on your promotion.
Thanks. I didn't know
it was public.
I wanted you
to hear that from me.
Well, you know things
spread around here.
Like herpes at
a swinger's party.
While you were stretched out
on the floor over there,
the paramedics found
Prednisone in your purse.
They called your doctor to find
out what you were being treated for.
Billings overheard
and reported to Phillips.
He just told me.
He thought lupus
was an emotional disorder.
I'm sorry.
You can't un-ring
that bell.
You don't trust me.
I made a mistake.
You made a choice to
think the worst about me.
I'll need your support.
I've got my work
cut out for me.
You'll do fine.
Whoever sits up there
has to have
an active mistrust
of everyone and
everything in this place.
I can't imagine anyone
better suited to the job.
Who were they?
Look, you guys, I hate
to step on the pussy and laughs,
but we gotta talk about
a change of plans.
What change?
You're not going to prison.
What are you
talking about?
We made a deal
with Antwon
to get you
safe passage inside.
It went bad.
The thing at
the warehouse?
Oh, Jesus Christ!
Kavanaugh's launched a department of
corrections investigation of Lompoc.
He's gonna make
Antwon's life hell.
Antwon's blaming me.
I won't end up
in Lompoc.
Word gets out that
Antwon's got a beef,
any prison,
any protective custody,
best-case scenario, you're gonna
bust enough heads to stay alive.
Which means I can kiss
early release good-bye.
Worst-case scenario, you're
gonna kiss everything good-bye.
What the hell
am I supposed to do?
You're gonna lay low
until I can figure out a way
to get Antwon
back on board.
You're putting him
on the run?
I can't run anymore!
We're out of options.
Look, Vic, I do not
wanna do this.
Do we even have a plan?
I'm working on one
right now.
- Where's he gonna go?
- I don't know!
I don't know!
Now...
you're gonna hide while
I find Gilroy's contacts.
Mexico?!
No! No!
Lem, it's only temporary.
But what about my deal?
If I run, man, they're
gonna throw it out.
They'll have
all new charges.
It's better than
the alternative!
Lem, right now, this is about
keeping you alive!
Lem, I promise you...
I promise you, man...
I promise you we're gonna
make this work.
I try to be handy,
but it's...
Good thing.
Whatever--
I don't know. I've heard
of a green thumb.
Hurry up!
Oh, God! Julien!
Shit!
Can I talk to you
for a second?
Just one second.
Subtitles:
FRM-xxy & Lemonhead
www.1000fr.com
www.theshield-laserie.com