Previously on The Shield...
Kleavon Gardner. Questioned
in four separate homicides.
Kleavon is not
a killer.
I'm his sister. Believe me, I'd know it.
We're releasing
your brother.
Deep down
you know we're right.
There's something
wrong with him.
You just don't want
to see it.
Now that you know,
things will add up.
About 6 months ago,
we found this kilo.
Pure heroin from the glove
compartment of your car.
But you never
logged it into evidence.
Lem got picked up
by IAD.
Got him wearing
a wire.
Kavanaugh is planning
to formally arrest you.
When that happens, we'll
be ready to bail you out.
Have you hired
a lawyer?
You need to
shift perception.
Make internal affairs
look like
they're hurting
good guys.
I got Mackey making a
deal with the russians.
Hot prescription drugs.
These are good faith.
Freeze!
What the hell
is going on?
IAD just shit
all over our sting.
What's this?
I don't know where you got
your intel, but it's wrong.
He ran the whole operation
by me this afternoon.
I guess IAD will spin
any kind of fiction
to stain good cops bad.
Keep coming.
All right.
It's gonna be tight.
Is there another way in?
No. This is it.
All right.
Come down here, guys.
Whoa! Watch it.
Delicate machinery, people.
Careful, guys.
Watch the turn.
Coming through.
Heads up.
Watch your back,
Dutch Boy.
What's going on here?
You gotta be
kidding me.
No. Hey, guys.
Just be careful
on the landing.
I don't want you
to scratch the leather.
Huh? After our big
pharmaceutical bust,
the brass put through
some of my purchase orders
they've been sitting on.
Now you'll be
sitting in style.
Anything for us?
Careful. Come on.
I give that couch
two weeks
before we're
moving it down here.
I'm not wired.
You're what?
Look. I'm not wired.
I don't get this guy.
What did Kavanaugh say?
I can't find him.
I went by the hotel.
It's empty.
I called his cell, office,
there's no answer.
Why hasn't he
arrested you?
Maybe he never
had a solid case.
You think
he's packing it in?
What, pull the plug
on the investigation?
Until we're sure, we
act like it's still on.
But I like the feeling
I'm getting.
Hey, I hate to start
your morning with this,
but multiple gang homicide.
Beautiful.
Better than
a strong cup of coffee.
Set tripping?
Drive by.
Male victims are
affiliated with Bop Street
judging by the ink.
That's what happens when
you cross enemy lines.
This turf's been
gang neutral
since Antwon's crew
slithered out of dodge.
Any witnesses?
Yeah. Friends of
the deceased.
And about as helpful.
Yo...
you two see anything?
Yeah. Brothas
having courage.
My boys went down
wet like real G's.
Do you know
who did this?
Some hater.
They almost capped
me and Moni too.
Beyond that,
I couldn't say.
Did you get a good
look at the car?
No. We didn't see nothing.
Well, you better start
searching your memory
or you're gonna get
a good look
at the inside of our car
on the way to the station.
So me and my breezie
almost catch hollowpoints
and po-po got his foot
up my ass.
Ain't that some
toy white cop bullshit.
You better check
your color, honky.
Chair over here,
all right?
You getting rid
of that chair?
You know the stuffing
in this one is shot.
My ass dies
a daily death.
Yeah, well, sorry.
It's headed back
to surplus.
Well, you can
send this one back.
Inventory's
expecting that one.
Well, well, well.
Pretty ballsy showing
your face around here.
I get to officially
notify you
that internal affairs is
investigating all four members
of your former strike team.
You got burned trying to
make that case already.
Why don't you move on?
Since all
the strike team's files,
all your files on them
are here,
I'm gonna be setting up
shop in the barn.
Until my investigation
is complete.
You're kidding me, right?
Most of the time.
Just not this time.
And where exactly
do you think you're
gonna drop anchor?
Well, I need some privacy.
And I don't want to restrict
any of these officers
from using
the interrogation rooms.
So the easiest thing
for me to do
is to use your office.
Excuse me, lieutenant.
Are you forgetting
that I'm captain here?
Acting captain.
And that entitles you to
a workspace and a phone.
Not a private office.
I understand the last captain
did very well right here
on the killing floor.
Sorry for
the inconvenience.
Scott.
Hey.
Get that stuff.
Put it over there...
until I can
work this shit out.
I didn't see nothing.
I don't know nothing.
I got nothing to say.
Except thank the most high
my man's ok.
Your man? He's a kid,
and you're not.
How's that work?
He laces me
with nice shit.
And got a big dick.
It's all good.
You're a deep one.
What I'm having a hard
time understanding I
aside from
the ghetto speak,
is why some evildoers
lit up on your peace posse
for no good reason.
Curse of the Fu Manchu.
Arrogant little prick
for only being 19, Preston.
That's my government name.
My homies call me Kasper.
The famous Kasper?
You're making quite
a name for yourself
these past few months
moving rock.
You must have me confused
with some other cat.
I hear you been working
with the rival sets.
Black, Brown,
One-Niner, Spook Street.
You're an equal
opportunity dope dealer.
Don't know about that,
but see, when you white
in Farmington,
you don't fit in.
So you gotta
make friends everywhere.
You'd make it
a whole lot easier on us
if we just put our heads
together on this.
Yeah, it would be.
But see, I ain't no
cheese-eating rodent.
Looks like you been gnawing
on something nasty to me.
Yeah.
Vic...
we got issues here.
What the hell
are you doing?
I know this will come
as a big surprise to you,
but you and your team
are the subject of
an IAD investigation
which I am heading up.
You already lost face
in front of the brass
blowing our russian bust.
How's this play
helping you?
I appreciate your concern,
but let me worry about that.
Don't expect
any cooperation
from those folks
down there.
They're a home crowd.
I wouldn't want to do
anything to upset them.
Last thing I want to do.
Is rock the boat.
RAP PAYBACK
Man, if he'd
arrest me already,
at least then he'd have to
lay out what he's got.
Goddamn it.
Come in.
Hi.
Lem, Ronnie, you remember Becca
Doyle from the Crawford case.
Yeah, sure.
She's representing us now.
Protecting us legally
against this nut job upstairs.
You lawyered up?
She's helping out
all of us.
For just such an occasion.
You're taken care of.
Your boy Kavanaugh's
quite the loose cannon.
Even his IAD buddies
are surprised by this move.
He's made it personal,
which helps me make the case
that you're being
unfairly targeted.
Oh, this looks like...
attorney client privilege.
Yes, it is.
Miss Doyle. Isn't it?
Yes.
Jon Kavanaugh.
I'm representing
all four of these detectives.
Make sure your communications
with them go through me.
Oh. It'll be my pleasure.
I'm looking forward
to working with you.
You just let me know
when you're ready, ok?
All right.
Thank you.
All right,
we're gonna concentrate
on doing our jobs,
let her worry about
whatever bullshit charges
he's trumping up.
The last thing you want
is him getting at you
through some side door.
Throws you off
your game,
he comes at you
on competency issues,
or some mistake
you make on the street.
We have some dead kids
to account for.
Kasper and his squeeze
gave us zip.
What's the next move?
The dead bangers
are Bop Street.
It could be
their own set whacked them
for breaking ranks.
Working with white folks.
That's a tree
worth shaking.
Appreciate what
you're doing.
Slip off, ho.
You got nothing to trade.
I've been flossin'
and pussy tossin'.
Hand it over.
Oh, shit!
Go out the back!
Police.
On the ground.
Couple of your crew
caught dirt naps today.
I'm thinking you Bop Street
boys are policing yourselves.
You tripping, man.
Then why were they
rolling with Kasper?
We a'right with Kasper.
Mostly.
As in you wanted him
and his crew mostly dead?
Or you're beefin'
with some other set.
I don't know.
This guy's
rank and file.
Look what I found.
We've been letting
Bop Street run game
as long as you
kept it low key.
Truce is over.
You tell Gunsmoke
I'm gonna shut down
a Bop Street rock house
every two hours
until I get that shooter.
Your clique, rival set,
doesn't matter.
We want a name.
Nice touch. Crack vials.
That's old school.
A name.
By the end of today.
Or Bop Street can start
filing for chapter 11.
Uh, no. Thank you.
Well, what do you know.
Robbery homicide.
Seems they're sniffing
around the Dutch Man.
Want to set up
an interview,
that's impressive.
Elite of the elite.
Well, it's not
a total surprise.
We've closed
some big ones.
The whole business with
the D.A. is behind us.
I guess we got some buzz.
You anyway.
Hey, isn't that, uh...
Fatima Gardner.
It's Kleavon's sister.
Yeah.
You all were pretty sure
Kleavon killed that girl
back when.
Lana Gregory.
Her and several others.
We just weren't able
to prove it.
I've been doing
what you said.
Watching and listening.
And I found this while
I was cleaning his room.
It's Kleavon's.
That's a lot of blood.
We'll check this for DNA.
I don't know if he's
noticed it's missing.
He hasn't mentioned
cutting himself,
or an accident.
If there's
nothing to it,
he never has to know
you were here.
I don't know how to
look at him anymore.
My own brother.
Just go home. Keep
doing what you're doing.
Don't be nervous.
Don't give him any reason
to think twice.
You know, she says
not to seem nervous.
How am I
supposed to do that?
I... I just don't know
if I can take this.
If we searched your
brother's room,
for evidence,
it's your house, you have every
legal right to let us inside.
Kleavon been keeping
odd hours?
Being secretive?
Nothing out of the
ordinary except the shirt.
His room's this way.
All the furniture's mine.
Only thing he brought
was in there.
Kleavon do anything else
with his time besides work?
Reads a little.
Watches TV.
Like everyone else.
Dear Lord.
Fatima?
Oh...
Fatima!
Hey. Changing
the sheets.
I thought you were
at the track.
Ah, bum day.
They only
needed me an hour.
Let me help. Then make me
a grilled cheese.
I got it. It's ok.
It's already done.
You all right?
Of course.
Come on. I'll make you
some lunch.
Can't believe
all that time and effort
just to get across town
then they send me home
after an hour.
You want
some pickles?
Sure.
Ok.
What about that...
that other job
you were looking into?
Manager told me
to call back next week.
Maybe something
will turn up.
Yeah.
You want a bottle
of 7-up?
Here it is.
You know, we need
some paper towels.
Where the hell
is our door?
The other one too.
That son of a bitch.
Thought you might like
a little fresh air.
Let a little
sunshine in.
Pretty cheap stunt.
I assume you guys have
got nothing to hide.
Right?
Anyway, with all
the confusion last week,
I never did get a chance
to congratulate you
on that bust.
Nice work.
Even if it was a little...
unorthodox.
But back to business.
I need to see you
in my office.
Not without my lawyer.
Becca Doyle.
Good call.
Let me know
when she gets here.
Vandrell, you got a sec?
Or do you need
a lawyer too?
No. I'm good.
Shane.
I'll answer whatever
questions you got.
I see you just bought
a new house.
L.A. Real Estate's Bananas.
You doing
a little moonlighting?
Security work on the side?
Mara's a realtor.
Between our two salaries,
we make due.
Reason I'm here is
I want to nail shut
the Terry Crawley file.
I see that.
That happened over
two years ago.
IAD cleared us.
Or didn't you hear the
squeeks in your rat hole?
Wonder if you'd mind taking
a look at a transcript.
Of your interview
after the shooting.
See if it
jars anything loose.
I've been looking
at your jacket.
Pretty effective cop.
Gotten yourself into
a couple of sketchy
situations along the way.
Black mark or two.
You were on your own
for a while last year.
Vice.
What made you come back
to the strike team?
I would think
that you would want
to make a name for yourself flying solo.
Like you dribbling shit
all over us
to make a name for yourself?
All the same.
Living in Mackey's
shadow all the time.
You don't feel that
he was trying to get
you back into the fold
so that he could get
a leash on you, do you?
What's here
is how it went down.
So there was just
you, Vic, Terry,
and Two Time
in that room.
Just me and Vic.
No Lemansky?
No Gardocki?
It was true then.
It's true now.
Thanks so much
for your help.
I'm gonna need you
to sign a document
confirming that you know
that we are reopening
the Terry Crawley case
and you are
under investigation.
Blow me.
I've talked to every
precinct in the city.
No recent bodies
matching Kleavon's M.O.
You gonna do something
with that?
Just got off the phone
with robbery-homicide.
Turns out they didn't
just find me.
A veteran detective
recommended they review my file.
I'm gonna check
missing persons again.
Are you trying
to get rid of me?
I thought robbery-homicide
was your dream job.
I didn't need your help.
There is buzz.
You guys have
a Fatima Gardner
sign in to see you
this morning?
Yeah.
Her brother
just reported her missing.
Yeah.
Captain left
a few things up here.
He asked me to get them.
Sure.
Anything you need.
I pulled this
off the wall downstairs.
Pretty demeaning,
don't you think?
Doesn't really
bother me.
It's just boys
being boys.
A lot of money on Vic
being your baby's daddy.
Everybody's
got an opinion.
Heard a lot of rumors
about the two of you.
Are you saying
that they aren't true?
Look, I'm sure
you won't blame me
when I don't discuss
stupid gossip
about my personal life
with IAD.
Sexual relationships
between department personnel
need to be divulged
in a timely manner.
According to
the employee handbook.
Failure to do so
can result in suspensions.
Even demotions.
You just got
a pay bump recently.
Didn't you?
Come on. There's no
relationship between me and Vic.
Should I
make this official?
Because I can do that.
Widen my investigation.
Vic and I had a thing, ok?
It's in the past.
When was that?
8 or 9 months ago?
You want to get
a court order
to draw blood,
go right ahead,
but this is
none of your business.
You still have to disclose
your relationship
with Mackey.
Fill out the forms today.
And I'll overlook
the tardiness.
Hey, Vic.
Checked out our next
Bop Street target
on Hoover.
Doors and windows
are fortified.
All right. Have Ronnie
get a doorknocker.
Flash bangs, too.
All right, Vic.
Hey. Hang on.
Gunsmoke.
We're just about
to pay a visit
to another one
of your crack palaces.
Man, I don't know
who capped my peoples.
But I tell you
straight up,
it wasn't no
Bop Street niggas.
After Hoover,
we're gonna stop by
your Temple Street
smoke house.
That'll bring your one
day loss to what, 12k?
You know what it does
to my street cred
even walking into
this pig farm?
Oink when you got
something we can use.
Hold up. Hold up.
Come here.
Tell them.
I'm chillin' at
homegirls around the way,
hear shots, see these
two vatos drive off.
What'd they
look like?
Vatos. You know.
Shaved heads.
White tees.
Guy driving had L.A.
tattooed all up in here.
But I didn't get a good
look at the dude shooting.
What kind of car?
Old. I don't know.
But they was riding on gold
anodized hundred spoke D's.
I know my wheels.
So we straight now?
Not yet.
How's a punk ass wigger
like Kasper
get respect from
a crew hard as Bop Street?
I thought he was a poser
myself for a minute.
White boy
got business skills.
Split 50-50 off top.
Folks is gettin' paid.
Comes with these names
for the product.
Pink yo, yellow fever.
Same old shit
only different color caps.
You moving
Kasper's product
out of the place we
took down this morning?
Look, man. Fiends want
what Kasper's selling.
Can't argue
with the free market.
Looking forward to that
truce again, fellas.
Hey, Vic.
You got a second?
I'll get on those rims.
What's up?
That guy from IAD got all over
me about department policy.
Disclosure of personal
relationships on the job.
None of his business.
Yeah, well, he's
pushing me really hard.
I can't take a suspension
or pay cut right now.
I gotta notify Billings.
Just wanted you to know.
When was the last time
you saw your sister?
Lunch time.
Said she was gonna run out
for some soda, never came back.
Family drinks
a lot of soda.
Seem to remember
you were out for soda
when Lana Gregory was killed.
It's only a few hours,
grown woman.
Bit premature
to call the police.
I know my sister.
She say she'll be back,
she'll be back.
Mind if we look around?
Wouldn't have
called you if I did.
I'll take her room,
you take his.
Fatima's room's clean.
Back door's unlocked.
What do you have?
It's what I don't have.
Kleavon's death kit.
Latex gloves, knife,
duct tape.
It's gone.
I was here earlier.
What?
Spur of the moment.
Fatima gave her consent.
You searched a murder
suspect's house without backup?
What if Kleavon
had showed up?
I hid in the closet.
He didn't see me.
I slipped out
the back door.
Jesus. If you're wrong,
and he confronted her
after you left...
I shouldn't have
come alone.
But I wasn't sure
you were up to it.
Stress is a trigger.
I saw you were
hurting this morning.
I am fine.
Got a neighbor
says he saw a prowler
exiting the backyard
this morning.
Wearing what he called
a hundred dollar suit.
I'll deal
with the neighbor.
If you think
I'm up to it.
Take Kleavon to the
barn and get a statement.
I paid $300 for this suit.
Hey.
Who's this ?
It's Terry Crowley.
One of my guys
killed by a drug dealer
a couple years ago.
That is one version.
Terry was working
for justice.
Investigating allegations
of the relationship
between drug dealers
and your clients.
You have
a different version?
Detective Mackey
either acted alone,
or with other members
of his team,
killed detective Crawley.
Or put him in a position
to be killed.
Just like that russian
I was gonna murder
before you blew our sting?
Any evidence or are you
all attitude?
In due course.
These theatrics
why you wanted to see us?
I'm sure the three of us
have better things to do.
Yes.
I'm officially informing you
you are under investigation
for the death of Terry Crowley
and other allegations
of corruption.
You have a right
to a PBA rep,
or a lawyer.
I see you already
got one.
And a good one.
Please, could you get him
to initial here and here
and his signature there.
We'll cooperate fully,
so you can stop wasting
everyone's time, lieutenant.
I suppose you want
a statement.
Actually, if you could
have your clients
walk me through the house
where Terry Crawley
was killed,
that would be great.
Arrange it soon.
Oh, and take down
these photos.
Or I'll file
for harassment.
Becca.
I thought the headline in this
case was David against Goliath.
Or did this murder charge
slip your mind?
I can't talk
about this right now.
This is a big
goddamn deal.
It's all a lie.
I'm sorry.
I'll call you later.
What the hell's
going on?
He told them
to bring me in.
Can you take the kids?
You don't have to talk to him, remember?
I just want to
get this over with.
He can't compel
your cooperation.
If you feel uncomfortable at any time,
you just leave.
Ok.
Corinne.
Thanks for coming.
The children,
they can wait inside.
I can take care
of my own kids.
Ok.
This way. Upstairs.
Dad, what the hell's
going on?
Don't talk like that.
He's a cop, right?
Did Mom do something wrong?
No. Never.
Come on, honey.
Vic...
I, um... caught a 187
times two.
We need you
to get on it.
What's 187 mean?
It means Dad's gonna
find you guys a ride.
Come on, kids.
Let's go.
You need anything?
Can I get you something?
Coffee?
Just ask your questions.
You told me
that it's difficult
to make both the tuitions.
Yet Vic seems to appear
to come up with the money
all the time.
How do you think
he does that?
Overtime.
Yeah. I've checked
those paystubs.
He always has been a good
provider, wouldn't you say?
I guess that my change
now that you
split the pie.
Four ways
instead of three, huh?
I don't understand.
Oh, maybe...
you're not aware?
Officer Danielle Sofer,
who works here,
is filing paperwork admitting
to a sexual relationship
with Vic over the last
couple of years.
When did you get divorced?
Last year.
Right.
Officer Sofer
is now pregnant.
Is this another
imaginary child like Andy?
I mean, what kind of a man
says he has an autistic child
to a woman that has
two of her own?
How sick is that?
I didn't really like
doing that. I'm sorry.
I just needed to know what
kind of woman you are, Corinne.
Really, I mean,
this is not about me.
This is about Vic.
It's about you,
it's about the kids.
It's about...
this new baby.
How we got
to this place
and where we're
gonna go from here.
Please...
have a seat.
L.A. Cali-for-nia.
Same caliber
as the Bop Street hit.
It's gotta be the
shooter from this morning.
Payback's a bitch.
And karma's a whore.
Amado Alvaro. His place.
No sign
of forced entry.
What about
ass boy over there?
No ID yet.
Neighbor called 911.
Saw Alvaro's car
driving away
a little while after
she heard the gunshots.
Hoopty? Gold rims?
Yeah. '69
Olds Cutlass.
Black.
Run Alvaro's registration.
Put an APB out
on the car.
Got it.
Let me get a run on
a '69 Olds Cutlass.
Vehicle should be rolling up
to you right now, detective.
You see it?
We got it.
Nice work, Larry.
Say hello to whoever
killed L.A. and ass boy.
Who's the Chinaman?
I don't know. But we're gonna find out.
Hey, get back here!
Stop!
Hey!
Hold. Hold it!
Hey, stop, dumb ass.
It's a barbed wire fence.
I didn't do nothing.
Except a double homicide.
That's crazy.
Amado's my main man.
Funny how you know exactly the
murders we're talking about.
We've got you fleeing
the scene of a murder
in the victim's car.
You take one last look
at the outside world.
Where'd you put
the murder weapon?
They were dead
when I got there.
I swear.
All right.
Search the car.
He was into me
for 10 grand.
Some white guy
named Kasper
was coming by
to drop off money.
Amado was
meeting Kasper?
I wasn't
supposed to know.
Kasper was coming by to pay
him for some work he did.
When I saw bodies,
I bounced.
We need to take another run at Kasper.
Remember Terry Crowley?
Sure. He was on
Vic's team.
Do you remember any change
in Vic's behavior
leading up to Terry's death?
No. But he was pretty
torn up afterwards.
We all were.
I'm sure it was terrible.
Terry was working
for justice.
Investigating your ex
husband's team for corruption.
Planting evidence,
extortion.
Kickbacks.
Laundry list of things.
When the Vic made Terry
as working for the feds,
we believe that he and
Shane Vandrell murdered him.
Vic's a lot of things,
but he's no killer.
Vic is a survivor.
He'll do
whatever it takes.
To protect himself,
his team,
and his family.
Are you really
trying to tell me
that after 12 years
of marriage,
you don't think
that that man
is capable of pulling
the trigger on someone
who's trying to take away
everything from him?
Everything?
You need to stop this, ok?
Don't cry.
I don't want to
see you shed one
single tear.
Because tears imply
that you didn't know.
And don't you sit here
and tell me
that you didn't know,
Mrs. Mackey.
12 years,
you share his bed.
You knew.
You paid your mortgage.
You paid your bills.
And now he's paying
for private schools.
You always knew what he
was capable of.
Just like you knew
about the other women.
Don't you sit here
and cry
and tell me that he's
a good man
because we both know
that's bullshit.
You left him
because you knew.
And yet you protect him...
you protect him
and you lie.
You lie to me.
No.
Don't you dare sit here
shedding tears...
you can only do that
if you've earned
that right.
If it was all a surprise.
But it's not a surprise
to the woman
who knew him better
than anyone on this earth.
Is it?
Police, open up!
Please...
Help me.
Please.
Sir, what's the problem?
Something's got me.
My dick. Please...
Please...
Hurry.
Sir, just relax.
I'm gonna try...
No! No! No!
Oh, god!
Oh, please.
Please hurry up!
You're caught
in a rat trap.
Call the paramedics.
One Tango Bravo
requesting paramedics
for male hispanic
mid thirties.
Sir, it's ok.
Paramedics are on the way.
Damn.
Ouch. Meanwhile,
this IAD guy
has got my nuts
in a waffle iron.
You say this happened
at a glory hole?
Yeah, it's pretty
sick, huh?
Yeah. Guy's lucky his
schlong wasn't cut off.
I figure the perp only
let it snap halfway.
Otherwise,
it would've...
no question.
Anyway, we're re-interviewing
the victim
as soon as he gets back
from the hospital.
Price tag. Check out the
hardware store that sold it.
Yeah. It's one of 20
in the same transaction
two days ago.
That's why my T.O. thought
you'd want to put
detectives on it.
I can't spare any, so why
don't you guys run with it.
It's right up
Julian's alley.
It's the kind of case,
he can really
sink his teeth into.
You and Fatima
had a fight.
She was nagging you
too much,
invading your privacy?
Lady, I came to you.
Now y'all want to pull me
in here about this thing.
You're wasting time.
My sister's missing.
And we're trying
to find her.
Then why ain't you out
talking to my neighbor
about the man he saw
at my place?
We're following up
on that.
To help you
find your sister,
you have to start
answering questions.
You gonna
cooperate or not?
Anything for her.
Give us a minute.
Anyone else, I'd say he's
genuinely concerned about her.
Given that he's a homicidal
sociopath, who knows.
When we get this guy, I want
to administer the needle myself.
Wow. He's really
under your skin.
I wish I could
get under his.
Ok. Maybe we hit Kleavon
with the bloody shirt,
the missing death kit,
we get him rattled.
We've already
exposed the team enough.
I don't want to
blow our cover.
She could still be
out there alive.
You know,
he could've realized
the bloody shirt
was missing,
figured out Fatima
turned on him
even if he
didn't see me.
Great. Now that we've
covered your ass,
you help me figure out
what to do.
4:00 this afternoon.
Where were you?
4:00 this afternoon?
I was at Monie's crib.
Hitting the skins
and smoking endo.
You don't believe me,
ask the girl.
You know
an Armado Alvaro?
No.
Shot and killed
in his home
along with a buddy.
Pretty messy.
Rest in peace.
Matches
the description
of someone we're
looking for in the attack
on you and your peeps.
Like the book says,
"No hand raised against
me shall prosper."
The other DB
is Adair Zeborio.
Vegas PD was looking at
him on a murder for hire.
Case didn't make.
Professional hit.
He didn't get
the whole job done,
wigger got the last word.
This punk? Unlikely.
Gilligan's still
half baked on chronic.
Let's keep him yapping.
See where it gets us.
All right.
Am I done here?
No, you're not done here.
Not until you tell us
what you were doing in Amado
Alvaro's apartment today.
You all are buggin'.
I was at my homegirl's.
How I'm gonna try
and kill somebody
I never even heard of?
And how long before you
piss of the wrong mandingo
and he wastes your pasty
wigger ass as reparations?
Streets got nothing
but love for Kasper
long as I'm putting
money in their pockets.
One bad month,
and you'll be
dangling from a balcony,
just like Vanilla Ice.
Another great
white wannabe.
Next thing you know,
we're gonna be hearing
about some shitty
rap album
you're gonna
want to put out.
Why you tripping on this
black-white shit?
Color ain't a thing.
Oh, come on, man.
This is just us
glacier monkeys.
We both know white is
right and black is wack.
Which is why
you're rolling
with the pretty white lady.
You might talk
like a brother,
but you hang
with your own.
Not that the sisters
would show you love anyway.
Man, I get more black ass
than a bus bench in Compton.
Ya heard.
Hard time imagining you
holding it down
with some nubian
mattress monster.
Well, then you need to
ask somebody, one time.
Taneisha's
my go-to girl.
She let me tear her phat
ass and sugar walls up
any time I want.
White ho's only around
'cuz she swallows nut,
and I can take her home
to moms without any drama.
Word.
That little douche bag is
starting to piss me off.
Yeah, well, he
gave us enough
to put his alibi
to the taste test.
Pick up the girlfriend.
I'm gonna stick around.
You must've
seen something.
The assailant had to walk right past you
to leave that bathroom.
I really didn't get
a look at him.
Get a booking slip going.
I need you to stand.
Hands behind your back.
What?
Stand. Hands behind
your back.
You're arresting me?
Public indecency.
Lewd conduct.
I'm not the one
who did anything.
You think maybe
I've suffered enough?
I have a wife
and daughters,
if they find out...
look, I don't normally
do this sort of thing.
Just once or twice
to work stuff out.
Please. Don't do this.
It'll ruin
my marriage.
Come on, Sir.
Come on.
I don't have to
say anything to you.
We were married,
and I'm protected
under spousal privilege.
He told you
to say that, didn't he?
Because it protects him.
You know you can
waive that right
anytime you want to, right?
Which is why he probably
didn't even tell you
to get an attorney,
did he?
He got his own lawyer.
Maybe you saw her
downstairs.
She's real pretty.
Dark haired.
Such a good provider.
And yet...
he's covering his ass.
He's covering
his guys' ass.
And he leaves you
just hanging out there.
You know why?
Because he doesn't
want you listening
to anybody else
but him.
Your lawyer would be
looking after your interests.
And that doesn't
help him.
That hurts him,
in fact, so...
your lawyer would
advise you to cooperate.
To tell me the truth. Tell
me what I want to know.
But you're here...
all alone.
You want to know
what I see?
I mean just looking
at you.
I see a mother of three,
going away for
obstructing justice
protecting a man
she knows is a criminal.
What are your two
autistic children gonna do
when you're... locked away
and serving your sentence?
What are they gonna do?
How are they gonna be
in foster care?
Stop it!
Well, tell me
what I want to know.
I'm just asking you
to tell me...
tell me
what I want to know.
Vic is not going
to take care of those
kids when you're gone.
Vic gave me some cash
in a bag
a little while ago.
That's it. I don't know anything else.
There was nothing else.
How... how much?
65,000.
Where'd it come from?
I didn't ask.
I never asked.
And where is it?
I spent most of it
on tuition,
and on therapists.
There's only about
$5,000 left.
I need that money.
I need that money back.
Now.
Now you can cry.
You might wanna
rethink this alibi
you're handing Kasper.
We can put him
in the crib
where Amado Alvaro
got his brains splashed.
That's the guy
that shot at you
and killed
your friends.
If you're lying to cover
for your mad boy toy,
we can get you on
conspiracy to commit murder.
Just like pulling the trigger yourself.
You'll be old
and in the way
by the time you see
the sky again.
I've got
nothing to say.
Period point blank.
Kasper's got plenty
to say about you.
I get more black ass than
a bunch bench in Compton.
Ya heard.
Hard time imagining you holding it down
with some nubian
mattress monster.
You better ask somebody, one time.
Taniesha's
my go-to girl.
She let me tear her phat
ass and sugar walls up
anytime I want.
White ho's only around
'cuz she swallows nut.
You all right?
Don't talk to me.
What happened?
Not now.
Just let me go.
Corinne...
Corinne,
I'll call you.
Vic, Moni gave up
our friendly ghost.
What's wrong?
Come on, man.
Let's go.
You know, the thing
about women.
And it doesn't really
matter what color they are.
When they get pissed off,
watch out.
Moni just threw your
pink-ass cheeks to the curb.
You had the smarts,
the business model,
stripper girlfriend.
What you didn't have
was the street cred.
Not really.
Not like some
hard ass brother.
You're only
a true baller
when somebody
wants you dead.
And if the bullets
miss you,
makes you immortal
to the streets, right?
So you hired
Alvaro and Zeborio
to shoot up your friends.
Make you look like
the target.
Market yourself
as some bad ass dude
instead of
a punk ass white boy.
You been smoking crack.
Your girl Moni
just gave us the key
to her locker
at the Cheetah
where she stashed
the Tek-Nine
you did the two
hit men with.
Shooter
out of the way,
you don't have to pay
for the hit, right?
The business man in you
saw a way to save a buck.
Instead it's gonna
cost you
three to five dimes
in the State Pen.
Bitches ain't shit.
Your sister's
a church going woman.
You grow up that way?
Jesus is my savior.
That's what you mean?
That's what I love
about the church.
No matter
how bad you are,
how often, forgiveness
is always there.
All you gotta do
is come clean.
What's that got to do with finding her?
I don't know.
Maybe she started
looking at you funny
after you murdered Lana.
Maybe she wanted
to ask you about it,
but she was too scared.
And then one day,
it all came out.
But you couldn't have that,
so you had her killed,
and reported her missing,
so you could make
yourself look innocent.
No!
I didn't kill my sister.
That's my blood.
They were all somebody's blood, Kleavon.
Didn't stop you then.
Why would it
stop you this time?
Don't talk to me
like that.
I'll talk to you any
way I goddamn please.
You can't arrest me, and
you're not helping me.
I'll find her myself.
I'd be willing to make
these charges go away
on two conditions.
Anything you want.
You never do this type
of thing again.
My word.
And you help us I.D.
The guy who did this.
Then I'll be involved
in a court case.
I know how this works.
My brother's a lawyer.
Either way,
it's all public.
I'll keep your name
out of this.
But I cannot
get this guy
and his 19 other
rat traps off the street
without your help.
Bridge of his nose
is right,
but his cheekbones
are higher.
Hey.
You decided
to cut him some slack?
Lesser of two evils.
Gets the kook
off the streets.
You think we're looking
for a vigilante?
Don't know.
Julien, you and I
got off to a rough start.
But I feel like things
are starting
to make more sense.
Good.
Look, man, I grew up
with my gay uncle
living with us.
So it's no
big deal to me.
But I saw what he
had to go through.
I honestly just didn't get
your situation.
I'm not sure what you're trying to say.
All I'm saying
is that I understand.
And it's between
you and your wife anyway,
so I'm cool.
You're cool with what?
That I'm the T.O.
That should've
washed you out
weeks ago?
You don't
understand anything.
I know why you recommended
me for robbery-homicide.
No need to thank me.
You're getting sicker,
and you can't bear
for me to see it.
A woman may be dead because
you wanted to protect me.
I shouldn't have done
the search without you.
I'm sorry.
I do not let my illness
get in the way of my job.
You do.
That's dangerous.
I'm not leaving you.
Detectives.
You wanted
to be notified
of any black, female
dump jobs.
Late forties.
Probably strangled.
That's not
Kleavon's M.O.
That's his sister.
Uni says
it looks like rape.
His own sister?
It's not Fatima.
Who is it?
Look at this.
He chopped her hair off.
Yeah.
Not with scissors.
Probably a knife.
You recognize the haircut?
Looks like I got under
Kleavon's skin after all.
Hey.
Thanks for swinging by.
I wanted to finish this
in person.
Me, too. If you didn't
before, now you can see
how out of control
Kavanaugh is.
I need to decide
if I want to represent you.
Any of you.
First, you're
a sacrificial lamb
to appease angry voters
after that referendum tanked.
We're the good guys
in this.
Only not that good.
Because then you tell me
Aceveda had you doing
dirty work for him
and is setting you up
to take the fall.
Today I find out,
this is about
capital murder on a cop.
Becca, it's a put up job.
Right now...
I have no clue about who
the hell you really are.
How can I help you
with that?
I actually had
a kernel of faith
that you could
take the guy down.
Now it just seems like
you've lost your senses.
You're under
investigation, Councilman.
For what?
Your connection
with Mackey.
I don't understand how you're
so gung-ho to get this guy,
yet be in his pocket
at the same time.
Something I got
to look at.
You still think
that I helped Vic
set you up
with that russian sting?
Man, he got to you.
Playing us
against each other.
You may as well fold up
your tent and go home.
One thing
I know for sure...
when you sat in this office,
could've put
an end to him.
But you didn't.
Now it's my turn.
You seriously think this
little display of yours
is going to work?
I need you to
initial here, here,
and I need
your signature here.
You're still
a reserve cop, right?
I do have
authority over you.
You walk out that door,
I'm gonna
take your badge.
And I'm gonna tell
every reporter in town why.
Then you may as well
add insubordination
to your list of
bullshit allegations.
You want any
paperwork signed,
you send it
to my office.
I'll have the city
attorney take a look at it.
Fine.
I'm chairman
of the Police Committee.
This is a fight
you don't want.
I didn't want
any of it.
But I'm here...
and I'm staying.
Corinne, call me.
Kavanaugh's upstairs
with Aceveda.
What the hell's
going on?
It's almost 8:00
and he's till at it.
What do we do,
just leave for the night?
Subtitles:
FRM-xxy & Sapotille
www.1000fr.com
www.theshield-laserie.com