Previously on The Shield...
yesterday, measure 16 on
the city ballot failed,
which means we'll have to make
do with the lack of manpower
here in the Barn
and on the streets.
If I hold this
up long enough,
some people
feel compelled
to take the gum.
It's a sign they'll
crack under pressure.
Gum?
Oh, no thanks.
Here you go.
Sure. Thanks.
Did you know that I.A.D has been
looking into detective Mackey
and the Strike Team he ran
while under your command?
We've got Lemansky.
He lifted a brick of tar
off the el Salvadorans.
We've been waiting for it
to spin into something more.
You've still got
nothing on Mackey.
We got a C.I. Next to him, and
when he jumps dirty, we'll know.
These guys are tight,
and Lemansky is a soldier.
So you're gonna
need something
to drive a wedge
between him and Mackey.
Terry was working with justice
to bring down Mackey,
and I think Vic
had him killed.
You killed... a cop?
Get over it.
Don't bring it up again.
Curtis Lemansky,
I want you to come with us.
Why is it that the guy
with the conscience
always has to get caught
holdin' the bag?
What do you want?
We want the guy that
put him into motion.
Who do you think
I want, Curtis?
Still no Lem?
Left a second message.
Probably knee-deep
in a booty call.
Hope he's gettin'
a cop discount.
Yeah. I hear yours
charges by the minute.
Hey, I get mine
for free.
Must be seeing
a charity worker.
I was just about
to call you again.
I think it's nice of you
to finally show up.
Better be a damned
good reason
for you blowin' up
my cell phone.
Who dimed you that
crack mule last year?
It's payback time, man.
Come look at this.
Jeez.
Man,
look at my windshields.
We don't monitor
lemon laws.
Good thing
they're sold "as is."
Look, don't
waste my time again.
Next time you call me,
it better be somethin' real.
Shit! The name "Vic Mackey" used
to have some juice around here.
Up to no good? Lookin' to
run and hide from Vic Mackey?
Oh, no, he'd find you,
and you'd get yours.
Now assholes like him
lean on honest people
'cause they know cops like you
can't do dick anymore.
Who's leanin'?
Wetback...
street name "Doomsday."
Squeezin' every shop on
the block for insurance.
Is that real enough
for you?
How long has it
been goin' on?
Couple months.
Now I've come in today, and I
missed on payment... one payment...
and look at
my windshields now.
Man, my son's right.
He's right. It's every man
for himself from now on.
Shit! I shoulda
paid that prick off!
You're scared.
It's understandable.
You made a serious mistake, and
you don't see a way out of this.
I didn't commit any crime.
I'm a goddamn cop.
Gotta start with denial till you
get your head around all this.
It's cool. I understand, really.
We got time yet.
I've never seen
those drugs before.
Come on, man.
It was taken from your
vehicle with a search warrant.
I got the seizure on videotape.
You know, I can walk
outta here right now?
Yeah, well, if you do,
I'm gonna have to arrest you,
take you downtown,
make it official.
I'm trying to save you
the embarrassment here.
I got nothin' to be
embarrassed about.
We've both been through
enough of these.
So I can be straight
with you, yeah?
Sure.
Every guilty suspect that
you've ever interviewed
started with denial,
right?
So did the innocent ones.
Ah, you must be Doomsday.
Who are you?
I'm Armageddon.
Say hello to the hounds
of hell.
Ruff.
You've been squeezin' some
of the local business owners.
Consider us
the better business bureau.
We're shuttin'
your ass down.
I didn't invite you in.
You got some paper
or somethin'?
It's an unofficial
visit.
Letting you know
the cops are still on
the job in Farmington.
Yeah. We're puttin'
the word out,
one asshole at a time.
Get your toy cop ass
outta here.
Are you gettin' my message,
or do you need
your ears cleaned?
What are you
laughin' at?
The only words I want
to hear out of your mouth
are "Sí, señor."
Suck my dick, señor.
Arrr!
Hey!
No warrant.
It's your call.
Hey, over here.
Come on.
Get up.
Get up!
Get him!
Here. Come on.
Hands up.
That'll give you
plenty of time
to think about your
new career direction.
We'll return this
to its rightful owners.
You're gonna take a piss,
be sure and give us a call.
Arrrr!
I need to get back
to my team.
Eat somethin'.
We're gonna be here
for a while.
The only thing outside
that door for you
is a prison cell,
and I haven't
been able to tell you
how I'm gonna keep you
out of it yet.
You know,
I read your package,
and I met with
one of your partners,
and he said that... he said that
you made a lot of great arrests.
You started off
an upright guy.
What happened to you?
How did you go from riding
with cops to haunting 'em?
"Tio osmond,
"diagur leyva,
connie reisler..."
they were all
Strike Team CIs?
So what?
Any of the people you work
with make it out alive?
They chose the life.
They chose to cooperate
with the police,
and now they're dead.
Better them than us.
Or did you forget that
from the academy?
Angie stubbs...
she was 15
when she helped you
before
she was murdered.
She choose the life, too?
No.
She was a good kid.
Bet she was.
What do you think
should happen to, uh...
to someone who kills
a kid like that...
to someone who kills a cop...
or a grandma?
Life in prison,
death penalty?
The needle's too good
for someone like that.
Finally...
we agree
on something here.
Detective Terry Crowley.
Remember him?
21/2 years ago, he was
on your Strike Team.
He was undercover
when he was killed,
part of a federal
investigation into your team.
You know what?
I've seen a lot of things
that make me think
that you're a good guy.
I just cannot figure out
how you could be involved
with this murder.
What are you
talking about?
Terry was killed
by a drug dealer.
I was there.
I know you were there.
But we both know that that
is not the way it went down.
Could you be more
full of shit right now?
Terry was killed
in the line of duty.
The one thing
I know for sure...
is that by the end
of the day,
you are only gonna be
helping me with the truth,
or you are going to be
behind bars.
THE ENEMY OF GOOD
What's up, big mama?
You ready to announce
papa yet?
Yeah, well, you'll
be the last to know.
Listen, guys,
Lem's running late.
He call in?
No. A friend did,
said his car broke down.
He'll be in
as soon as he can.
OK, thanks.
I guess honey wasn't
nothin' to write home about.
Got multiple homicides
on dozier.
Billings
gave this to you.
This gang?
You tell us.
2 black males,
a black female.
You're no one till
somebody kills ya.
Not in this corner
of paradise.
These kids
aren't flyin' colors.
Any forced entry?
Back door's
busted in.
Victims had cash
on them, credit cards.
Whoever it was
didn't get much.
Whoever it was got
exactly what they came for.
She called it in.
Came over to study
with her friends,
saw the bodies
through the window.
Street's gang neutral.
Plus, this was a beating,
not a shooting.
Strictly personal.
Any crack houses
in this neighborhood?
None that register.
All right, let's find
out who these kids were,
what they were into.
Bodies are still warm.
Let's crack it
before they cool.
Shop owner found him
on the pavement.
He didn't recognize him.
Strong odor of alcohol.
Any bars nearby?
No. A couple of
auto body shops,
church up the street.
I checked the wallet.
He lives 10 blocks from here.
Good. You're starting
to get an instinct
for the right things
to look for.
Well, he didn't
walk here on his own,
not in that condition.
Check the houses on
this side of the alley
and look around
for some teeth.
Guillermo solis...
alcohol-induced coma.
The emt says 50/50.
Where have you been?
I'm here now.
Since when does a misdemeanor
drunk-in-public need 2 detectives?
I don't think this guy
got plastered and fell over.
He had broken teeth,
facial cuts.
I'm callin' it
an assault.
Any sign of robbery?
They didn't
take his money.
I'm thinkin'
he was dumped here.
So he got drunk.
He passed out.
They drug him here and let
somebody else deal with it.
It's not the most
neighborly thing,
but we've seen worse,
and we didn't call it assault.
Well... maybe.
Hang on a second.
I saw you look out.
Now, open up. Now!
Always look out your window?
There's cops.
I was curious.
Curious enough to see somethin' that
happened earlier across the street?
Uh-uh.
We're gonna keep talkin'.
It's only gonna take
your neighbors about 30 seconds
to figure you do
know somethin'.
So you might as well tell me
so I can get off your porch.
Quiet.
I came home
to let my dogs out,
and I saw somebody
leaving that house.
What did he look like?
You got somethin'?
I'm not leavin'
till I find out.
Look,
the guy was scary.
He looked right at me,
and I went cold.
He looked like evil, OK?
Go now.
I'm gonna take you and put you
with a sketch artist.
You said you'd
leave me alone.
A lot of people wanna know
what evil looks like.
Councilman,
hey, hey, hey!
Hey, I picked up
Lemansky last night.
Where is he?
Back at the motel.
Feel him out before I
make a move, you know?
What about the rest
of the team?
You were right about Lemansky.
And this Terry murder...
it is a soft spot.
But with me, you know,
it's still theoretical.
I mean, I'm trying to
get inside him,
and I will
get inside it,
but I need you to add that
personal element to it.
The department brought you
in to close this,
and you come
running back to me.
I can just see
where this is goin',
and I'm not above
askin' for help.
Besides, I thought
Crowley was your friend.
He was.
You suspected Mackey
all along,
and you just let him go.
I pursued it
as far as I could.
Yeah, well,
here's another chance.
Mackey's out the door
in 4 months,
forced retirement.
Out the door?
15-year pension...
that ain't a bad reward
for killin' a cop, is it?
I'm sorry.
Please. Sorry.
We could never prove it.
But you know it...
and now, we've got someone
that can prove it.
Hold on a second.
Witness
give you something?
You gotta see this.
Sure looks a lot like the
Salvadoran we leaned on today...
Doomsday?
It could be.
It's hard to tell.
Besides, he's tied up.
Is that Doomsday?
You put this out yet?
Yeah. It went out on
the wire a few minutes ago.
It gets worse. I.D. S came
back on victims at the house.
Community college geeks,
no history of trouble.
One of the males
last names was Hughes.
As in Hughes used cars?
It was his kid.
Big-d said he didn't pay
last week, remember?
So Doomsday
sent a message.
We don't know that yet.
A couple of
busted windshields.
Why did we push so hard?
'Cause there's still some
goddamn laws in Farmington,
no matter what
the voters reject.
Plus, he came at me.
He was in my face.
That the suspect in
the triple murder?
Yeah.
Do we know him?
Ah, it could be a Salvadoran
lowlife lives in the neighborhood.
We're trying to
get a 20 on him now.
You think it's
another racial incident?
I'll let you know.
Great. Grab some extra
unis if you need 'em.
If we can find one.
So we 'cause a triple murder
before breakfast,
start a race war
before dinner.
That's a pretty good day.
Get the word out
to the aztecs and zulus
that this wasn't retribution.
Some beef about business,
that's all.
You with me?
Yeah.
He chew through
that goddamn thing?
Holy shit!
We gotta find this guy.
You got a minute?
Sure.
Come in.
I need a line
on a Salvadoran,
calls himself Doomsday.
You heard of him?
No. Know where he lives?
Temple/colter area.
You got friends
down there?
I'd have to spread
a little love around.
Ahh... boy...
I need to pull this guy
off the street now.
This is one
of those times
you can earn yourself
some real money.
That's too much, Vic.
All I need is a couple
of dubs for my girls.
Keep what you save.
10 times that amount if
we can get him in custody.
Everything copasetic?
Yeah.
That's what I like to hear.
All the emperor needs is a toga
and a violin while Farmington burns.
And they offered you
that job first,
and you turned it down.
And it would have been
yours, but you screwed it up.
Mrs. Solis,
thanks for comin' in.
How's your husband?
At the hospital they said the
machines are keeping him alive,
but his brain...
sorry.
We, uh, we just need
your signature... here,
and you can take
his personal effects.
Did you see your husband
last night?
I took him to church
for his meeting.
Is it
a 12-step program?
AA didn't work
for guillermo.
He just kept on
drinking.
Well, what sort
of meeting was this?
Señor Romero has them drink
until the alcohol
cures the sickness.
Aversion therapy?
You weren't concerned
when he didn't come home?
Señor Romero lets them
sleep at the church
if they're in, you know,
bad shape.
Who's señor Romero
again?
Our minister.
Señor Romero?
Yes?
We need to talk to you
about guillermo solis.
Is there a problem?
He's in a coma.
He may not live.
Too much drink.
Lord...
bless his soul.
We understand you were
treating him for substance abuse
at the church last night?
No. I don't treat people. I
don't have a license for that.
He attends our prayer group.
Where you feed booze
to alcoholics.
That's fascinating.
Everything they drink, they
drink of their own free will.
We fight the sickness
with sickness.
This aversion therapy... it
really works for some people?
It's how I conquered
my issues with alcohol,
otherwise I wouldn't have
my business and my church.
My ex-wife was a drunk.
Do you think if I'd hauled her
off to happy hour every night
I could've
saved the marriage?
I wouldn't
want to speculate.
Who else was there
last night?
Hector santiago...
he works at the church,
and he's going through
the therapy.
Just the 3 of you?
Well, the group
gets smaller
as more of us
are healed.
Well, uh...
keep up the good work.
Sure.
Told you
I had a feeling.
Preachers need to
stick to preaching.
Want me to ask Romero if
he's got that in your size?
OK, witness was worried
about her dogs.
She made me promise
to come check on 'em.
Living room.
This Doomsday ain't
a member of p.e.t.a.
What do we know
about Doomsday?
He's from north carolina,
did a stint for agg assault
in atascadero,
got out 6 months ago.
Took a guy's eye out
with a fork
for stealin'
his food
in Junior high.
Keep pressin'
the local sets.
Guys like this
make friends all over.
It's a good thing
you pulled Irma in.
Where are the heads?
Nowhere. Checked
the whole place.
He took
the goddamn dogs' heads?
What's he gonna do,
put 'em on a pike?
We gotta find this freak.
Councilman.
You two know each other
already.
Curtis.
What are you doing here?
You've got a big decision to
make, and not a lot of time.
So I thought you should get as
much information as possible.
It's time for you to step
into the sunlight, Lem.
Look, I didn't
do anything wrong.
You're not
my captain anymore.
You took some heroin.
You got caught.
Now, we're not just talkin'
about your career here, Lem.
The city referendum showed all of
us what the public thinks of cops,
and the department's fighting
to change that perception,
so somebody
has to pay a price,
and right now, that's you.
Well, you know what? I'll take my
chances with the truth in court.
Everything that lieutenant Kavanaugh
told you about Terry was true.
You know, Terry didn't have
a grudge against Vic going in.
But it only took him 2 weeks to
find out that Vic was a dirty cop.
I have his original notes
detailing his suspicions.
He was your teammate,
he was a threat,
so he had to die.
No! Never!
You didn't know, did you?
Vic never told you.
All this time, I thought the
four of you were in it together,
but you really didn't know.
This changes everything.
You're sayin'...
you didn't know about it
until right now.
It was the other guys.
I didn't say that!
I didn't say that.
But you didn't know.
I mean, I respect a guy
bein' loyal,
but now you're protecting
a guy for somethin'
that you don't
have any stake in,
somethin' that
you told me
the death penalty
was too good for.
This is a damn
witch hunt right now.
You cannot be a cop and
be a part of it with him.
You gotta choose.
Vic did not kill Terry!
So prove it.
Wear a wire.
Ask him as a friend.
Let's see what
he's got to say.
You want to railroad
an innocent guy,
go ahead and do it.
Do it.
But I do not
have to help.
So you'd rather
take on prison
than someone who took out
one of your own?
Oh, that...
that is a tough choice...
but I understand.
Guillermo
was a jealous man.
The drinking
only made it worse.
You give him a reason
to be jealous?
Why are you asking me
those questions?
Those are nice shoes.
You get those
from Romero?
Saw a pair like 'em.
They were a gift
from el señor.
How long have you
been sleepin' with Romero?
I have never done that.
But he's made advances, hasn't he?
I'm a married woman.
He made me feel good,
but I told el señor I
would not betray my vows.
You mean, uh...
"till death do us part"?
You know what?
I need a decision.
What happened to
havin' some time?
I can't believe
you need any.
Look, Vic is your friend
and you're loyal,
but you also gotta
be loyal to your badge.
You gotta be loyal
to yourself...
to an innocent...
brother cop.
It's decision time now.
You tell me... do I
parade you into police one,
or do I
call a technician,
wire you up?
You know, Lem, if Vic
is innocent, like you say,
you'd be
helping him out.
If I do...
what do I get out of it?
Doomsday's here?
According to
Emolia's friend.
He's not exactly
layin' low.
All right, let's go.
On the ground now!
Let's go right now!
On the ground!
Get down
on the ground!
You son of a bitch,
you do need your ears cleaned.
Where'd you put
the dogs' heads?
What are you talking about?
Right.
Where does Mackey
like to put these?
On the chest.
Make a case on Mackey,
the others,
you walk away free.
Here you go.
Just one more thing...
if you lie to me
or try to screw me,
or you just
don't live up to the deal,
I will push
for the maximum for
distribution of heroin.
Just know
that's the truth.
Did you get all that?
Perfect.
Mic's working great.
Let's go.
Hey, hey!
Where you going?
Oh, I've got to
run an errand.
I'm sorry. I'll be back
in about an hour.
Can't it wait? I'm
trying to close this up.
Sorry.
Is everything OK?
Yeah. I'll hurry back.
Well, I'll start.
You jump in
when you get back?
The tox report
came back.
He was practically
embalmed.
No way he had enough
motor function to swallow,
much less
hold the bottle.
It even amazes me
sometimes
how much these chronic
alcoholics can put away.
You, uh, screwing any other
sheep in your flock, reverend,
or do you just like giving
shoes to all the pretty wives?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
And in my faith, I am called
apostle, not reverend.
How did guillermo's
front teeth get broken?
He must have fallen down.
You shoved a bottle
in his mouth.
Celia solis said she
wouldn't sleep with you
while her husband
was alive,
so you tried
to kill him,
but only his brain died.
No, the devil
did that to him.
Alcohol was his demon.
Santiago said guillermo
had the shakes.
Did you notice
anything like that?
I left them both asleep
in the sanctuary.
I went to my office.
I wrote
this week's sermon.
When I returned,
guillermo wasn't in the church.
I figured he had sobered up
enough to walk home.
Santiago was too out
of it to say otherwise.
You've got all your
bases covered.
I'll put my hand
on the bible...
not as much fun as putting
your hand on another man's wife.
Get in there!
Sick prick!
Glad you could join us.
Hey.
Smells ripe.
Hope you put a little
boom in her womb.
I had to stop by
my friend's
on the way back
from chino.
The car broke down,
so I waited a half day
for a mechanic.
Yeah, well, good thing you
didn't call back, buddy.
'Cause I had a thought to haul
my ass out there and pick you up.
Hey, Vic.
Downtown called.
They want to see any records
that you have on Terry Crowley.
Did they say why?
No. Just that they want
anything you got.
They probably just want
to close out the file.
Yeah.
I gotta pull a couple
little boxes,
but I'll see
what I can do.
You missed
the first half.
We're still
in the game.
We just picked up a
suspect in a triple murder.
Put me in, coach.
It's not him.
Oh, for Christ's sake.
Don't do this.
I said it's not him.
This man killed
3 innocent people today.
That's not my fault.
What about the next person
he kills? That will be.
He already killed my dogs.
You think just 'cause
you're not I.D. Ing him
that he's not gonna try
to kill you, too?
You're protecting a killer.
It makes you no better
than he is.
I'm sorry.
For the record,
I saw someone...
but not him.
What happened
to your hands?
Looks like you got into
one hell of a dogfight.
Scratched 'em up
someplace.
Senior Hughes refuses
to pay you protection,
Junior winds up dead.
Niggers die
every day.
You save that grin
for the lineup
before I smack it
off your face!
You need a witness
for a lineup.
Ruff ruff.
I'm holding you on suspicion of
vandalism, cruelty to animals.
That means we're about 8 minutes
into a 12-hour conversation.
Wanna see how cruel I can
be to animals like you?
A lot can happen
in 12 hours.
Problem for you is we
don't scare like girls,
and our bite's as good
as our bark, asshole!
We gain entry
and do what?
Separate the parties,
look for provisional
signs of injury.
You taking the son?
Yeah, you get
the father.
Control the scene.
Use force
if necessary.
Over there.
Hey!
Calm down!
He steals all my shit,
and you let him...
He gets all crazed!
Shit!
Hey! That's enough!
Tina!
That's enough!
Thanks.
He wouldn't
listen to me.
It's your job
to make him listen.
I was trying.
Trying gets you killed.
You failed to get
the father out of the room,
then you used
excessive force.
You said to use force
if necessary.
Controlled hits.
Behind his knees.
That's exactly
what I was doing!
No force would have
been necessary, none,
if you had followed
proper procedure.
That's gonna need
stitches.
Corrine.
Hi. Jon. Um,
you picking up your son?
Um, yeah.
My ex was supposed to.
She bailed out at
the last second, so...
I skipped out of work
and came here.
I'm sorry.
It's par for the course.
Hey, guys.
You know what? Why don't
you guys go play
over by the swings
for a little bit?
Watch your sister
for me, OK?
So was it a bad
divorce or...
yeah.
Uh, she's with this
other guy now.
I got primary custody.
She's, uh...
supposed to be paying
child support.
She's this big time
money manager.
I haven't seen a cent,
though, in, like, 3 months.
You're kidding? I mean, she
doesn't even help out at all?
No. I'm a little late
on the tuition here.
And you?
You're paying for your
children all by yourself?
Oh, no. Uh...
Vic helps out.
But the occupational
therapists
and the evaluations
and the...
yeah. Um, you know,
Vic always comes up
with whatever extra cash
I need for the kids, so...
sounds like a great guy.
Ah, well, let's not
make him a saint quite yet.
Yeah?
What's his bad side?
just trying to compare it
my ex's bad side, because...
OK. Well, he's hardheaded.
Uh, he likes
to get his way,
and... job comes first.
Same here.
But he loves his kids.
What's your boy's name again?
Andrew. Andy.
Uh, is he...
no. He's, um...
he's doing
some extra work
with one of his teachers
right now.
Maybe you can bring andy
around for a play date sometime?
That would be a huge,
huge help.
Billings keeps
asking what we got.
We got nothing.
We got no prints.
We got no weapons.
No goddamn witness.
Maybe we just cut
this guy loose
and continue this conversation
on the street.
What kind of
conversation?
Irma's the only
thing we had.
She ain't sticking
her neck out ever.
We could turn him onto special
cases. Let them roll with it.
Pass the buck?
And have the streets
still think
that we're stuck
behind desks
with our tail
between our legs?
They got the resources,
the manpower...
every minute he walks around
free, we're a bigger joke.
We're gonna
handle this guy
so that people know
that we got him.
Hey, what about the, uh...
the guy that we met
on the mexi sting last year?
What about him?
Hold on.
I gotta take off, man.
Where are you going?
My stomach's been
bugging me all day.
Do you mind if
I pick it back up tomorrow?
Sure. Are you gonna
be all right?
Yeah. Just some medicine
I'm back on.
I left it at home.
All right.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Is he gonna get
paid for today?
Keep going.
It's a great country.
Respecting
the human rights
of a blood-thirsty
piece of shit like yourself.
I just might have
to sue your ass.
I got a feeling your life
just took a turn for the worse.
Or it could be
just wishful thinking.
You go back to filling
out your paperwork.
Stay the hell
off my street.
Well, I told you
to lose the earrings.
Figured it was
no big deal,
but I should have
listened to you.
Protocol's there
for a reason.
Well, it won't
happen again.
You know what?
Do yourself a favor.
Don't turn being a cop
and a girl into a juggling act.
All right.
See you later.
You were Julien's
training officer, right?
I mean, he's a good guy
and all, reads the bible,
but maybe he has a
problem working with women.
We may have
the same plumbing,
but that doesn't mean I'm gonna
dish with you about your t.o.
I didn't mean it
like that.
You wanna succeed
around here?
Do yourself a favor. Just...
listen up and do like you're told.
What did I miss?
Uh... everything.
I lasered the power points on
the Romero thing for the D.A.
They weren't biting.
You called the D.A.?
Yeah. I just said
I lasered them.
What'd you tell 'em?
What Claudette told me.
On my way out, he asked me
where we were. I filled him in.
Well, we're still
investigating. The guy's guilty.
Look, your hunches not
withstanding, my strong sense is
they're not gonna find the
arena sexy enough to file on.
Sexy enough?
Hey, I'm just passing along
what your partner told me
and what I found out. You got a
beef with her, you figure it out
instead of walking on me
with your anger shoes.
Anger shoes?
That's him.
Hello, asshole.
Against the wall.
Come on.
Somebody called
for a police escort.
Must have
been you.
Always happy to help out
a citizen in need.
Let's go.
You sure you want in?
Yeah.
We can do this
without you.
What's the fun in that?
We're a team.
OK.
What are you guys
talking about?
Want in on what?
Now take everything
that's a name brand
trademark violation.
You got it.
Take him into custody.
Is it worth taking
another run at the D.A.?
Romero skates
on attempted murder.
At least he won't be selling
knock-off shoes anymore.
You get lemons,
you make lemonade.
Hey, where is this,
"hey, man, it's all good,
whatever," bullshit
coming from all of a sudden?
Excuse me?
Catch the mediocrity flu
Billings has been passing around?
This guy tried to kill
somebody.
He's getting off
on a class-b felony
while you took a half
day of personal time.
I was out of the Barn for an
hour and a half today, max.
Come on.
You're coming in late,
when you're here, your
head's not in the game.
I'm sorry the case
didn't make.
It was never a slam-dunk.
Hey, Julian.
"Officer hamlin used
unnecessary and excessive force
in subduing
the second suspect."
You really want that
on her record?
That's what happened.
Look, Billings
hasn't seen this yet.
Why don't you
sleep on it?
Especially since she
was coming to the aid
of a fellow officer.
The department
is still liable
for her actions
against an unarmed citizen.
She's 5'4". Excessive
for you, excessive for her
are probably
2 different things.
It's my call.
Good night.
Have you requested extra
baton training for her?
No.
Well, maybe you should think
about your responsibilities
as a training officer.
I also have
a responsibility
to wash her out
if she can't handle it.
I could have washed you out
a couple of times.
I'd like to think that I
made the right decision.
Where are the dogs'
heads?
They're in the freezer.
I was gonna make them
into soup.
Make that bitch
who saw me drink it.
Where are we going?
Over there.
Come here!
Amigo.
¿Y la cosita
que me perdi?
Para tu.
¿Zapatos para los niños,
eh?
Guy spends a weekend a
month in a whorehouse in T.J.
Like his Mexican pussy.
Just keep him away
from the chihuahuas.
But he shoulda
left this at home.
Es algo muy mal.
Possession of a weapon
in my country
is a very serious
crime.
You can't do this shit!
I'm a citizen!
Yeah? Phones work
in those mexi jails.
Maybe they'll let you
call the state department.
Government types
aren't too helpful
getting murder suspects
out of foreign prisons.
Mexico makes our gun laws
look like parking violations.
Good luck.
See ya
in 20 years, asshole.
I know you hate
passin' the buck.
What are ya gonna do?
Hey.
Hey, man.
Something's
bothering me.
We need to talk.
Sure, what's going on?
I was reading through
those Terry files
that Danny asked for.
Why?
It's ancient history.
Well, he died
on our watch.
Something
always seemed weird,
and now people are
asking for these files.
Where's this comin'
from?
What happened
that night?
You were there. You know what
happened. Two-time shot...
you're not tellin'
me everything.
Of course I am!
No. No, you're not.
He was my friend.
I'm your friend.
Tell me. What the hell
do you think you're doing?
You lied to me!
Don't lie to me!
What are you doin'?
Stop!
What just happened?
Uh...
where's the sound?
I'm working.
I.A.D. Has me wired, all
right? I just disconnected it.
I.A.D. Has me wired. They're
watching us right now.
They busted me
with some heroin,
and they're talking
prison if I don't do this.
What else?
I've been protecting you
all day.
They're gunning
for all of us.
Some I.A.D. Player
and Aceveda.
I've got to make a decision,
and I've got to make it quick.
Why's it even
a question?
Because I think
you're lying to me.
I'm not.
Then you look me in the eye
and you tell me the truth
about Terry.
If I don't believe you,
I'm gonna start
lookin' out for myself.
No, listen, Lem. Don't
buy into their bullshit.
Tell me... the truth.
We're a team.
Yeah, that Terry
was a part of once.
Come on. Come on.
Now tell me.
How can you even
ask me that?
They told me Terry was working
with the feds to bring us down.
Now answer me, OK? You look me
in the eye, you tell me the truth.
If we're really
a team, man,
tell me the truth
already!
Oh, my God.
Lem, we're in this
together, right?
I need to go.
We're... we're...
everything's fine.
Where you going?
We gotta talk.
I need to go.
Don't!
Where... is... the sound?
It's gotta be his mic.
Lem!
Subtitles:
FRM-xxy & Lemonhead
www.1000fr.com
www.theshield-laserie.com