[Man On Speaker]
Lot number 149...
2004 Cadillac Escalade EXT,
black leather interior.
Bidding starts at $22,000.
- Twenty-two.
- Twenty-two. Do I have 23?
Twenty-three? Anybody say 24?
- Twenty-four.
- Twenty-five. /'ve got 25.
Can / get 26? Twenty-six.
How about 27? Twenty-seven.
Twenty-seven. How about 28?
Twenty-eight? Twenty-eight?
Twenty-nine? Twenty-nine?
[Auctioneer Continues]
[Mackey]
Sucks / didn't bring my checkbook.
Laverneous'd pop a vessel, he knew
all these whiteys were scopin' out his ride.
[Monica] / put ads
in El Clasificado and the Sentinel...
but apparently only the Times
crowd was interested.
[Auctioneer] Who wants to go 31?
Thirty-one? Going.
Going. Sold, $31,000.
Okay, now we have
lot number 611.
I did a little show-and-tell
for the city attorney last night.
- She sign off on the injunctions?
- [Auctioneer Continues]
One-niners are
Antwon Mitchell's foot soldiers.
These injunctions are gonna keep them
off the street pushin' dope.
- He's gonna feel the pressure.
- Yeah, he's already feeling it.
This is gonna...
jack up the pain.
[Auctioneer]
Sold, $ 17,000. Okay, next item.
Lot number 684.
Yamaha motorcycle, minimal damage.
Let's make this quick.
We gotta clock in to the boss.
You forget I'm your boss?
- What do you need?
- This address.
Chink herone dealer.
Hear a shipment came in last night.
And you don't like competitors.
You know, Bill Gates
has his hit. I got mine.
[Army]
Yeah, and bustin'dealers is ours, so sure.
All right, we'll pay a visit...
do our part to keep
the, uh, black tar monopoly safe.
Plus, I'm gonna need
half his inventory.
We're good on demand, but we're light on
supply 'cause of your intel failure last week.
We give you information. We don't
move product, get hung up in your shit.
Hey.
I'll beep you
when we got the stuff.
Bitch with a badge
doin' my bidding.
It's a wonderful day.
[Laughs]
As you all know, we had
our first auction this morning.
Try to keep your jaws
off the floor.
We raised over $900,000.
[Cheering]
Guess taking houses is profitable.
That's money out of the bad guys'hands
and back into the community.
Yeah, and a third comes to us.
That's not the only good news.
Officers Sofer and Lowe have done
a fantastic job documenting the One-niners.
And thanks to their hard work,
we got injunctions.
After we serve these, if you see two
or more One-niners together in Farmington...
that's called "congregating in groups,"
and that's jail time.
The One-niners
arejust the beginning...
so let's get these served
by the end of the day.
Match the glamour shots
to the injunctions.
If you have any questions,
get in touch with Danny orJulien.
- Can't find them, come to me.
- [Monica] Thanks, everyone.
- [Mackey] Any word on the girl?
- I talked to Angie's friends, kids at school.
No one's seen her, man.
She dropped off the map.
Her mom goes
in the ground tomorrow.
This girl checks in with me
once a week. Now nothing.
- Talking about Angie?
- Yeah.
You speak to the family
in Georgia?
- [Man] Let's go.
- [Chattering]
She, um-She hasn't been
back to her apartment.
Didn't pack any bags.
What if Antwon Mitchell found out
Angie gave up the cul-de-sac bust?
That would have to come
from here. You ran that.
Is there any chance
that word got out?
None.
Well, I'm glad to hear I.A.D.
cleared you on the shooting.
Yeah, thanks
for the word you put in.
Your C.O.'s anxious to get you back.
I took personal time the rest
of the week to look for Angie.
- Let me know what you find.
- All right.
- [Man] Sorry about that.
- Come here.
What the hell was that?
Shane is slipping
inside info to Antwon.
Angie goes missing the night
we take his distribution center.
She fingered, and I'm supposed
to pretend those two things aren't related?
- Shane wouldn't give up a girl.
- He was down for planting
evidence, burning a body.
- We were all part of that.
- He'd have been down for a lot more...
if we hadn't been there
to rein in his shit.
On his own, we got no idea
what he would do.
We're keeping Shane out of trouble.
You makin' noises
to my boss doesn't help.
He didn't do this.
I'll look around to make sure of it.
You keep looking for Angie.
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Ends]
[Chattering, Shouting]
[Siren Chirps]
Oh, you knuckleheads
make it way too easy!
[Ronnie] Game's over.
Against the fence.
Get against the fence right now!
Move! Move your ass!
- You!
- Face me!
- We were just ballin'.
- Yeah?
Well, from now on, T-Gun, a cop sees you
so much as playin' with your own dicks...
in the same room,
you're going to County.
Oh, this one's for you, Notch.
It's called an injunction.
You're all documented members of
a known criminal organization.
Judge thinks you're
domestic terrorists, ladies.
- I ain't no sheet-head.
- You're just a shithead.
Injunctions are zero tolerance.
That means no associating
with known bangers-
No bangin'with your homies.
No riding together in cars.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
You tryin' to say it's illegal for me
to hang out with my own brother?
- He your real brother?
- Yeah, like we came out of the same vagina.
Well, the court says
you're One-niners first.
/ mean, what y'all think?
We bangin'24-7?
It's not up to me.
All right, see who we got.
I'll tell the bartender his
One-niner clientele is banned.
All right, police! You know the dance!
You know the dance!
- Buy me a damn drink!
- Let's go.
- You gonna buy me a Hennessy, bitch!
- Break up!
- Break it up!
- Look, I'm D.E.A.
- What?
- I'm undercover.
You bust this place,
you're gonna screw it all up.
- Get off me, pig!
- Hold it right there!
- Don't shoot. / got him.
- Get me a Henny and Coke!
- Hold it right there!
- I got him.
It's okay. This is the guy that Billings
was looking for on that 211.
All right, come on, asshole.
- [Whimpering]
- Come on.
Hospital says that alkie you knocked
around barely has a bruise.
Drunks are like Superballs.
Bounce 'em off the floors,
they never get a scratch.
/'ll have to remember that one.
Credentials cleared.
Agent Hendricks say
what he was doing at Lucky's?
[Hendricks]
Couldn't tell you if / wanted to.
How long you been
on the One-niners?
A while.
Obviously we're tilling
the same ground.
One-niner heroin trade.
Probably Antwon Mitchell too.
I'm just a guy on the street.
Say / talk to the guy
in the corner office?
You'd have to be pretty convincing.
Well, give me a name.
I'll work on my sales pitch.
Federal investigations
take precedence.
We say keep away from that bar,
you better do it.
We can help you.
You don't even have working lights.
I'm bringing the place into the 21 st century-
rewiring, high-speed Internet.
Meanwhile, here's the low-tech version.
You guys're into the One-niners.
We know everything about 'em-
ink, homies, drug dens.
And the bangers know
that we're plugged into them.
We do the bust for you,
get the heroin off the street.
You get closer
to Antwon Mitchell...
and your agent's cover
isn't compromised.
You're making
a lot of assumptions.
The D.E.A.'s set up
on a One-niner bar.
One-niners are front
and center in the tar trade.
I'm a local, not a moron.
Antwon never sees
the light of day again.
I host the party.
One-niners have been trading
stolen cars for tar heroin.
Pipeline runs between L.A.
and El Salvador.
[Mackey]
Tar comes from Mexico.
[Agent] /t's grown there.
/mported through El Salvador.
Salvadoran named Spider's
the go-between with the bangers.
Has a garage of stolen Camrys
on Broadway.
How did the El Salvadorans get
hooked up with the One-niners?
Antwon. Back in Lompoc, he took
advantage of some bad blood.
He made an alliance with the Salvadorans
against the Mexicans.
They're still tight.
You know where he unloads the tar?
Four months, no clue.
Slips us every time we get close.
So we use my people
to bust the garage...
convince Spider to share
where he takes the drugs...
work up the chain from there.
I'll have some unis round up
Spider's family for leverage.
It's a good bet
most of them are illegals.
So we're clear, this is my op.
You screw it up-
Wouldn't do that to you.
Antwon was some
Iraqi National Guard general...
we'd wait till he was all tucked in bed,
having a real nice dream...
and then cluster-bomb his ass.
Worst thing we could do
is take a straight shot.
Not till we know where
he's keeping that girl's body.
No, we gotta be patient.
Captain's got something cookin'
with the D.E.A. Wants us all on it.
Fed bullshit?
No, I think we'll pass.
Captain's orders. You wanna skate,
you gotta talk to her yourself.
Hey, Vic, your nanny is here.
Cass? Everything okay?
You still feeling sick, kid?
Ay, Mr. Vic.
I'm very sorry.
My girl,
she's having a baby.
- I thought that was next month.
- Baby come early.
- Problems, I think. Do you understand, right?
- Sí. Sí.
- ¿Sí? Thank you.
- It's okay.
Come on, honey.
- [Door Buzzes]
- Go ahead.
- Sorry, Dad.
- /t's okay, sweetie.
/t's not your fault.
- Who's this?
- Cassidy.
She's feeling
a little under the weather.
This is my boss,
Captain Rawling.
- Nice to meet you.
- You too.
Why don't you take her home?
- I'll have Shane take the lead on Spider.
- Oh, no, no, no.
Uh, I got it covered.
I just have to call my backup sitter.
Your dad is very dedicated.
Why you lettin' that bald cracker-ass
run my boys off their corners...
with this injunction shit, huh?
They ain't hardly earnin'.
I can only wrap my arms
around so much.
The injunctions
are comin'from the top.
Maybe a, uh-a brick
of China white will ease the pain.
Fresh from your Asian friends.
/ don't touch the stuff.
There's somethin'else. An El Salvadoran
named Spider showed up on the radar.
So you got business
with him, shut it down.
Cat named Verdice
may show up on the same radar.
Make sure you shut that down.
- Yeah.
- Pick up your trash.
- [Cell Phone Rings]
- Yeah?
- [Shane On Phone] Hey, it's me.
- Where the hell have you been?
- Checkin'out Spider's casita.
- For the last halfhour?
- It takes as long as it takes.
- All right.
Well, Spider drove up
about 10 minutes ago.
- Feel like doin' some work?
- Let's tear down the web then.
Let's go.
- Hey.
- Get down.
- Drop the bag!
- Get down right now! Get down!
- [Army Shouting In Spanish]
- Don't move!
- Clear.
- [Ronnie] Clear.
[Mackey] Whoo. Spider's sendin'more
than just cars back to the homeland.
You get a shitload of tar with those.
El Salvador, they got AK's up the ass,
all the guerillas.
But handguns? They're like tight pussy-
rare and precious.
All right, let's pop the trunks,
see what else we can find.
Here.
Nothin'!
Hey!
Wetback's got some greenbacks.
Holy shit!
How much you think that is?
Hundred grand. More.
Let's call it in.
You know, you have to talk
to me eventually.
Victim is Raine Powell. Worked
down the street at Electronics Emporium.
- What's this?
- Just what it looks like.
Wasn't us. Talk to him.
I knew you'd want to see where
the body was, so I drew it for you.
Where the body was?
You moved her?
Yeah, the way people come speedin'
through here, she would've been a pancake.
Did it ever occur to you
to redirect traffic?
Hey, I used up
half my kid's chalk.
I don't need a "thank you,"
but how about you get up off my ass?
And this is?
Oh, / had to move
the pocketbook too.
You were a big help
in the community meeting last week.
I mean, a real asset.
/ believed in what / was saying.
Well, / hope you still do.
I've heard things.
Maybe some of the minority officers here
aren't so thrilled with my policies.
Maybe you're one of them.
Some people feel
like it all sounds good...
but the reality out there
seems a little bit different.
We're arresting bad guys,
just like always.
The way seizures work,
everyone is guilty until proven innocent.
If we take the wrong car, it's not like
people around here can afford a lawyer.
Well, maybe you can do
something about that.
Look into using seizure money
to start a legal fund.
l-I guess so. Sure.
/t's a work in progress.
This policy isn't the usual Band-Aid.
Your guys got a location
on Verdice's drug stash.
Grab your partner.
Come with.
Did Raine have any problems
that you know of?
Man trouble?
Money trouble?
- No, she was a good girl, you know.
- What about boyfriends?
Just Bear. But he
wouldn't have done this.
- So you saw Raine last night?
- / was overseeing a shipment.
She was stuck behind
her computer screen, like always.
Type "A" personality?
Familiar.
I told her not to park down here,
but the girl was a stickler for the policy.
- The policy?
- The rules say employees
can't park at the store lot.
Raine's the only one
who ever listened.
She lives with Cornelius Aimes,
a.k.a. Bear, over on Palmer.
Check it out.
See? You're, uh-
You're talking to me.
To the extent necessary
to solve this case, yes.
All right, Spider says he dropped off two keys
here last night to a guy named Verdice.
Could have dogs and shooters,
so stay awake. Let's go.
- They're in position.
- Go when ready.
[Shouts, Grunts]
[Man]
Clear.
- Clear?
- Clear.
[Chattering]
Shit.
You sold me on this.
Spider gave us
the right location.
This guy Verdice
got lucky, bailed.
Bullshit. Somebody couldn't
keep their mouth shut...
which is why we don't work
with people like you.
No one here leaked anything.
We go back to Spider. We find-
I'm not letting you
near my guy again.
I need to borrow this asshole.
- All right.
- Come here!
You got about 30 seconds
to spill your guts.
How tough are you gonna be when your little
brother's being hacked to pieces with a machete?
I don't got no little brother, eh.
Oh, that must be some otherJuan Emilio
I got back at the station.
It's gonna be too bad when they
have to deport him down south.
You got a lot of enemies. La Colonia
doesn't get him, the Mexicans will.
Twenty seconds.
Tar that comes to me,
I bring it here.
Most of it Verdice gets
at the church.
- The church?
- Verdice is a believer, man.
Stuff comes in there.
He takes what he needs...
keeps the rest safe...
with Jesus.
/'m gonna have to scrap
the whole operation, pull my agent.
A couple of months,
put in a new face-
Where's my informant?
Right here, sir. Thought
he might need to stretch his legs...
before he took his ride.
First Angie fell off our radar, and now
this guy clears out like he's been tipped off.
After I give my word I'm not gonna screw
this up. What the hell's going on?
Aw, maybe the wrong person
saw us nab Spider...
spread the word.
Doesn't explain Angie's disappearance.
These were both your operations.
Both of them were successes.
Verdice and the heroin
are still missing. So is Angie.
Lem's out looking for her.
We can still salvage this one.
Spider gave up
his One-niner contact.
Do I want to know
how you managed that?
We brought his family in
for leverage. I used it.
Look, you ask me, they probably just
packed up. Cook houses move all the time.
What did you get from Spider?
The El Salvadorans are shipping
their drugs through a church on Avon.
Verdice is a member. He has his guys
posin'as good, God-fearin'folk.
- You're kidding me!
- Sounds like Spider sold you a load.
He's not risking his family.
It's the real thing.
I'll work on a warrant.
Let's keep this contained.
The three of us, Army, Ronnie.
That's it. Just the people we trust.
All right.
Yeah, that's good.
Here, take this.
[Claudette]
Occurred to me to take that down.
I see Vic's humor grows
more sophisticated by the day.
Boyfriend wasn't home.
I grabbed Raine's diary.
Seems there were bumps
along the relationship road.
DetectiveJuarez in San Antonio
has got a different angle.
He's been tracking murders
in the L.A. area.
'Cause there aren't enough in Texas?
'Cause their suspect relocated
to Farmington a month ago.
Hey, exposed dick.
Thanks for the warning, Dutch-boy.
Kleavon Gardner. Questioned
in four separate homicides.
Suspected him on two murders
three days apart.
- Then nothing for six months?
- Witnesses placed him at a couple of the
scenes...
but detectives in San Antonio
weren't able to make anything stick.
Well, what's the connection
to our body?
All the victims are young
black women in public places.
Raine was killed seven blocks
from where Kleavon's sister lives.
Are we gonna be
like this from now on?
Juarez tried to warn somebody
in this department a few weeks ago...
that we had a thrill killer
on our hands.
Uh, thrill killers need the juice.
They take chances.
This guy's patient.
He's an opportunity killer.
No wonder San Antonio P.D.
screwed it up.
Get your profiles right, people.
Whatever he is,
I'm going to introduce myself.
Oh, what-
I'm not coming with?
Stick to your true confessions.
[Man]
Looks good.
San Antonio Police
interviewed you 11 times.
They got you killin'
everybody but Osama.
What I don't get is why you?
They got no D.N.A. They got no prints.
Any excuse to fry a brother.
- Justice Texas style.
- You said it.
He send you after me?
Juarez.
Got a real hard-on.
Why is that?
Might've mentioned he don't know
how to screw his wife too well.
[Chuckles]
Shouldn't have done that...
but he just got me worked up.
You get angry a lot, Kleavon?
Nah, not more than usual.
About how long is this gonna take?
Twelve hours
was the limit in Texas.
Where were you last night, Bear,
a little after midnight?
Drivin'... around, collectin'
my nighttime thoughts.
Nighttime thoughts?
About what?
Life shit.
I think better at night.
Found this in Raine's
underwear drawer.
She mentions you.
Man, she's gone.
Why do you wanna dig up-
"Dear Diary: This job is just
a steppingstone. I'm going places.
But /'m not sure Cornelius
is ready to go with me. '"
Then she talks about you
and a girl named Janelle.
Janelle's just some white chick.
Raine find out about you two?
Man, did you read where she talks about
the collage shit I did for her birthday?
What kinda grown-ass man
does collages and kills his woman?
- You read this?
- Man, I saw her put it away
like a hundred times.
What was I supposed to do, brother?
See, man,
/ knew this shit looked bad.
Where were you last night?
AtJanelle's.
But it wasn't like that.
We were in the bed,
but the clothes were on.
It was platonic.
You were sleeping together,
but you weren't sleeping together?
Yeah, there you go.
Bless this child, Father...
in the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Ghost.
- I say Amen!
- [Congregation] Amen.
[Organ]
We thank you, Lord, for bringing
this child- [Continues, Indistinct]
- Reverend, I'm Captain Rawling. I need a moment.
- Oh. All right.
Must be some kind of problem,
they sendin' a captain.
Well, we believe
a few of your members...
are using this church
to import illegal drugs.
- That's not possible.
- Well, I'm sure it's without your knowledge.
Are these three boys here right now?
Muncelle's car is in your lot, and he's
known to hang out with the other two.
They were makin' sandwiches in the kitchen
about a half an hour ago.
Those boys volunteer.
Their criminal days are in the past.
They're tagged One-niners. Just being
here together is against the law.
I know about those injunctions. You find
'em out on the street, they're all yours.
But this here is a house of the Lord.
We have a warrant on the way. We need to
talk to the boys, do a search of the premises.
- We'll be very respectful.
- [Sighs]
How do you think
it's going in there?
I'm more worried about
what's going on over there.
/ mean, they snag him
and he gets caught...
I don't even wanna hear
what Antwon's gonna say.
Damn it. Here he is now.
Verdice is walking right into an arrest.
- Get outta here!
- [Horn Honks]
- Get outta here.
- Shit!
- That's Verdice's ride.
- You think he's coming for a pickup?
Not coming for the wine.
- [Ronnie] He's runnin
- Asshole's gonna try to split.
Hey, what are you doing?
Army! What the hell
are you doing?
Get outta the car!
[Horn Continues Honking]
Come here. You talk, Antwon'll know.
You keep your mouth shut!
- Maybe you'll get out of this alive.
- Hey, man, take it easy.
- Let's go. Come on. Get up.
Hands behind your back.
- What the hell was that?
Guy was gonna bail!
Stay out of my church.
[Shane]
Let's go. Get up.
Reading the good parts?
Looking for more clues.
/t's a real window into the mind.
How are things going with
your Texas chainsaw murderer?
He says he's a victim
of the good ol' boys network...
but something's off about him.
- Maybe you'll have a take.
- So we're back?
No, but I can put up with you long enough
to put someone like this behind bars.
I've been telling my partner
about how you were harassed in Texas.
Can we get you something to drink?
So you can stop me from going
to the can when my bladder fills up?
- No, thanks.
- [Laughing]
So, uh, witnesses spotting you near those
crime scenes was just dumb luck, huh?
I just happened by.
No law against that.
Why'd you leave
San Antonio, Kleavon?
/ just got sick of the Alamo.
Kind of feels like
we're wasting our time. His too.
Probably got somewhere you need to be.
Job? Girlfriend?
Like we established,
I'm new in town.
[Dutch] Must have a lot of free time.
What do you like to do?
People watch.
Tell us where you were last night,
and we can end this now.
- Oh, / was home.
- I know, but give us the rundown
of the whole night.
So you can go over my statement
50 times tryin' to trip me up? No, thanks.
A woman named Raine Powell
was murdered last night.
Bludgeoned to death.
Maybe you, uh, happened by
this crime scene too.
Yeah, I didn't kill her.
He didn't even blink
at those photos.
Classic sociopathic nonreaction.
I don't know. He seems pretty confident
we won't come up with something.
- He's already gotten away with at least four others.
- What else we got?
Raine's diary mentions
some beef with a coworker...
a friend she lent
her bingo winnings to.
I'll have the unis pick him up.
Have to admit it felt good in there-
the two of us clicking.
Dutch. Do you know where Vic is?
- No. Why?
- He's got me watching his sick kid.
- My shift ended, and the sitter never showed.
- Did you try his cell phone?
- No answer.
- I know the mom. She works in Mission Cross.
Uh, I can call her.
- How's she doin'?
- Good. Thanks again.
Um, you know, Vic had a uni
with her the whole time.
It wasn't like he left her
totally alone.
I can't believe he didn't call me.
Divorce is tough.
Mine was a while ago.
Anyway, thanks again.
- It was really nice of you.
- You're welcome.
Listen, um, do you
wanna have dinner sometime?
- Dinner?
- Why not?
Three kids, a job,
selling our house.
- / don't have time.
- We'll work around your schedule.
- I don't know. You work with Vic.
- We barely see each other.
I tried it with a cop once.
Vic and I could not be more different.
[Sighs]
Reverend, I have a signed search warrant.
You must open the door.
This is a house of worship.
There's an easier way to do this.
- There are no drugs here!
- Except for the heroin.
Reverend, I have
the legal right to come inside...
use force if I have to.
Neither of us wants that.
Then let the Lord be your judge.
We could pack it up,
come back tonight.
Yeah, and give 'em time
to flush the tar.
We already look like assholes. Go in now,
at least we have something to show for it.
- You believe in your intel, right?
- Oh, yeah.
Okay, people, let's go.
You know who we're looking for.
Remember that this is a church.
There are civilians inside.
So do your jobs,
but use extra care.
- Who's got the hawk?
- We do.
Good. Four teams.
Two in the front.
One in the side.
One in the back. Let's do it.
Captain, I'm not
breaking down a church door.
Well, just think of it as a drug warehouse,
because that's what it is today.
We shouldn't be going in like this.
Get in the back.
Both of you.
What the hell are you doing?
You're knocking us out of this?
All right, Reverend,
last chance. Open the door!
Do it.
Look upon this child-
[Reverend]
The Lord is the stronghold of my life.
Of whom, then,
should / go in dread?
When evildoers close in
on me to devour me-
- Hold it, Muncelle!
- My enemies themselves will stumble and fall.
- Don't you move! Don't move!
- Are you all right?
Sofer and Lowe got the other ones
comin'out the back.
[Reverend]
My heart does not fear.
Though wars are waged against me,
even then do / trust.
[Church Bells Ringing]
- Any drugs?
- [Julien] Nothin'here.
Just a.38.
We're gonna have to search
the whole church and everyone in it.
Just... be gentle.
Hey. Hey! All that
fast and furious shit?
You're sendin' smoke signals
to Vic and the captain.
What are they gonna do?
Reprimand me?
Look, we gotta find
that heroin first...
show him we're not
Antwon's butt buddies.
I told you.
It's temporary.
- Ow!
- You got something?
Yeah, botulism.
But no residue.
K-9 could do this in five minutes.
Yeah, if they'd ever show up.
Hey, just found a receipt
in the good reverend's office.
The church candles are imported
from El Salvador.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
[Reverend]
Heaven help them.
- Vic?
- Get these sinners baptized.
- What's up?
- I got the toxies on Angie's mom.
Levels indicate she had
over 500 bucks of heroin in her system.
Jesus! Even a frat boy knows
not to shoot that much poison.
Yeah, and this was a lifetime junkie who could
barely scrape enough together for a dime bag.
Somebody made sure
she copped till she dropped.
Well, I'm connecting the dots,
and all I'm seeing...
is a picture of Shane
with Antwon Mitchell.
Did Paula find you?
She was trying to call.
Oh, shit. I had it on
silent for the bust.
Something about Detective Wagenbach
taking your daughter to the hospital.
We'll do this later.
She was sick. You brought her
to a police station.
Carmen dropped a bomb on me. Backup sitter
blew a tire. What was I supposed to do?
- You should've called me.
- I had it under control.
Obviously not, otherwise you wouldn't
have dumped her with a uni.
Christ! The first time in seven months
there's been a problem.
Come on, Cass. Let's go.
Maybe / should stay with Mom.
She's gotta work, sweetie.
Genine's waiting for us. Let's go.
Go with your father.
I'll see you tomorrow.
One-time thing. That's it.
You were pretty broken up about
Raine earlier. How are you doing now?
Ah, a bunch of us
from the store set up a shrine.
- Teddy bears, flowers.
- That's nice.
You know, your boss found those
order forms you've been changing.
I sold a few DVD players,
a couple of XBoxes on the side.
I was gonna tell you all about it.
Did Raine know
about your enterprise?
- No way.
- Really? /n her diary it says she confronted you.
Said she was gonna go
to your manager. / know.
You were gonna tell me all about it.
When Raine confronted you,
what happened?
You probably tried
to reason with her.
Look, if it were up to me,
I'd pin this on a real killer...
some asshole
who murders for fun.
The problem is,
the unis eyeballed your car...
with what looks to be blood inside.
You didn't plan this.
Second-degree murder.
You can get out one day,
but we need to know the truth.
I offered her a cut.
But she pulled the moral
high ground shit on you, didn't she?
One thing I hate
is a self-righteous bitch.
[Dutch]
Tell me about it.
You did what you had to do.
She left you no choice.
So much for San Antonio
eating our dust.
- He's innocent.
- Of murdering Raine.
Guy's still a stone-cold killer,
and he just pitched a tent in our backyard.
Got a suspect and no victim.
That's new.
This is when it bites
we don't live in a dictatorship.
Put the guy in a hole
and forget about him.
There's an impulse
I can understand.
We can't turn Kleavon over to S./.S.
until he commits a crime in L.A.
You know, I thought I hated
being on the D.A.'s shit list...
but this is actually worse.
l-I can't believe
you're still freezing me out.
I can't believe you sold me out.
Officer Lowe.
I think you should stick
to desk duty the next few days.
See if you could find your way
into what we're doing here.
/f not, / understand.
But you should consider
putting in for a transfer.
I wasn't gonna
break into a church.
There was heroin
in the holy candles.
This time.
[Mackey] Altar boys pin you
as the head honcho.
We can't make a deal, you're eatin'
roadkill goulash over at Lompoc.
[Scoffs]
Where my spoon then?
/f you wanna be a barrio martyr,
that's fine with me.
But why not serve up
Antwon instead?
Antwon who?
We can put you into relocation.
Keep you safe.
[Lowers Voice]
Lone Ranger and Tonto...
they hauled your ass outta that car,
what did they say to you?
They told me get out the car
and put my hands on my head.
And that's the last I'm sayin'.
Dutch-boy! Hero of the hour.
Your daughter was sick.
She wanted her mother.
You can't take a joke, so you make me
look like a prick in front of my ex.
I'm sure your ex doesn't need any help
from me seeing what kind of prick you are.
I just saw Angie's mother's tox report.
Lem have any news on Angie?
- I don't know.
- Well, find him.
/ wanna hear what he's got.
[Antwon] Used to be bad cops
was good business.
But now I got a stash gone, a whole crew
locked up and sellers who can't sell.
You wanna tell me how the world
got turned upside down on your watch?
Seein' as how you were misusing a house
of the Lord, I'd say divine intervention.
He must really hate you.
Only reason
he talk to me like that-
'cause he wants to see
y'all dead or in jail.
Vic Mackey wants you gone.
We're the only thing
standing in his way.
You think I need your ass?
You're wrong!
You think you don't?
Protecting you is a full-time gig.
Plus overtime.
So you can either tell me
what you're into...
or I can keep chasin' Vic's tail.
Some days we'll catch it.
Some days we won't.
I'll think about it.
Yeah, you do that.
[Army] Antwon's gonna drop
the body. You know it.
- He's not that stupid.
- Him being stupid's not what I'm worried about.
I didn't hear you complainin' about my
leadership skills when I was gettin' you blown.
This isn't doin' favors
to get intel on bad guys.
You got me takin' it up the ass from Antwon
Mitchell, ramming cars to keep us out of prison.
I've dealt with guys
like this before.
You or Mackey?
Do you even have a clue
how we're getting out of this?
Look, I'm getting us close.
This guy thinks he can kill
this little girl right in front of us?
We're gonna find that little girl.
We're gonna give her a proper burial.
And when the time is right, we're gonna
shove a stick of dynamite up his ass.
[Monica] Dr. Alvin Bernard's
clinic has been providing...
free prenatal care to Farmington's
poor for 21 years...
which is why I'm so pleased now
to give you this check for $10,000.
[Man]
/s that money from seizures?
Part of my promise to give
a third of what we get...
from asset forfeitures
back to the community.
How does that community feel
about your decision to invade a church?
I wouldn't characterize it
quite that way.
We found 12 kilos of tar heroin inside
there. /'d say they're pretty damn happy.
- Any plans to seize the church?
- No.
/s the reverend under arrest?
The only people under arrest
are known drug dealers...
with affiliations
to Farmington One-niners.
So you'd interrupt another baptism
to put away a gang member?
I'd interrupt
my grandmother's funeral...
if it meant taking dangerous narcotics
off the streets our children walk on.
But don't tell that to my grandma...
'cause she's still full
of piss and vinegar in Tarzana.
Reporters were tough today.
We keep storming churches,
they're gonna get tougher.
- You were all for it earlier.
- I was.
I am. It's just this thing
is too good to blow on-
Hoda Stubbs was killed.
Angie too, I'm guessing.
I plan on finding
the asshole who did it.
When you do, ask about the leak
at the warehouse today.
We don't know there was a leak, and even
if there was, we don't know they're related.
- Could be accidental.
- Stop bullshitting me.
You vouched for Shane.
What about Army?
He seems like a good kid.
I don't think-
/ don't care what you think.
What do you know?
Is there some reason you don't
want to dig deeper on this?
I'm not about witch hunts.
I've been on the other side of a few.
I chose you for this job...
because I needed somebody
as hungry as me to make it work.
And I'm gettin' it done.
Why are you riding me?
Because shit is falling
through the cracks.
Pressure on the seizure program
is only gonna get more intense.
And when it does, that shit
is gonna rise straight to the surface.
/f you can't withstand scrutiny-
about anything-
I need you to step aside.
I don't step aside.
I step up.
Which is the other reason
I chose you.
Find the leak.
- That's some cold-ass shit.
- You can't tell the Iraqi insurgents...
- from the plain old Iraqi idiots.
- Yeah, and no difference here.
- Somebody gets in the way, we keep rollin'.
- Oh, man.
I'm just sayin', maybe that's the way
we gotta look at things.
- What's up?
- You son of a bitch. What did you do?
- She was 14!
- What the hell's your problem, man?
You bring Angie to
Antwon Mitchell yourself? Huh?
Hand her over with a goddamn bow?
Or just tell 'em where to find her?
- No.
- No?
- Where is she then?
- Back off! Just back off!
- I got it, okay?
- Where is she then, Shane?
- Where is Angie?
- What are you asking me for, man?
- You tellin' me you're not
in bed with Antwon Mitchell?
- What?
- You told him Angie gave up
that cul-de-sac bust!
- No! I would never do that.
What happened to her, Shane?
What happened to her then?
- l-I don't know.
- She was 14.
She just wanted
to get her mom clean.
- You tell me what you did!
- Nothing! Nothing!
Look, you know that I would never-
You know I would never hurt a kid.
I got one of my own now, man.
Yeah, I know you.
I know you're lyin'.
I didn't kill that girl.
And I didn't give
her name up to Antwon.
So you just stay out of my face.
I lose that one percent
of doubt I got...
we'll be mixing it up again.
Captain says she wants
to hear your opinion...
but only hers is right.
Agendas have a way
of creating tunnel vision.
She said I could put in for a transfer.
Sure. Stock the pond
with true believers.
Make implied threats
to get rid of the ones who aren't.
You don't think I should leave?
I think if you wanted to,
you wouldn't have called me.
I grew up in Farmington.
I don't want to see it torn more apart.
What is it you want me to do, Julien?
You've got power.
Help us to stop her.
Going after a police captain
is no walk in the park.
I should know.
There are other officers
of color that agree with me.
- We wouldn't be alone.
- / remember the last time
you and / went down this path.
Things got messy, and you
left me twisting in the wind.
Not this time.
Vic Mackey- He's got
a lot invested in this policy.
He'll come after you.
Could dredge up the past.
/ can handle it.
/ am a different man now.
[Ronnie] Russian taxi king's expanded his
realm. Added three more cabs to the fleet.
Alex the Conqueror. How many
cabs you got wired so far?
Even dozen. Even managed
to get one in his personal ride.
Sweet.
[Curtis]
Yeah? What do you want?
What the hell do you think
you're doin' goin' after Shane?
He ran right back
and told you, huh?
You got suspicions, fine. We all agreed
we'd keep 'em to ourselves.
There's a 14-year-old girl rotting out there
someplace. Are you in on that too?
- What?
- You keep sayin' you gotta keep Shane close.
Well, maybe you gotta keep me far away
because you're back to business as usual...
ridin' in Mitchell's pocket with Shane.
I wanna bring down Antwon
and find that girl as much as you do.
Really? Prove it. Let me back in.
It's complicated.
You gotta do things my way.
Oh, you mean I agree
to protect Shane, like always?
Right? Right?
We added another car
to the garage sting.
Shane didn't tell me
you came after him.
I saw it.
Jesus Christ.
Lem's one crazy-ass white boy.
You really used to be tight?
[Shane]
Yeah.
A lifetime ago.
What does he know about us?
Nothing. He's just guessing.
He can't prove anything.
I'll handle him.
Look, you're just
gonna have to trust me.
I'm gonna handle all this shit.
It's not about protecting
Shane anymore.
It's about stopping him.
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Continues]
[Ends]