Take the back.
Yes, sir.
Suspect's inside.
We're ready.
[Pistol Chamber Cocks]
Get your hands on your head!
Right now!
Get down! Get down!
Don't move!
Stay right there.
You got the ink. I got the paper.
- [Screaming]
- [Snarling]
[Screaming Continues]
- [Gunshot]
- [Continues]
That's one way
to get him to heel.
Six grand, two dozen DVD players,
a loaded strap- sweet.
/ called in a Code 4
since the only casualty was Cujo.
- I didn't even hear him.
- Suspect cut the vocal cords.
Didn't your T.O. warn you
they do that now?
- The assistant chief s on his way down.
- Goddamn it.
- [Sighs]
- Good luck, rookie.
You would have been better off
shooting the suspect.
Why?
Uh, the ass chief figures...
it's just a matter of time...
before someone mistakes some kid
coming around a corner for Rover.
The truth is...
the wife raises cockapoos.
Probably stops giving him hummers
every time a mutt gets shot.
Didn't you read his mandate
a couple of months back?
I just started last week.
What's he coming down here for?
I'm sure it's not
to give you a medal.
Don't sweat it, Scooby.
- We'll figure something out.
- Oh, shit.
Assistant Chief Phillips, you didn't need
to come all the way down here, sir.
Another dog was shot?
Nobody else was, thank God.
And we nailed Billings an armed robbery suspect.
[Billings]
We got all the stolen merchandise.
[Phillips]
Where's the triggerman?
[Mackey]
Kid's just a rookie, sir.
Too young to read mandates
from the chief s office?
- Nothing else he could have done.
- Is he the shooter?
Sir, /'m telling you.
The kid had no choice.
The dog was reaching.
It was kill or be killed.
Oh, come on, Roy.
If the dog had a piece, he was gonna use it.
Nice collar.
[Chuckling]
[Danny]
Who was that?
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Ends]
David Aceveda, Monica Rawling,
your replacement.
- Hello.
- Hi.
I didn't expect to see you
until next week.
I'm using vacation time
to see what I'm getting myself into.
Congratulations on the promotion.
I think it should be
the other way around- city council.
I'm honored to serve.
Monica started as a patrol officer
in Farmington.
Yeah. Everyone knows
you put in your time.
I can't wait to see
what she's like now.
Well, if there's anything
I can do to help-
Well, I'd love to meet the troops.
/f / know unis, rumors are flying
like bills in a strip club.
Guys, /'d like to introduce you to
Monica Rawling, the new captain of the Barn.
- Hello.
- Nice to meet you.
That Aceveda's replacement?
I have no idea.
I thought Troy Akerman was in,
from Robbery-Homicide.
- A real detective's detective.
- That's funny.
I heard he didn't have a clue.
I just didn't expect them to go for another woman,
you know, after they torpedoed you.
Hey, at least it's
a fresh start for us. Right?
And, uh... Diane. Right?
You've done your homework.
Well, I've gone through everyone's packages,
so I have the dirt on all of you.
- [All Laughing]
- Let me show you around some more.
It'll be good working with you.
Monica Rawling, these are
Detectives Wagenbach and Wyms.
Your new captain as of next week.
- Dutch Wagenbach. It's a pleasure to meet you.
- Hello, Dutch.
And you must be Claudette.
I've heard a lot about you.
I'm sure you have.
Yeah. But we'll
make it work anyway.
So, let's see the rest of the place.
Don't let that fresh start hit you in the ass.
- Screamer? Moaner?
- Oh, dude.
You gotta start gettin'
your own snatch.
Vic Mackey, Ronnie Gardocki...
I'd like to present the next captain
of the Barn, Monica Rawling.
Hi. Nice to meet you, Ronnie.
We met. Thanks for
the backup out there.
Thanks for the laugh.
So, uh, what is this, mission control?
Well, we call it the garage sting.
[Aceveda]
We're targeting a custom car outfit...
that's been washing dirty money
for a number of criminal enterprises.
- How's it going?
- Six months in, gearing up
for the mother of all sweeps.
- How many bad guys you expect to net?
- Uh-
About three dozen. Right?
More or less.
Let me introduce you
to our watch commander.
/ am really dying
to get out onto the street.
Can you spare Detective Mackey
a few hours to give me the tour?
Sure, butjust a few.
He does have tapes to log.
You feel like some fresh air?
That hardware store used to be a butcher shop.
He ran numbers in the back.
Now he dabbles in I.D. theft.
- Yeah, well, things just change sideways.
- [Chuckles]
Do you miss the street?
Three years heading up Domestic Abuse.
I hear that unit really turned around.
Well, I did what I could there.
/ see the Farm's as rough as ever.
Ah, you know these people.
You do what you can.
You offer 'em a hand, they slap it away.
Why'd they
shut your Strike Team down?
A couple of guys moved on.
One of'em got in a car accident.
No money to restock.
Ah, department's really
quick to save a dime...
even if it means pulling the plug
on something that works.
Sounds like you're the one
who misses the street now.
I'll be back on it soon.
- You mean, wrapping up the garage sting?
- More like leaving it behind.
[Radio: Dispatcher] Requesting
additional units for a 187 crime scene.
- Multiple victims, Pavo Real Motel.
- Oh, shit.
We taking the call?
Yeah.
I know that place.
- [Officers Chattering]
- [Officer] Yeah, hold on.
[Dutch] The Veneza family. All locals.
Checked in last month.
- Why were they staying here?
- They were evicted from their house on Hoover.
They've been charging the room
to several over-maxed credit cards.
They slipped through the cracks
for a while.
No gunshots. Looks like they
were all drowned in the bathtub.
I don't want the new captain
thinking I'm leaving her a mess.
I want this wrapped up
before next week.
Dutch and I caught this one.
And if / leave you two as the leads,
the D.A. will screw it to death.
Even they're not stupid enough
to get in the way of four homicides.
- We'll never know. Answer to Billings.
- Oh-
Hey, look, the D.A. put you two
on the shit list, not me.
Feelin' the love?
How can / help?
See if the car's in the lot. Then give the unis
a hand with witness statements.
Thanks.
Bathroom. Family of four
drowned one by one.
Damn.
[Clears Throat]
Welcome back to Farmington.
[Siren Wailing]
- That's when I heard somebody scream.
- Did you call for help?
- No.
- Why not?
- I had a mouthful of dick at the time.
- Lovely.
Found something!
Key to some sort of pay locker?
We got the needle.
All we need's a haystack.
Well, we got bigger problems.
- What's that?
- Why would you need a booster seat unless-
- There's a missing kid!
- How old?
No idea, but if the killer's got him,
he's not the nurturing type.
[Monica] Where's the mom's purse?
Somebody check in there.
/ got it.
Boy. Looks two or three.
Check with the detectives.
There's a little boy missing.
Are you going somewhere?
Pico One-niners
run junk out of this place.
No one does anything
without them knowing about it.
- Could you get a ride back
to the Barn with the unis?
- I'm sure I could.
But I signed up for the full tour.
[Clears Throat]
- Hey, yo.
- What up?
Somebody offed a family
at the Pavo Real.
They drowned 'em in the tub
and took a little kid.
- First /'m hearin'it.
- Yeah?
I know you maggots use that motel
like it's a frat house.
You give us back the boy alive, and
I won't burn your cash cow to the ground.
Man, we ain't been to that spot
for a minute.
You wanna step to a brother,
get yo'facts straight.
Hey, big man. You wanna get into it?
Come over here.
What's your name?
T-Gun.
Turn around, T-Gun.
Put your hands on your head.
Still joustin' and roustin'.
Yeah, well, I wouldn't be surprised
if I ran in your old man.
- I never knew my pop.
- Yeah, well, I bet I did.
What's this right here?
Are you on probation, T-Gun?
- Hmm?
- Yes, ma'am.
And you're carrying a knife?
- When are you gonna get it right?
- Never.
He'll be a shithead his whole life, which,
at this rate, will be a couple of months.
How about our missing kid?
We don't know shit.
- Yeah, well, I'll just keep your I.D. Okay?
- What for?
/ gotta write up the blade,
but / don't have time now.
So just come by the Farmington Station
and ask for the new captain.
Otherwise, I know
where to find you... Gunther.
That was a waste.
Well, we stirred up the pot.
Now we'll see what boils over.
You all know Assistant D.A. Insardi?
Hey, have you
identified the child yet?
Little Eddie. Three years old.
- I've got the crime lab rushing everything.
- Robbery, kidnapping-
But why kill the people who'd pay the ransom?
They must want him for some other reason.
We found a pay locker key in the car. Dutch
and Claudette'll run down nearby businesses.
There's a kid missing. Your office
wants us on locker-hunting scut work.
Excuse me?
I don't hand out assignments here.
You know what /'m talking about.
Your office is blackballing us.
Shut it down, Dutch.
Find the locker.
I can think of some possibilities.
Come on. Let's make ourselves useful.
[Corrine] Any chance you can stop by
to sign that Realtor's agreement today?
[Laughs]
Yeah. Next to none.
She needs your signature
in order to show the house.
Well, listen, uh, can you drop off the
paperwork at the Barn after you're done?
Um, sure.
Cassidy still got the sniffles?
Nah, she's-she's better.
What about Matthew and Megan?
What are they up to?
Matthew's been great this week.
He's in a good routine.
Wish I could say the same.
[Chuckles] Listen, I gotta go.
I'm kinda tailing someone.
- Okay. Don't lose 'em.
- Okay, good.
[Beeps]
Wife?
- Soon-to-be ex.
- Oh. I'm sorry.
[Radio: Dispatcher
Chattering, /ndistinct]
So, you're planning
on leaving the Barn?
Uh, you might as well know. I put in
to head up the new street crime detail.
- Oh, the citywide thing?
- Mm-hmm.
Paul Reyes took that.
Reyes?
No, I don't think so.
Yeah. Last night.
He's been kicking ass in Inglewood.
Huh.
Good for him.
- [All] Respect!
- [Man] We're only killing ourselves.
- That's right.
- Mm-hmm.
Our sisters need us.
They're raising our babies alone...
while we're out in the street chasing women,
money or drugs instead of giving them respect.
[All]
Respect!
[Man] Our babies,
they need us in their lives.
- Not in jail. Not in the street.
- That's right!
And not in the grave.
Our mothers need us.
Too many have cried
too many tears...
buried too many sons.
Word.
Our brothers, they need us...
lifting each other up
and not shootin' 'em down.
Is that respect?
[All]
Respect!
That's Antwon Mitchell.
O.G. One-niner.
Yeah, I know Antwon.
There's the Harbor set,
Warren, Crenshaw.
- [Antwon] One night they tore up my boys.
- [Monica] Pico.
Came straight through the wall.
And his woman had to shield their baby.
A lot of these folks
aren't wearing colors.
A lot of them are just citizens.
The bullet ripped through her body,
killing that child.
We're keeping the gravediggers
too busy...
and that's a damn shame.
[Woman]
Mm-hmm.
And I guess the police,
they need us too.
You put more than two black men together,
and look who shows up.
Hey, but you know what?
It's our own fault.
Because we commit the crimes.
I did myself.
I slung rock...
messed people up.
But I don't fight the power anymore.
[Men Muttering]
We got to be about
changing that power.
And you, keep your heads up.
Be a man.
Demand respect!
[All]
Respect!
Because sooner or later,
they got to give it to you.
You take the skills
that they forced on us-
slingin, pimpin, survivin
These are business skills...
skills that we need
to open our restaurants...
our banks, shops that we own.
Take back this neighborhood
and make it ours.
- Then we'll get respect!
- [All] Respect!
- Respect!
- Respect.
- [All] Respect!
- Keep sayin'it.
- Say it again.
- [All] Respect!
- Keep sayin'it. Live for it.
- Respect! Respect!
- Die for it!
- Respect!
- Sleep with it! Eat with it!
- Respect! Respect!
- Mean it. Give it.
- Respect. Respect.
- Get it.
- Respect.
We've been frozen out for months.
- They'll take us out of the doghouse eventually.
- Yeah, when?
- What do you want me to do, Dutch?
Take obedience training?
- How's it going?
If the D.A. is waiting for me to apologize,
hell isn't nearly cold enough.
And you're happy to let my career
rot along with yours, huh?
/ appreciate your support.
I won't hold it against you
if you want to put in for a new partner.
So I can either be a traitor
or a coward? Thanks.
Don't mind me.
Oh, I won't.
Well, these match.
Yeah?
You could definitely
fit a child in there.
[Chuckles]
Or a shitload of cash.
- [Hip-hop]
- [Chattering, Laughing]
[Continues]
Stank, come on.
Someone drowns an entire family
on your turf, snatches a little kid...
and you don't know nothin' about it?
If they mindin' they own business,
we cool.
- We chillin', not killin'.
- Right, right.
'Cause you're all about
using your drug-dealing skills...
to get free checking.
Excuse me.
Can I help you with something?
Antwon Mitchell.
- Do I know you?
- [Chuckles] I know your mug shot.
I worked with Rich Nelson.
- How's he doin'?
- Passed three years ago.
- Cancer.
- Damn.
Cancer's rough.
But he was always talkin' 'bout
how he was gonna piss on my grave.
[Laughs] Guess I gotta grab me a 40
and go pay my respects.
[Men Laughing]
Somebody drowned a family at the Pavo Real,
snatched a three-year-old boy.
Nobody here would do that.
- That motel is a One-niner cesspool.
- Mmm.
These Million Men?
They're One-niners.
You do the math.
We're here just enjoying a cookout.
Bullshit.
It's a gang council.
I'm sure that hanging with known bangers
violates your parole.
Probation... ended four months ago.
I ain't the system's slave no more.
Well, I hear you haven't exactly retired.
Dealing again, Antwon?
Just tryin' to keep these kids
from makin' my mistakes.
Well, lesson number one:
Never piss off the P.D.
- We're gonna take a little ride.
- [Chuckles]
- Why'd I do that?
- 'Cause you ain't fightin' the power no mo'.
Some of my boys'll have to escort.
[Laughing]
This is the city that plants evidence
on innocent brothers...
shoots us in the back,
says we were resisting...
takes us to their police house
and sticks a plunger in our ass.
Actually, that one was New York.
It's all white America, lady.
- Uh, yeah, thanks.
- [Receiver Hangs Up]
The father visited an all-night gym
at 2:00 a.m. last night.
Stashed 35 grand in a locker.
The Venezas are 22,000 in debt,
and they couldn't make the rent.
Yeah, well, to get the ransom for their boy
they'd do whatever it took.
I spoke to some of the dead son's classmates.
He's got a buddy.
Street name- Chalindo. Member of the
Coronado Boys. Real hard-coreJuvie record.
The Coronados have kidnapped
for profit in the past.
Pick him up.
See what he knows.
My moms used to bring me to church here
as a kid. Sorry to see it's gone to shit.
- Vic give you the slip?
- No, he's making a call.
This is Antwon Mitchell.
Major O.G. drug distributor
from the early '90s.
Miguel, would you mind?
- [Aceveda] /nterrogation 1.
- His buddies can wait down here.
What's Antwon got to do with this?
His old gang runs the Pavo Real.
I didn't get the street crime detail
I put in for.
/ didn't know you were
looking to transfer.
Then why'd you write a four-page letter
sabotaging it?
I just got off the phone with someone
who owes me a favor over there.
You goddamn buried me
to the selection committee.
- I apprised them of your qualifications.
- You stabbed me in the back.
You didn't want me to find out about it
until you ran out of here.
I won't pass you along to
become someone else's problem.
Who's been running
your precious garage sting?
You mean that load of crap you sold me
for a goddamn nine minor busts?
/ saw you tap-dancing on that one
for a few weeks.
While you were on the streets, / made Ronnie
run through every bust you had working.
- It didn't take long.
- So what is this? Payback?
Consider it the bill coming due.
You ran the Strike Team into the ground.
To get you under control / parked you
in front of videotapes for six months...
and you even managed to botch that.
You are a joke.
- /'m a joke? Come on.
- Hey! Come on! Hey!
Get off me!
[Grunts]
You really thought, after everything,
/ wouldn't get the last word?
One happy family, huh?
Oh, yeah.
You hit the jackpot.
You expect me to buy
you hung up your colors to preach the peace?
/ gotta claim O.G.
That's what keeps me real
with the little homies.
/ play my strengths.
Then don't play me.
Dealin', pimpin', runnin' numbers.
Why's everybody whispering
this flows up to you?
People talk, man.
That don't make it the truth.
I was planning on
warning you about Mackey.
It took me a while to learn
how to get him under control.
Didn't look like anyone
was in control downstairs.
There's some things
you need to know about Vic.
Yeah, I read your letter. If it's true, you've had
plenty of opportunities to get rid of him.
But in three years you haven't.
Why not?
[Vic On Monitor]
Bullshit artist.
Is he too effective?
Looking for a missing kid is a waste of time?
Someone's got the kid. You can tell us who.
Or should I take a closer look into how you plan
on financing these new banks and restaurants?
Didn't you hear
what that cop lady said?
I sent her partner to his grave...
tryin' to dig shit up on me.
Take your shot.
[Door Opens]
Maybe 13 years in Lompoc
straightened him out.
Maybe he really does want to
save Farmington one banger at a time.
- Lady speaks the truth.
- Rich Nelson and his task force
had a rough time nailing you.
But they did...
for a pled-down trafficking charge.
Not for that crack house
shootout on Olympic.
You remember. Three dead? Couldn't
get you for that knife in the cop's leg either.
Nelson came after me nine times
and finally trumped up that charge.
Took 13 years of my life.
If whoever took that kid turns out
to be a One-niner, you'll do more.
Make us come after you.
We'll get you.
Respect.
[Door Slams]
The drowned son was tight
with Chalindo Gopez, 17.
Did nine months in one of ourJuvie camps
for robbery- no kidnapping.
- Where is he?
- We lost him two weeks ago.
- So he could be involved.
- I could talk to his mom,
see if she knows where he's at.
/'m happy to pick her up for you.
Thanks. We better
handle this ourselves.
What are you guys thinking?
- Maybe the family sold the boy for sex.
- No shit?
- Why?
- 'Cause that's how Dutch thinks.
No, because that's how the world is.
Uh, how's the youth authority
treating you?
/t's pretty cool.
Lots ofkids.
We'll follow up on this.
Thanks.
Yeah, okay.
Later.
Hello?
Oh. I'm sorry.
I was- I was looking for-
Vic? He's on a case.
Gardocki too.
All right.
Just tell him Lem stopped by.
Lemansky?
From the, uh, Strike Team?
Yeah.
/'m the new captain.
Monica Rawling.
Oh. It's good to meet you.
How are you?
I read your personnel package.
I'm sorry to have lost you.
Yeah, well, I needed a change.
Problems with the team?
Sounds like Vic can be
a little rough to work with.
No. No.
Vic was always great.
It was, uh- It w-
You know, just time.
Just time.
- Look, I gotta go. It was good meeting you.
- Yeah.
[Door Closes]
I haven't seen Chalindo in weeks.
He may know
who drowned that family.
He might lead us to the missing boy.
Do you have any idea
where he is right now?
I couldn't have been a better mom!
Do you know the things I did for him?
- Ma'am, this isn't about you.
- It's about my boy. Why else would I be here?
- I see you looking at me.
- Ma'am, no one's accusing you of anything.
You shouldn't be. It's not my fault.
That boy just did whatever.
You try stopping him.
I tried more than any mom I know.
- Any mom.
- Yes.
I can see that.
[Hip-hop, Faint]
[Knocking]
Huh.
Looks like Lompoc.
Tell you what-
for Christmas I'll throw
a couple of bars in the window.
Thirteen years, you learn
what you can live without.
All I wanted was a view.
Where's the witness?
Stop askin' around about me, man.
If there's something you wanna know,
come straight at me.
- Do you even have a witness?
- Elena!
[Door Opens]
Elena, she mops up at the motel.
Says she saw two dudes-
Latino-
leavin' that room with that kid.
Those cholos took him
screaming and crying.
They got in a blue Honda. I got some
of the license plate. I didn't see the rest.
You didn't say anything
to the detective on scene?
Once I offered her protection,
she agreed to come forward.
Tell me, what kind of protection can
an ex-con motivational speaker offer?
Hey, man, you asked for a favor,
and I gave it to you.
- Now maybe one day you'll give me one.
- I doubt it.
I gotta run a partial.
Yeah.
Billings tells me he found a loan shark
who spotted the drowned dad 35 grand.
He was bound to find trouble
one way or another.
- What are you working?
- Oh, Coronado Boys.
A gang in the loosest sense.
I'm trying to make ties
to find Chalindo Gopez...
the supposed friend
of the drowned boy.
All these should be in a database,
or at least on a wall somewhere.
The Barn's an apt name.
We're low-tech.
When Mackey ran point on gangs,
how did he organize his intel for everyone?
Organization's not
one of Vic's strong suits.
What is?
Uh, I'll let you do
your own evaluations.
I know you were on track
to be captain here.
Yes, I was.
Whoever cost you thatjob,
it wasn't me.
/'ll remember that.
What do you plan on doing
to square things with the D.A.?
What are they planning on doing
to square things with me?
Seventeen cases overturned?
Another 40 on appeal?
They have a right to be pissed.
Aceveda could have fought for me.
So could you.
You've made your point.
Might be time to move on.
Claudette.
Vic's got a location on a suspect.
- [TV: "Skip to My Lou"]
- [Vic] Clear!
Clear!
- Skip to my Lou my darling
- Left!
- Lost my partner, what'll I do
- Clear.
- [Continues]
- Hey.
Hey, buddy.
- Don't be scared. /t's okay.
- Hey, hey.
- Eddie?
- [Whimpering]
- Hey, Eddie. Come on.
- It's okay.
- Come on out. No one's gonna hurt you.
- Come on. Come with us.
- I know. I know.
- [Whimpering Continues]
- They've got him on a leash.
- Let's take you off this.
- Come on. Good boy.
- [Whimpering, Sobbing]
- [Continues]
- [Monica] There. That's right.
Okay.
Shh.
They've taken the boy
to Mission Cross Hospital.
[Monica] I'll call my friend there.
She'll take care of him.
- What about finding the suspect
who lives here, Fernando Cruz?
- I got his cell phone number.
If we get a warrant, the phone carrier
can triangulate his position.
- Grab who you need and pick him up.
- Good work, Vic.
Those are both the suspects.
- Pick 'em up.
- Let's go.
[Tires Squealing]
- Hey! Rabbit!
- [Sirens Wailing]
Suspects bailed.
Detectives in foot pursuit.
- [Radio: Dispatcher, /ndistinct]
- Go! Go!
Let me see your hands!
[Grunting]
Hey, you go straight!
You go straight!
[Growls]
- [Groans]
- Stay down!
Hands behind your back!
Don't move!
[Handcuffs Snap]
All right, sir,
your ambulance is here.
I thought I said no hospital.
But you've been shot.
See that exit wound?
- I don't have no insurance.
- [Julien] The city will cover it.
For now, till they send me the bill
and hound me to death. Just ask my cousin.
Hey, look, you need medical attention.
It's not an option.
Sir, please, look, who shot you?
Man, I don't know, man.
It was a drive-by.
Dispatch wants us to hang here
until the detectives arrive.
- [Chattering, Indistinct]
- A hundred witnesses, no eyes.
Can you blame 'em?
Guy got shot cleaning his yard.
What do you think they'd do to someone
willing to testify in open court?
No, sit down.
You know, when the, uh, the assistant chief
gave me the rundown of this place...
your name came up.
Uh, well, the D.A.'s
got a hard-on for my partner.
Claudette seems dug in.
That's because she's... right.
Well, whether she's right or not,
she's gonna drag you down with her.
Hey.
- Congratulations in order?
- Well, one guy has aggravated assault.
I bet he's the killer.
The other, a few misdemeanors.
He's probably just a puppy.
You know, it's, uh,
really not my business...
but could you give the puppy
to Wagenbach and Wyms?
Well, he'll probably break first.
But they could use the win.
It's really not my place.
I can tell you're not the sort.
What sort?
The sort that would parade a family
down to a bathroom...
and drown them one by one.
[Dutch]
Each one coming in...
seeing their mother, father,
sister lying there...
knowing they're gonna be next.
Must have been terrible, huh?
[Dutch] Your boy, Fernando,
is on the verge of collapse.
Good, 'cause this little prick
ain't talking.
Last chance to cut yourself
a decent deal.
You drowned four people, but you let the
little boy live. That'll count for something.
Now I know you're talking bullshit.
Your buddy's about to crack.
Just a matter of time before he helps himself
and hangs you out to dry.
He's acting like he thinks
the little kid's dead. Now, why is that?
I couldn't do it.
Killing a little kid?
But you could drown four people?
Tito held Pops's head underwater to
get him to talk, but the old man died.
Tito said we had to do the others too.
- What was Pops supposed to say?
- Where the 35 grand was.
What was he doing
with that much cash in the first place?
He thought he was buying la cura.
- The cure? Heroin.
- Chalindo convinced the son to set it up.
We sell some to Pops, he turns around
and sells it for five times the money.
- Maybe he buys the family a house.
- So what went wrong?
There was no "H. '"
Plan was just a rip-off.
So the son set up his own father
to be robbed.
- Beautiful.
- Pops should have just handed over the cash.
So why'd you take the kid?
After the others, I couldn't let Tito do him.
A little kid?
But Tito said he could I.D. us to the cops.
- He's three years old.
- And talks, right?
Tito wanted to put a body onto my hands,
so he told me to do him.
And I couldn't, so I hid him at my place,
told him I did the killing.
This is all gonna help me, right?
I di- I didn't drown anyone myself,
and I saved the kid!
That's all good. Right?
[Scoffs]
[Stereo: Blues]
Dead-Eye? /'m here to talk
about a friend of ours.
Antwon Mitchell.
Let's talk inside.
I'm either gonna tell you to blow me,
or you gonna tune me up.
Either way,
my boys can know the score.
I hear you got booted
off your corner.
I'm branchin' out.
Onward and upward.
Yeah. Right.
What's the matter?
A little dispute with the management?
I can relate.
It's all good.
You got mouths to feed.
How you plan on makin' coin?
I'm resourceful.
If Antwon Mitchell has it in for you,
you might as well find a corner in Miami.
How long you think he's gonna
let you play in his sandbox...
before he sends some smoker
to whack you?
- What do you want?
- We could set you up.
Police?
[Chuckles]
Man, you can't afford me.
Try me.
Boys. Inside.
Your daddy talkin' business.
You bring me a number.
- And you give me Antwon.
- That depends on the number.
Hey, fellas.
Come here.
- You see who shot the man over there?
- Sure did.
Yeah?
What'd he look like?
Some white dude in a limo.
/ saw him too. / think it was the governor.
Shot him up Terminator-style.
What do you think they looked like?
Probably some niggers in a car.
- You kiss your mother with that mouth?
- Nah, I kiss your mother.
- [Boys Laughing]
- You think it's funny, throwing away your lives?
Wanna see what it looks like
down in juvenile detention?
- Ooh!
- Look out.
Here comes the beat-down.
[Humming Beats]
[Rapping] Search a nigger down
You grabbin'his nuts
But on the other hand without a gun
they can't get none
But don't let it be
a black and a white one
- [Danny] Get outta here.
- They slam you down to the street top
Black police showin' out
to the white cop
- Show some respect.
- Respect?
You heard me.
Go!
Why do you let 'em
give you all that shit?
Jesus said,
"Suffer the little children unto me."
That doesn't mean that
we have to suffer too.
Get anything new on tape?
Yeah.
Mike Winston.
We finally nail him
shaking down those store owners?
Not exactly a store owner.
Son looks about... 12.
[Imitating Car Engine]
[Ronnie]
Now here comes Winston.
[Car Door Opens]
What'd I tell you?
- I didn't.
- I saw you.
Stop lyin'.
Ow! I didn't!
- Yes, you-
- Ow. Ow, Dad.
- Stop it! Oww! I didn't do it!
- Yes, you did!
- [Blow Lands]
- Oww! Stop! All right, Dad! I won't do it again!
Mom's got a psych history,
so she's out of the picture on a 51-50.
And running in Winston blows our surveillance
cover on him, maybe everyone else.
- [Winston] You'll get it twice as bad!
- Yeah.
- Shut up! See what you made me do?
- [Boy Sobbing]
Stop your whining.
[Jukebox: Blues Rock]
Let me see your liquor license.
Somethin' wrong?
No.
No, looks good.
Now give me a beer.
[Door Opens, Closes]
It's on the house.
Long day.
Appreciate it.
Hey, buddy, you're in my seat.
That's my drink, my smokes.
Well, smoke 'em somewhere else.
You tryin' to be an asshole?
No, I'm just looking at one.
You saving this seat
for your boyfriend?
- [Bartender] Mike, he's a cop.
- [Grunting, Groaning]
Back off! It's okay!
We're police!
Back off!
[Winston Grunting]
No.
[Winston Coughing]
[Winston Groaning]
Okay, keep this on until you leave.
- I'm not leaving now?
- Not yet. I've got that Realtor's
agreement in my locker.
I told you I'd stop by.
- You sure we're doing the right thing?
- Prices are up right now.
We're gonna bank that money.
Send the kids to your mom's school district.
I know.
It's just a house.
- Go get the papers. I'll sign 'em right now.
- Okay.
You really did a number on Winston.
- You gonna shed a tear
for that kid-beatin' asshole?
- Naw.
Anyway, Junior doesn't have to worry.
He's got grandparents in Simi Valley.
- I thought they were gonna fix your face.
- [Laughs]
They're gonna have to fix yours
in a minute.
One-Tango-13, uh, listen,
we've been out here all day.
You got an E.T.A.
on those detectives?
[Dispatcher] One-Tango-13,
you should have come in at 1900 hours.
One-Tango-7 needs the car.
[Chuckles]
Are they serious?
If a guy gets shot in the ghetto
but the detectives never show up...
did the crime really happen?
Come on.
One-Tango-7 needs the car.
- [Knocking]
- Yeah.
[Door Closes]
That was quite a day yesterday.
Quite a night too, / see.
Got another big one
planned for tonight.
One of Antwon Mitchell's pawns seems
to be willing to roll over on the king.
I got a C.I. contract snaking its way
through the system.
Who'd you mix it up with?
Just some drunk
looking to pick a fight.
What kind of future are we gonna have
if you're already lying to me?
- What are you talking about?
- That drunk you put in
the hospital is Mike Winston.
An extortionist in your garage sting.
That's quite a coincidence.
He was smoking in a public place.
Wait a second.
We caught the prick on tape
whacking his kid.
It seemed like a regular thing.
We couldn't make a case against him
without jeopardizing the whole garage sting.
- You beat the shit out of him.
- I gave him a chance to take the first shot. He did.
Got him on assaulting a cop, which violates
his parole, sends him back, minimum one year.
Gets his son away from him
and back to his grandparents.
- Well, that's smart.
- Thank you.
Pretty stupid too.
You were all fired up
about those motel murders...
before you knew a boy was missing.
Why?
[Sighs]
Look, when I had
the Strike Team, we were-
we were setting up to close
that joint down, and then-
- Then other things got in the way.
- You're dedicated.
You know the streets.
But you also accessed
a confidential letter...
went after your C. O...
topped it off with a bar brawl chaser.
Seems to me like you're
looking for a way out.
I don't want out.
Aceveda's letter means that
no other unit's gonna hire you.
I'm stuck with you.
I was thinking of putting you
back into play, but now-
I'm starting a task force
to target gangs.
Unis, detectives.
Study their turf, ink,
chains of command.
- We crack down, improve life for everyone else.
- Good luck.
Department wouldn't even fund another guy
for the Strike Team.
It's gonna be funded
through a forfeiture program.
You're seizing property?
Houses, cars, businesses-
anything bought with drug money.
Some cash comes to us...
some to the D.A.
What sold the chief is putting a third
back into neighborhood programs.
/ need someone to spearhead the plan
on the street...
someone who... won't lose control.
Someone who can make it work
without embarrassing me.
I want it.
People out there think that Antwon Mitchell
is an actual option...
because we haven't
given him any competition.
/ believe in offering people a hand,
even if they do slap it away.
I said I want the job.
I need to trust you.
Right now...
I don't.
You have a week to get your shit together.
Show me something.
[Door Closes]
They're pointing the finger at each other.
We got 'em both.
- Any luck finding the friend who set it up?
- Chalindo.
Looks like he skipped.
Mom of the Year probably tipped him off.
Juvie is tracking him now.
Excuse me.
[Insardi]
Good work catching these guys.
Actually, I couldn't have done it
without Wagenbach and Wyms.
Well, you're the primary.
Glad to know getting a confession...
finding the money, had nothing to do
with solving this case.
I guess it's just you and me.
- This is couples counseling. I can't do it myself.
- Lower your voice.
What is it?
You don't like this doctor either?
- I'm trying.
- You say that, but you're not.
Not at home.
Not in Hawaii.
I'm sorry your therapy's
not working for me.
You've given up.
You need to get past it.
I'm tired of feeling like I was raped too.
If I'm not good enough for you,
go find someone else.
We shouldjust end this,
say it isn't working.
A divorce?
/'m not even gonna listen to this.
Whatever it is you need
to do to help yourself...
do it already.
[Door Opens]
[Door Closes]
Dead-Eye's two boys are in with the mom.
We'll bring them in later.
- I'll round up a couple cots.
- God, I hope this guy's not boning us.
[Stereo: Blues]
- Shit. We got a problem.
- [Dog Barking]
[Continues]
- [Rattling]
- [Whispers] Down.
[Man] Freeze. Police.
All right, come out.
- Come out right now.
- Shane?
What the hell are you doing here?
I had a call about a shooting.
What are you doin'?
- We didn't hear any call.
- One of my C.I.'s phoned in a tip.
[Mackey]
Where's your backup?
I'm solo tonight.
[Mackey]
Well, did you call it in?
I was about to.
What's your vice unit
have to do with this guy?
Dead-Eye had a lot of vices.
Watch the door.
So, how you doin'?
Kids all right?
Is, uh- Is Cassidy still with you?
Yeah.
Heard you and Mara had the baby.
Yeah. Yeah.
Three, uh-
[Chuckles]
Three weeks ago.
Named him Jackson.
As in Michael?
As in Stonewall.
Congrats.
So, I heard about Reyes
takin' the, uh, street crime detail.
Guess you'll be stuck on videotapes
for a while, huh?
I worked the drowning.
The hotel.
Yesterday?
The Pavo Real?
Yeah.
That place always was a pit.
Yeah, a pit we were
about to pull the plug on.
Except we were too busy
covering our asses.
Yeah, well, too many dickheads,
too little time.
[Continues]
- What are you doin'?
- Taking his BlackBerry.
Had some dealings with this guy.
You know how that is.
No, I don't.
Put it back.
I can't do that.
My name's in there.
What about Antwon Mitchell's?
What are you, I.A.D. now?
I don't see that jacket fitting.
Why are you here?
Who did this?
You wanna smell my gun?
Antwon Mitchell do this?
You know,
I honestly don't know.
But I tell you what-
I'll let you call it in.
- [Door Opens]
- [Dog Barking]
[Door Closes]
[Continues]
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Continues]
[Ends]