Previously on The Shield...
The bosses are
shipping grenades into L.A.
Get him off!
Grenade!
Guardo's gone.
Vic. What the hell?
Kavanaugh.
What did you tell him?
That I saw your guy
take the heroin.
That's it.
6 months,
you could've warned me!
Maybe all of us are going
to jail because of you.
Without you,
IAD's case goes away.
Jesus. It's you.
You're trying to get
Mackey running to me.
And I so want there
to be trust between you two.
Oh, what the enemy
of my enemy is my friend?
They're gonna need a friend
in a high place, that's you.
If Kavanaugh is successful,
I'm gonna scorch the earth
covering this whole department,
starting with you.
You ever hear of
an Armenian money train?
It's a money laundering
operation of the Armenian mob.
I think the Strike Team
ripped them off.
I heard you had
a rough week,
so I told John
I'd stop by and check--
Your ex-wife's pussy
tastes like sweet butter.
You're under arrest
for possession
of heroin with intent
to distribute.
If I plead guilty
to the heroin,
without me,
this whole deal's off.
He's got nothing
on you guys.
I got Niners
in every pen in the state.
So wherever he touches down,
it will happen.
You sent Lem to Lompoc.
It's you that's
the real murderer.
You don't have
the stomach
to serve Lem up
to Antwon.
I didn't used to.
I'm taking him to the
courthouse 9:00 tomorrow morning.
Listen, I gotta
tell you something.
What?
You're not going
to prison.
Look, we made
a deal with Antwon
to get you
safe passage inside.
It went bad.
Christ, what the hell
am I supposed to do?
We're gonna
hide you locally.
You mean, put him on the run?
Lem, right now, this is
about keeping you alive.
No, no.
Lem, it's only temporary.
I promise you, man.
I promise you
we're gonna make this work.
He screwed my ex-wife
with the sole purpose
of making
this investigation
seem like
a personal vendetta.
You have 48 hours
to tie up the loose ends.
Can I talk to you
for a second?
First of all,
I need you to know,
I've always liked you.
From the first moment
that we met at the school.
I hated that I wasn't able
to tell you the truth
about who I was.
Maybe if I had,
you'd have a whole
different picture of me.
I mean, you like me, right?
Before you found out
I was a, you know...
you thought I was,
like, a decent guy.
Yes.
Different circumstances,
a different time,
Our relationship could've
taken a different turn.
I'm just really, really
tired, you know?
I haven't been able
to eat lately.
Why aren't
you guys inside?
Lem's not here yet.
Where is he?
He's already 1/2 hour late.
He'll be here.
How are you
this morning?
I'm OK.
He didn't leave a message.
If I was going to jail for 18 months,
I wouldn't be
in a rush either.
Give him some time.
I've made you coffee,
and I've been patient.
You need to go.
OK, stop. Stop.
Stop!
Don't touch me!
You're right.
That's good. That's good.
Why are you still here?
Because there's
nowhere else.
You see how lonely
he's made both of us?
I'm not lonely.
I'm moving on with my life.
You need to do the same.
No. Not until
there's justice.
You need to let this go.
You need to let it go.
No, don't.
Cause nobody ever
fights back against him.
Nobody ever
takes his punch
and just smacks him
one right back.
You need to leave.
If I take this fight to him...
and I win.
I need to know
that you're gonna be OK.
Because I don't want you
to hurt anymore.
What are you
talking about?
Would you
be all right...
without him?
- No.
- Mom?
What's going on?
Your mom, she's
a very good person.
She's a...
very good person.
Kavanaugh was here?
All morning.
Yeah.
He said
he wanted to ask me
a few questions to wrap
up this case, but...
did he try to touch you?
Why would you ask that?
What did he say?
Well, he was desperate
and kind of lonely,
and I felt bad for him,
and then out of nowhere,
he said
he was coming after you,
and that he wanted
to make sure
me and the kids
would be OK--
If something
happened to me.
This is about Lem.
He didn't show up at
court to turn himself in.
Where is he?
Nobody knows.
He's a fugitive.
Kavanaugh probably figures
I had something to do with it.
No, I didn't.
He's just pissed because
his case against Lem tanked.
He's making it personal.
He wants to hurt me
through you.
Please, don't let him
in this house again.
All right?
All right.
Be careful.
Always.
Where's Lemansky?
I don't know.
You screwed him once, and now
you've done it again.
Putting him on the run.
Didn't they kick your ass
out of the Barn?
You aid and abet him,
you communicate with him
in any way
without reporting it,
you'll be put in prison
along side him.
We had nothing
to do with this.
My office will have eyes
on all of you, every
second of every day
until Lemansky's caught.
Thank you...
for bringing me back
into your life.
POSTPARTUM
All right, where are we
with those errands?
Spoke to our
federale buddy,
who took Doomsday
off our hands.
He's gonna meet
Lem in TJ,
get him to a safe house
in Ensenada.
That's wall-to-wall
wetbacks.
Surfer Boy will be
a little obvious.
He'll be on the move.
Taco Cop's got a
brother owns a goat ranch
in the mountains north of San Ignacio.
It's a really good place to get lost.
How much?
It's two grand.
And a call on our services
to be determined later.
I can't wait.
What about
living expenses?
Got a line on wire
transfers to Guatemala.
How secure?
Enough to keep it
off immigration's radar.
Used to pay
coyotes mostly.
He's gonna need cash.
It's gonna be
his only leverage.
Let me work on that.
Now all we need is a way
to get him across the border.
How are we gonna
pull that off, man?
Kavanaugh and his cronies
are watching us 24/7.
We're gonna pull it off
the way we always do.
Right under their noses
with a goddamn smile.
Claudette.
We were working
something else.
Not anymore.
You've got history
with these grenade tossers.
Any victims?
Just a half dozen
crown vics.
You've tangled with
some well-armed
Salvadorans before, right?
The guy who imports the
grenades is named Guardo.
We hit him hard
and his weapons stash,
but he got away.
Looks like
he didn't go far.
Agent Gallagher. DEA.
Captain Wyms.
Farmington division.
This is our lot.
We've been running an
op on the El Salvadorans
out of
the travel agency.
Someone wants to move up
to first class.
Detective Mackey
and his team
busted some of that gang
a week ago.
Swept up
a bunch of grenades, MP5s,
a few top level
lieutenants.
And let their
playmaker, Guardo,
slip out
from under your nose.
We're here to assist.
Great. Start
directing traffic.
If a grenade goes off
on my turf,
you get help whether
you like it or not.
Don't step on our toes,
we'll stay off yours.
What an asshole.
Rawlings did burn them.
So now's our chance
to make it up.
Track down whatever
you can find.
Run everything by me.
And Vic,
that renegade shit's
not gonna fly
on my watch.
But you already
knew that.
Looks like a new sheriff
just limped into town.
She's smart. She keeps tabs
on us from her end,
DEA keeps an eye on us
from the other.
I don't give a shit
about neither.
We'll follow up on this,
but finding Lem
safe passage to Mexico
is still priority one.
Hey, hello?
Hey, open the door.
Open the door now.
Hey, it's OK. It's OK.
Where's your mommy?
Hey, buddy,
what's your name?
What's his name?
Wendell.
Wendell, will you let me
wash it off for you?
Shh. It's OK.
It's gonna be
all right, buddy.
It's all right.
It's gonna be OK.
It's just a little cut.
Here we go.
It's all right.
What the hell's
going on in here, guys?
It's OK.
It's all right.
Lisa.
Call the police.
It's OK. I'm a cop.
Lisa, there's a gun.
Call the police!
Come here, come here.
Hold this tight.
Hold it till
someone gets here, OK?
Are you calling?
Yo.
Hey.
We're cops. We're cops.
Get up!
Get him down.
Let me see your hands.
What do you want?
Some of our Salvadoran
amigos went all Superdome
on a DEA
parking lot.
Turned some crown vics
into some scrap metal.
I'd start talking before he
goes Superdome on your head.
The DEA's
been up our ass.
Busted our number
two Osorio.
Bosses sent
a message to the feds.
That's the third Mexican
that gave up
that it's payback
for busting Osorio.
Which means it can't
possibly be true.
Soldiers have been fed
their cover story,
but what's the truth?
I think Kavanaugh
found Lem's trailer.
What?
Sheriff's department
got called
to the trailer park
on a disturbance.
Cliff says Kavanaugh's
on his way there now.
Your pal say anything
about Lem?
No. Radio blackout,
but something's poppin'.
Kavanaugh's
poking around, man.
What else
could it be?
Look, we would've heard
something if they arrested him.
Maybe. Maybe not.
Who knows with Kavanaugh.
Maybe they found him,
and he was...
There's no way
he'd eat his gun.
No way.
We told him not to
contact us at any cost.
We're in
no man's land.
Best case scenario,
he's on the run with
Kavanaugh on his ass.
Look, man.
Lem knows the score.
He's gonna meet us tonight,
get supplies,
which means we gotta
pull our shit together
to get his ticket
out of here by then.
The truth is,
this could be good bye.
Come on.
Well... he been runnin' that way.
This is it?
This the man you saw?
Yeah, that's him.
So...
what happened?
I heard something.
Came outside,
saw him in the trailer.
Saw the kid bleeding.
Did he say
anything to you?
He said he was a cop.
The whole thing seemed pretty weird
so I had my lady called the real cops.
What then?
Oh, he was off and running.
Funny thing was,
big guy like that
with a gun and all,
he still looked
awful scared.
Yeah, it's funny.
What's this?
Your former C.I. says
she's got information
on the demolished
DEA cars.
Well, give her to the feds.
We don't want her.
I tried. She'll only
talk to you.
Kavanaugh cut me
loose, Vic.
I'm not working
for him no more.
Now that you've stabbed one
of my guys with an indictment.
You need another
PD tit to suck on?
It's real good intel.
It's not my dime.
Your call.
Give us a minute.
I know she's the one Kavanaugh
had testify against Lem.
It's all bullshit.
She as inside
as she says?
See what the story is.
Make sure she sticks
around the Barn
where I can see her.
Blowing up those DEA
cars wasn't retaliation.
Nothing we don't know.
Guardo's play for drug
protection's paid off.
Colombians have a huge
shipment coming up from Mexico.
Hired him and his crew
to guard it.
The feds feel like they
were making a dent
in the Salvadoran
drug game.
Meanwhile, something else is
going on underneath their noses.
Yeah. Guardo's
a crazy shithead.
Any excuse to blow
something up.
When and where?
Tonight.
Going through a grocery import guy.
Aldo Melchor.
The importer.
He Salvadoran?
Mexican.
Need a place and a time.
That's all I got.
That's real good
information though.
If it's true.
Not just another chance
for you to help Kavanaugh
to nail us again.
No. I never wanted
to help Kavanaugh.
Right. Now who's the source
of your intel?
You never needed
to know that before.
I trusted you before.
Fine.
I want to get paid
up front then.
I need money
to get out of L.A.
Take Sebastio,
head up to Seattle,
be with my sister.
I'm so happy you got
a little plan.
What about Lem?
He gonna head up
to Seattle?
Live with
your sister, too?
Oh, that's right.
He can't.
Because he's gonna
be in prison.
I'm sorry.
Vic took care of you.
He fed you and your kid
for months.
And you were sticking us
the whole goddamn time.
No! You see this?
I slept with
this scumbag Ignacio
to get this info
for you, OK?
Then two of his buddies
joined in.
Ripped me up pretty bad.
If you...
made different choices
from the beginning...
none of us would be
ripped up right now.
Becca.
Come on, make it look
like we're on a date.
I can't do anything to
help you escape the police.
Make it look like
a lovers quarrel then.
Look, the only advice
I can give you legally
is to turn yourself in now.
That's exactly what
I want to do.
Then we're on
the wrong side of town.
Look, I need assurances.
You're not exactly
in a position--
I need to do
my time someplace
where the One-Niners and
Antwon Mitchell can't get to me.
Federal prison
back east.
The feds aren't calling this
and going fugitive means
the original deal's gone.
Then I'll plead to
new federal charges.
I'll tell them
all the shit that I did.
You can't just serve them
your head on a platter either.
Kavanaugh's
not gonna stop
until he's
carving me up.
Tell them that
I ripped off
an Armenian money laundering operation,
stole cash that was
part of a federal sting.
I'll plead to that.
You did this by yourself?
Yeah.
Listen to me.
They're going to insist
on Vic and the others.
I got nothing to say
about them.
Then why are you running?
I'm not running.
I'm giving myself up.
All right,
I'm ending it.
You want a new deal,
they'll want new information.
I'm giving them
new information on myself.
You are not hearing me.
There will be no deal
until you give them
more than you.
Curtis, please,
you listen to me.
You have got to
think about yourself.
This one time.
It's your only option.
Now, Vic told me
that you guys sometimes
would spread around
some drug money
to keep peace on the streets.
Listen to me,
this Armenian thing
was armed robbery.
People got killed.
And they weren't
the only ones.
You think it was all just
pawning off some drug money
to keep the streets quiet?
I can't tell the truth
about the others because...
they'll throw us away
for the rest of our lives.
Open your goddamn eyes
to who we are.
People got killed?
This is all
attorney/client privilege.
Detective Terry Crowley.
You've heard enough.
Just get me my deal,
do my time back east.
Then I'll
turn myself in.
I'll call you
in a few hours.
Ow! Goddamnit!
Piece of shit just
scalded my hand.
Could've been
user error.
If you can push
through the pain,
we've got a woman
assaulted on Vermont.
Let's roll.
Get a statement
from her.
Um, you're not
pairing me up with him.
You're the only
two singles on the floor.
Consider it permanent.
Cross Street, 7th.
Hey, it's no great joy
for me, either.
I'm gonna put
some ice on this.
6 months I kept this place
running smooth as silk,
and for what?
No commendation, no
letter for my package,
not even a "hey, Steve,
way to go."
It's humiliating.
Welcome back.
See? No respect.
Wyms is even
moving my desk
where everybody can get
a good gander
at Caesar lying
in a puddle of blood.
In this story,
you're Caesar?
Did I get stabbed
in the back or not?
Um, I'm driving.
I get nauseous
in the passenger seat.
Why don't you apply
for a transfer?
Show them they can't
kick you around.
No, I got this commute
all figured out.
Besides, it's only
56 months 'til I retire.
And then I get out of
this shithole for good.
Aldo Melchor?
Hey, let me see
your hands!
Easy, easy.
It's a knife.
To cut my chorizo.
It's OK if I have my lunch?
As long as it's
finger food.
What can I do
for you, officers?
Rumor has it
you import
more than just
chorizo from down south.
Everything in this store
is legal.
Really?
You won't mind
if we stick around
and monitor your
import-export.
I close at 7:00.
Not tonight.
You're gonna stay open until
that shipment of coke arrives.
We're just
gonna hang out.
Provide a little
after hours security.
Salvadorans realize
you snitched on them,
they're gonna grind you
into chorizo.
Sell you by
the quarter pound
like the rest of the sausage
you got down there.
Is there something
I can do for you?
Tell us what time
the shipment comes.
We'll keep you out of it.
Bust the Salvadorans
after they leave.
Keep your pipeline
up and running.
What else?
Obviously, you can import.
Your exporting skills
better be just as good.
I've stayed in business
15 years.
We have a little package
we want to overnight
to Mexico.
How big is it?
About 6'2".
Just heard.
There's a good-looking kid.
His name's Lee.
After my dad.
Congratulations.
Yeah. Thanks.
You good? Do you
need anything?
My mom's coming tomorrow.
My two brothers,
this weekend.
I got more help than
I know what to do with.
Cash from the baby pool.
Pretty shrewd.
Not revealing
the baby's daddy.
Want to hold him?
Sure.
Hey...
Shh. OK. OK.
We didn't find one of...
Everyone thought you could use
it more than anyone else, so...
It's almost 3 grand.
My evil plan worked.
Tell everyone
I said, thank you.
When he's old enough
and he asks,
I'll tell him.
But for now, I just...
When he's
old enough.
Hey. Yo.
You want to tell me what the
hell Becca's doing up there?
Talking to Kavanaugh
and Aceveda.
Can you think
of any scenario
where that's a good thing?
Curtis Lemansky is
prepared to turn himself in.
If you've talked to him,
you have an obligation
to tell us where he is.
I know my obligations.
I don't know
where he is.
Curtis knows where
the Barn is
if he wants to
turn himself in.
He couldn't turn himself
over to you
for reasons
that involve his safety.
Any cop who's incarcerated
faces those risks.
He knew that.
He made his choice
when he broke the law.
This was a calculated move
by lieutenant Kavanaugh
to put Curtis' life
in jeopardy
to compel him to testify
against his team.
Any proof of that?
Look, the department wants
to mitigate the damage.
And when Lemansky didn't
show up for processing,
the chief
handed authority
over to my
police committee.
All we're asking for
is protection.
At least until I have
a chance to investigate
his claims against
lieutenant Kavanaugh.
And after that?
He'll accept
the previous deal.
As long as we can reasonably
guarantee his safety.
He can't have
the same deal.
He ran away
from that deal,
and if the council signs
off, they're gonna want more.
My client is willing
to plead to new charges.
But he wants his choice
of federal prisons.
What's he have to say
about his friends?
Nothing.
Not good enough.
I have to run this
up a few ladders,
so... give me 'til
the end of the day.
Look, I'll find him first.
Then we can
dictate the terms.
I need bodies, though.
I want two surveillance
teams on Mackey and his guys
in case they try to help
Lemansky escape.
You burned your bridges
with the chief.
I need my people
on the street.
Becca.
What happened with Lem,
is he all right?
Privileged information.
Tell me he's OK.
Well, at least
tell me what's wrong.
Wait.
Don't touch me.
Haven't you done
enough damage yet?
Becca, come on.
Come on. Let's go
somewhere and talk.
Talk about
armed robbery of an Armenian
money laundering operation?
Talk about murdering
Terry Crowley?
I told you.
Yes, you did.
And now,
I know the truth.
I let you touch me.
It makes me sick.
Becca, I don't know
what Lem told you...
No more explanations.
It's all bullshit.
You've lied so much
you forgot
what the truth is.
Was I lying
to you last night?
I don't ever want to think
about last night.
You know, I was worried about
what I'd do if I had to
choose between
being Curtis's lawyer
or your friend.
Not anymore.
Did you see the guy
who attacked you?
No. He just came up
from behind me
and started
hitting me.
I was trying
to cover my face.
This area can get pretty
rough even in daylight.
What were you
doing here
besides prettying up
the place.
Um, I'm a volunteer tutor at the
community center on the corner.
I was trying
to help some kids, you know.
We're gonna have you come
in, look at some pictures.
But why? I told you,
I didn't see him.
Maybe you saw more
than you think.
Is that really
necessary?
Excuse us for a minute.
Send her home.
If she remembers anything,
she can call us.
Well, figure out another
way to get her phone number
because I'm
bringing her in.
I was acting captain,
remember?
I'm making the call.
Hey, I talked to the owner
of the store
across from where
Tori was attacked.
He see anything?
She saw them arguing,
she went in the back,
when she came out,
the guy had Tori on the
ground and was hitting her.
- You get the description?
- I got an I.D.
Owner says the guy's
a curb jockey.
Sits in a green cab
most days
waiting for fares
by the intersection.
Yeah, well,
miss pretty thing
never said anything
about arguing with the guy.
No. I know she didn't.
We should take another
run at Tori.
Maybe she'll ask you
to give her a hug.
Let's wait.
Bring the suspect
in first.
Uh, yes, yes.
I'd like to talk
to the owner
of the vending machines
at the Farmington
police station.
- Hey, it's Curtis.
- Hi.
Look, I'm kind of in a
hurry. What's going on?
You're in
a holding pattern.
They said they'd take your
offer under advisement,
but gave no
indication when
or what
the answer might be.
Jesus Christ.
OK, look. I need you to get
a message to Vic.
That would be
breaking the law.
Shit.
All right. Forget it.
Forget it.
It's gonna be worse
if they catch you.
Now that I've told them
what you want.
They know there's more
shit to uncover.
Kavanaugh will show
no mercy.
I know.
There is one other
option though.
What?
Witness protection.
And you tell them
everything.
Witness protection.
The entire truth.
Imagine. You'll be free
of the lies, the running.
People pay a price
for what they did.
I can't. I can't.
Curtis, you're the one
with the heart.
Now, use your head.
This isn't about
my goddamn heart.
I'm just trying
to help you here, Curtis.
No, you're trying
to get me to turn
on my family.
Please, just get me my deal.
He held out
as long as he could.
He's still holding.
He didn't want to run
in the first place.
He would run
before he would rat.
How do they know about
the money train?
Educated guess.
There's always been
plenty of suspicion,
just never any proof.
Unless Lem gave it
to them.
We know Lem, look...
if he had
a change of heart,
he would've tipped us.
He wouldn't if his deal
meant us going down.
Look, I'm not saying
that it happened.
I'm just saying are we
willing to bet our freedom
that it didn't.
I'm not gonna believe it 'til
I see it with my own eyes.
Lem's not
contacting us
to protect us.
We're gonna meet him
tonight at midnight,
and he's gonna
travel tonight.
That's it.
OK. On whose nickel?
This spic cop doesn't take
American Express.
It's already
taken care of.
I told Mara
that Lem was in trouble.
She felt very strongly
that we needed to help him.
So we pulled a little
cash out of the house.
I mean,
it's not a lot, but...
Hey, 5 grand ought to
keep him in burritos and beer
long enough, man.
Yeah.
All right.
Go get this cashed.
Keep half of it
for tonight.
Put the rest
on the wire.
Lem must've said something
to Becca about Terry, too.
All that gives Kavanaugh
is a little more suspicion.
Doesn't mean
we're gonna catch a case.
Let alone a needle.
Lem starts talking,
it puts teeth in an
otherwise empty rumor.
These people,
every time
they look at us,
they're gonna see
two cop killers.
That's on me.
Terry was a decision
that we both made.
I forced it on you.
Now you're in
Kavanaugh's crosshairs.
That's on me.
Lem's gonna have to hide
under a rock
for the rest of his life.
That's on me, too.
I know that.
And skewering yourself
is helping Lem how?
How's that gonna help
any of us?
You made a call,
and that call was
to protect the team.
That couldn't have
gone down any other way.
It's done.
Now is he still on our
side against Kavanaugh?
I'm gonna find out.
You!
What the hell was that
pow-wow upstairs about?
Call me later.
I'm running out
of later.
Now. Are you and me still
allies against Kavanaugh?
Or do I pull out
my flame thrower
and start that
scorched earth plan
that I talked to you about?
Becca's being
a good lawyer.
Lem wants to
turn himself in
if he can get his
original deal back,
but Kavanaugh
won't sign off on it.
He's gonna file
new charges
for him running.
I thought Kavanaugh
was out of the picture.
He was until
Lem didn't show.
And now,
the chief's believing
that Kavanaugh was right.
He's giving him back
all his power.
What about Lem?
He'll let him
twist in the wind?
Claudette's gonna
call the D.A.,
but she's waiting
as long as she can
to give Kavanaugh a chance to find Lem.
That's all I know.
You got to throw
a wrench in the works.
You wanted an inside guy
for intel.
You got one.
You need help aiding
and abetting a fugitive,
find someone else.
What happened
to your face?
Nothing.
What happened to yours?
Where were you
at 8 AM this morning?
Driving. Working.
On what,
your right cross?
Witness says
you attacked Tori Birke.
Also says you two
had an argument first.
What was that about?
You just think
you can go around
beating women on the street?
How do you know her?
She take your cab?
You stalking her
or something?
OK, your thing is just
knocking the shit
out of random,
total strangers.
Works for me, Gilbos.
So I...
so I picked up a hooker.
I'm not the only guy
who's had to
bust out of a slump.
Doesn't mean I deserved
to get rolled and robbed.
Say again?
She set me up.
Soon as I got
my clothes off,
and my dick hard,
These two black guys
ran in.
Started
smashing me up.
Took everything.
The woman you attacked
is a volunteer tutor
for at risk kids.
She was on her way
to a session
when you jumped her.
That whore
flagged my cab.
OK, offered me
anything in the book
for a "C" note.
Picked the motel.
Then had her buddies
steal my wallet and a
chain my mother gave me.
So I gave her
a little payback.
Arrest her ass,
not mine.
So, did you find him?
We did.
Good. So I guess that means
that I can go now,
and you'll just let me know
if you need me
in court or anything?
We talked to people
at the community center.
You volunteer there
at least 3 days a week?
Yeah. I read to
disadvantaged kids.
Are you
a prostitute, Tori?
Maybe in your fantasy
I'm a prostitute.
All right,
you know what?
If I'm gonna be insulted
on top of assaulted,
I think I'd--
I think I'd like to leave.
OK. We need to ask you
a few more questions.
You're a suspect
in a separate
assault and robbery.
I'd like to see
my legal counsel.
All right. They're moving
blow into the van.
Still no sign of Guardo?
They'll lead us to him.
That's the second time
that car's passed
by here tonight.
What the Mexi chicks
in the el camino?
They don't look like
Kavanaugh's boys.
I think we're all right.
Hey. Wire transfer
went through.
Meet and greet
in TJ Is confirmed.
Now he just need
to get Lem on board.
OK, good.
Almost home.
They're on the move.
Hey.
Come on.
Pairing me up with Billings.
You know a guy like that
is gonna throw me
off my game.
You'll adjust.
I'm filing
for a transfer.
Dutch.
No. I'm serious.
Things haven't been
the same between us.
Even before
you got captain.
There is no reason why
we can't work this out
in a new way.
Yes, there is.
The only reason I was
hanging around here
was because we were
partners, and that's gone.
I'd just like
to move on.
OK. I'll prepare
the paperwork.
OK. Check this out.
Tori has an MBA
from UCLA.
Worked as an account
manager at a brokerage firm
until she was fired
6 months ago.
What for?
Her work started
to get sloppy,
and she stopped showing
up half the time.
But no arrest.
Yeah, if she's a hooker,
she had me fooled.
And I can
usually smell them.
This guy is here
for Tori Birke.
I'm her legal counselor.
And what are
your credentials
Mr. Wallis, esquire?
What I have
is a client.
And I need to see her
immediately.
Now, do I get to
see her now?
Or do I file
for a dismissal?
She's in 2.
Show him up.
I'll check him out.
I'm getting a whiff
of something now.
Gallagher's DEA bozos are
tied up in a sting in Compton,
and they're a little
short on cars.
Maybe in a few hours.
We can't wait that long.
We gotta meet Lem.
What about back-up
from the Barn?
There's a manhunt
on Curson.
Byz-Lats shot
a grocery clerk,
and there's no units
to spare.
We gotta go in.
There are 6 of them
at least.
We don't know
how many more inside.
Lem's gonna be
waiting on us.
Who's coming?
Get down!
Down on the ground!
On the floor!
Don't move!
Get down on your knees.
Hands up!
I got rabbits!
Let them run.
Get up. Let's go.
Hands on your head.
You all right?
Yeah.
Let's go. Right now.
On the ground.
On the ground right now.
How many of these things
these guys got?
Claudette's so hot
for these guys,
she can book them
herself.
We gotta go get Lem.
Yes, yes. I still
want to hold.
Tyrez Wallis
is no more a lawyer
than I am
a figure skater.
Really?
So Dutch's girlfriend's
got a pimp?
You know, they've
been up there awhile.
Dutch, let's go.
No, no.
I want the name of the
owner of these machines
right now, or you will be
sitting in a holding cell
for as long as it takes
me to track it down.
Dutch, let's go.
Hang it up.
You own those machines?
I was just
filling a need.
Isn't it illegal
for department employees
to profit from things
like vending machines?
Especially when you
use your position
as acting captain
to create a defacto
monopoly?
I think it's more of
a gray area than that.
I don't think so.
I think it's more
black and white.
All right, so what now?
You gonna snitch me out
to Wyms?
Like I haven't been
shithammered enough around here.
Is that what this
is gonna be?
I don't know what
I'm gonna do yet.
Attorney/client privilege?
It's illegal to practice law
in the state of California
without a license,
counselor.
What do you think?
Did I need
anymore practice?
Bomb Squad's
on a crank call
at some westside
abortion clinic.
They'll pick up
the grenades later.
I told you to call in
every move.
You were outnumbered
three to one.
They were getting ready
to bolt.
Split up in two vans.
We had no choice.
Sorry I missed
all the action.
Good work.
Just wish we were able
to nail Guardo.
He's been staying off
the frontlines these days.
Probably feeling
the heat from you guys.
Two busts
in as many weeks.
He's feeling your heat.
And I've seen what they
do when they get pissed.
Better watch
your crown vics.
You should be
warning him. Not me.
Thanks.
Glad you caught the guys.
Actually, we didn't
nail Guardo.
I'll see if I can
find something out.
You find another tip,
find another buyer.
Please don't be this way.
I'm sorry I made that deal.
Helped Kavanaugh.
You should go.
I did it for Sebastio.
You'd do the same thing
for your kids, too.
Take your rat money,
your retarded rat
baby kid,
and get on
the first bus--
Don't you say that
about my boy!
What?
You gonna let him talk
about Sebastio that way?
I showed you mercy once,
and it ruined
my friend's life.
Not gonna happen again.
Get out.
The police committee is
willing to consider a deal.
But like I thought, they
insist on adding more time.
How much?
Maximum of 10 years
with parole in 4
if he turns himself
in immediately.
What about
the safety issue?
He'll be held in
protective custody.
Until it's all
sorted out,
but there's no guarantee
of location.
Unless you can
prove your claims.
What about the others?
No condition about him
giving us something on them?
We want to put this
behind us.
Now if he's caught
before he comes in,
all bets are off.
Excuse me.
What's going on, man?
What was that?
It wasn't my choice.
It's what the police
committee wanted.
If we don't find
Lemansky
before he comes in,
or he gets out of the country,
we're gonna lose our
last... chance at nailing Vic
before this case
seals off.
What do you want
me to do, Jon?
He trusts you now, right,
when it comes to me?
Maybe.
I want you to scare him.
I want you to make Vic
lead us to him.
How?
We both failed at trying
to nail Mackey
on old business.
They don't crack.
They don't
turn on each other.
Good for them.
The way to get him
is we gotta catch him
in the act.
With Lemansky AWOL,
Vic knows he's got eyes
and ears all over him.
He's not gonna do
anything stupid.
Unless he thinks he's got
one last mess
to clean up.
What mess?
There's a detective
I spoke to here.
He suspects
that the Strike Team
robbed an Armenian
money train.
Wagenbach.
Yeah, but he doesn't
know it was Dutch.
You gotta make him believe
that Lemansky gave it up
for witness protection.
It'll put him in motion.
We follow him.
We catch him
trying to help
Lemansky escape
and nail them for
harboring a fugitive.
It won't be the amount
of time that they deserve,
but it'll be enough time
to make them
lose their badges,
and get them off the street.
Catch them in the act.
That's gonna
give us leverage.
Lemansky, he may have
held his tongue,
but the other ones,
they might not
be as strong.
David.
It's time to put the mess
that Mackey made
behind both of us.
Lemansky's talking.
That's bullshit.
Is the Armenian
money train bullshit?
Because that's what
he gave them.
He's coming clean.
There's nothing
to come clean about.
That explains
where your 65,000
unaccounted for
dollars comes from, huh?
Look, he's tired.
He's scared.
He doesn't want to die
at the hands of Antwon Mitchell.
The D.A. said he's got to give
them something on the team.
I guess he's agreed.
Lem would never
agree to that.
D.A. gave him no choice.
He has to
give you guys up.
And now all this bullshit
can blow back on me.
Now you gotta get
a message to your boy.
Tell him to
shut the hell up.
Can you do that, hmm?
If you can speak to him,
can you convince him
to keep his mouth shut?
Yes.
Then do it,
for Christ's sake.
I don't know
where he is.
You know, Kavanaugh
is out of control.
With Lemansky
unaccounted for,
he's got
the chief's ear.
And now the D.A.
is smelling blood.
All of ours.
I shouldn't be telling you any of this,
but you've
threatened me,
so now I've told you
everything I know.
Now start
cleaning this up.
We'll look the other
way on solicitation,
but you gotta
make a statement
about Spank's involvement in
the robbery and the beating.
Do a little time yourself
for the stick-up.
No. Spank wasn't there
when the cabbie got rolled.
If you're
afraid of Spank,
we'll protect you.
He will not hurt you.
You guys just see
pimp and hooker.
That's not who we are.
Yeah, says the hooker
letting pimp daddy
drag her into
the shit with him.
No, actually,
he dragged me out.
He dragged me out
of the steaming
shitpiles
of a superficial,
empty...
everything.
And then
he hosed me off,
and he held me.
And he made me whole.
I had nothing.
I was nothing.
Before I met him.
According to your sister,
you had a pretty nice condo.
You equate a roof
over your head to love?
What exactly
does equal love?
Do you see the wrinkles
on my face?
Do you see them?
Yes.
Well, Spank doesn't.
I understand you not
wanting to be away
from your, uh...
boyfriend.
But what do you think
is gonna happen
when you go to jail?
Because we both know
that your man
is just gonna
set his sights
on the next piece of
Century City ass
that comes his way.
Shut your mouth!
Shut your
goddamn mouth!
Who do you think you are?
You don't know us.
How dare you.
Let go of me!
No, no, no.
Let's just sit down.
You don't know me!
Let go of me.
Sit down.
The girl just gave you up.
Says it was all
your idea,
and you're the one
that beat up the John.
I know that
didn't happen.
Oh, she put the claws
in you, right?
You shouldn't let no
woman do you like that.
Someone like Tori.
Smart, educated,
good job.
How do you turn out
a girl like that?
Any punk can get
some crack ho
to go down on dick.
But how do I get a little
pink toe from Westwood
to do what I say
whenever I say.
Every chick's got a hole
in her heart.
And it's connected to
the one between her legs.
I just figure out
how to fill it.
And then I feed it to her.
And I keep
feeding it to her.
'Til it's overflowing.
Until she can't live
without it.
And then,
I take it away.
That makes me God.
Tori was easy.
Her fiance
left her last year
for some young blood bitch.
I just kept telling
old girl
she was still
the prom queen
like back in the day.
And that white
faggot dude,
he didn't have eyes
to see.
Sooner or later,
all bitches break.
Every goddamn one.
That's if you got game.
And that's why
she's your whore?
If you born a woman,
I can make you my ho.
Which is why she's saying
I had nothing to do
with no illegal shit.
Now that y'all got some
pimpology,
no charge,
my black ass is out
of here, right?
Anyone here believe
Lem cut a deal?
Maybe he felt like
he had no choice.
I mean, he's out there
in the wind alone.
Becca's probably
pushing it.
He has no idea about
this ranch in San Ignacio.
Or the money we're gonna
be funneling to him.
Becca told you
he took a deal?
No.
Aceveda.
Aceveda?
He's got a stake
in this, too.
Not like we do.
He could be
full of shit, man.
Look, the truth is,
we can't know what's inside Lem's head
until we see him
face to face.
We need an exit strategy.
How are we gonna
get out of this?
We don't need
an exit strategy.
We need to fill Lem in.
On the cash, the ranch.
The lines
of communication.
He's right.
You know Lem,
he's been in the dark
as much as we've been.
And if Lem is talking,
it's because he believes
that Antwon has marked him
as a dead man
behind bars.
Now, once he knows
what we've pulled
together for him,
he'll go along.
He will.
We go to the spot.
If he doesn't show...
assume he made the deal.
And then what?
If he does show,
then we'll
take his temperature.
And make sure he's still
solidly on board.
He'll be on board.
Lem trusts us.
He trusts us.
And I still trust Lem.
I do.
Where's Vendrell?
Shit. They're taking
different cars.
I'll take Mackey.
Ronnie, I got a tail.
I'm trying to lose him.
- You sure?
- It's pretty far back but he's there.
Watch your back, man.
Looks like I got one, too.
Call Shane.
Give him a heads up.
Yeah.
Vic and I
both have tails.
Shit.
Yeah, I'm looking.
We gotta lose him without
looking like we're trying to lose him.
Take your time.
- We can't lead Kavanaugh to Lem.
- I don't see anyone on me yet.
Vic says, whoever
loses his tail first,
gets to Lem, moves him
someplace safe,
'til we can all regroup.
Got it.
Jesus, am I glad to see you.
Man, how you doing?
- We gotta get out of here.
- What's going on?
Kavanaugh's got a tail
on Vic and Ronnie.
He could have an eye
up in the sky.
Follow me to the old
body shop
that closed down.
The one on Mission, OK?
All right, man.
Captain.
I've been reviewing
officer Hanlon's package.
Julien's T.O. report.
You ignored a
recommendation for dismissal.
Right. You know, with all
due respect to Julien,
you'll find, as I did, that
he's a little tightly wound.
Suffice it to say,
I felt he was too tough
on Tina,
and she deserved
a second chance.
Two counts
of excessive force,
contamination
of crime scenes,
failure to identify an
undercover officer in the field.
Seems more like
a sixth chance.
She's still learning
her field work.
But her instincts are good.
That's why Dutch agreed
to take her under his wing.
She's very intuitive.
I'm calling
her PBA rep.
Start the paperwork
for dismissal.
You know, you may not
want to do that.
Tina and I, we...
made an arrangement.
Someone was ripping off
the gourmet quick-mealer.
I figured it was
an inside job,
so I put a nanny cam
in the locker room.
There are photos of officer
Hanlon in her skivvies
that got out
into the world.
The important thing is
is that Dutch and I
handled it quietly
and efficiently.
Uh, all I did
was find the pictures,
bring them
to Steve's attention.
I had nothing to do with--
Oh, please, you helped
cover up this mess
for a shot
in Hanlon's panties.
Asshole.
Look, you want to spend
your first month on the job
overseeing
a full-time lawsuit?
Ruining several careers,
Wagenbach's included?
You go right ahead.
Asshole.
I never thought
it'd come to this.
Hasn't come
to anything yet.
What now?
I'll go back and get
Vic and Ronnie.
We got a way for you
to get to Mexico.
What, like Gilroy?
No, man.
The man died alone.
I'm not going that route.
You're not
a miserable drunk.
It's gonna be different.
No. It won't.
It won't.
Look, I'm not going.
No more running.
Oh, so you spend
the rest of your life
looking over your shoulder
for Antwon Mitchell?
You in Mexico
is the only thing
that keeps us all safe.
Especially you.
How the hell am I
going to live in Mexico?
We got it all
figured out.
How?
San Ignacio.
What the hell is that?
Some shithole?
No, man. It's a ranch.
Up in the mountains.
We got a federale that's
going to get you there.
It's beautiful, man.
It's going
to be peaceful.
We got money parked
in an account for you.
It's all set up.
Mara and I even kicked in
5 grand for you.
I don't want that.
It's just a start.
We'll keep skimming
off the street, man.
We'll keep you
hooked up.
I can't.
I can't do that.
It's all in play.
Trust me, man.
It's gonna work.
There's a way for me
to take the hit solo.
No, there's not, man.
No, there's not.
Man, Kavanaugh.
Aceveda, the D.A.
There's no other
deal to make.
They're gonna make you
give us up.
Maybe not now.
Maybe a year from now.
But man, you got one chance
to get out of here.
Take it, man. Take that chance,
right now. Take it.
I got it figured out.
Why'd you even
come back here tonight
if you weren't
planning on leaving?
I came to see you guys.
Don't do this, man.
Look, where's Vic?
I want to talk
to Vic.
He'll call when
he loses his tail.
We can't let Kavanaugh
catch us with you, man.
Mara's pregnant again.
No shit.
Yeah, yeah.
Almost 3 months.
I wasn't supposed to
say anything to anybody
until next week,
but, uh...
Hey, congratulations.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
That's another
mouth to feed.
Mara's gonna be laid up
near the end,
so I'm gonna have to...
have to step it up,
you know?
I hope I get to see
the little guy.
Or girl.
Little girl, huh?
Yeah.
Yeah. A little girl.
Hey, I'm gonna
be all right.
Shane.
Yeah.
I'm gonna be all right.
It's all about
family, right?
Look, what if Vic and Ronnie
can't shake the tail?
Maybe they doubled back
to the Barn.
I'll go check it out,
all right?
Move your car.
Get it out of sight.
Did you get enough
to eat today?
No, man. I'm hungry.
I brought you some food.
Thanks.
Thanks, man.
My favourite.
Shane? Shane!
I'm sorry.
Shane...
I'm sorry, buddy...
I'm so sorry...
Lem?
Lem, I'm sorry!
But I had to, right?
But you know I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, man.
Oh, God!
What are we gonna do
if Lem doesn't show?
He's gonna show.
He will.
Hey...
I had a tail.
- Took me a while to shake it.
- Yeah.
- Lem hadn't shown, huh?
- He's late.
But he'll be here.
Hey!
It's your lucky day.
The cab driver can't ID
and she won't testify against you.
Only thing to testify about
is my love for that girl right there.
I'm gettin' you out of here soon, baby.
Yeah, get yourself out of here.
Take him out, will ya?
Dutch,
I spoke to your ex-partner,
the new captain,
and she says
she trusts your instincts, so...
she wants me to increase
the number of hours I trail you.
I just wanted to say thank you
for putting in the good word.
Yeah, sure.
Okay.
Hey, hmm...
You know why you're gonna be
such a great detective someday?
Because most people don't realize
how damn smart you are.
They just see the surface.
They cannot get paste your looks
to see what you're really about.
I know, right?
But you're not nearly
as smart as you need to be.
The help I'm offering
doesn't come along every day.
And if I'm gonna spend
my valuable time focusing it on you,
well...
you'd better make it worth my while.
Sure.
Definitely, of course.
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
- He did it.
- No.
He's not coming.
Maybe he had some heat on him,
he had to hide.
He's coming,
or he's gonna get a message to us.
And we're gonna wait for him,
gonna give him more time.
Kavanaugh could be
at our houses right now man,
we have got to get out of here!
Vic.
Go home.
Check around,
look for anything incriminating.
Don't take any chances.
No.
We're gonna wait.
Yeah?
The transfert is denied.
I need my best detective on this.
Grenades.
The thing this morning.
El Salvadorans. The leader's missing.
His name is Guardo.
Start there.
Oh my God!
Vic, Vic...
You can't touch anything.
You're happy?
Are you happy now,
detective Mackey?
Stop it!
Stop!
Break 'em up!
Come on.
That's enough, come on.
Break it up!
Get off of him.
Calm down, calm down...
We're gonna find out who did this.
And we're gonna kill him.
Subtitles:
FRM-xxy & Lemonhead
www.1000fr.com
www.theshield-laserie.com