Detective Terry Crowley.
Remember him?
21/2 years ago, he was
on your Strike Team.
He was undercover, part
of a federal investigation.
He was your teammate,
he was a threat,
so he had to die.
We killed a cop.
Get over it and don't
bring it up again.
You didn't know, did you?
Vic never told you.
Vic did not
kill Terry.
So prove it.
Wear a wire.
Hey.
Hey, man.
We need to talk.
You lied to me.
Don't lie to me.
What are you doin'?
Stop.
I need
sound.
They asked me to wear a
wire. Just disconnected it.
They're watching us
right now.
They busted me with heroin, and they're
talkin' prison if I don't do this.
Why is it even a question?
I think you're lying to me.
Look me in the eye and tell
me the truth about Terry.
Don't buy into
their bullshit.
Look me in the eye.
You tell me the truth.
Oh, my God.
What happened to your mic
last night?
It got disconnected in the
fight. How much you get?
Nothin' after you two
started to mix it up.
You wanna fill me in?
I asked about him Terry. He still says
it was the drug dealer who shot him.
How'd it get physical
with Vic?
Guys like him don't come out
and tell you shit.
I had to make it personal
to get the truth.
I can't believe I was stupid
enough to let you in my head,
make me think Vic had something
to do with Terry dying.
Lift up your shirt.
Nah. I'm done with that.
Done? Let's put a pin
in Terry for a minute.
I still need to get a sense
of what your team is into.
And I got a 15-year sentence
hanging over your head, so...
please, lift up your shirt.
Let's avoid any technical
malfunctions this time.
A'ight? OK.
Hold on, buddy.
Hey, what is it?
When we're alone, man.
Baby, can you take him?
Hey, guys.
Come here, cutie.
Be just a second.
OK.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Yeah. What's up?
Lem got picked up
by I.A.D.
For what?
They nabbed him
for heroin.
Heroin? We haven't busted
any heroin in a while.
What's Lem doin' with horse?
He's not using.
You tellin' me he's runnin'
somethin' on the side?
He wouldn't do anything
without tellin' us.
Like burn
the money train cash?
I.A.D.'s got him
wearin' a wire.
So they're comin' after us.
We planted a gun
on Doomsday
and dropped him off
in Mexico yesterday.
Lem wasn't there. He was coverin' us
the whole time. We didn't have a clue.
What do you think
they're lookin' at us for?
How long's this
been going on?
I don't know, but now we gotta
stay focused on Lem,
figure out exactly what they have
on him, how we can get him out of it.
How we gonna do that
is he's wired?
Grab your laptop.
Sweep the Clubhouse for bugs
and meet us there in a few.
Hey, let's keep
our regular routine.
I.A.D. Gets a whiff that Lem
tipped us, it's over for him.
Lem asked me about Terry
last night.
On tape? He pulled the mic out first.
What did you tell him?
Nothin',
but he knows.
So what are we gonna do?
Lem needs help right now.
We gotta back him up.
We'll explain
everything to him
once he's
out of trouble.
First, downtown asks us for
our records on Terry. Now Lem.
You think
he told 'em something?
He's got nothing to tell. That's
my I.A.D.'s coming after us!
You and I were the only
2 people in that room.
Nothing that Lem or I.A.D. Can do
can ever change that simple fact.
Just gotta
stick together.
First one in. Came to put
the java on when I found 'em.
What time was that?
Let the detectives
handle the interviews.
We just need to preserve
the crime scene.
What do you think,
heart attack
and then she got crushed
underneath him?
Talk about
coitus interruptus.
Oh, Christ.
She's alive.
Gimme a hand.
Jesus.
She looked dead.
You got no sense of humor,
asshole. It's not that funny.
Tell me this isn't...
hysterical. Don't tell it again.
You got 3 explorers
in the Congo, right?
They get captured by natives,
who tie up the 3 bodies.
They bind and gag 'em.
Chief walks up to the
first explorer and he says,
"you have 2 choices... you
can choose death or chi-chi."
First explorer doesn't wanna die,
so he says, "I'll take chi-chi."
12 men grab him, rape him,
sodomize him for hours,
cut off his dick and balls,
shove 'em into his mouth,
send him into the woods
bleeding from every hole.
The chief walks up to the
second explorer, and he says,
"you have 2 choices. You
can choose death or chi-chi."
The second explorer debates in
his head. He doesn't wanna die.
He says,
"I'll take chi-chi."
18 tribesmen grab him,
rape, sodomize him for hours,
cut off his dick
and his balls,
shove it into his mouth, send him into
the woods bleeding from every hole.
The chief goes up to the last
explorer, right, and he says,
"you have 2 choices.
You must choose death
or chi-chi."
Third explorer,
big macho guy, mustache,
looks at him and says,
"I'll choose death."
The chief turns to his entire
tribe of a hundred natives
and says...
"very well, then.
Death by chi-chi."
I told you it was funny.
That's not funny.
Guys,
it's locked.
Hold on. Sorry about that.
Didn't know it was locked.
You got a dead body.
Possible sex crime.
Can you give that to somebody
else whose time isn't as valuable?
We got a million balls in the air
right now. Welcome to my world, hon.
Boys, what do you say we clear
this d.b. By lunchtime?
All right, man.
You OK?
Yeah.
He just kicked.
He? It's a boy?
Congrats.
Thanks. I just found out.
Congratulations.
I'll get the car.
We're gonna find out everything
we can about this Kavanaugh
sweating Lem.
What about the heroin
they got him on?
Could be chum
to set us in motion.
No, let's get a bead on this guy
before we take his bait.
OK.
We found him on top of
an unknown female.
Arms were bound.
We found keys on the table.
Guy's got a truck outside.
Let himself in.
Poppers.
Intensifies the orgasm.
Guess he popped more than
he bargained for. Run it.
Shop owner
called it in.
You know this guy?
Never seen him before.
Really? Then why does he
have keys to your place?
It's a teamster shop.
Shane, call the local 629.
Tell 'em Rick here is taking
hard-earned cash out of their pockets
and feeding it to
the non-union wetbacks.
Rodrigo's a part-time driver.
He never made trouble before.
Union wages are killing
my bottom line.
I see the scabs are working out
real nice for ya.
Where's his rig parked?
You know what? Check the cab
for a purse. We need an ID.
Check 'em.
Dude, no drugs,
no candy.
Nothing in the cab.
Hey, guys...
yo.
Lemme see that crowbar.
Help me out.
Watch out,
watch out.
Oh, Jesus.
Watch out, watch out.
Come on, let's go!
They gone?
Yeah, all three of 'em.
JAILBAIT
Guy covered up the vents with
electric tape to keep 'em quiet.
Shithead suffocated them
all. No ID's on any of 'em.
Rodrigo did a nickel in chino
for assault and rape
a few years back,
and you saw
the Los Perdidos ink.
Must have expanded from drugs
to skin trafficking.
License address is old, but
his p.o. Gave me a new one.
Why don't we file
for a warrant?
Gotta check out his crib,
see what's there.
Lem and I will hit mission cross,
see what we can get from the victim.
How's she doing?
She's sedated and severely
dehydrated, but she'll live.
Any signs
of sexual assault?
There's multiple tears.
It's pretty bad.
Tox report shows
rohypnol in her blood.
She give you a name?
Magdalena. Says that
a federale in Mexico
sold her and her little
brother to Mexican gangbangers.
She's not too big on cops.
I told her you were
2 of the good guys.
Come on.
We found 3 girls in the
truck. We didn't find your brother.
It's OK to talk to them.
They drop him off
just before we stopped.
I heard a man take him.
About 10 minutes later,
we stopped again.
That's when the driver
took me inside...
forced me...
then he... just died.
Ha ha ha ha.
Is there anything you could tell
us about the men who sold you
or who you were
supposed to go to?
They tell us nothing.
My brother Pablo.
Please find him.
We're gonna do
everything we can.
Excuse me, detectives.
I have an attorney here for you.
I'm Becca Doyle.
You arrested my client,
Evan Dayne,
for the cafeteria shooting
during the school riot?
Evan? Calls himself
"Every-Day."
How'd that come to
your attention?
I represented him 2 years ago
when he was guilty.
This time he's innocent, so I
offered my services pro Bono.
What makes you think
this guy is innocent?
Is there someplace
we can talk?
Several eyewitnesses
I.D. Ed your boy.
I re-interviewed
your witnesses.
Sorry to say,
pretty shoddy work.
Mariano gave us Evan.
4 others confirmed it.
They're all Mariano's close
friends. Did you know that?
We're not gonna
reopen this case
based on who's
in what clique.
Mariano gave you a Patsy,
and his buddies backed him up.
You didn't look into your original
witness very hard, did you?
Evan has a history of
weapons and assault.
And he's cleaned
himself up since.
He's stayed away
from guns and gangs.
I've checked in with him every
few months for the past 2 years.
We do our own
investigations.
Look, we all
have tough jobs
and we all
make mistakes.
Mine's having a little
bit too much faith
in my clients
sometimes.
But this time,
my faith is justified.
We'll look into it.
Thank you. I'll wait.
Yeah, all right.
No. You got it.
The coroner says rodrigo
died of a heart attack.
Mixed too much
party fuel.
Shane and Ronnie
got the warrant.
Call 'em back. Tell 'em
we'll meet 'em there.
I'll see you at the car in a minute. OK.
Has anyone from the
department come around
asking
any questions?
What are you
talking about?
There's a rumor
flying around
that someone might be trying
to make political hay
by coming after my team.
Could be I.A.D.
And this
is just a rumor?
We're clean.
But they might come poking
around asking questions.
But the fact is that
you and I were married,
so spousal privilege
applies to that entire time.
So you don't have to
tell anyone anything.
What do I say
if they ask?
Just tell them nothing.
Call me.
What?
Is there something that
I need to hide from them?
Of course not.
Listen, thanks for the help
with Magdalena.
Rodrigo's place.
Something wrong?
No, I'm fine.
Come on, ladies.
It's playtime.
Police!
Clear!
Clear.
Tear it up.
Yeah.
Rodrigo's gonna be pushing the
snooze button in hell from now on.
Nothing.
No, it can't be
that easy.
He's an ex-con
from Mexico.
It damn well could be.
Oh.
Jackpot.
Pictures of girls,
a few boys.
Hey, it's Magdalena.
The other 3 girls
in the truck.
That accounts
for 4 of them.
What about the rest
of these kids?
Where are they?
Hey, Magdalena's
brother.
Names, prices.
A passenger manifest.
It's a goddamn
kiddie catalogue.
Hey, what's granny
doing in here?
I don't know. Either
someone's into dry pussy
or she's helping him
traffic these kids.
5th and alvarado.
Let's go.
I just checked
with my witnesses.
Those kids are contradicting
everything they told you.
They still say
Mariano's innocent
and Every-Day
did do the shooting.
Maybe it's time
to reexamine your faith.
Mariano must have scared
his friends
to keep their mouth
shut.
We just want to get
to the bottom of this.
You don't know anybody who would
be willing to give up Mariano?
If he did, I would've
given it to you already.
Look, Mariano's
a bad dude.
Besides, it was a riot.
We were all running.
Maybe I was the only one
that seen him pull a gun.
So right now, it's still his
word against 5 others, right?
No one said
this would be easy,
but someone will tell
the truth, eventually.
Or maybe it's just
a play on your part.
You get us
to reopen the case.
That creates the reasonable
doubt you need to go to trial.
He's facing 12 to 25.
All I'm asking
is we be sure.
Why are you still
playing along with her?
You know witness statements.
They go down quick.
Maybe we got taken.
No, this is about
something else.
No, it isn't.
You're pissed that I called you
out about dragging your feet,
and now you're undermining
a case I pushed for.
Excuse me, detectives. I'm really
shorthanded. Is one of you free?
Dutch is.
Dutch? This is parole
officer Marshall Traynor.
He's got a case. I think
it's right up your alley.
Loel missed his court date the
other day, violated his parole.
Means he goes back
for another 2 years.
My friend ned just did a
stretch for armed robbery.
Some dude was taking
care of his dog,
and ned asked me to
drive him to pick it up,
but the dude wouldn't
give it back.
So we go to this guy's
place...
A trailer.
Where?
Somewhere around here.
He doesn't remember.
So I'm sitting in the
truck and all of a sudden
ned comes out
all bloody and shit.
Tells me the guy wouldn't
give him back the dog.
They fought and ned did him
in the head with a shotgun.
So you just decided to hang
around and violate your parole?
Ned had the gun. Made me grab
the dead body, hack the head off,
bag it in a field and
then... chopped up the body.
What'd you do with
the body parts?
There's this junkyard...
with like half a dozen
guard dogs.
I was an unwilling
participant, OK?
Did you buy his story?
I believe
he's telling the truth.
Because you dealt
with him a lot?
'Cause his brows were raised,
his lips parted and stretched.
I've studied up
on reading faces,
and I'm pretty good
at it.
L... I've read up on
micro-expression facial action units.
It's fascinating stuff.
The results are disputed.
Proof's in the pudding.
So can you spare some time
and help me find
this headless pile
of dog food?
Yeah. Uh, first,
though...
what do you think
of this kid?
I don't know, Every-Day.
You sure you're not wasting our time?
Lady, I don't have a lot
of friends at that school.
But I ain't never
shot no one.
My initial hit
is he's being truthful.
There's our granny.
Who's she with?
Abuela!
Hey, hey! You get the
tortoise, we get the hare!
Get out of the way!
Stop! Stop!
Drop the knife.
Drop it!
You got him?
Yeah!
Gimme your hand!
Gimme your other one.
I want my lawyer.
In a minute, you're gonna want a doctor!
Take it easy!
Hey, hey, hey!
Hey!
If he wants his lawyer,
he gets his lawyer.
Big, macho guy,
mustache, looks at him and says,
"I'll choose death."
The chief turns to his entire
tribe of a hundred natives
and says, "very well then.
Death... by chl-chi."
I always get a kick outta that one.
He's got it wrong,
right?
It's kee-kee.
Not chl-chi.
Must be some kind of
white thing or something.
I got your message about
Lemansky's wire mishap last night.
You think your
operation's compromised?
I sweated him
pretty good.
I'm hoping
we're still OK.
You're still making the same
mistakes everyone else makes.
And what is that?
I used to think that Mackey was
the luckiest son of a bitch alive.
That things just fell
into place for him.
Then I realized...
he was creating
his own luck.
So what you see as... a
simple microphone malfunction
I see as calculated.
The worst animal
in the joint...
98% of the time,
he's just like
everybody else.
Anybody.
It's the other 2%
that lands him
where he is...
and I'm going to know
everything... everything
about Vic Mackey.
And when he goes into
the 2% zone,
I got him.
You still don't know
who you're dealing with.
Maybe you're still
too convinced
that he's evil
100% of the time.
And that's why you keep grabbing for air
and he keeps...
slippin' away.
You never looked
Mackey in the eye,
had him lie
straight to your face
and made you doubt yourself even
though you know he was full of shit.
So until you do...
this... is all just
a waste of time.
I am so surprised
that you're here.
Yeah, you knew
I couldn't let go.
Well, Terry was your guy,
so I understand.
Stop playing me
and start worrying about Mackey.
This could be
our last shot at him.
And I'm gonna be right here
to make sure you don't blow it.
Here, here, here, here.
Now, where are these kids,
lady?
¿Señora, donde estan
estos niños?
You're not exactly
his type.
Nixon was in office the last time
you could pull off wearing a skirt.
Rodrigo
likes the young bloods.
Rodrigo le gusta
Las jovencitas.
¡Escucheme bien,
pedazo de mierda!
Listen to me,
you piece of shit.
I don't know these girls, and
I've never seen them before.
And I don't have to talk
to no goddamn cops.
This is just more
gringo bullshit...
... una pobre vieja...
threatening me because I'm
some poor, old, sick Mexican.
I hope your syphilis-
infected dick
hey, come on. Gets ripped
off by rabid dogs...
and fed to your whore mother,
and may she rot in hell.
That's enough of that.
I want to talk
to an attorney.
Did you get that?
That is one cold slice.
It's a skill she picked
up doing a dime and a half
in chowchilla for murder
30 years ago.
How's this going?
It's not.
She lawyered up.
There goes 8 hours
before we can push her p.d.
About these missing kids.
Call a public defender's
office.
See if they can get
a lawyer here soon.
All right.
You got a minute?
It's Doyle, right?
I'm working a case
now...
that's funny. So am I.
Got a little old lady
right in the middle of
a sex trafficking ring.
Uh... she needs a lawyer.
I'm sure the public
defender's office
will send a capable
candidate right over.
It can't wait. I still got almost
50 Mexican sex slaves in play.
Once word hits the street that
grandma and jethro got busted,
whole operation goes underground,
they cover their tracks.
How'd you like to do a
good deed for the day?
Already have.
And I seem to remember
you have a talent for shading things
on the witness stand, detective.
I think you'll be fine.
You still upset
about the crawford case?
The jury felt that
that guy was guilty.
You can't hold that
against me.
The case rested solely
on your testimony.
Which was completely
on the level.
Sorry. I have my hands
full.
So you'd rather hold a
grudge than help make a case
that could save lives?
Actually, it's about picking
and choosing my clients.
As appealing
as your offer sounds,
I'd rather not devote
the next month of my life
to protecting a sex
slave master grandmother.
All I'm asking is an hour.
Usted puede contestar
Las preguntas.
They bring me the girls to the
fruit stand, a few at a time.
Her job is to take them
to the drop-off point.
¿A donde?
Diferentes partes.
Different places. Places
with a lot of kids around.
A bunch of teenaged kids with
a little old lady like yourself
doesn't raise eyebrows.
Who's the contact?
¿Quien es el contacto?
It always changes. He finds
her after she makes the call.
We gotta set up a meet.
That's not part
of the deal.
I have to send one
of my people to the meet,
then we follow the contact and
bust up the whole operation.
If you want her doing field
work, which wasn't in the deal,
then I need probation.
Dream on.
If everything hinges on her, I'd
be a fool to give up that hammer.
Just like you were foolish
for letting me know
how important she is
to making your case.
Come here.
You'd set her free.
No. You will.
And maybe next time, you
won't make that mistake.
Right now, it's the
only deal to be made.
We're gonna be able to
hear every word you say.
You're gonna be in our
sight lines at all time.
Questions?
No, I'm good.
Officer Lowe
has some misgivings
about putting
his trainee under.
She's still
on probation.
Decoy's supposed to
look young.
Wide-eyed and new to
the game works for us.
The only thing I don't
want is the bad guys
getting even one whiff
of cop off of her.
Could jeopardize
the whole takedown.
What about you, honey? You
think you can handle this?
They got me covered.
I don't see a problem.
Well,
let's do this.
Julien, you're in charge of uni backup.
I appreciate
the support.
You heard my reasons.
My only concern now is
getting you home safely.
Hey, Vic?
Yeah.
That, uh... report
you asked for.
Everything we could find on
Kavanaugh on such short notice.
Word is, he gave up his
own partner to I.A.D.
Back in the day.
Flies solo. Only investigator
that works without a partner.
Means it's 4 and 1.
That's good. Anything else?
He grew up in inglewood.
Poor kid done good.
Put himself through school with
degrees in psychology, criminology.
Bookworm.
No. Golden glove
champion at the academy.
5 in vice, a stint
in robbery homicide.
Family?
Divorced. No kids.
We gotta figure out
what this guy has to lose.
Look, everybody's all-American
can't be that clean.
Keep diggin'.
She's droppin'
her off.
What's this guy doing?
Teresa?
Sí?
Vámonos.
Looks like
our trafficker.
They're
getting in the van.
You speak english?
Sure.
Julien, the suspect's driving
a brown 2-toned shit-box van.
Just keep your team
in position.
The gringos, they
like it when you talk in english.
Whatever you want.
Hey, move it, shithead!
Hey!
Hey, move your car!
Shithead, get outta the way!
Hey, buddy, move!
Move outta the way!
Move your car!
Get outta the way, man!
Hold on!
Shit, shit,
shit, shit!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Turning left
on Wilshire.
Come on, man.
We're losing her.
When you get to the
house, señorita gets you started.
- Gives you clothing, makeup, morning-after pills.
- He's turning again.
Vic, where are you?
Minor detour, Julien.
Just hold your position.
When can I see
my brother Pablo?
You turn a lot of tricks,
then you get the privileges.
Till then,
just do as we say.
Is he safe?
Yeah. As long as you behave,
he'll stay that way.
He's turning
into the alley.
What is going on?
He's stopping
in front of the gate.
Get down on your knees!
What?
Fiesta time, amigos!
It's fiesta time.
It's a gang-bang.
Screw it.
Let's go, man.
No, no. Hold on.
You boys
got a condom?
We're gonna do your mouth,
not your clam, bitch.
Come on, open up.
L... I got gonorrhea
in my throat.
What?
Look, I'll suck
you boys off,
but don't hit me later
if it burns.
Forget about it.
Never mind.
When we get
to the house,
we're gonna run
a train on your ass.
And don't you be telling any
customers that you're sick.
Good girl.
Yeah. Shorty's
got game.
They're movin'.
You, uh... you sure
they're chained up tight?
As long as you don't
piss me off, we're good.
I always thought, uh...
face reading should be one
of the first things they teach
at the academy.
I taught myself.
Be happy to lend you
some books and dvds.
If you wanna grab
a bite later,
I'll give you
a quick rundown.
Yeah. Sounds good.
You'd be surprised how
transparent people become.
Your partner,
for instance.
Claudette.
She's trying to hide
something from you.
It's pretty obvious.
Something's
in the closet.
Whole pack was over
here the entire day.
That's when
I found him.
Well...
thanks for the hand.
Is this his place
or they run girls from here?
Hold on.
We jump too early,
we'll get nothin'.
OK...
looks like the madame to me.
All right, that's it.
Everybody move in!
Hope you take
walk-ins!
Get up now! Get up!
You, right now!
Hands behind your head!
On your knees!
Get down!
Get on the
ground right now! Down!
Down! Turn around!
Hands behind your head!
- Hey, find Tina!
- Vic!
Clear!
Tina!
Vic!
Don't you move!
You OK?
Yeah. Didn't have
my baton,
but every guy's
got their weak spot.
How right you are.
Good girl. Nice work.
Where's the kid?
This idiot's acting
like he doesn't understand.
Got 10 girls off this sheet.
The rest are still missing.
You don't know about Pablo?
What about the rest of the girls?
And the boys?
I want my lawyer.
Is that the first thing they teach
you pricks once you cross the border?
Put him in the van.
Hey, we take this shithead to
the Barn, he's gonna clam up.
Word gets out about this bust,
we'll never find the rest of 'em.
Well, maybe he's not
as stupid as he looks.
Come on.
Let's go,
asshole.
This is a shitty day.
We only got about
half those kids.
At least we get to stick
the needle in someone for it.
What are you talkin' about?
Gutierrez is gonna get 5 to 7, max.
Hey, we got
3 dead girls.
This asshole
was nowhere near that.
We got conspiracy charges, so
he's up for the murders, too.
That's right.
That... that is good news.
Doesn't mean he's gonna get
the death penalty, though.
Well, calhoun
is prosecuting.
Man, so I guess
that means he will.
Who's calhoun?
Hey, shut up, you prick!
You wanted a lawyer,
now we can't talk to you.
Yeah, but I ain't getting
no death penalty
for some girls I didn't
kill, man, I didn't even see.
Save it for your last
words lyin' on the gurney.
I wouldn't expect any clemency
with the Terminator as governor.
Carlos odonez.
He's the boss.
Whoa, ho, ho!
You waiving your right
to an attorney?
Of your own free
will?
Yeah.
But you'll help me, right?
Where are the rest
of the girls?
There's a house in colquitt.
Another one on adams.
And the boy Pablo,
where's he at?
Bangkok. They flew him and the
rest of the boys out this afternoon.
Bangkok?
Jesus.
Corrine.
Hey.
Jon, hi.
Hey, help your sister
in the car, OK? Thanks.
How you holding up?
Good. Andy's a handful,
but, you know, it's worth it.
Yeah, listen. Here is my
address and phone number.
We still on for
that Friday play date?
Yeah. I mean, if there's
a problem, I'll call you,
but, yeah, I'm looking
forward to this, really.
OK. Where's andy?
Sometimes I wonder
if this extra program
is just an excuse to
bilk me outta extra money.
From the school, yes.
But teachers, no.
You liking the teacher
or...
I'm blanking on her name
right now. Um... remind me.
It's the woman
with the, uh...
um... I thought Mr. Dunhill
taught the after school program.
He does. But I'm talking
about her aide. His aide.
Anyway, look,
I'll see you on Friday,
if not sooner.
Yeah, good. I gotta
get my kids home,
but I'll see you then, OK?
See ya.
Just got this case
an hour ago.
Why is my client arrested
for second-degree murder
when another boy
was already arrested?
I'm sure you've heard Every-Day's
attorney is making my life hell.
She's taken depositions
from half the high school,
depositions listing you
as the shooter.
Bullshit.
My friends were there.
They saw Every-Day
pull that gun.
What are you writing?
Every-Day's release.
The D.A.'s decided to drop
the case, charging your client.
Based solely
on witness statements.
They also just found
gun reside in his locker.
Ha ha ha ha.
What else do you have?
D.A. Doesn't want me revealing
it until we're closer to trial.
This does not need
to go to trial.
What do I have to do
to make a deal?
Convince your client to drop
the high school clique crap,
school him in what it's like
to have this evidence,
a high-priced lawyer,
and a very pissed-off cop
working against him.
Gun residue
in a locker?
I'd never let you
get away with that.
Cops are allowed to twist
the facts to suspects.
I directed my comments
to him.
Evan's being released
tonight.
I know.
Thanks for your help.
I owe you one.
I mean that. You call in a
favor whenever you need it.
I will.
I, uh... I heard.
Nice work.
Thanks.
How's yours going?
Turns out the parolee
was coerced.
So he won't go down for the
murder or hacking up the body.
The other guy's going
away for a long time.
And I'm, uh,
sure about him.
Good! Well, where you
running off to?
Dinner with Marshall.
I can't have other
colleagues as friends?
Marshall has quite
a reputation
as a man's man,
if you know what I mean.
He's... he's gay?
While you were reading faces,
he was reading your package.
Have fun, though.
Cage would look
a whole lot prettier
with Abuela's
ugly mug in it.
Sure you don't wanna find
a loophole in our deal?
I couldn't let you run
rough-shod over a little old lady,
much as she deserved it.
You lookin'
for more business?
I appreciate the offer,
but I'm OK watching from the
sidelines while they get theirs.
Right now, I'd like to go home
and wash this place off me.
You talkin' about the cops
or the criminals?
See you in court some day,
detective.
Vic.
I got something important.
Someone has been
asking questions.
Who?
This man. He's
approached me a few times.
Where at?
Glenridge. He, uh...
he said he was a parent
of an autistic child.
But I've been around cops long
enough to know what they sound like.
Besides, I've never
even seen his kid. So...
that him?
Yeah.
Why's he coming
to our school?
What'd he ask ya?
I'm trying to remember.
Something about
paying the tuition
and how we do it,
how involved you are.
What'd you tell him?
Told him you give us money
for whatever we needed.
I was trying to sell you
as a good dad.
I didn't tell him
about the cash in the bag.
Good.
Don't tell him shit.
Asshole has no business
talking to you about this.
It's my problem.
And I'll take care
of it.
All right?
Everything OK?
Yeah.
Yeah?
That was great.
But, uh...
you were somewhere else.
Is it about
that meeting this morning?
Yeah.
Lem's in some
hot water.
Yeah.
How hot?
I don't know yet.
I thought you said that
you were done with all that,
that you were gonna
keep clean.
I have been. I swear.
Then why are you
so worried?
Hmm?
Don't you worry.
OK?
We'll figure it out.
Figure it out.
"We" meaning...
you and Vic?
Together as a team,
standing by Lem.
Listen. Listen to me.
Listen to me.
Team's one thing,
but family's another.
All that stuff that I had with Antwon...
you know?
Yeah.
I was looking at prison
in the eye.
I know. I know.
Hey...
I'm not gonna let
anything happen to us.
Jackson needs his father.
Well, I need
the both of you.
Buddy in immigration called.
He's putting the word out
on Pablo.
Spoke to an American
diplomat in bangkok.
I meant what I said about
not giving up on him.
OK. Good.
I feel like there's some
unfinished business between us.
What's that?
It's this Terry thing.
You thought I was
hidin' something from ya.
Here's the truth.
I swept through
that house.
I cleared
that bathroom.
At least
I thought I did.
Somehow, two-time
got past me.
I left Terry exposed.
I made a mistake.
I never told anybody
I thought it was my fault.
That's something I been livin'
with for a long time now.
Finally, I decided
to move on.
Something you're gonna
have to push past, too.
Yeah.
OK.
Hey, Vic.
Her majesty Billings
needs to see you.
Tell him
I'll be right there.
Got it.
What's up?
Somebody here to see you.
Jon Kavanaugh.
Internal affairs.
Vic Mackey.
Yeah.
You mind if I have a
moment alone, captain?
No, not at all.
Thank you.
What can I do for you,
detective?
It's lieutenant.
Right.
We're just cops
just like you.
I guess the good looks, it
just throws everybody off.
Anyhow...
we're making a tour
of the division.
With the budget cuts,
the bosses,
they're afraid that
there might be, uh...
a lot of temptation
to take shortcuts.
And I'm just here to
remind everyone that...
I'm still on the case
and there is a right way
to do things.
I've been a cop
for 14 years.
You guys never toured
before.
New management.
Putting
a friendlier face
on the old rat squad.
Ha ha ha!
Anyhow, there is no reason why you
and I should not be on the same page.
Why are you talkin'
to me?
You run a special team.
Those get most of
the abuse allegations.
And from what I hear,
those people out there,
they all follow
your lead.
Well, can't blame 'em
for having good judgment.
Ha ha!
Is there anything brewing
that I should know about?
I mean, anything
at all... suspicious?
Not that I can think of.
You sure?
It is good to meet you.
You, too.
Subtitles:
FRM-xxy & Lemonhead
www.1000fr.com
www.theshield-laserie.com