[Rock]
[Radio Chatter]
[Continues]
[Hip-hop]
[Rock Continues]
[Tires Screeching]
[Continues]
- [Footsteps Approaching]
- [Door Opening]
Come in.
[Ends]
What do you think?
This is yours?
Well, only 15% of us actually
live in the neighborhoods we patrol.
[Chuckles]
Ah, taming the frontier
isn't enough for you?
Well, /'m thinking
of staking a claim.
Seemed like a good idea a month ago
when I put down the deposit.
But, uh, now with
everything heating up-
Antwon Mitchell-
maybe it's not such a good idea.
- [Dog Barking]
- [Man Shouting, Distant]
Get extra patrols,
undercover units, to look over you.
/ can't divert police resources
for my own protection.
That would defeat the purpose
of living in the hood.
Why am / here?
You want me to find
a couple of code violations...
sweat your landlord
to get your deposit back?
I didn't sell you out.
[Scoffs]
Everyone in L.A. saw you on that tape
grabbing that kid in the church and smiling.
/ had to ask you
to take a step back.
A backseat.
Let me guess. Either you're with Vic Mackey
or you're against him, right?
- Keeps things simple.
- I'm with you...
but I expect you
to be with me.
Wherever your head is these days,
just don't start cutting me out...
or going around me,
like you did with Aceveda.
Keeps things simple.
Hey, man,
where the hell you been?
- Taking care of some things.
- I hope you're talking about Shane.
- We need to stick together.
- I don't need babysitters.
Antwon's got Shane coming out to kill you, for
Christ's sakes. What the hell we doing about it?
- I'm watching my back.
- Really? Out there in the open?
He could be setting you up.
Could be a drive-by.
Could be waiting for you at your house.
He and Army are off the grid.
You seen them at all today?
We went by Shane's truck
to pick up the latest tape...
- they're nowhere.
- Come on, let's get out there.
Come straight at him.
Don't worry.
When the time's right.
- Why did you change your hair?
- It was a whim.
It's like seeing a stranger
in the mirror.
That's a bit drastic.
/ wish you'd have asked me first.
I could've offered
an opinion.
You don't like it?
I'll get used to it.
[Phone Ringing]
- [Sighs]
- What-What is it?
My sister's having a meltdown.
Her asshole boss fired her today.
I'm sure your sister
will be fine.
She wants to come over.
- You told her it's not a good time.
- Look, / wouldn't do this.
It's just,
she's really on edge, depressed.
We can hurry.
[Sighs]
I'll make it up to you.
I promise.
Hey.
- Come on in.
- Yeah.
You're lookin' beautiful.
[Helicopter Whirring]
[Radio Chatter]
[Billings]
Mitch Robville, 33, throat slashed.
Was supposed to pick up a friend
for work this morning. Never showed.
He should've used
a safety razor.
- Did you say Mitch Robville?
- You know him?
Yeah, he's one of our informants.
He tipped us about the crack house on Rivermore.
Took the money and ran. Idiot shouldn't have
turned down our offer to move him.
Tip leads to a seizure,
and this is what happens.
We have to assume the same thing
happened to Angie.
Yeah, that's one way
to make sure the snitch-well runs dry.
Very first roll call, / said that
we would protect the people who helped us.
Now we've lost two of'em.
You giving me the wheel,
or am / still in the backseat?
I want who did this.
Police! Antwon,
get your ass out here!
[Baby Crying, Distant]
- You better have a warrant.
- Warrant?
I saw your door busted wide open.
Wanted to make sure you were okay.
You okay?
One-niners got a campaign
against police informants?
I'm done with this.
You think you can just
go after anyone?
You think
you're indestructible?
I don't know
what you're spittin'.
[Crowbar Clatters]
If you've given the word,
and some informant...
or some citizen,
or some cop gets hurt...
you're gonna be spittin' teeth.
[Chuckles]
I'm going back to bed.
Make sure you get
that door fixed.
Anyone could just
walk right in.
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Ends]
The other players on Rivermore all got
the same inter-ghetto memo.
Word's out
our dead guy was our tip.
[Sighs]
I tried to take every precaution...
with our seizure C.I.'s
since Angie disappeared.
[Sighs] Pull in the rest of the tipsters
until we get a handle on this.
Pulling in C.I.'s is only gonna
expose them more or ratchet things up.
They're all at risk. Could be
Antwon Mitchell sending out a hell of a signal.
- Well, I'll see about sending him one back.
- I'm also calling in I.A.D.
Seizures are stirring things up.
We could be gettin' ourselves all worked up...
about a leak that
doesn't exist.
Then let them prove that.
Do you really want to give Aceveda
more ammunition to shut this thing down?
Give me one last chance
to find the leak and plug it.
Okay. But first,
solve this murder.
[Door Opens]
Somebody killed one of our rats.
I'm running it down.
- Where do you want us?
- Captain's digging deeper into our leak.
Get the info from Billings, compare it to Angie's,
see what they have in common.
Why bother? Shane and Antwon
are responsible for Angie.
We can't tell the captain,
can we?
- [Curtis] What about Shane?
- [Mackey] This again?
You just want us to sit on our asses?
Do you have a plan?
You gonna tell us what it is?
Shane's cell phone.
I palmed it from
his locker yesterday.
Keep an eye on it,
see who calls.
That's it?
That's the master plan?
- Part of it.
- What are we doing to end this?
I appreciate you two
having my back...
but I don't need it.
Meet me on the other side
in three minutes.
[Cell Phone Beeps]
Your unfinished business
kicked down my door last night.
You know, it's complicated.
He's a smart guy.
- I got to do it right.
- Yeah. He's coming straight at me, man.
I'm not gonna lose no more sleep
over this asshole, you feel me?
Tomorrow morning's news will have
a big picture of Mackey's kids...
crying their eyes out.
Or a picture of your son,
crying his.
You don't want to make that threat.
Your wife still
sell real estate? Hmm?
Still show
those open houses?
Yeah.
Playtime is over.
Get it done tonight.
[Grunts]
- [Cell Phone Beeps]
- I'm on my way.
- [Chattering]
- Ken Gibbin, science teacher.
Been at this high school
seven years.
[Monica]
He's not one of our C./. 's.
Maybe he dropped a dime on one ofhis students.
This ain't exactly finishing school.
- [Billings] I ran his name. It's coming up dry.
- Keep checking.
Grab the class rosters. Run the names with
the principal. See who's not on the dean's list.
He may or may not
be connected.
Sure the throat's cut,
but it could be a copycat.
You have a different way to go? You have
a lead on the first murder I'm not aware of?
- Are all the other snitches in safe houses yet?
- I just finished that.
Call in the next shift O.T.
Increase their protection.
- You don't think the one shift's got it covered?
- No. I don't.
He's been doing 15 months
for possession.
Only 14 months to go.
Someone planted
all that weight in my locker.
Mr. Gibbin, your old teacher...
somebody cut him,
ear to ear.
- That your idea of payback?
- Gibbs?
Nah, Gibbs wasn't no rat.
He was always trying
to keep me straight.
I'd screw up and we'd talk,
but he'd never take it to 5-O.
They cut him?
Head almost completely off.
Sheriff tells me the kid
didn't have any colors before he hitJuvie...
but to stay alive,
he had to claim Spookstreet.
- He could be covering for his crew.
- Spookstreet supplied rock...
to the house our victim
gave up on Rivermore.
- Uh-huh.
- Puts them in the middle of both killings.
- And off of Antwon's plate.
- Well, not necessarily.
Pull in all the unis
assigned to Spookstreet.
I'll do you one better.
Danny's baby-mama C.I. is a Spookstreet ho.
- She's watching cable in a safe house on our dime.
- The one with the two-year-old?
All her tips have been on One-niners.
She'd never give up her own.
Danny knows her pretty well.
She thinks she might have a soft spot.
It's worth a shot.
Bring her in here.
I have a theory...
about the leaks.
Isn't Aceveda's office reviewing
every one of the seizures?
I thought of that.
I see him pulling
political moves...
not moves that actually
get people's throats cut.
I'm not pointing any fingers.
It's just a notion.
You've given us some great intel
on the One-niners.
And you pay good money
for the things I hear.
Anyone in Spookstreet taking it upon themselves
to pay back people they think might be rats?
Everyone wants to know
who's been talkin'.
Getting the cops to take
their houses and shit.
[Sighs]
/t's a good thing / keep my mouth shut.
But Spookstreet is in the middle
of both killings.
- You must've heard something?
- I can't help you.
Sure, you can.
How much is it gonna cost us?
Money's for One-niner shit only.
Spookstreet's my blood.
I ain't spillin'.
[Danny]
Let me talk to her?
[Claudette]
What did he look like?
[Dutch]
He already said he doesn't remember.
- He was black.
- I got that. Any identifying features?
Guy beat my head with a bottle.
I was unconscious.
I'm lucky I remember
my own name.
[Claudette]
How much did he get away with?
At this hour,
maybe 300.
[Dutch] We need you to, uh,
check the receipts, tally a total.
So, a black guy comes in,
attacks you...
and next thing you remember
is a different guy dialing 911 for help?
You ever try
writing this shit down?
[Dutch]
Come on. We got his statement.
[Bells Jingling]
[Man]
/ was by my car pumping gas.
I look up, I see somebody
hitting the clerk.
- You got a good look inside the station?
- Uh, not really.
It wasn't till he came outside
that I got a good look at him.
- Hot off the press.
- You should work that up into a flyer.
- I thought he'd get another look at it again first.
- Looks great to me. Right?
How do you know?
You never saw the guy.
That's him.
I have a good eye for detail.
We appreciate it.
/f we need anything else, we'll call you.
- Okay.
- Thanks. This way.
Hey, Julien.
Captain got you riding the desk?
Yeah, until
my complaint's addressed.
The stand you're taking
sets a great example.
Let me know
if you need anything.
Hey, listen,
since I got you...
a Jag dinged Aurora's car in the Gelson's
parking lot and took off without stopping.
Do me a favor,
run the plates.
- Uh, sure.
- Thanks.
- Thanks for coming down.
- Sure.
- [Clears Throat]
- So, uh, how can / help?
We're afraid our seizure C.I. list
has been compromised.
/s there any chance
there's a leak on your end?
My end?
That's ridiculous.
You just took office.
You sure you vetted everyone on staff properly?
They've got confidential police documents
running across their desks.
I'll call I.A.D. myself.
We've got nothing to hide.
What'd they say
about this place?
I'm still investigating.
Oh, so you haven't had I.A.D. in here?
You haven't run Mackey?
Vic may have a hard-on
for authority...
but he would never
put innocents at risk.
He's not the leak.
Have /.A.D. here in the morning.
My staff will be happy to speak with them...
as soon as
they finish with Vic.
You know you're safe here.
But you also know
that living the way you do...
one foot in with the bangers, one foot trying
to get out, it's never gonna work.
- I got no place to go.
- Well, that's what the money's for.
- It's a big world out there.
- Single black mom-
I just pick up
and move to Beverly Hills?
Stayin'half-in is gonna get you killed.
Or Malcolm.
Maybe not now, maybe not next year,
but somewhere down the line.
I'm safe with Spookstreet. If I go off on my own,
who am I gonna count on?
You think you can count on
those assholes?
Those guys and their hos will
slash your neck...
if they found out that
you ratted on the One-niners.
Come on. Why don't we just take the baby
right now? We'll go get him inked with gang tats.
So, it's a done deal,
isn't it?
He's gonna wear colors.
You're gonna wear black to his funeral.
She says that if any one of
the Spookstreeters did the slashings...
they'd get a brand
before the day's out.
Some guy named Skitch
is doing 'em all now.
Check it out.
He comes in for looseys
two or three times a week.
- What's a loosey?
- You don't know what a loosey is?
A single
loose cigarette-loosey.
- [Claudette] You sure it's the same guy?
- He makes me break a pack.
/'m not supposed to, but he winds up buying
it anyways, one smoke at a time.
Wh-What else
can you tell us about him?
He comes in for looseys two, three times a week.
Looks just like that.
- Sorry.
- If he comes in again, you give us a call, all right?
[Bells Jingling]
[Engine Starting]
Where are you going?
That guy was standing out there
like he was waiting for us to clear out.
[Rock]
That's a buck, 20.
Hey. Hey. Police.
Don't throw that coffee.
Shit!
Stay down. Stay down.
You're under arrest.
- You okay?
- Yeah. You?
We just caught
the big, bad "Coffee Bandit."
We've been looking
for you, "Starbuck."
- [Continues]
- I told you to wear your vest.
[Chuckles]
Yo, Skitch! We're looking to skin
some Spookstreet hide.
You brand any today?
- Nope.
- None?
No one came in here looking for
a grim reaper on their ass?
Id have remembered that.
I can heat up a swastika for you though, Adolf.
Hey, Vic, why don't I wait in the car?
I'll let the two of you
maybe talk in private?
Works for me. Don't mind
any strange noises emanating from this area.
Okay. Okay.
/ see how we're doin
Maybe there were
two other guys around here.
But you keep my name out of it though.
These guys ain't too fond of snitches.
Okay. This is Hook.
This is Cutter-10.
Plainclothes unit has them
spotted on Blythe and Fountain.
Uh, Curtis,
I need you to take point.
Uh, Billings and /
have been workin'this.
You're staying.
[Chuckles] Real estate between me
and anything seizure-related.
You did a great job finding
these assholes...
and you'll get a chance to interrogate them
when the others bring them in.
- But you cannot be the arresting officer.
- Mm-hmm.
I appreciate you understanding.
[Curtis On Radio]
Go. Go.
[Tires Screeching]
- Get your hands where I can see 'em!
- Freeze! Get out of the car!
Get out of the car!
Hey, get out.
Get out of the car right now.
You heard the lady.
- Get down.
- [Groans]
Got something.
- [Man] Come on, man.
- [Officer] Shut up.
[Grunts]
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Mackey]
Victim's blood, your fingerprints.
Somebody should've branded
"dumb shit" on your forehead.
Yeah, but it took a whole fleet
of blue to bring me in though, didn't it?
What's your reason
for killing anyone helping us?
/ ain't got no problem with the po-po
cleaning up the streets.
That's what white law
gets paid for.
[Mackey]
You just don't like anyone cooperating with us.
Come on, my man, some dick
buys himself a brand-new Caddy...
he ridin' around
like he's some kind of mack.
People gonna thank me
for doing him.
As a matter of fact, you make sure
the pen hears all about it before I sit down.
What about the teacher?
You looking to make your bones
for the kids in detention?
Nah. Nah, he was
a snitch's snitch, man.
Everybody knew that he the one
that gave up that One-niner's drug den.
Ah, we'll show you the books.
He wasn't our informant on anything.
What kind of cred's killing
some innocent dude buy you in the can, huh?
He wasn't innocent, man. He- He was a rat,
big time. Everybody knew he was rattin'.
You got played, man. People found out
you got all worked up about snitches...
just gave you a name
to settle some personal score.
[Monica] We'll make sure they hear
about that in the pen too.
Someone punked you like that?
You're not going to let them share the pain?
[Chuckling]
Some breezy-
she one of his students.
Tracy something.
She on the drill team, man.
I'm not admittin'
to anything, so-
Sure, whatever. We-We're bringing in
the other clerks to identify you.
They're pissed.
They'll remember.
[Sighs]
You know, uh...
every once in a while somebody commits
a crime that we cops have to smile at.
Yeah. A hot cup of coffee,
no other weapon is brilliant.
Pour it, pay for it- bam.
You're back home
before the guy's washing off.
- [Laughing]
- Any dumb-shit criminal can use a gun, you know?
Where'd you think
of the idea?
Some broad threw coffee
in my face.
I remember thinking to myself,
l-l-I'm lucky this isn't hot.
[Laughing]
After that,
it all came together.
/ heard you took one
in the line of duty.
The Coffee Bandit
is now in custody.
- Dutch did a great job.
- It was a team thing.
Congratulations.
- We'll pay to have your suit dry-cleaned.
- [Chuckles] Thanks.
Anything on the gas station assault
that put you there in the first place?
Uh, suspect's
a part-time smoker.
He'd go into the gas station
a couple times a week for looseys.
I used to pay
a dime for mine.
Ah, the good old days.
You were both smokers, huh?
Uh, the suspect's sketch has been
put in every gas station in the area.
So if he lives nearby,
maybe he'll hit another one.
Good work.
A meeting got canceled.
I figured I'd take a chance.
- Expecting someone?
- No.
But, uh, you need to call first.
You know, you can't just drop by.
Right. I might
run into your sister.
How is she?
This isn't how it works.
Please leave now.
Go.
This place, your clothes,
your hair-
It must all add up, huh?
- That's why you bring the gifts.
- [Door Closes]
As nice as Dell Rossetti's?
Did you forget I'm a police officer?
Your bullshit lies
don't work on me.
- He's a friend.
- You don't have friends. You have clients.
/'m guessing Rossetti's
a generous one.
But then again,
he showed up empty-handed.
Maybe we're standing
in his gift.
He the reason you changed your hair?
He prefer blondes?
/ told you a lie
to keep our lie alive.
You want to puncture that balloon,
that's your deal.
Yeah? Well, what's
this guy's flavor, huh?
Up the ass?
Shitting on you?
You don't get to talk to me like that.
Not even when I'm on the clock.
Well, Rossetti can certainly afford
the all-access pass.
He's got condos going up
all over the city.
- We don't talk business.
- From what / can tell, he cuts corners...
which could land him in some
serious trouble with the authorities.
/ don't know what shit you're trying
to work through with me, but it's not working.
You know, he got married
a couple years ago.
If the wife has any brains,
she put a cheating clause in the prenup.
You gonna call her?
Sort of a bitch move, don't you think?
I don't think
she'd see it that way.
Or I could call my friends
in the D.A.'s office.
I could call
my friends in the P.D.
I could hit him with
a dozen different shit storms...
and my fingerprints
wouldn't be on any of them.
You've got a wife too.
Should I let her know
how to make you happy at home?
Oh, you wouldn't do that,
not to me.
'Cause you're
so powerful, right?
You want to see
the things I can do?
[Sighs]
Look, David...
I like our time together.
Let's not screw it up
over something stupid.
Just tell me
what you want.
I don't come second
to anyone.
- You're working today.
- Yeah. What-What are you doing here?
Uh, I'm just trying to catch Vic. Kid stuff.
What happened to your suit?
Uh, takedown got pretty messy.
It's no problem. We got the guy.
- Great. We'll celebrate later.
- [Chuckles] There's Vic.
Uh, listen, I've got a robbery
I'm working on, so I'll talk to you later.
/ got a pretty full plate.
What's going on?
/ heard back from that clinical trial
/ signed Megan up for.
- Uh-huh.
- She's not eligible.
[Sighs]
Shit. Come on.
- She's under three years old.
- [Door Closes]
Second kid in the family with autism.
Isn't that what they wanted?
/t's not Megan.
/t's us. Our lawsuit.
Pyren Pharmaceuticals excludes
anyone with pending legal action against them.
Wait a minute. First, these are the people
who make the vaccines that make our kids sick...
and then they're the goddamn gatekeepers
of the ones who get better?
I spoke to Mamyn.
We can drop out of the lawsuit if we want.
- It's just the money that we sunk into the tests.
- We're not eating 15 grand!
These clinical trials- I've seen video of kids who-
they haven't even talked.
And now they're playing
and they're laughing.
That'll never be Matthew...
but Megan
still has a chance.
Or she could end up being
the one eatin' the sugar pill.
She shouldn't miss out.
But this lawsuit was our one chance
for financial security for Matthew.
/- / don't know
what to do.
I'll take care of it.
- [Tools Whirring]
- [Chattering]
- There he is.
- Hey!
H-H-Hey, I been
lookin' for you all day.
Don't know why the "helping out kids" angle
wasn't my first stop.
Hop in.
- I have something you're gonna wanna hear.
- I'll hear it right here, man.
What, I ain't forget what happened
last time I conferenced with you two.
I got you and the 4-H Club a new road
to heroin. You should take this ride.
Come on.
Let's go.
- Little Pop-
- Mm-hmm.
Los Mag O.G. -
he owes me a favor.
They got a Nogales
Customs agent on payroll.
Tar slips over
the Arizona border.
- Just a Sunday drive away.
- Antwon's beefing with the wetbacks.
That's why
we use the El Salvadorans.
That's where
the deal gets interesting though.
We know you were next in line
to be the One-niner don.
Antwon got sprung,
decided to reclaim his crown.
Things change, you know?
You wanna live,
you change with 'em.
Well, it's time
for another change, brother.
Those Mags are willing to work
with the new One-niner's boss.
That's you.
Ain't a smilin' matter.
Antwon keeps playing his Malcolm X games,
the heat's gonna cripple you guys.
Already is.
He doesn't give a shit
about the One-niners.
He was just using his old set
to climb back on top.
And you didn't
come up with him.
You got no loyalty to him.
Say what you gotta say, man.
I've negotiated a deal
between you and the Los Mags.
One condition...
Antwon goes away.
Clean, simple.
Look, he's beefin' with enough people.
It's an easy pin.
You step up. You earn your crew's respect
with this new product.
With Antwon gone, our captain,
she loses her hard-on...
P.D. backs off...
injunctions go away.
Brothers get back
to making money.
Everybody wins.
What you win, huh?
That little girl's body.
Mm-mmm. Nah.
/ don't need to be
the head nigger in charge, man.
Antwon-he can have
the limelight and the heat.
- I'm gonna pass.
- Come on, man. That's thinking like a pussy.
Nah. A pussy, that's someone who's willing
to off a partner to cover his own ass.
- We're not talking about that.
- Kill what partner?
Don't worry, Pablo, it ain't you.
Not yet anyway.
- [Chuckling]
- It's nothing.
Wha-Antwon wants you
to kill Mackey?
No, Antwon wants a lot of things.
The question is, what does this guy want?
I've got a deal on the table.
It's in your best interests.
That's your opinion.
/'m gonna tell Antwon we chatted.
- Come on. Where you going? We're still talking.
- You stay right there.
You better
control your boy.
- That's not the way to handle this.
- How do we do this, boss?
He downloads to Antwon, and we're
dick deep in dead girls and bullets!
- Yo, handle this shit.
- Hey, put it away.
Put the thing away. Okay?
The Los Mags think that
I've been dealing in your name.
- You back out of this, man, they're not-
- [Gunshot]
- l- l- I didn't mean that.
- Jesus Christ!
- I didn't mean it!
- That asshole shot me, man!
- What the hell are you thinking?
- That asshole shot me.
What's wrong with y'all?
Holy shit.
- Why didn't you tell me about Vic?
- Now's not the time.
- [Dispatcher On Radio]
6-Paul-24. 6-Paul-24. Come in.
- [Groaning]
- What the hell have you gotten us into?
- Shut up!
- Everyone, just shut up!
- 24, 6-Paul-
[Radio Turns Off]
Jesus.
All right.
Where's that little girl's body?
- I ain't sayin' shit!
- I can drop you at a hospital...
or I can let you
bleed out in the desert.
Where did Antwon put her?
Okay, fine. Fine.
Next stop, Joshua Tree.
[Engine Starts]
[Monica] We heard that your teacher
failed you for cutting class.
You think I slit his throat?
I'm half his size.
Everyone knows you busted
Hook and Cutter-10 already. I ain't scared of you.
We need to know who else
you've been talking trash about.
/f you've been shooting your mouth,
your goddamn lynch mob might go after them.
Why you ain't out
arresting Dynamite?
That nigga running girls
on a track.
Or my mail-lady-
she's running numbers, for Christ's sakes.
So, the code of silence
is for everyone else?
Everybody got their own code.
That's the only law out there.
Hmm. You all
just something to get around.
Well, you're not getting
around us today.
We're booking you for
conspiracy to commit murder...
reckless endangerment and anything else
that we can think of.
- Bullshit charges will never fly.
- We're supposed to let her walk?
- There's no law against trash-talkin'.
- She knew the climate out there.
She used it to get
a schoolteacher killed.
You'll never prove intent.
It's a loser.
She's tuned into what's going on out there.
We're not.
I am s-sick
of being blindsided by it.
I'm gonna move
into that house.
You want to drop yourself in the middle
of all that crap? Good luck.
The only way to be a real catalyst
for change is to leap in the mix...
show them you're
right there with them.
They won't give a shit.
Not at first.
Good work
closing this one.
Zerkow, how are we
on patrols tonight?
- Short. Why?
- Captain's moving into the hood.
- You're kidding.
- I wish.
Point of pride with her though.
She won't order up extra patrols for herself.
But we're gonna make sure
no assholes get any cute ideas.
- I'll put it in effect tomorrow.
- Thanks.
I'll look in on her tonight.
[Clears Throat] Heard you were right in
the thick of things out there.
Uh, I shouldn't have
broken that damn window.
It's bullshit
you couldn't be with us.
- Next time.
- Hey, um, Vic...
you wanna grab
a beer or somethin'?
- Big bust like that, I sure
could blow off some steam.
- I can't.
I got something with the kids,
and then a stakeout.
All right. Well, if you want some company
for the stakeout, give me a call.
I'm still a little wired.
Okay.
- [Shane] Wake up. Where is she?
- She's in the crapper on the right.
She's buried underneath,
wrapped in plastic.
- Jesus.
- Not only do you kill her,
you gotta shit on her too!
Methane helps hide
the death smell.
- [Horn Honking]
- Gotta get me some help.
- What time's this place shut down?
- /t don't shut down.
The-The shelter's
got guards 24-7, man.
- How we gonna get her out?
- / don't know.
- [Tires Screeching]
What are you doing?
- [Groaning]
- I send unis to recover that body...
you and Antwon will be
waist deep in shit too.
- You try to move it, I'll nail it in transit. Okay?
- [Grunts]
We can't just
leave him here.
You tell Antwon /'m done with his shit-
all of it.
He tries to come after us,
my family, or Vic...
I'll walk up to him
and I'll put a bullet in his head.
You got that?
Move. Get out of my way.
[Door Shuts]
I'm so sorry we can't-
[Indistinct]
[Rossetti]
What are you talkin'about?
Tomorrow night.
All right.
- [Knocking]
- [Radio: Pop]
Was that like you wanted?
[Gasps]
That's too hard.
[Gasps, Pants]
No! You're too powerful.
[Whimpering]
[Gasping]
No!
[Moaning]
/t's so big.
Hey, Detective, did you talk
to that guy who was looking for you?
- What guy?
- He said something about a mini-mart.
Uh, where is he?
You looking for me?
- You the one handling the gas station beatings?
- Yeah.
Yeah, that was me.
Y-You're here
to turn yourself in?
After I finish this,
I'll tell you all about it.
Take your time.
All I needed was one cigarette,
and then I'm good.
- If I buy a pack-
- Smoke 'em all.
So what happened
in the store?
This new idiot was working.
I told him the other clerk
always busts a pack for me...
but he wouldn't do it.
I told him.
I said, "I'm trying to quit."
I'm begging him-
"Show me some love."
But he wanted
to be an asshole, and...
I lost it.
[Breathing Heavily]
Just-Just one cigarette.
And $300.
What?
You stole $300
from the register.
Maybe now you can afford
the whole pack.
No. I came here
to admit my wrong.
I shouldn't have
hit that man...
and I'll take
my punishment...
but I'm not a thief.
Police intel's making
its way into the street.
I thought those slashings
was a little girl playing witch-hunt.
Yeah, they were.
But we never did find our missing C./., Angie.
We never determined who tipped off
that warehouse raid when D.E.A. was in town.
Sounds like
plain old bad intel.
I thought all you guys took cynical pills.
Are you I.A.D. or not?
At your service.
What's my cover?
/'m gonna put you in
as part of the Gang Task Force.
You'll be working
with Vic Mackey.
His name's run across our desks a few times.
You think he's involved?
No. But I need to prove
to someone that he's not.
l- I told you,
we don't have to decide tonight.
What's going on?
You need to take this.
You've been
hiding money from me?
This isn't
about ducking alimony.
I wanna take care
of my children.
Where did this come from?
Where did you get this?
The money's clean.
Just make sure you don't deposit more
than five grand every couple of months.
Do it.
- [Zipper Closes]
- Don't bring this in the house. I don't want it.
You want to drop the lawsuit,
get Megan into that clinical trial?
This is how you do it.
Use this for Matty.
I wanna go
kiss the kids good night.
- They're asleep.
- I'm not gonna wake them up.
Why did you have me
take Cassidy tonight?
Are you okay?
Nothing I can't handle.
I want to say good night
to the kids.
It feels like good-bye.
- Vic?
- [Door Opens]
[Door Closes]
[Sighs]
[Helicopter Whirring]
You're pretty quiet tonight.
Anything you want
to talk about?
Think the captain is dumb
or brave for doing this?
Gang Task Force was
a pretty good idea.
It sure as hell keeps me
from spinning my wheels out there, you know?
Thanks for putting me up
for that.
So, you wanna call it?
No.
Oh, Jesus. Come here.
[Mackey Moans]
Oh, yeah, like that.
[Moans]
[Moaning]
[Dutch] We just, uh, need
a few more details for your statement.
After the suspect ran out, how long
did it take you to get to the victim?
Uh, a few seconds.
Once the thief drove off,
/ ran in, found him unconscious.
Called 911.
[Dutch]
Uh, anybody else there?
I don't think so.
Place was empty.
- Probably why he robbed it then.
- Or why you robbed it then.
/ called this in.
Remember, guys?
You might be smart, but you're not
criminal smart. And you're a terrible liar.
I've never done
anything like this before.
You always need more.
Rent goes up. Alimony.
You feel so stretched.
And there was some cash
just sitting there.
- I'm really sorry.
- You're sorry you got caught.
/f you were really sorry,
you would have turned yourself in.
[Chuckles]
Come on. Who the hell would do that?
Shit! I can't get ahold
of his machine.
What the hell kind of plan is this?
We can't even reach Shane.
I don't feel right at all.
Part of me wants it to go down tonight,
get this all over with.
We can't let Vic go alone.
If Shane shows up, brings Army, it's two on one.
- I know.
- [Door Opens]
Hey, uh, where the hell's Vic?
I've been looking for him everywhere.
We haven't seen him
for a while.
- That's my cell.
- Yeah, watch commander found it.
- Thanks for the heads-up.
- Your phone was here.
What was I supposed to call?
Never mind.
Easy. It's the way
Vic wants it.
[Cell Phone Ringing]
- Yeah.
- [Shane] Hey.
Hey, I've been trying
to reach you.
Look, uh-
Look, I need your help
with somethin'.
Can you meet me?
Just you?
Yeah. Sure. Where?
[Train Whistle Blowing]
- [Car Door Opening]
- [Shane] Hey...
- thanks for coming.
- [Car Door Closes]
Uh-
Look, uh-
I'm in
some serious shit.
Hey. Hey, what the hell
are you doing?
- What the hell's the matter with you?
- Bugged your car.
It's you or me, right?
- I guess it's you.
- No. No, no, no. Look-
l-l-I'm explaining.
Pl-Please, l-listen to me!
Goddamn it. Listen to me.
Antwon killed Angie right in front
of me and Army. He did it with our guns.
That's what I came
to talk to you about!
I thought you had
nothing to do with Antwon.
That's nothing
that we haven't done before.
Look, he's squeezing us.
He says the body
will turn up if- if I don't-
But I would never do that.
Never! You know that!
Look, / was just bluffing him
to buy time.
Look-
We- We took a run at Halpern.
He showed us where Angie's body was,
but we can't get to it, just the two of us.
Army's gun went off. It-
Halpern's still alive.
But once Antwon finds out,
I'm dead.
/ got Mara and Jackson
out of town, but /'m-
Look, I'm-
I'm in trouble, man.
l- I don't know
how it got this deep.
You got one shot.
Take it.
No.
I would never
choose him over you.
We let that money train bullshit
get in the way, but you're-
- Come on. You're my friend.
- [Gun Cocks]
Look, I need you.
Will you help me?
[Gun Clicks]
[Train Whistle Blowing]
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Continues]
[Ends]