Carl and Scooby were murdered.
Stabbed to death in a sewer.
[Cop] Now Antwon cuts a deal
with D.E.A. andjust walks?
[Monica]
The deal was made behind my back.
- [Cop #2] That shithead killed two of us.
- / know.
I'm assured that Antwon's cooperation
will lead to numerous arrests.
[Cop #1]
Except the prick who organized it.
Should've put a bullet in him
when we had the chance.
The feeling is understandable, but / need
everyone to be professional in the street.
This is as painful to me as it is to you.
Hood's happy. Kill a cop,
cut a deal with D.E.A. and skate.
[Monica] The department's looking
into that arrangement.
We're gonna do everything we can
to make sure this doesn't happen again.
[Female Cop] So the ship's sailed?
Antwon's free?
And there's nothing
we can do about it.
/s it true that they're pulling the plug
on the seizure policy?
The policy's being discussed by Pol Com
tomorrow. No decision's been made yet.
We're dropping like damn flies,
and nobody's paying for it.
We are really hurting
and angry right now.
But we've got a job to do...
so let's do it.
We have got to undermine
Antwon's deal with D.E.A.
The same thought's
been ringing in our ear too.
What about Aceveda and Phillips?
You're hanging from a pretty thin rope.
Yeah, they disagree with me
about a couple of things...
but there's one thing
we don't disagree on...
and that's wanting to see Antwon
in a short stay on death row.
Even so, brass'll never sign off on us
undercutting a D.E.A. investigation.
That's why they can't find out about it...
until after we pull it off.
[Julien]
Help Danny through this trial.
Guide her, Lord.
Give her strength in adversity.
Oh, Jesus, Julien.
Amen.
- How you doin'?
- Oh, I'm okay.
/ just can't handle all the "Save her, Lord'"
stuff right now, you know.
Anyway, he already did, right?
Look, I was just waiting
for you to wake up.
I thought I'd say a prayer.
Well, as long as you're talking to the man
upstairs, just ask him for a Vicodin.
Thanks for your prayers.
I'll come back later.
I'll help you home.
That'd be great. Thanks.
Anything?
I checked into
Aceveda and Antwon.
Aceveda only visited
Antwon one time.
- No phone calls, no letters.
- Aceveda visited another inmate
before that though.
- Who?
- Juan Lozano.
- Who's that?
- You mean who was that.
The Byz Lat who grabbed Aceveda's gun,
then got busted by him for armed robbery.
- What happened to him?
- Took a 40-pound dumbbell
to the back of the head in County.
Bled out in his cell.
So Aceveda meets with Juan,
then with Antwon.
Antwon gets a deal.
Juan gets killed.
What the hell is up with that?
[Laughing]
What?
I heard you visited Juan Lozano
in County the other day.
Here's your doll. Go play.
I'll be right there.
Yeah, he's filed an appeal.
Claims that / forced his confession.
Oh, lucky for you
he had a little sports injury.
Somebody in County went
Mr. Universe on his skull.
Guy's dead.
We can't say
the world will miss him.
- Seems to have a lot of enemies.
- Especially you.
I've been going over the paperwork
for his arrest last year.
First he assaults you,
takes your gun.
Then you make the collar,
put him away.
Go visit him at County.
Next thing you know, he's dead.
Well, he's not the first person
to piss off the wrong inmate in jail.
Instead of rehashing the past, I was hoping
that you could help us with the future.
In what way?
Your boyJuan- He have a relationship
with Antwon Mitchell?
Maybe Antwon was
the inmate he pissed off.
Juan seemed pretty desperate.
He lost his juice up in Terminal Island.
Maybe he thought going after Antwon
would get him back his street cred.
Antwon found out and struck first?
/fJuan was bludgeoned after Antwon
made his deal with the D.E. A...
it could kill his immunity.
That's where you come in.
I'm sorry I ever
gave those guys a hand.
Then for Antwon to be responsible
for our cops' deaths.
Now maybe this Juan too.
Give me some time.
I'll look into it.
Nice to have you on board.
Bonilla? He's the solo gatekeeper
between U.S. dirt and El Salvador, man.
And old-school crazy.
You know, a technophobe.
No cell phone, no e-mail.
Everything gets
hand-delivered to him.
Now, I say everything.
I mean everything.
Shipments, distribution,
slaughter crews.
They all go through him
and him only.
That's why you guys keep
coming up with these dead-ends.
[Agent On Monitor] He's the only one
that deals directly with the cartel?
Here's the rest
of what we have on Mitchell.
- [Antwon] He's the /acocca.
- I hope it helps.
[Man] We could've sent
an agent over to pick these up.
/ wanted to see him for one last time
before you send him off to Shangri-la.
[Agent]
You know his full name?
I only know him as Bonilla.
Cat's got to be
about 50, 60 years old.
He's given us more in a day
than we got in a year.
But the deal's only good
ifhis testimony...
leads to arrests and convictions.
Only reason we do it.
It's gonna be huge.
They get the messages to him.
/ know it's painful.
You have no idea.
[Antwon]
This Bonilla is the key to 'em all.
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Ends]
[Car Door Closes]
/ just came from the D.E.A. safe house
where they're keeping Antwon.
Hope Mr. Mitchell's comfortable.
The key target he's giving up
is an El Salvadoran named Bonilla.
- Name ring a bell?
- No.
He's either lyin'...
or this Bonilla is way high
on the food chain.
So we got half a Latino name
in a city of four million Latinos?
We should rattle our boy Gusano. Shake
the Salvadorean tree, see if Bonilla falls out.
Yeah, this guy
is Antwon's biggest chit.
If we can take down that asshole first,
we'd blow Mitchell's leverage.
Then we could barter with the D.E.A.
Bonilla for Antwon. Straight up.
[Chattering /n Spanish]
- [Crashing]
- Let's go. Hands on your head.
- Get away from me!
- Shut up!
What the hell do you want?
We smelled smoke. Thought
the whole place might burn down.
- But since we're already here-
- Bullshit! Get outta here!
- Tear the place apart.
- You got it, man.
- Hey! Hey!
- Lookin' for a big fish named Bonilla.
- I don't know no Bonilla.
- Get the crowbars.
- Pull up every goddamn floorboard.
- You got it.
Hey, hey. Okay.
All right, look.
Check the flower store.
Eighth and Western.
- You babysit him.
- All right.
- We're gonna go check this out.
- Get him down.
Proud of yourself?
I stood up to Billings, Vic.
No more pranks or jokes since.
- Damn straight I'm proud.
- [Siren Wailing]
Men- doesn't matter
if they're five or 65.
- It's all about the pecking order
on the playground.
- You're just figuring that out?
- Wedding?
- Quinceañera, probably.
/t's a Latin coming-out party.
They present the girl as a woman
when she turns 15.
Get 'em while you can.
Well, looks like this guy got his.
- [Police Radio, /ndistinct]
- Everything was fine
until her boyfriend showed up.
- It wasn't his fault.
- He wasn't supposed to come.
- Papi told you.
- What's your boyfriend's name?
Alejandro.
My papi hated him.
He told Xylina to keep him away.
- Did Alejandro shoot him?
- No.
Then who did?
When my father saw her going
to the parking lot to talk to Alejandro...
he went over there
to tell him to leave.
There was someone else with him.
/ heard arguing, then the shots.
Did you see the other person?
Too many cars.
But she knows.
You're gonna protect the person
who murdered your father?
You're 15. You're
supposed to be a woman.
Start acting like one.
Unis are rolling up.
Captain said Bonilla was old.
Like 50 or 60.
These guys just got out of diapers.
Hey.
It's tar.
Where you from, ese?
Jalisco, Mexico.
- Mexico?
- Gusano humped us.
He sent us to bust his competition.
[Cell Phone Ringing]
- Yeah?
- Gusano sent us on a wild-goose chase.
- No shit?
- Yeah, he gave us some Mexican tar house.
- You still got 'em?
- [Speaking Spanish]
- Yeah. Hey, shut up.
- We're comin' back to have a little chat.
Hey, shut up! English only!
- [Speaking Spanish]
- Hey, sit down! Sit down!
- Lem, what's happening?
- Go ahead! Shoot!
- Sit your ass down!
- You'll never find Bonilla!
- [Shouting Continues]
- Lem? Lem?
Goddamn it! Sit down!
- [Gunshot]
- [Grunting]
- Shots fired. Hold it.
- Officer needs assistance.
[Grunting Continues]
Ah, bitch!
- [Tires Screeching]
- [Dog Barking]
- Hey, hey, hey!
- All right! All right!
Hey, Lem, you all right?
- All right?
- Yeah.
Where's Gusano, man?
- He got away.
- Hey, hey. Hey.
[Mutters]
[Sirens Wailing]
What the hell happened?
/t was my fault.
/ left him alone.
- Lem kicked some serious ass.
- You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
We got a lead
from our guy Gusano.
We left Lem here to watch him
while we checked it out.
He took down two of them,
but Gusano bolted.
- Way to take care of yourself.
- [Curtis] Thanks.
- What about the lead?
- Turned out to be bullshit.
You still think Gusano
can take us to Bonilla?
Emolia's a C.I. of mine.
She worked as an H-cutter
for a lowlife named Pitarrio.
He was our initial contact
for Gusano.
Hello. I'm Captain Rawling.
We've lost track of Gusano.
Any help you can give us finding him
would be extremely valuable.
/ don't know much.
/ talked to him on the phone.
Saw him a couple of times
when he stopped at Pitarrio's.
- How did Pitarrio get in touch with him?
- Called him.
- I never knew the number.
- Do you know anyone else connected with him?
Any friends? Associates?
Have you ever heard of a guy
called Bonilla?
/ met Gusano's girlfriend.
She knew / had a kid...
so I babysat for her
a couple of times.
- Where'd you babysit?
- At her place.
- Rosaria?
- Sí.
Get out. Get out.
[Rosaria Shouting /n Spanish]
- [Chattering]
- Clear!
- Clear.
- Looks like a little family vacation.
Hey, check this out.
/ found it by the phone.
Directions
to Industrial Discount Clothing.
It's off Rampart.
I shop there.
That explains a few things.
Come on, brother. Let's go get you
the arresting officer's discount.
¿Habla /nglés?
Is this where you're
gonna go meet Gusano?
No means yes.
[Claudette]
This must be horrible for you.
Your father killed
on your quinceañera.
Look, we believe you
when you say he didn't do it.
But he knows who did.
And if we can't clear Alejandro...
that makes your boyfriend
an accessory to murder.
But he didn't shoot him.
But he's protecting the killer.
Your boyfriend's friend
murdered your father.
My father tried
to throw 'em both out.
Why'd he have to do that?
It was my quinceañera.
Alejandro is scared,
and he should be.
He'll go to prison.
But if you don't mind waiting-
Twenty, 30 years sound good?
Boy's name is Miguel.
He's crazy.
Always on drugs.
Alejandro is not like that.
Gusano.
See if there's an entrance
in the back. Get outta here.
[Quiet Chattering]
- Police!
- Get on the ground right now! Get down!
- Get down right now!
- On the floor!
- [Grunting] Get off me!
- Bitch.
Dealing, concealed weapon,
dealing, dealing again. All kicked down.
Must have some powerful
connections, Gusano.
Somebody's payin' for the lawyer.
I guess they'll pick up the tab for you and
your idiots trying to kill a police officer.
You're lucky.
We don't want you.
Even luckier, you hook us up,
you can help yourself.
- [Scoffs]
- Look.
Let me talk to him,
man-to-scum.
Give us up Bonilla, I'll get
my guy to drop the charges.
We'll go our separate ways.
No one'll know we ever met.
Yeah, except /'m still out a key of tar,
thanks to you, puta.
You listen to me, shithead.
I did you a favor
by gettin' that tar back to you.
Whatever that crap was,
it wasn't tar.
I tried to pass that fake shit
down to one of my hookups.
Looked like I was trying to play his ass. I had to
kick him down with two keys to make it right.
So don't think I owe you a favor.
- Don't dick me around.
- You left me holding a pile of shit.
- [Door Closes]
- Gusano claims the dope we returned was bogus.
- Is that possible?
- Pitarrio sometimes had me thin out his supply.
- Not thin. Fake.
- / don't know nothin'about that.
- Gusano thinks I'm in on it?
- We'll keep you hidden.
Vic, check this out.
Gusano's phone.
All regular numbers.
No names. But look at these.
- They're coded.
- Yeah. Third grade code.
Instead of 213,
he's got 324.
Dipshit's adding one
to every number.
- Let me see that.
- Hey, Vic.
So I looked into this possible relationship
between Juan Lozano and Antwon Mitchell.
There's no connection.
Except you visited both of them in prison
the day Lozano was killed.
Look, Juan was killed before Antwon
made his deal, so there's no violation.
- So basically you got zero?
- Yeah.
Maybe I should do some digging
into what got this Juan killed.
Why do I get the feeling that you're
actually working another angle?
Maybe I should do some digging
to see what you're up to today.
If we can bust the main target
of the D.E.A.'s case, this Bonilla...
we can kill Antwon's deal,
get him to pay for Carl and Scooby.
I'm taking a chance telling you this...
but we may need you to help the feds
swallow the pill when the time's right.
And why would I want to assist
on an unauthorized investigation
that could blow up in our faces?
Why would / want to look the other way
on this weird Juan-Antwon-Aceveda triangle?
/ want Antwon for those murders.
Dig all you want.
I've got nothing to hide.
But /'m still gonna help you,
if you need it...
because I want justice
for Carl and Scooby too.
Either way, I'm good.
You got a lot of friends
in funny area codes.
434. That's Virginia.
324 doesn't even exist.
You better start talking,
or we're gonna call a few.
- Don't forget to subtract one from every number.
- Huh?
- Yeah, 324? That's really 213.
- Really?
434. That's really 323,
right here in Los Angeles.
Nicejob, wind talker.
If the Germans had you
in World War II...
we could've stopped that thing
before it started.
All right.
[Sighs]
Hello? Who's this?
Alberto?
This is Detective Mackey.
/'m at the station with your friend Gusano.
Yeah, he thinks you have some information
you'd like to share with us.
Hello?
Alberto doesn't care to share.
We keep letting our fingers
do the walking...
won't be long till we're talking
to Bonilla or one of his goons.
- You better think about helping us, quick.
- [Line Ringing]
Bonilla loves music.
- He's got a club on Eighth.
- That his corporate headquarters?
Place where he warehouses
his product?
No. Just hangs out there.
He loves music,
poppies, black whores.
Who doesn't?
[Curtis] Looks like a goddamn
Viagra convention.
Hangin' with the Depends crowd
keeps Bonilla under the radar.
If I get that low pro, tie off
my colostomy bag and call it a day.
Man, you're gonna be on wife
number what? Six by then?
- [All Laughing]
- Five.
This better be our guy. Antwon's
kissing fed ass, and we're losing time.
Hey.
Gusano says
he likes to burn coal.
With three hotties like that,
tell Santa /'ve been naughty.
[All Laughing]
[Chattering]
- Captain-
- Yeah?
We nailed the shooter in the quinceañera
murder. Kid named Miguel.
- Good.
- There's something else.
You're gonna want to hear this.
Kid's a pill freak. Found some scrip
bottles in his car when we picked him up.
All from the same place.
The foster homeJoya was assaulted in.
Was there a date on those bottles?
One of them's only a few days old.
According to Family Services, there's
some new kids in that house. Teenagers.
One of them goes to school
with our shooter.
That place was supposed
to be shut down.
What the hell
is Family Services doing?
- Anything else you need?
- No, I'm just gonna, um-
Thanks. Watch some TV
and probably fall asleep.
All right.
I'll check in later.
Hey, Julien.
Yeah?
/'ve been thinking a lot
about the head-butting...
and everything
that went on between us.
You know, with the injunctions
and the seizures and everything.
Now you're the only one
taking care of me.
You'd do the same for me.
I'm glad you know that.
Why are the Walkers
still supervising children?
Their foster care license
is under appeal.
They have a right to operate
until a final decision has been made.
We have criminal charges
pending against them.
Misdemeanor charges.
And they're presumed innocent.
Two months since that little girl...
had drain cleaner
forced down her throat...
one of their kids is selling
prescription meds out of that house.
When do you get mad?
Give me the name of the kid dealing,
and I'll handle it.
What I'll give you is notification.
We're seizing the Walkers' house.
- What?
- If you won't shut it down, I will.
- Isn't that a little bit out of your realm?
- Excuse me.
I'm done talking to you.
Round up some unis.
We're seizing the Walkers' house.
- I thought there was a moratorium on seizures.
- I'm making an exception.
They're having a meeting
about it tomorrow.
If you throw this in their face now,
it doesn't help your policy or you.
Well, this was the Walkers' second strike.
I'm not gonna give them a third.
So do it. I'll take the heat.
She's gonna hang herself.
There's nothing you can do about it.
We just have to be careful
we don't get caught in the middle again.
I'm not sticking my nose anywhere.
You know, if she goes,
they'll come to you to take over.
[Sighs]
They don't want me.
They'll get some company
yes-man jellyfish...
from outside that'll keep us all in line.
- [Chattering]
- Black Betty's taking a little stroll.
This hood-
We better protect her.
- [Bell Chimes]
- Hey, darling, how much for a blow job?
- I ain't no ho.
- Oh, no.
You just joined Grandpa's harem
for the free paella.
Aw, man, come on.
I just need a smoke.
Looks more like you need
a nap. What are you on?
- Nothin'.
- Sister's oozin' O.P.
- What you want?
- Bonilla. You been with him all day?
He in town.
I'm with him every day.
Anybody drop by his club,
tipping him off about the cops, huh?
- He don't tell me shit.
- I don't have time for this.
- [Retching]
- [Mackey] Oh, shit.
[Coughing]
God, are you all right?
There's some blood in that.
Looks like an ulcer.
- If you don't get that thing treated-
- It'll kill me. I know.
That's the plan.
Here's a new plan.
I'm gonna get the city
to pay for your medical bills.
We're gonna fix up your gut, and you're
gonna answer a few questions, all right?
[Coughs]
Please don't be screwing with me.
I'm not.
[Sighs]
One of his soldiers passed a message.
Really pissed him off.
You know, more than usual.
Something about the stuff
being moved to la cueva.
The cave. What's that?
Don't know. Just passed
on the message.
[Line Ringing]
Yeah, you still got Gusano?
[Monica]
Antwon gave up Gusano to D.E.A.
Lamberti and Phillips are taking
him away in about two minutes.
We only need him for one.
Get his phone.
You have time for one
phone call. Make it now.
Get Bonilla on the phone, now.
[Shane] Guy doesn't like to use
cell phones. Must be important.
"El assholé'" better talk fast.
Yeah, I got busted.
They think I'm talking
to my attorney.
They're asking me about la cueva.
So much for age and wisdom.
Shithead's going for it.
[Shouting /n Spanish]
[Shouting Continues]
[Spanish]
[Whistling]
- Shit! Spotters!
- [Shouting In Spanish]
[Shouting Continues]
- Go.
- [Gunshots]
- I'm gonna get Bonilla!
- [Shouting Continues]
Stop!
[Grunts]
[Shouting /n Spanish]
[Grunting]
Get your ass over here!
Get over here!
Shane, get it out!
- Hurry up!
- Damn it.
- Shit.
- Come on, buddy.
A little light reading for the D.E.A.?
Jesus Christ!
Shipping receipts,
distribution charts.
Pretty meticulous. We got names
from D.C. to San Salvador.
This'll put the Salvadorans
back two years. Nice work.
Number one on our most wanted.
Some coincidence.
Yeah, my guys were working a routine
sting, and they just stumbled across this.
And you just happened to nail the one
godfather with a Salvadoran Rolodex...
the one Antwon Mitchell's
been telling us all about.
Sometimes you just get lucky.
I'm taking him and those files.
Right after he gets processed
for attempted murder.
His guys took shots at my officers.
We'll also need to log
all that stuff into evidence.
You do that, his organization will
have time to learn about his capture...
and seal off the damage.
/ got him fair and square.
He's a goddamn whale to us.
You really expect that I'd let him go?
What do you want?
I want Antwon Mitchell.
I'll run it up the ladder.
[Police Radio, /ndistinct]
Cover things here. I'm leading
a seizure down the road.
What? What seizure?
The kid selling scrips from that abusive
foster home a couple of months back.
Pol Com's meeting tomorrow.
A seizure's the worst thing you can do.
We just busted Bonilla,
snagged Antwon.
I think I just bought myself
a little cover.
Or we can quit while we're ahead.
- Duly noted.
- [Engine Starts]
Again, nice work.
All right, come on.
Why do I have to go?
I didn't do anything.
- You sure about this?
- We busted the actual dealer.
A 14-year-old. Assigned to the house
three weeks afterJoya's rape.
You still have some doubts?
Glad you could make it.
I'm glad too.
You're out of control...
and now everyone can see that.
- [Child Fussing]
- I'll take these children now.
Oh, that scares the shit out of me.
These kids will end up
sleeping in my office tonight.
- Well, at least it won't be here.
- And now you've shut down this home.
Congratulations.
You think it's about
shutting down one home?
This system fails
thousands of kids every year.
This is about not putting up
with this shit anymore.
Cass?
What are you doing here?
Dad had to work late,
and I'm taking you home.
Grab whatever you need
and let's... go.
Hello.
We were studying.
We didn't hear the door.
- Who are you?
- Evan.
Nice to meet you,
Mrs. Mackey.
Where are your books?
What's going on?
I saw something when I went
to get Cassidy at your apartment.
- What?
- She was there with a boy.
Evan something.
He lives in your building.
It took them a long time
to get to that door.
- What were they doing?
- She says studying, but there were no books.
She's been lying to me lately, and when
she's not lying to me, she's shutting me out.
- You know what they say. Eleven's the new 13.
- No shit.
[Chuckles]
Your mom tells me
you had a friend over.
She makes a big deal
out of everything.
Well, that's her job, right?
Come on, Cass.
You know you're not supposed
to have anyone over there alone...
without Carmen or I there.
Let alone some cute boy, right?
We weren't doing anything.
Okay. Has he been
over there before?
No.
Who is he?
Evan. He lives in 3A.
His folks know he's been
over there studying?
He's cool.
Just like you.
- Me?
- Yeah.
Other kids like him, and he
doesn't take shit from anyone.
Cassidy...
no, no.
Y-Y-You understand there's more
important things to being a person, right?
Like being honest and trustworthy.
Someone caring about you.
I like him. Why did Mom
have to say anything?
She didn't get you,
and now she doesn't get me.
Stupid.
[Door Closes]
I had every reason to seize that house.
Neglected, unsupervised foster kids...
selling prescription drugs
that contributed to a murder.
/t's a P.R. win for us.
This isn't about seizures.
Then why the executioner looks?
The Department ofJustice
has been on the phone with the mayor...
ever since you twisted
D.E.A. 's arm to hand over Mitchell.
They're threatening
to pull federal funds...
for everything from law
enforcement to drug treatment.
I gave them Bonilla.
They got what they wanted.
You made them eat shit, and now
they're making the mayor eat it.
/f you think he's gonna let them yank
tens of millions of dollars from this city-
- I'll apologize.
- The D.E.A. chief doesn't want your apology.
He wants your job.
And now the mayor wants it too.
Pol Com's recommending
you be relieved of duty.
And the chief's decided
to act on the request.
And no one's gonna fight for me?
Cops watching each other's backs?
/ tried. / explained
the situation to my colleagues.
I got D.E.A.
to hand Antwon over to us.
But that's where myjuice stops.
So now you're letting
D.E.A. buy my job?
I'm sorry it ended like this.
You'll fight for me, right, Roy?
The chief too.
Because you know that
Farmington is better off now...
than when I found it.
Because the seizures were working.
Because I made sure
that Antwon Mitchell paid...
for what he did to our two cops.
I looked after them:
now you'll look after me, right?
I don't have much time.
What is it?
You were right
about the Strike Team.
Emolia, come in here.
Emolia's one of our C./. 's.
She's made money in the past...
by giving up tips
on Salvadoran runners.
Now, on the sixth of this month, she was
cutting "H'"for her dealer, Pitarrio...
when Detective Curtis Lemansky
had words with him, assaulted him...
and confiscated a kilo of tar heroin.
Now, those drugs were
never logged into evidence.
When was this reported?
Emolia called in
one of my colleagues immediately.
They were able to /.D.
Lemansky from her description...
searched his vehicle
while he was sleeping...
procured the heroin and replaced it
with a non-narcotic substance.
I thought you were Vic's C.I.
Whoever's got the money.
So you, uh, moving on Lemansky?
Not yet.
My boss wants to use this
to net the whole team.
Vic likes me and my boy.
He wants to take care of us.
We can use that.
I just lost my job.
This is someone else's problem.
[Door Opens, Closes]
You are gonna appeal, right?
If I lose, they take my pension.
I've had my run.
/ never got to put this up.
Carl and Scooby's.
Families said / could frame them.
Make sure this gets hung
in a place where everyone can see them.
I will.
Ma'am? Assistant Chief Phillips
sent us over.
We're to escort you
out of the building.
Hey, guys, she's a captain,
not a criminal.
- We're just carrying out our assignment.
- Well, not tonight!
We're waiting for Antwon Mitchell
to be remanded into our custody.
The captain has to make that arrest.
As long as it's not too long.
All right, Cass, get in the car.
I love you.
I gotta get back to Matt and Megan.
Are you done here?
Not yet. But everything's
squared away with Cassidy.
No more hangin' around
with boys in empty apartments.
I guess she listens to you.
Yeah.
Listen, uh, maybe she
should move back in with you.
Are you serious?
Well, she's gettin' to be that age.
She needs her mom.
This is because of what happened.
It's a lot of things.
She's gonna meet more boys,
other stuff.
You can keep an eye on her
better than I can.
- You're sure?
- Positive.
[Car Door Opens]
Thanks.
Antwon Mitchell...
you're under arrest...
for conspiracy
to commit the murders...
of Officers Carl Miller
and Wayne Haimes.
[Gate Closes]
Right over there is great.
- Okay.
- Thanks.
[Sighs]
I signed a six-month lease.
Only now, not only do
the neighbors not want me here...
neither does the department.
I guess that means you're staying.
[Sighs]
Yeah. Might be fun.
I like the place.
It was good working with you.
What's gonna happen to you now?
What do you mean?
I feel like I started
something with you...
but I didn't get to finish it.
Well, we got Antwon Mitchell.
Yeah.
You ever think about how
it's all gonna end up for you?
I'll take things as they come.
Promise me... you take a good
look at where you're going...
and you take care of yourself.
As long as you promise
to do the same.
Yeah.
Good luck.
You too.
- Wagenbach?
- Yes, sir.
Don't know if you heard what happened,
but your captain's been relieved of duty.
- Yes.
- We need someone to cover
in an interim capacity.
Claudette's the best person.
She's learned-
I'd like you to step up.
- Me?
- There's no guarantees...
but if it works out,
it could be permanent.
Uh, I'm sorry. I can't.
Not that I'm not honored-
flattered-
but, uh, I can't leave my partner.
I'm more valuable
to you on the street.
Well, I'd like you upstairs.
To be honest, if you think
I'm the kind of guy you're looking for...
you've made a mistake.
I'm sorry.
What was that about?
He asked me to be
the company yes-man jellyfish.
I told him to shove it.
Sometimes you have to take
the moral high ground.
One day you'll understand.
Uh, we're all heading over toJamie's...
to celebrate nailing Antwon
and closing Carl and Scooby's case.
Wanna join?
/'m sure we could all use a few.
[Country]
Dutch-boy!
[Indistinct]... in the hood.
I swear to God!
[Chattering Continues]
/t's Danny.
- [Cheering]
- All right!
[All Cheering]
Danny.
[Chattering Continues]
- You want a beer?
- Uh, no. I'm still on pain medication.
- Anybody got a glass?
- [All Laughing]
Hey, hey, get 'em up.
Get 'em up! Come on!
To Carl and Scooby,
a couple of good cops.
- Cheers.
- [Continues]
- [Chattering]
Do not fear!
[Chattering Continues]
Rent a room!
[Rock]
[Continues]
[Ends]