- [R& B]
- [Shane] Hey.
- Take a break.
- [Woman] Okay.
You ready?
Hey. Shh.
- /s Cromo strapped?
- [Man] Let's find out.
We'll let you take
the first round, sweetheart.
[Woman]
Yeah, he got a gun, and it's loaded.
How do you want
to do this, boss?
- Cuff'em to something outside.
- Got it.
Right here, ladies.
[Woman Moaning]
Yeah. Yeah.
- [Moaning Continues]
- [Pager Beeping]
[Man] This better be important,
stupid goddamn bitch.
[Beeping Continues]
It sure is, you stupid, goddamn bitch.
Let's go.
Let's go. Hands on your head.
Behind your head.
Right now. Come on, cornrow.
Let's go.
You okay?
Two minutes later, I would have
been doing a lot better.
Raping a minor- Doesn't that
break some pimp code of ethics?
Man, she bragged she was 18.
- You see she wanted it. It's like a Kobe thing.
- Yeah?
Well, it looks like you just lost
your endorsement deal.
Let's go, Kobe.
- What the hell happened, man?
- Oh, it's just a scrape.
I'll be okay. Hey, I miss you
and your guys coming in here.
I figured with all the free meals,
you'd be happy to get rid of us.
/ need a favor. Remember Cyril,
the kid that works for me?
Hasn't shown up in a couple of weeks
until this morning.
- He ripped off your payroll?
- Yeah.
/ tried to stop him.
He shoved me out of the way.
- He only got 30 bucks.
- He a rockhead?
Come on, Cal.
Only one thing that turns a good kid
into a thief that fast.
/ didn't want
to lead with that.
I was afraid you wouldn't want
to help if you knew about the drugs.
- Oh, and this one I should?
- I just thought maybe you could help me...
put him on the straight.
Excuse me.
There's a shipment here for you-
a bunch of Polaroid cameras.
Oh, uh, stack 'em
on that desk over there.
- Danny, right?
- Yeah. We haven't officially met.
Hi. Now we have.
- /'m Monica Rawling.
- So, can I ask what the cameras are for?
- David needs to push the transition meeting.
- Okay.
I didn't see any paperwork
for cameras.
You're leaving
with David, right?
Of course. Why?
No reason.
What are you doing
in here?
I'm, uh-
Uh, our- Our men's room doesn't work.
We all share this one.
- No, we don't.
- Yeah, we-we do. We ha-
You mean we don't share it with you.
[Chuckles]
Uh, there's somebody in there.
Hey, Dutch-boy's been promoted
to bathroom monitor.
- [Laughing]
- It's a shitty job, but someone's gotta do it.
- [Cops Laughing]
- Big man-pass these out to the unis...
17-year-old base chaser.
Anybody sees him, call me.
All yours.
I got a teenager on a drug tear-
friend of a friend.
Gonna track him down before he does
damage. I wanted to give you a heads-up.
You should tell your C.O.
- Like I said, I wanted to give you a heads-up.
- Like I said...
I'm not in charge yet.
Seriously, tell Aceveda.
All right, Social Services
is on the way...
sojust wait in the other room,
sweetheart.
[Groans]
Such a fine line, isn't it?
Amen, brother.
Book him with two of those
and pocket the other one.
That's currency on the street. We use
the blow to buy intel on the next asshole.
Hmm. You serious?
How do you think I got Night Train
to give up this place?
It's old school Vice, baby.
You use the world to bust the world.
Hmm.
All right.
Hey. It's all good
in the hood, brother.
[Chuckles]
I'm sorry, Nance.
The Mexican authorities
sent him back.
/ got the call this morning.
Can I help you?
Yeah. We're here
to I.D. Ben Gilroy.
You family?
Wife and, uh, friend.
Give me a minute.
How are the girls
taking it?
I haven't told them yet.
They can barely wrap their brains
around him leaving the first time.
- Yeah.
- [Door Opens]
Follow me, please.
Nance, you don't
have to see him this way.
[Scoffs] I just don't want
to feel sorry for the piece of shit.
Federales found him
with a bunch of fake Mexican I.D.'s...
and an expired
California driver's license.
Benjamin Wescott Gilroy?
- Shit.
- That a positive /.D.?
How did he die?
Take your pick.
Cirrhosis, malnutrition-
Official cause
was suffocation.
Aspirated on his own vomit.
Christ. This guy was the assistant
police chief? What happened?
[Sighs]
Take your pick.
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Ends]
Ha-yea. Pimp's in the barn,
and we havin'a hoedown.
- [Cops Laughing]
- Look, it's the Lord of the Vice.
Just here to brighten up your day,
you bunch of sad, little desk monkeys.
- Who's the cowboy?
- A guy I used to run with.
He jumped over to Vice,
Central Bureau.
Guessing by the look on your face,
it ended shit-side up.
Just haven't seen him
for a while.
How's that new partner
working out?
It clicks.
Well, I gotta get
back to this.
Yeah, get to it.
Cyril's got twoJuvie hearings pending...
one for crack cocaine,
and the other's for public lewdness-
getting head on a bench
in Griffith Park.
- The head attached to a name?
- She fled.
Cops got a description though.
Slight, blonde, piercings,
early 20s.
You know what?
I spoke
to theJesus-whacked mom.
Her address is different
than the one he gave...
when he got busted
in the park.
- Could be the blonde's place.
- Hmm.
[Sighs]
You know, it's strange,
the clubhouse being this way.
Yeah. Thanks for unsealing this.
/t's cool.
Hey, / heard about Gilroy. Damn.
Yeah. Burial's tomorrow.
Be great if you could make it.
I'm trying to give him
a decent send-off.
Is, uh, Shane going?
I don't know.
- [Siren Wailing]
- [Radio, : Dispatcher] 211 in progress...
- at Darmond Wash and Go, 612 Ames Street.
- [Shouting]
- [Julien] Tango 13, Code 6. Backup.
- [Gunshots]
- Don't move. Don't move.
- [Groans]
- [Officer] Second shooter ran out the back.
- Cover this.
- [Shouting, /ndistinct]
- [Speaking Spanish]
On the ground, now!
On the ground. Down!
Hang on. Okay.
Just stay still. Just stay still.
- [Radio Chatter, /ndistinct]
- [Groaning, Coughing]
I have an update
on the garage sting...
that I think you two
might want to hear.
- Who's that with him?
- Lewis Sperling.
Guy we flipped
to give us the sting.
Other than a few busts
in the first month...
our cameras haven't
turned up anything.
No major deals,
no major connections.
I can't control
what folks say and do.
[Aceveda]
You played us, Lewis-
set up another corporation
in your daughter's name.
That's a violation
of the terms of your deal.
I got two ex-wives,
five kids.
/ can't make a living
with you guys perpetually up my ass.
Maybe Mackey couldn't figure out
how you were end-running us...
but / did.
You tipped off
big-fish clients.
They gave you seed money
to start a new company.
You got your income back,
and they got a new place...
- to launder cash.
- Jesus.
How'd you miss this?
[Lewis]
/'ll give you more names...
from the new business.
- Bigger guys.
- / don't think so, Lewis.
It's over-
and now you're going to jail.
[Sighs]
Six months and thousands
of tax dollars pissed away.
At least now we know why.
- I dropped the ball.
- Little late for the humble servant routine.
I'll set up the collars
on the ones we have.
Make sure
it gets done right.
Oh, and you're
the man to do it right?
Just let him
fix the problem, okay?
Sir, there are two people dead
at that Laundromat robbery.
- One of them's an officer-involved shooting.
- Shit.
- What do we know?
- Two suspects, looks like a Hispanic male...
and a white female.
- Do we have a description of the shooters?
- Just the girl.
She's one of the D.O.A.'s.
Blonde, pierced nose, 120 pounds.
What?
This shooting might have something
to do with the kid that I'm looking for.
Your wayward juvie's tied in
with a 187?
If you're trying
to win me over...
it's not working.
Little Bonnie and Clyde shot and killed
the manager for $11 in quarters.
The boy got away.
Did you pull a name
and address on the girl?
- Hope Anthony, 9246 East Olympic.
- Goddamn it!
Problem?
You got that xerox of Cyril on you?
- Yeah.
- Okay, run it by the witnesses.
Hey, I, uh, think the other shooter's
this kid I've been looking for.
Unbelievable. You were putting cops
at risk by running this off the grid?
- I didn't have all the facts.
- Well, at least you're consistent.
Give the information
on the kid to Billings...
- and finish closing out the garage sting.
- Come on.
It sounded like you had something more
you wanted to share up there.
What if I did?
- Who are you?
- Captain Rawling.
Aceveda's on his way out.
I'll be deciding what happens in the Barn.
Well.
I got a name will spin
your pretty little head around.
Well, my pretty little head
doesn't spin that easy.
Who is it?
I want my deal
back in place.
No jail time.
That deal got flushed
with your corporate switcheroo.
You gotta put something real
on the table...
or the D.A.
won't even take my call.
No deal, no name.
No problem then.
- [Phone Rings]
- There he is.
- [Mackey] Yeah?
/t's me. / just messengered you
a package.
- Is it ticking?
- Sort of.
It's a class action lawsuit against the
Pyren Merril Pharmaceutical Company.
What's that got
to do with us?
Well, it claims that the rise in autism
is due to a vaccine preservative-
vaccines that both Matthew and Megan
got when they were two.
- That was right around when-
- I know, I know. Listen.
There's a deadline, and we need
to sit down and talk with the lawyer.
- Okay. How about tomorrow morning
when / drop off Cassie?
- Great.
I'll set it up
and I will see you then. Bye.
Armando Renta,
this is Vic Mackey.
Good to meet you.
Army's fresh off
a 14-month roll in "shock and awe. '"
Gave those sand pigs a little taste
of the red, white and brown.
- Mission accomplished?
- That's what they told us, so it must be true.
How do you like running
with Wild Bill?
Beats going door to door in Baghdad.
Now it's hick and the spic.
That's clever.
Can you give us a minute?
So, uh- So what's up?
I need to know who's running crack
in Ashmore Heights these days.
That's hard to day. Last few weeks,
someone's flooded the market.
Every pusher in the hood's rock-heavy,
scrambling to unload product.
- Since when do you need help powder tracking?
- You hear about Gilroy?
What, is he back in town?
Yeah. Spilling his guts
at the morgue.
Drank himself to death.
They're gonna bury him tomorrow.
- You should be there.
- I wanted the guy dead.
Well, you got your wish.
It's about his wife
and kids now.
Are you forgetting he threatened
your family? He hung you out to I.A.D.?
Money and pussy make man
do evil shit.
Before all that,
he was a friend.
Some bodies in blue
should show respect.
I'll see if I can
shake myself free.
- So we, uh-We done?
- I, uh-
I got some worries about what I saw
over at Dead-Eye's the other night.
Well, stop worrying.
Dead-Eye was about to start
C./. duties for me...
tracking Antwon Mitchell's new game-
till someone tapped his mute button.
Now I'm watching Antwon.
So if you got
any kind of relationship-
I got no relationship with him.
Then I got no problem.
[Army]
Everything cool?
Yeah, it's all good.
All right?
Gonna take two, maybe three days
to lay a new piece of pipe.
Get started. I want
to hear flushing in 48 hours.
- What's going on?
- Having the men's room repaired.
I didn't fix the men's room 'cause it
would have chewed up 35% of our budget.
That's my worry now.
Plumbing crews, cameras-
Either you're completely naive
about our financial constraints-
which I doubt-
or you've got something planned.
[Sighs]
I'm instituting seizures-
across the board.
Cars, houses, businesses,
anything drug- or gang-related.
- Asset forfeiture? The chiefll never go for that.
- He's already signed on.
- Pol Com too.
- Citizens here can't afford lawyers...
- to fight seized assets.
- I'm not worried about pissing off dealers...
'cause we swiped
their pimp rides.
We're gonna target
the right people.
And you're thinking
of using Mackey for this?
I'm still deciding.
I mean, your letter made him untradable.
I have to use him somewhere.
Keep him parked inside.
Anything else is dangerous. Trust me.
Appreciate your input.
[Plumber]
/ need a signature to start the work.
- So why is this the first /'m hearing about all this?
- Oh, it happened fast.
Thanks.
Anyway, after tomorrow, it's...
mine to win or lose.
She was unconscious
when they brought her in.
Fishnets, Spandex- I don't think
she was out walking her dog.
- Hooker rape?
- The name she put on her form...
was Olive Martini.
This is the only thing
that she had on her.
- Ralphs card. That's official.
- She's in six.
I'll go see if she's
shaken or stirred.
You know what? Test results aren't
gonna be in till this afternoon.
- I usually, uh, grab a taco across the street.
- From Rullio's?
We treat at least four cases of food
poisoning a week from that place.
/t's got an "A '"
in the window.
- Stands for "acute gastritis."
- [Claudette] Did you say Room 6?
Olive has left the building.
[Dutch]
Okay.
James has got a family friend.
Thinks you two would hit it off.
Really?
She does public affairs work.
Smart.
- For some reason she likes cops.
- What's she look like?
Petite, dark-skinned,
attractive.
She's black?
Never mind.
- [Beeps]
- What?
I dated a black girl
in college.
Quarter black, but, I mean,
you could definitely tell.
Forget it. What's on
the raped hooker's grocery card?
[Stammering]
No address, bogus phone number.
Hey, ifJames thinks
we should-
- What hooker?
- Paramedics took her over to Mission Cross.
She was beaten,
sexually assaulted.
Gave a fake name
and disappeared.
Did you have hospital personnel
go through the mug books?
- No.
- Where did the attack happen?
We don't know yet.
Is there anything
you do know?
Last week she bought three gallons
of Chablis and 11 boxes of condoms.
/f she's pissed off a pimp,
her life could be in danger.
Why don't you see
if anyone's called it in to 911.
[Dial Tone]
Transport's running late.
You'll miss lunch call
at County.
You think my price
is a couple of candy bars?
Maybe you think better
on a full stomach.
I'm thinking fine.
I called the D.A.
They won't budge
without a name first.
- Looks like we got ourselves
an old-fashioned stalemate.
- Yeah, I guess so-
except I'm going home
to a warm bed tonight.
You go home to them.
[Claudette]
The 911 call came in from a pay phone...
- outside a Korean bakery.
- They were robbed 11 times last year.
They installed
state-of-the-art surveillance.
Cameras picked this up
early this morning.
- [Moaning]
- [Grunting]
We have the face
of our victim.
And the back
of a rapist's head.
Make some dubs of that tape.
The D.A. 's gonna need a copy.
And let me know
when you locate her.
- [Antwon Speaking, /ndistinct]
- Yo.
- What are you building, Antwon?
- Are you here to pitch in?
Forgot my tool belt at home.
Still got my cuffs though.
House was in foreclosure.
Crackheads took it over, so we took it back.
Help the owners
get back on their feet.
M.L.K. toJimmy Carter.
You got all your bases covered, don't you?
I got work to do, man.
Hey. We're looking
for this kid.
Put the word out
to your dealers.
Give me a heads-up
if he tries to score.
I run a rec center.
Just because you
pound some nails...
into some poor slob's house
doesn't mean shit to me.
We both know you run drugs,
not a rec center.
All right.
My next step,
I start sweating the slangers.
Those pussies always give up
chain of command.
- / want to eradicate the crack
epidemic as much as you, man.
- [Phone Rings]
- But my relationship to dealers-
- Hold that lie.
- Yeah?
- [Whispering]
Beauty. Hang on.
Lem may have a lead on Cyril's drug dealer.
That gives you 20 minutes to find me
a shortcut to this missing kid...
before I start twisting
the truth out of his dealer.
There he is, on the black bike.
Right there. Pull over.
- [Siren Blares]
- [Man] Cops.
- You little dick!
- [Tires Screeching]
[Man]
Go, Jaymon.
[Voice Amplified]
Park the Schwinn, shithead.
This is why you should
always wear a helmet.
[Grunts, Groans]
Damn!
[Panting]
- Where'd he go? Where?
- Ran out the back.
Psst.
Hey, put that shit down.
Aw, goddamn it.
He swallowed it.
Shit.
Come here.
[Gagging]
- Goddamn.
- [Retching]
Did you sell to him?
Did you? Did you?
Know what?
Seems a little bound up.
He bought a crumb from me a couple
hours ago. Asshole paid in quarters.
- Where is he now?
- / don't know. / never sell to him before.
- Bullshit.
- He ain't a regular.
That's the truth, man.
I swear to God, man.
- I swear. I swear.
- Get on your feet.
Hey. Clean up, aisle four.
You're really gonna set up
your office down here?
I feel more at home
on the floor with the grunts.
You know, for someone
who's supposed to be observing...
you sure are
awfully active.
I saw you chatting
with Lewis Sperling.
Just trying to talk some sense
into him while he's still ours.
I closed down
the garage sting.
You know, your instincts,
six months ago, were right.
It's got great potential.
It just took a wrong turn.
It's been compromised.
It's dead.
The A.G.C. angle, yes...
but the new business
that Lewis set up is untainted.
You got a good system in place.
We own the spyware.
We get the bugs in the cars,
we're back in business.
Yeah. You don't have
the authority yet...
to be interviewing suspects,
getting the goddamn toilet fixed...
or overturning my decisions.
So until you're actually
in my office...
- observe.
- [Drawer Slides Shut]
[Door Buzzes]
That the kid you almost choked out
with a bottle of mustard?
- Who ratted? The condiment weasel?
- [Curtis Laughing]
Kid's a novice. He was swallowing
open jums of crack.
I induced vomiting.
Saved his goddamn life.
I'm still allowed
to save lives, right?
I want a complete report.
Oh, sure. Have one for you
day after tomorrow.
Oh, that's right. You'll be gone.
I'll mail one to you.
We can't post these
in the Barn.
Looks like the department
sanctioned people to attend the funeral.
It's just a flyer.
Cyril forged you this check
from his boss's restaurant.
This bounced, man.
Kid didn't even write this anyway.
It was this blonde T-girl.
She said she worked there.
- Is this her?
- Shit.
- That's her?
- Yeah.
- [Curtis] She's a tranny?
- She tried to blow me to cover it.
I ain't down with that
chicks-with-dicks shit, so I said no...
and she came with the check.
Where did he-she
score from you?
- I ain't saying no more.
- You saw what I could do with a bottle of mustard.
You imagine me
with the butt of a gun. Huh?
- Underhell.
- "Underhell"?
Under the tile factory,
by the freeway.
All right, thanks.
Coroner just confirmed it.
Hope had a rope.
Here we go.
- [Man] Turn the lights off.
- [Mackey]Jesus.
[Man #2]
/t's the cops.
- There!
- [Ronnie] Gun.
[Gun Clicking]
Hold on! Hold your fire!
He's dry firing. The gun's empty.
Cyril, drop the gun, kid! Cyril!
Cyril, put the gun down, kid.
All right, Cyril, that's it.
It's over. Come on.
- [Sobbing]
- On your feet. Get up.
Come on, kid.
Look, I done
nothin' wrong.
I don't know why Barbie and Skipper
hauled my ass down here.
[Dutch]
They found you tricking.
We just wanted to know
what happened to you.
Yeah, like you're real concerned.
[Scoffs]
/ was walking to the market.
Someonejumped me. Woke up in the E.R.
We have security tape
that shows the assault, Olive.
- Then go arrest the prick.
- We can't identify him.
Me either then.
Hey. Olive's prints
came back.
Real name, Olivia Kenshaw.
She's mapped, restricted
from the zone where she was raped...
and she's H.I.V. -positive.
How long have you
been tricking sick?
I don't know. Ten months?
Risk is hype.
Make all my customers
strap up.
[Claudette]
What about the guy who raped you?
- Was he using a condom?
- He wanted it, he got it.
- What about all the innocent people
he could infect?
- Please.
They should all die
sore and ugly.
Wejust need
his name or description.
And I just need a pussy
ain't so stretched.
You've been mapped
with H.I.V., Olivia.
State considers that
attempted murder.
You'll do real time.
[Claudette] Do you know how hard
it is to get the cocktail inside?
If I give him up, I want
the other charges dropped.
- / could ask the D.A.
- / want some kind of guarantee...
and I want it in writing.
The D.A. will never go for it. She's got
a four-page sheet, mapped with H.I.V.
You mean the D.A. will never
go for it because it's our case.
Well, that doesn't help.
- I'll go play good cop.
- I already played good cop.
I'll play better cop.
What's that about?
- Captain-hooker confidentiality?
- [Chuckles]
- So, uh, what's James's friend's name?
- Forget it.
You know, just because I asked if
she was black doesn't mean I'm a racist.
And there are plenty of sisters
I think are hot. Halle Berry.
Uh, Tyra Banks.
Beyoncé.
- [Laughing] Jesus.
- What?
Cyril! Who put you on the rock, Cyril?
Who's your main score?
- Fat Benish.
- Where can I find Fat Benish?
Where, Cyril?
Above Pip's Quick Lube.
[Phone Beeping]
Ronnie, Cyril's dealer
is a cat named, uh, Benish.
He lives above
the Quick Lube on Hauser.
Get a warrant.
- Is he making sense yet?
- He's pretty doped up. He's detoxing.
Cop downstairs said it was the other shooter
that killed the woman at the Laundromat.
- That clears Cyril, right?
- He was part of the robbery.
- Makes it his murder too.
- He didn't know what he was doing.
It's that shit rock. What about
the guy that sold him the crack?
I'm taking care of his dealer.
Look, he's gonna be asleep
for a while.
Why don't you go home,
get some rest?
I want to be here
when he wakes up.
- I think you're in a lot of pain.
- I don't need pity.
Not pity.
Compassion.
Even if you don't think
you're worthy of it.
We're guilty
of perpetuating that-
- letting the streets take care of themselves.
- Got that right.
- Can you tell me what happened?
- You seen the tape.
I did.
And I am so sorry.
He was at the end
of an all-nighter.
Paid for a suck.
Got me in the back alley.
Threw the first punch...
before I could hit my knees.
It was all about the hurt
with this guy.
Hey.
I see you got
our ho basket.
[Army]
Nice addition to your stable.
Don't know if they
worth a thing.
[Coughing]
[Shane]
Let me tell you how this works.
You and the syphilis brigade,
you see anything, you hear anything-
new players, new product,
anything happens on the street-
I'm your first call.
Got that?
- All right, Venus, you come with us.
- What for?
To suck his big Latin dick.
[Laughs]
Hey. This ain't for real.
It's the only way to establish dominance
with these slit-mongers.
Tail's the only currency they know.
- Then let her suck you off.
- Come on, man, I'm married.
Look, you got an E.D. thing
happening, just say so.
- Blow me.
- I'll let her. Come on, sweetheart.
Just sit back and relax, all right?
Enjoy the ride.
You getting some back-alley Clinton
is really gonna help the cause.
- Two's a mouthful, three's a crowd.
- Yeah.
Man, Venus is going at it like
she's taking the rust off a low-rider.
That's some
Boss Hogg bullshit, man.
- Let's talk percentages.
- Percentages?
Yeah. Keeping you
and your girls out of lockup...
is gonna require
additional man hours.
That's gonna cost you 10%.
- That wasn't part of the deal.
- Make no mistake. There's no deal here.
This is you doing what I say...
or else you getting a cap
in the back of your ear...
in something we like to call
"the line of duty."
Now sit back down.
If you're dicking us around again,
not only won't you get your deal...
we'll make sure
you do your time in Solano.
Warden's a friend of mine.
You think the inmates are bad?
- Wait till you spend some happy time
with the guards.
- [Chuckling]
Alex Kozodav.
The taxi king?
[Mackey]
Old-school Russian mob.
Any other cab tries to pick up
a fare in Farmington...
both car and driver end up
stolen and chopped.
[Lewis] Ever since
the Armenian money train gotjacked...
the Russians have been looking
for another place to launder their cash.
And you've been more than willing
to help, for a fee.
I'm also putting radios
in his cars.
You ever see
Taxi Cab Confessions?
Kozi cabs are the Russians' favorites.
A lot of potential marks.
I'll see if there's a deal
to be made.
Signed, sealed,
and deceitful.
Bring him in,
you can release her.
Bust her again,
it's attempted murder.
- Make sure she's clear on that.
- Got it.
Thanks for running
interference for us.
- My pleasure.
- Another win for Billings.
Okay, Olivia, let's take a look
at some of our mug shots...
of known sexual offenders.
He's white.
Pierced tongue.
Delivers pizza.
There's one of those Pizza Shack things
on the top of his car.
I just talked with Lewis.
Apparently his ride left
without him.
Lewis's name.
- "Alex Kozodav."
- L.A. boss, Russian organized crime.
This guy's on everybody's
top-ten list.
The D.A. wants to play ball.
/ think you are making decisions
to settle a grudge-
decisions /'m gonna
have to live with.
These property seizures
that you want to impose-
who's gonna have to live
with those decisions?
l-I could have let Lewis get lost
in the system for a couple of days...
taken the credit
when you were gone...
but you've earned this.
I figured we could present it
to the chief together.
I'll take a look at it.
- [Tires Screeching]
- Shit!
God!
Somebody torched
Benish's place.
God!
Hey, Chief.
- Hey, I got a warrant to search upstairs.
- Pretty hot in there right now.
Yeah, I'm aware of that.
Any way of putting it down?
I doubt it.
We've already lost the top floor.
All right. Thanks.
- Hey! Who owns the bikes?
- [Man] Fat guy. He lives there.
- You sure?
- You don't forget a 300-pound dude
on a scooter.
Check the plates.
[Olive Screaming]
- Oh, man.
- [Mackey] What's the matter, fat man?
- You got insurance, don't you?
- Yeah, I'm in real good hands.
- Too bad about your little crack factory upstairs.
- What's that smell?
- Oh, yeah. You got smoke.
- [Laughing]
I ran the VI N numbers
on your scooters.
Stolen the same night
six other bikes got jacked.
I got grand theft.
Antwon Mitchell-
he the one filling
the cesspool with new rock?
Rumor is Mr. Mitchell's walking
the straight and narrow now.
Oh, it's gonna be hard
maintaining that edge in the joint...
when gen pop finds out you
the little red scooter bandit.
- There's been a crack flood 'cause
everybody's dumping what they got.
- Why?
It's getting pushed out.
Crack's bad business.
Cluckers all crazy.
Die fast.
Strip a hood
of its potential.
Pushed out for what?
- Tar.
- Heroin?
Sleepers hold a job.
Less crime, less heat. Everybody wins.
Antwon the one
enforcing that mandate?
That part of his
community salvation?
- Ain't no salvation here.
- [Phone Rings]
- Yeah?
- [Shane] Looked into Ashmore.
Niners used to have
the lion's share...
but since this new product
hit town, it's real messy.
That ain't new product.
It's old.
Street's dumping all their crack
to make way for tar heroin.
- Who told you that?
- A guy with weight.
I'll see you.
Try to make it to the funeral.
Vic, inspector says
it started with a grease fire.
- What, engine grease?
- Cooking grease.
Shit.
[Mackey] How many more pictures of this kid
am / gonna find if / start opening drawers?
What are you talking about?
I care about him.
Guy dealing to Cyril-
his place got torched tonight.
Fire was started
with cooking grease.
You're not
a very good criminal, Cal.
I smell the smoke.
Please don't make me search the place.
- You screwing this kid?
- Don't say that.
Are you?
He slept here...
but I never laid a hand on him.
He wanted to get the operation
when he turned 18.
/ told him /'d pay for it.
We were-
We were gonna be together.
Jesus Christ!
I'm sorry.
l- I know it was wrong.
You could have hurt someone
setting that fire, Cal.
Nobody was home.
That dealer took away...
the only thing I love.
You know what that feels like?
You know
what that feels like?
[Weeping]
Call a lawyer.
When the detectives come,
don't say anything.
Get rid of the photos.
The dresses too.
[Man]
Thimerosal has been used...
as a vaccine preservative
since the '30s...
- even though it's 49% mercury.
- Which is extremely toxic...
especially with children
under three.
And you think this mercury
in the vaccine is the missing link?
Yeah, the increase
in the rate of autism...
parallels the rise
in Thimerosal exposure.
It's all broken down
in the science there.
They're just figuring
this out now?
Look. Forgive the hard press, but the statute
of limitations is running out on Matthew.
You have only three years from
the time of diagnosis to file a suit.
Okay.
There's no legal fees, Mr. Mackey.
We only collect if we win the case.
But expert witness costs are expensive-
$10,000 to $15,000 per child.
Jesus.
Yeah. Well, you got a lot
to think about...
so why don't you take some time
and let me know what you decide.
I know someone should pay.
[Aceveda]
And that's it.
/ can't think of anything else
/ need to tell you.
You seem to have strong opinions
on how you want to do things.
Okay.
Well, we can tell the bosses
we had our transition meeting.
Thanks.
Oh, there is one more thing.
I spoke to Chief Bankston.
He seems to be excited at the prospect
of netting Alex Kozodav...
so the garage sting
will stay up and running.
- Did my name come up?
- Oh, / don't believe so, but Vic's name did.
Chief wants him running the project,
which keeps him on a tight leash.
You'll thank me for that.
[Bagpipes: "A mazing Grace'"]
[Woman Weeping]
Sorry for your loss.
Excuse me.
- You didn't have to come.
- I knew Ben a little... in better years.
Yeah, me too.
Puts everyday bullshit
in perspective.
I told Aceveda
about Kozodav.
He went behind my back,
got the chief pregnant on the idea.
Took credit,
covered his ass.
He also convinced the chief
that you should still run the sting.
- Means I gotta find someone else
to head up the task force.
- I can do both.
Look, Ronnie knows the drill.
He can handle
the garage stuff.
Put me back
on the street with the unis.
Nobody knows the bangers
better than I do.
Please.
Put me somewhere
where I can make a dent.
The only way
I can sell that to the chief...
is I give Internal Affairs full access
to the Barn- open house.
- Means you can play hard, but-
- I get it.
I.A.D. gets a whiff
of anything dirty...
near these seizures-
me, this policy, everything-
it's dead in the water.
I'll do it right.
Okay.
Go in the car. Go on.
I know that, uh, you're the one
that got this turnout.
- Means a lot to my girls.
- He was my oldest friend.
You doing okay?
I hope he was scared...
and alone...
and in a lot of pain.
- He had his demons, Nance.
- He had a dick he couldn't keep in his pants.
Threw away 20 years
on the job.
He shit all over this family.
[Continues]
[Punk Rock]
That goes right there.
Thanks, Stephens.
Have a gumball.
- [Continues]
- [Chattering]
[Chattering]
[Toilet Flushes]
[Radio: Song Continues]
We gave you Cromo
and his underage hit...
but the girls, that was Antwon
paying back a favor.
Now you, you taking a piece,
that makes him look the fool.
Yeah? Well, you tell
the great reformist...
- that's the cost of doing business.
- Doesn't work that way.
What doesn't work
is me finding out secondhand...
about dealers dumping crack
to make room for tar.
I don't know nothing
about that, man.
Of course you wouldn't.
You're just
a slow-witted bitch.
What?
Shit!
[Man]
Just relax, police man. Chill.
/t's just a beeper.
/t's just a beeper, all right?
From now on, it's me and you
face-to-face or nothing at all!
You got that?
[Continues]
- [Ends]
- [Applause]
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Continues]
[Ends]