Previously on The Shield...
I have an attorney
for you.
I'm Becca Doyle.
If everything hinges
on her,
I'd be a fool to
give up that hammer.
Just like you were foolish for
letting me know how important she is
to making your case.
You're looking
for more business?
Right now I'd like to go home
and wash this place off.
Has anyone from the
department come around
asking any
questions?
Someone has been
asking questions.
He said he was a parent
of an autistic child.
That him?
Yeah.
Pittario,
where's your stash?
About 6 months ago,
we found this kilo
of pure heroin
in the glove compartment
of your car,
but you never logged it
into evidence.
Lem got picked up
by IAD.
Got him
wearing a wire.
I'm going after Mackey
and his team.
And I'm going to be right here
to make sure you don't blow it.
We got to see our next
moment. When he jumps dirty,
we'll know.
Here.
It's OK.
I'm on the clock.
I thought you were
Vic's CI.
Whoever's got the money.
Check 1, 2,
check 1, 2.
Good. It's good.
Hey, I need admissions
from Mackey and the others
on crimes they committed,
all right?
Questions make cops
suspicious.
You walk out of the room
every time he opens his mouth
to say more than
good morning.
You think I haven't
noticed this?
I'm just doin' my job,
all right?
Vic and I aren't
attached at the hip.
Well, then get attached!
'Cause you're
dragging this out,
trying to have it
both ways.
You're torturing yourself.
You made a choice.
It was the right one.
And now you got to start
living with it.
Hold on a second, OK?
One second.
L... I know it's your birthday.
You mentioned that
you're a fly Fisher
on one of the tapes.
Thanks.
We're going to be working
together for a while
and I just thought, you know...
I know this is tough.
But we're both going to make
our way through all of this.
All right?
Yeah.
I would've pegged you
for a corner office.
First time a police officer's
stepped foot in here.
I've got a case
that'll interest you.
My schedule's full
and I've been finding
my own cases since I was 30.
Not like this one.
5 minutes.
Everything
I'm about to say
falls under attorney-client privilege.
Yeah, but it doesn't
obligate me to take your case.
IAD's launched
an investigation
into one of the guys
on my Strike Team.
I don't represent cops.
Especially corrupt ones.
We're good cops.
This is about the system
turning its back
on 4 of its own.
You'd be better off
going somewhere else.
You shuffle gang bangers
in and out jail all day.
This is a chance for you to
take a shot at the big boys.
What do they
have on him?
Claim they found a brick of tar
in his glove compartment.
It's bullshit.
What else?
The only thing
I know for sure
is that they're going
after my whole team.
Guy named Kavanaugh
is in charge.
I'd dig into it myself, but it
would raise too many red flags.
Now there's the first
real truth I've heard.
You want to keep your knowledge
of the investigation secret,
and no one would suspect
I'm working for you.
So we agree that
you work for me then.
I've got an old boyfriend
in the city attorney's office.
I'll ask a couple questions.
But that's it.
Next thing I knew
she was laying there.
Fiji, Barbados... all those
tropical vacation places,
you're talking typhoon.
Just looking out
for you.
Look out
for the tape.
Angle looks car-to-car.
Bumper's got a dent.
Could be fresh.
Maybe there's an incident
out on the road,
someone in the other
car shoots,
victim veers off here.
Oh, Christ.
Get additional units
down here.
Tell Danny
I said now.
Umbilical cord.
TAPA BOCA
Then get me a witness,
a description of the
other car. Something!
If they wanted the child,
why risk pumping the mother
with bullets?
Someone wanted it
to look random.
Maybe the boyfriend.
What do we know about him?
Works nights
in a machine shop.
Hasn't been home
since the murder.
I've got unis
stationed at the house.
Vultures are gathering.
I'll get rid of 'em.
Wait, wait. No, no, no.
Let's use them.
Somebody
knows something.
We just need to pull
the right heartstrings.
All right. Good. You
keep working. I'll do it.
Wilshire's not giving us
any bodies for the search team.
Not if we can't prove
the baby's alive.
That's bullshit!
Call again.
No. I'll call.
Who would do something
like this?
What'd the ex
have to say?
Absolutely nothing.
And I called a couple
adas I went to school with...
quiet on all fronts.
Good.
Not good.
None of them offered
to look into it for me,
which means they know
something major's in motion.
What haven't you told me?
David Aceveda's name
come up with your friends?
The city councilman?
He's assisting Kavanaugh
in this investigation.
Why?
Because he used to be
captain here.
He had me pushing the
legal line a couple of times
when it meant getting
a killer off the street,
making him look good
to the voters.
Overseeing the investigation means
he can steer it away from himself,
make me and my guys
play the heavies.
Starting to get your
blood running yet?
I'm interested in the true story of
this heroin they caught Lemansky with.
What does he say
about it?
I haven't been able
to ask him.
IAD's got him
all wired up,
listening to our
every word.
Well, they wouldn't
make that move
unless they had a witness
or corroborating evidence.
I'll find out what I can.
Good.
Me, too.
So the kid's about,
well, uh... here.
Right?
The knife goes in,
goes straight down,
got to be careful
about the depth.
I'd say it's intuitive.
You wouldn't need
medical training at all.
So tell the newshounds
we're not looking for einstein,
just a garden-variety
psychopath,
possibly a woman.
Usually it's a woman
who's recently lost a baby
or who's been claiming
to be pregnant.
I'm never going
to be able to sleep
until I have
this kid.
Yeah, I'm here.
You're not going to get
any sleep then, either.
Thanks. 911 received a call
at 5:17 this morning
from a payphone
one block from the scene.
They hung up.
That could be
our line to the baby.
So how
we gonna find them?
You've got to convince them
to come to us.
Need another cup?
Two should do it.
We on that
missing baby yet?
No. Dutch and Claudette
are handling it.
Captain wants us
available to round up
all the other
miscellaneous sickos.
Listen, I'll
be back in a few.
I gotta take a dump.
Smells like
you already did.
All right. 5 minutes to hear
what's going on with Kavanaugh.
Every detail.
He suspects
I'm protecting you.
All right? I've been helpful,
but not too helpful.
Nothing he can check out.
Any chance
he's got a witness,
someone who saw you
take that tar?
Shit.
Pittario.
Or Emolia. I mean, she
was in the house, too.
No, no, no. I got
a 6-month relationship
with her. She's solid.
Pittario's the one
with an axe to grind.
Look, if they got
Pittario, man, I'm screwed.
We don't know that yet,
but we're gonna find out.
No, no, he puts
that heroin in my car,
makes IAD's case,
what then?
A first-time offender,
you do what?
5 years max,
probably less.
Shane...
I'm just saying
worst case scenario...
you refuse to wear the wire,
you let Kavanaugh arrest you.
We'll work behind the scenes
to undermine him,
and you'll seal us off
from this, right?
Look, the shit you've done
and I'm the one going to jail?
Nobody's going away.
Are you kidding me?
Hasn't been a jam yet
we haven't slipped out of.
There hasn't been
a witness before
or an IAD cop
wiring one of us.
Nobody jumped ship when Antwon
had your balls in a sling.
And I was willing to
put a bullet into Antwon
to keep it off the
rest of you. Remember?
Yeah, and we got you
out of that
before you had to
go through with it.
Which is exactly what
we're gonna do for Lem,
but if we can't...
you're gonna look out
for us, right?
Yeah.
OK.
But we're gonna get you
clear of this.
Now, Ronnie and I will
track down Pittario
and we'll squeeze
his balls.
I hate this.
Don't worry.
We got you.
Let's get the wire
back on.
What kind of a person cuts a
baby out of its mother's stomach?
The kind that shoulda
been an abortion.
There's the man.
Gimme a sec.
For what?
Aceveda's been updating me
on a few things.
Be right back.
Councilman!
A moment
of your time.
What is it?
Some asshole dumped
a few couches
over on benton.
I got a la-z-boy
over on Scott.
Bums find that out,
it's a motel 6.
You screeched up here to talk
to me about trash pickups?
Billings is too squirrelly to
ask the city for an extra dime.
Someone's gotta do it.
Hey,
we got a 187!
Anyway Farmington's garbage
is your area.
That's a little below
my pay grade.
Call someone
in waste removal.
OK.
But I hate to see your entire
district become a fire hazard.
Get what you need?
Yeah, he was very helpful.
The car's on this side.
Down there.
Hank Preminger.
Green Explorer
came around the corner,
started blasting
as he exited the diner.
Nice piece.
Let this be
a cautionary tale.
You find that heroin dealer?
Pittario cleared out
of his house.
He's a ghost.
Only sign of life is
a couple of squatter
crackheads.
Hey, telephone worker got
a bird's-eye from the pole.
He getfor the suv?
No, but he gave unis
a partial plate
on a witness who
had a better view.
Another white guy,
jumped in his ride after
the shooting, took off.
All right.
You guys work your angle.
Lem and I will figure out who's got
a problem with the hair club for men.
All right, man.
That baby is still
out there.
This disgusting crime occurred at
approximately 5:15 A.M. This morning.
E beg you,
while the baby
can still be saved,
Please call if you have
any information
about the altercation that
led to the heinous murder
of isabelle arrington.
We need you to call
our tip line.
I pulled the records
of every single person
who worked with
isabelle arrington.
So far just petty stuff.
Here's our grieving
boyfriend.
Your neighbor told us isabelle
was screwing somebody else.
That's bullshit.
Baby probably
wasn't even yours.
Don't you say that!
You goddamn liar!
If the baby's alive,
tell us.
Oh, God.
Please let him be alive.
It's a boy?
You noticed that when you cut
him out of isabelle's stomach?
We did one of those scans.
We saw his stuff.
You gotta believe me.
OK. Um... we'll get somebody
to give you a ride home.
Stay by the phone, OK?
We may have more questions.
You accuse me of slicin' my
baby out of my girl's stomach,
and now you want me to
go home and wait on you?!
We're sorry for your loss.
I don't want your
damn apologies!
I want you to find out
who did this to her!
And where my baby is!
Victim did a stint
in Lompoc 8 years ago.
Been clean ever since.
No family, but coworkers
at the pet store
said he's
got no enemies.
These matches to the
partial plate on the witness?
Yeah. I ruled out
50 of them.
Got about a half-dozen
possibles here.
Pittario hasn't been
arrested in 6 months.
That's the longest he's
gone since he turned 18.
He's off the grid.
If the him up and he made
a deal to give up Lem,
that arrest wouldn't
show up on his record.
Check this out. Leon Frankel.
Lives in the same building
as our victim.
Turns out they both got
the geds in Lompoc.
Oh. Let's find out why
hank's study buddy
didn't stick around
to talk to the police.
We lookin' at this guy
as a coward or suspect?
Well, whichever jacket fits.
Hold on. Hold on.
Is that Leon Frankel?
That's me.
We were just on our way out
looking for him.
What did he do?
We were canvassing
on that baby.
He threw a bottle
at the car,
cracked the windshield.
Then he asked if he could
smell my sweet spot.
Even shane stopped
using that line.
Pretty stupid way to get
yourself arrested, Leon.
I had a bad day.
That bad day include
seeing your pal hank
preminger shot dead?
If a friend of mine
was in trouble,
I'd do everything I could
to help him out.
Sit down.
I was scared.
I heard shots. I ran.
Hey, look, maybe if I
sit here for a while,
something will come to me.
You're walking down the street
with your enemy-free friend hank.
Shots go off, he's dead and you know
those bullets were meant for you.
Now you're not safe.
You're too damn cheap to spend
20 bucks on a fleabag motel.
You get yourself arrested because it's
safer in here than it is out there.
Only we're not your
goddamn bodyguards!
Who did it?
L... I don't know.
Get out.
What?
Get out!
No, no, no.
Wait a second.
I remember
a green suv.
Great. Think of anything else,
give us a call.
We're releasing Leon
on his own recognizance.
Wait a minute. He's
supposed to post bail.
I'm overriding bail.
You're gonna get me
killed out there.
That's a chance
I'm willing to take.
OK, OK, come on.
Please.
A couple days ago
I had a client,
fell behind on his payment.
Awesome pool player.
Now, I knew this guy,
right?
He did me a solid
back in the day.
We used to hang out
at Gary's tavern,
a little place on sunset.
Cut to the part where
someone wants to kill you.
My boss gus wanted me to take
a crowbar to his right arm,
and if I did that, his break
would never be the same.
So, you know, I gave him
an extra 24 hours.
Most loan sharks don't take too
kindly to independent thinking.
Look, gus never
would've known,
but this ungrateful prick
disappears with
the 40 large he owes.
Now gus thinks
we split the money
and he wants me dead.
And your friend hank takes
the hit meant for you.
Yeah. I feel like shit
about that.
Who shot at you?
I'll bet you anything it was that
little ass-suck works for gus.
He's always trying to
hone in on my business.
What's his name?
I don't know.
I just call him ass-suck.
Excuse me
while I get a kleenex
for the rest
of this sob story.
It's a protection game.
I got all these young guys
comin' up behind me.
It's like no one wants
Leon to get ahead.
Jesus, what
took so long?
I had to track Pittario
through ins.
Miguelez construction registered
his social security number
with payroll 2 months ago.
Scumbag got a real job?
He's working on a site
over on hillhurst.
Pittaro's breaking a sweat,
we know he's into the feds.
Let me wrap this up.
Hey! You're early.
So am I. Ha ha.
How's andy?
He's good actually.
He's inside.
Um, I was wondering,
how old was andy
when he was diagnosed?
Around 3.
There's an andy
at this school,
but he's not your son.
What's going on?
When were you planning on
telling me you're a cop?
Who told you that?
Nobody.
I was married to one.
I see them everyday
in the e.r.
You all walk the same.
Ha. Yeah, we do.
I'm a lieutenant,
IAD.
You'd make a good
detective, Corrine.
I don't know what you want or
why you've been lying to me,
but stay away.
Ms. Mackey.
I need you to know that
your husband and his team
are under investigation.
So what? I was his wife,
not his partner.
I don't know what your
involvement is yet,
but you and are going to
do a lot more talking.
And you mention
anything to him about me
or this investigation,
it is obstruction of justice,
so I find out that you told him
anything about this case,
that's on you,
and that's prison.
We'll talk later!
I wouldn't be here
if it wasn't a baby,
just so you know.
It's very generous
of you to come in.
Could you tell us
what you saw?
That pregnant lady decided she
had to turn all of a sudden,
almost drove
into that other car.
Other car,
think it was white,
goes honking, gets crazy,
starts shootin'.
911 put me on hold.
5:30 in the morning.
So I hung up.
You said you saw
something on the car,
something that could help?
The white car had one of those
decals on the back window.
What did the decal say?
Jevontrey.
I have a nephew named
Devontrey.
So I remembered
the decal.
It was one of those
R.I.P. ones.
The kind that
shoulda been an abortion.
There's the man.
Gimme a sec.
For what?
Aceveda's been updating me
on a few things.
Be right back.
Councilman!
A moment of your time.
What is it?
Come in.
You said you have
an update.
Lemansky's
birthday's today.
His pals, they
either don't know
or they just
don't care.
That's the update?
My best friend
forgot my birthday,
I'd be pissed.
This could be
a way in.
Anything interesting
happen with you today?
Like what?
Like visitors?
Mackey?
He came by the office.
What about?
Some bullshit
sanitation complaint.
I think he just wants
to shove it in my face
that he's de facto
running the Barn.
You didn't call him?
Don't have regular sit-down
meetings with him or anything?
Just trying to figure out
which uniform you're wearing,
councilman.
Well, it sure as hell
isn't Mackey's.
Sorry for getting you
down here.
Next time I have
a birthday alert,
I'll just call you
on the phone.
You're not safe here
anymore.
I'm taking you. We
got to go, got to move.
Why? What happened?
We got a couple
of possible leaks.
Get your stuff.
Whatever Sebastio needs, OK?
You said Vic
wouldn't find out.
I'm not saying
that he has.
Either way, he calls,
you don't answer.
He comes by, you're not
going to even be here.
The volume on this thing
just got turned way up.
Let's go.
Pittario!
Sí.
Yes, I'm Pittario.
Nice try, dickwad.
We know the guy.
Where
give me your papers.
Let's see 'em.
You got a job off this.
What'd Pittario get
for his papers?
He got dead.
Dead?
What? You sure
he's not laying low,
taking a cut off of your
hard-earned money?
Huh?
No. 3 months ago,
we were down
in el sa
doing a heroin deal.
The sombra negra...
he got to him.
And he sliced
his neck in half.
You got to consider
Emolia.
They might have some other kind of
corroborating evidence against Lem.
Man, she's got a messed
up kid, she's got no job.
If the IAD offered
her a deal,
she could've
jumped at it.
I've spent time
with this girl.
And the boy.
She's not going
to turn on me.
Why don't you
call her then?
Check in.
Emolia!
Sir? Have you seen
the woman who lives here?
¿Que?
Niño, mujer.
Ya se fue.
Hace como dos horas.
Se metio en un carro
con un negro.
Gracias.
Thanks.
I got every decal place in
town checking special orders.
Meantime I need
an extra pair of eyes.
3 years of death
in L.A. County.
Holler if you see
a Jevontrey.
Wagenbach.
Dutch, it's Corrine.
Are you there?
Hey! What's...
I need to ask you
some questions.
Oh
I can't right now.
Please. I'm pulling up now.
It's important.
Sorry, I didn't know
who else to call.
I can't stay long.
What's going on?
Promise this stays
between us, OK?
Promise that you're gonna
give me straight answers,
no matter what
you think of Vic.
Of course.
Well, what is it?
Some IAD guy's been coming
to the kids' school,
trying to get me
to say things about him.
IAD's into Vic?
I wonder what
they've got on him.
I mean, probably
take your pick.
Listen, I don't know, but he's
threatened to send me to jail
if I said anything
or if I don't cooperate.
I need to know if
he's bullshitting me.
I mean, can he
send me to jail?
Well, a lot of times
a person who goes down
didn't have anything to do
with the original crime.
They found out about it
afterwards, lied, covered it up.
Well, what about
spousal privilege?
They can't force you to talk,
but if they can prove
you knew about
any of Vic's actions,
it makes you
a coconspirator.
What's going to happen to your
kids if something happens to you?
You see?
You're their best leverage
against him.
But I don't know anything.
Well, then,
take away their leverage.
Be completely up front
and honest.
L-l-I'm sorry.
I've really got to go.
Hey, um...
why would someone
take prednisone?
I don't know.
A lot of reasons.
Arthritis, lupus,
asthma,
crohn's disease.
It's a common
antl-inflammatory.
Thanks.
I'm sorry.
You don't have to
memorize every picture.
Just flip.
Flip it, man.
You want me
to make a mistake?
Cut the guy some slack,
all right?
He's got a target
on his back.
Emolia, it's me again.
I got a Salvadoran
thing going on.
It's time-sensitive,
so call me back.
I need some air.
I'll come with.
That's the guy
that works for gus.
That's ass-suck.
Right there.
Justin Lamott?
Emolia's gone.
Neighbor saw her leave
with a black guy.
Kavanaugh.
You call her cell?
3 times,
including just now.
You're her paycheck.
When is the last time she didn't
call you back in 5 minutes?
If Kavanaugh
got to her somehow,
it's nothing
I can't turn around.
He's probably got her stashed
in a safe house somewhere.
Come over here.
Had to start
with Pittario.
IAD flips, some shithead ends up dead.
They got nothing...
they go to Emolia,
twist her against her will.
What does she know
besides the heroin?
Nothin'.
I've kept her clean.
Is there any chance Lem's
really working with these guys?
See, that's what
Kavanaugh wants...
for us to doubt
each other.
This guy's using
every angle.
Prick talked to Corrine
at our kids' school!
This guy's chattin' up
your ex?
You think you might
have mentioned that?
I just did. Warn Mara.
Ronnie, you tell whatever
you're bangin' this week,
don't talk to strangers.
All I need is 5 minutes with
Emolia to coach her on what to say,
let her know that
we're there to help her.
Trust me, we find her,
this whole thing goes away.
Well, how are we
gonna find her?
Hey, we got an I.D.
On our shooter.
Justin Lamott.
Vehicle matches.
Yeah. Better luck
than we're havin'.
We're gonna need to
stick Leon in a safe house
until we make
the arrest.
All right. I've got a list
of available hud houses.
Let me see.
These are for captains
and above only.
Captain.
They found the baby.
Won't leave your office.
The bones in his chest
are essentially pulverized.
Pulverized? How?
I'd say a fist.
Somebody punched
a newborn?
Stepped on him, maybe.
There's a variety of trauma,
skull fracture,
knife wound on the left leg.
I'll know more later.
Thanks for the rush.
On this one,
anything you need.
A typhoon in fiji's looking
pretty good right now.
Did he even have
a chance?
Crime scene says
he died hours ago.
It's a special
kind of monster.
Yeah, and that monster's
name's tevares glade.
Just got a call back
from a decal place on pico.
2 years ago, tevares
placed a special ord
R.I.P. Jevontrey.
In honor of a dead
uncle. Pulled his record.
Tevares drives
a white monte carlo.
And has 6 arrests,
all for violent crimes. 4
of them with a Sean deeks.
Why did 2 men cut a baby
out of a woman's stomach
just to beat him
to death?
There were more than
2 of them. Look.
In the blood.
Fingerprints. Jesus,
he's covered in them.
The big ones tevares glade,
or Sean deeks... maybe both?
But the little ones...
you think maybe
there was a girl here, too?
Ass suck, 12:00.
Out of 6 rounds, this dude
manages to get 4 in the wall,
2 in the wrong guy.
Loan shark
hired a professional.
That's some shit to be
dealing with on my birthday.
It's your birthday?
We should get wasted, man.
Yeah.
Hey, buddy,
you Justin?
Why?
Gus sent us.
Little pissed off about the way
things went down this morning.
What are you talking about?
You shot the wrong guy.
I didn't shoot the wrong guy. I
seen that prick hit the ground.
But you saw his friend hit the
ground. You just confessed to murder.
You want to spare yourself the
needle, tell us where to find gus.
Gus!
All right, all right!
Justin ided the loan shark,
got 'em both.
You tell Leon
he's in the clear?
Yeah. Freak tried
to hug me.
But you insisted
on the blow job.
I musta ate somethin'
this morning.
Third time
I gotta shit today.
Be sure to inform us
of number 4.
Look, Pittario's
a dead end... literally.
We think Kavanaugh's gonna try
to get Emolia to give you up.
I don't even think
she saw me take the h.
Good. Meantime, Vic's
convinced a little t-l-c
puts her on our side.
If Kavanaugh finds out we
got to her, this blows up.
We even know where
she is?
Ronnie and I checked out the
safe houses, came up empty.
But her son has occupational
therapy twice a week.
Emolia won't let Sebastio
miss those.
I chased down this
therapist's unfaithful wife
in exchange for a couple of
sessions for Emolia's kid.
What do you want me
to do?
Just put on your wire,
head home,
kick back your feet,
have a beer.
Kavanaugh's
turning up the heat.
We think, uh...
we think he might be planning
to formally arrest you.
If that happens, we'll
be ready to bail you out.
Hey.
Hey, I need you two guys.
This old man here, he's
been waiting here for hours.
Apparently, some assho moving around
in a camper trailer.
The guy sets up streamers, flags...
whole thing's very patriotic.
He's selling care packages and bogus
body armor to our troops in iraq.
Grandpa here paid 300 bucks
of-the-art vest.
His grandson called from
iraq when he got the mail...
let me guess...
piece of shit.
Yep.
Go pull a car.
Glad to see you two kids
are workin' it out.
yeah.
Your p.r. Instructor said you
weren't in class the other night.
Yeah, well,
something about
almost having to blow
a van full of skin peddlers
made me wanna go home
and drink a bottle of wine.
I wasn't up for baton training
that night.
So you missed a class
with no valid excuse.
I took 3 classes
already.
And when exactly
do you lay off?
When I feel safe
riding with you.
There's our patriot.
Put him in the cage.
Night, officer.
What's a little bit like
you doin' being a cop?
Put your hands
on top of your head.
What'd he do?
He a murderer?
Hey, listen, I know we're
shorthanded and everything,
but do you think
I can get reassigned?
You want
a different t.o.?
I've tried with Julien.
I really have.
If there's murderers here...
it seems like he doesn't know
the difference between
teaching and bitching.
I can't be in here
with murderers!
I've taken
3 baton classes.
My instructor thinks
I'm doing great.
It's Julien...
he just keeps on...
gotta have a room
or something!
Look, we don't have a room.
This isn't an inn.
This guy's in here
for resisting arrest.
And this guy's in here
for scamming grandpas
into buying bogus body armor
for their grandkids over in iraq.
No murderers. So don't get
your panties up in a bunch.
Same goes for you.
We found your fingerprints
on the baby, tevares,
dried in the mother's blood.
Sean and tevares
killed that lady
so you could have
the baby.
And then what? He got too
much for you to handle.
He cried too much.
So you let them
beat him to death.
We also have your friends.
We've got their finger prints.
Pretty soon, one of them's
gonna start to talk.
Good defense attorney'll just says
they found the baby in the dumpster.
Fingerprints mean
they tried to revive it.
Think the girl's
the way to go?
She's our best shot.
Want me to give it a run?
I've got someone else
in mind.
OK. Let me feel him...
like right here.
It's his foot.
You wanna touch it?
You know, I didn't even...
ever really want a baby.
But now I've...
I guess you're too young to
know what I'm talking about, huh,
all those maternal
feelings and all?
Which is why I'm thinking
that you did the cutting.
No.
Oh, come on.
Those idiots you're
hooked up with,
they wouldn't even
know how to make a baby,
much less cut one
out of somebody.
You feel it? That man
lost his baby son,
his girlfriend.
Bitch brought that
on herself.
Is that why
you wanted that baby?
You didn't think
she'd be a good enough mother?
Shit, we didn't even
know she was pregnant.
When you shot her?
She almost ran us
off the road.
My man don't stand
for that.
She almost killed us,
so... shooting her
was like self-defense.
Right?
We didn't see the belly
till she got out of the car
and started
trying to run.
They was just gonna
drive off,
but I said, "no.
We gotta save the baby."
They was thinking
they was gonna sell it.
But my sister myesha, she had
2 abortions when she was my age.
Now she wants a baby.
But... those doctors messed
up something in there, so...
I thought maybe
she could take him.
But the baby
wasn't breathing right,
so we did the stuff
you see on doctor shows.
We... cleared out his mouth
and turned him upside down.
But that didn't work,
did it?
So I made tevares do
that cpr stuff and...
the minute
he pressed down...
we heard everything
crack.
That's enough.
We was just trying
to save...
you know what? Just...
just stop talking.
They've given this
Kavanaugh carte blanche
to work your case,
any resources he needs.
What's Kavanaugh
trying to nail you for?
Because this isn't about
some misplaced heroin.
Aceveda and the department
need a poster boy for corruption
to sell their softer,
gentler force to the voters.
Why pick you
as a scapegoat?
You're a push-the-envelope
kinda lawyer.
I'm a push-the-envelope
kinda cop.
Which Aceveda
sanctioned.
This really does
go to the top.
There's some pretty
high-powered cages to rattle.
So you'll
represent us?
Just you.
No.
We're a team.
The four of us
come as a package.
I've seen these things
go down.
Everyone eventually needs
to look out for themselves.
You don't understand.
We're not the typical
lowlifes that you represent.
We're a family.
We're surviving this together,
or we go down together.
Hey, hey!
I need some officers
in here... quick!
Stand back!
What the hell are you doing? What?!
You took your gun
into the cage?
Someone could have
grabbed your weapon!
Do you see all these
people around you, huh?!
Look at me.
You trying to kill
one of them...
or you trying to kill
one of us?
Hopefully
one of you!
You know why
you're dangerous?
'Cause this isn't real
for you yet.
So you're gonna
get on me, too?
If you wanna be a cop, you
gotta recognize your mistakes,
learn from 'em.
All I've done is try to be
nice to you... to everyone.
You got a problem with me,
it's because of your own shit!
You're used to being
the queen bee around here,
but you don't get so much attention
now with those stretch marks.
So you're gonna make
my life miserable.
Every cop here has made
mistakes... including you.
And I bet you anything all of
you got cut more slack than me.
If you go out of this room with
that sniffly nose and those red eyes,
those guys will never,
ever respect you.
So you pull your shit
together.
Jesus, it's bitches like you that
make the job hard for the rest of us.
Hey, man,
where is she?
She hasn't
come out yet.
She should have been
outta there 10 minutes ago.
You sure you saw her
go in?
Yeah, man, unless
she went out the back.
OK. Here we go.
Get in.
Is she getting
an IAD escort?
Hey, hang loose.
They might be watching.
You're not going
on vacation, are you?
I haven't decided
where yet.
No, um...
you're sick.
How sick?
Dutch, I was here
yesterday.
I'm here today.
I'll be here tomorrow.
I don't know what that means.
I'm your partner.
Look, all that stuff
I said
about you not being
committed, checked out,
I'm...
Dutch.
It's OK.
I got to take
these pills.
If anybody shows up,
you call me.
Vic. What the hell?
You didn't return
any of my calls.
I got worried.
This dealer
was giving me a hard time.
I had to get away.
Sebastio asleep?
Those sessions
take it outta him.
What's up with you?
When did IAD approach you? What?
Kavanaugh. What's he
trying to get you to...
no. I don't know
a Kavanaugh.
Why are you lying
to me?
I'm sorry, Vic.
What happened?
Did he come to you
and threaten to put you in
jail if you didn't cooperate?
Huh? Because... there's a
way out of this, you know.
What did you tell him?
That I saw your guy
take the heroin.
That's it.
All right. It's OK.
Soon as we get you
outta town,
your statement
won't mean anything.
No, l... I can't leave.
Whatever Kavanaugh's squeezing
you with, I can make it go away.
Now pack your shit...
but Sebastio.
I'm gonna take him
to your mother's.
I'll make sure he gets back
with you once you get settled.
Vic!
I didn't know you then.
What?
You've been behind this
all along?
You tipped the IAD
about the heroin?
If I had to do it over
again, I'd have said no.
You've been good
to me and Sebastio.
You didn't...
you didn't say anything?
You never warned me...
all this goddamn time?!
I told them that...
shut up!
He checks in on me,
Vic.
He'll be here.
What else
did you tell him?
Nothing, I swear!
6 months!
6 months,
you coulda warned me!
God...
one of men... maybe all of us
are going to jail because of you!
I was scared.
I helped your son!
I tried to get you
out of this life!
I'll leave... tonight.
And go where? To a phone
booth to call Kavanaugh?
No.
Without you,
IAD's case goes away.
You knew what I was, and
you started running with me.
I report on people for
money, Vic! That's what I do!
Ohh... ha.
Aah!
I found you once.
I can do it again.
Who'd you call today?
What?
On your cell phone.
Who did you call?
L... only my cousin,
a few hours ago.
You called her
to get a message to her
to tell me
how to find you.
Got it?
Oh, Jesus. It's you.
Detective Mackey...
what are you doing here?
Ha. It's my CI. What the
hell are you doing here?
Emolia's helping us
with a Salvadoran
drug ring.
IAD, vice...
you're a Jack
of all trades.
I'm sorry.
Did I miss something?
Why is it that you're here?
I got spooked.
Called my cousin.
She called Vic for me.
Next time you hide
one of my CIs...
will you put
a car out front?
This isn't safe.
Subtitles:
FRM-xxy & Lemonhead
www.1000fr.com
www.theshield-laserie.com