Previously on The Shield...
You're sick.
Dutch, I was here
yesterday.
I'm here today.
I'll be here tomorrow.
6 months ago we found
this kilo of pure heroin
in the glove compartment of your car.
But you never logged
it into evidence.
Lem got picked up by IAD.
They got him wearing a wire.
Councilman,
a moment of your time!
He came by the office.
You have regular sit-down
meetings with him?
Just trying to figure out
which uniform you're wearing.
It sure as hell
isn't Mackey's.
We think Kavanaugh's gonna try
to get Emolia to give you up.
You're not safe here
anymore.
I gotta move you.
Why? What happened?
Got a couple
of possible leaks.
You said Vic
wouldn't find out.
Vic! What the hell?
You haven't returned
any of my calls.
Kavanaugh--What did
you tell him?
That I saw your guy take
the heroin-- That's it.
6 months,
you could have warned me!
One of my men, maybe all of us
are going to jail because of you!
I found you once.
I can do it again.
Oh, Jesus. It's you.
What are you doin' here?
I had no idea that
Vic knew about...
you giving up
one of his guys.
That's my fault.
I made a mistake. I'm sorry. But now...
we can make sure that
you and Sebastio are safe.
Nobody's gonna hurt you.
I gotta get him
to school now.
You need anything?
You want anything?
No! I'm good. Thanks.
Can your guy
take me back now?
An. Sure.
You know you may have to testify
against Vic and his guys in court.
That's part of the deal you
signed. You know that, right?
No. Not--Not with him
there.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
It's, um...
part of the...
conditions.
No, you never said that.
Just get him to admit
stuff-- That's all.
But you haven't got him
to admit anything, Emolia.
Tienes que hacerlo
decir algo.
Por favor, Emolia.
Por favor.
I don't want to do this
no more.
He's been good to me.
I don't want your money.
Please! Take it!
Scott!
Scott?
Yeah?
Double security.
Take her home.
Other than the kid
going to school,
no one comes, no one goes,
no one calls, right?
Christ.
See you next time, dad.
I can't wait, sweetie.
Jump in.
Love you.
Mi amor.
I can't believe how much
homework these kids get.
Aaaaaahhhh!
Jesus Christ!
Watch her!
Hang on!
Help the driver!
Get off!
Shit!
It's OK.
Just calm down, sir.
We're gonna get you
some help, all right?
We're gonna help you out. No problem.
Nice work, man.
How's Cass?
Uh, nurse's lounge.
She thought it was cool.
Been hanging around you
too much.
Hey, this was your world
this time, not mine.
Speaking of your world,
is there anything else I need to
know about that special work thing?
Everything's OK
with that now.
Corrine, good.
Uh, Dr. Lesser runs our
E.R. wanted to talk to you.
Vic Mackey.
What about?
The girl
who just died.
Yeah, officer said they found her
strolling down the 110 freeway.
Nothing new. She's a total
nut job. Schizophrenic. But...
I found
these meds on her.
Brother says she's been
taking them for the last month.
French label. No doctor.
Bad scrips?
What's on the label,
what's inside--
2 very different things.
This shit's killed
5 people in 3 months.
Thought you guys would have
made a dent in this by now.
We've been on this?
Yeah. Filled out a complaint
with your captain last month.
Who do I need
to bitch to?
Let me do the bitching
for you.
Where'd your sister
get her meds?
The drugs were supposed
to stop the psychotic breaks.
Where'd you get them?
Just... you know,
the drug store.
What kind of drug store fills a
bottle without a doctor's name?
Would you give us
a minute?
Be gentle.
His sister just died.
I'm oozing gentle.
Sis was screamin' about
devils before she died.
I hope she wasn't talkin'
about you feeding her bad meds.
I--I didn't know
they were bad.
You tell me where you got them,
and don't tell me rite-aid.
Clinica esquina.
The guy who runs it helps locals
with affordable prescriptions.
Black market blue cross.
Better than nothing at all.
Kavanaugh's gotta know we're on to
Lem's wire... us tracking down Emolia.
Why hasn't he
arrested Lem yet?
This guy doesn't follow a
script. We can't assume anything.
You think you convinced
Emolia? At the time.
But I'm sure Kavanaugh's
crawlin' inside her head.
Who knows where
she's at now?
So the next move is...
get a note to Lem,
get him up to date.
Everything else,
business as usual.
Go easy
with that, huh?
Hey, Billings. You remember
a doc over at Mission Cross
filing a bad scrip
complaint?
Yeah, sorta.
The body count's
sorta piling up.
The hospital board's
about to bring in the feds.
It's gonna make
some noise.
Shit. I just thought it
was some bogus viagra.
Stone was gonna get around
to it, time permitting.
5 dead citizens. Phillips is
gonna be crawling up your ass.
All right, look. It's
drugs. That's you guys.
Run with it.
Just keep me plugged in.
So they got to
your C.I., huh?
He's resourceful.
It won't happen again.
I can tap
some justice contacts.
Maybe we can get her
under witness protection.
She's protected.
Thanks, though.
Yeah, well,
they're on to you.
So when are you gonna
arrest Lemansky?
You ever get one of those,
like... big, bad feelings?
You can't explain it... can't
explain it at all, but...
can't shake it off
either.
I got one of those...
about you
and Mackey.
And I think this investigation
is going off point
because you're too distracted
about those bad feelings.
I've got Emolia
ready to testify
and one of his own men
on the edge of turning.
So if you are...
for whatever reason...
maybe...
working on both sides
of the street here...
well, I appreciate the,
uh, friendly heads-up.
But I know what side
of the street I'm on.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Check this out.
What's this?
This... would be
one of my good feelings.
... what they told us about that
clinic selling the counterfeit scrips?
Most of the prescriptions came
from a French drug company.
They went bankrupt
2 years ago.
Doc was right.
Pharmacology's hit and miss.
Pretty much
a loaded gun.
Tell Billings we need a
warrant for this Esquina clinic.
So what? They
probably already know
you've
got Lem wired.
It's not just scumbags
dying, it's families.
They're sending him on another
one of those bullshit errands.
That way,
he's out of earshot.
The threat out of sight,
- They now feel comfortable to share.
- How's Lem feeling?
He won't go to the doctor.
I think he's puking blood again.
Shit. Keep
looking in on him.
You bugged
the Clubhouse, too.
Yeah.
Oig signed off on it.
I planted it last night at
the base of a softball trophy.
Did you know that they
were police league champs?
Make sure
all our heads are straight.
OK.
Don't worry. I got this
whole thing sealed off.
TROPHY
Hey, that's sophisticated machinery.
Dude, it's a vending
machine.
You put your money in,
shit comes out.
It's a gourmet
quick-mealer, asshole.
Ain't nothin'
without power.
Where are
the goddamn outlets?
Hey, this is Danny.
Leave a message.
I'll get back to you as
soon as I can. Thanks.
Sofer,
what happened
to the goddamn outlets
for the vending machines?
Aw, shit!
You were supposed to call
the electrician.
I'll chalk it up
to hormones,
but you better get
down here and fix this.
So how'd we do?
Some of it looks legit.
Fda seals,
valid expiration.
But there's over a dozen
boxes that don't have seals.
No record of
these being logged in.
We'll run 'em against
bad scrips at Mission Cross.
City council in the house.
How'd Aceveda
get here so quick?
You think this is the
source of the bad drugs?
What the hell
is Aceveda doing there?
I should get back.
Keep me posted
and so forth.
Bring over Dr. Feelgood. OK.
My office
got a call.
I want to make sure everyone's
getting the care they need.
It looks like half
their stock's bootleg meds.
I'm shutting it down.
Mission Cross has been
overflowing with bad scrip deaths.
We hear your clinic
is ground zero.
Our drugs aren't bad.
They're illegal.
Yeah,
but they're not bad.
Look, I make a few deals,
cut some corners.
It's not about the profit. It's
about helping these people cope.
These are different than
the ones we got from the E.R.
Real labels. American.
Where'd you get these?
Gruhani brothers.
Persian dudes.
Run a small
trucking company.
Got a contract with Pyren
Meryl pharmaceuticals.
Distribute to east L.A.
Gruhani skims off
their shipments.
I buy at a third
the price.
Take him.
Come on.
You know a lot of people can't
afford these drugs any other way.
I'm not looking
to hurt this place.
But I got black market scrips
poisoning the Farm.
I gotta come down on every
one till we figure it out.
I know, but...
the sooner we can get this
place up and running again...
I'm workin' on it.
Someone I want ya
to meet.
Who?
- It's that lawyer chick, right?
- Yeah.
You hittin' that?
No. I hired that.
You hired a lawyer? Why?
Not me. Us.
She's walkin' us through
this thing with Lem.
Collecting intel on the whole
suit and tie side of things.
You think we're gonna
need lawyers?
Just wanna be prepared. It's a whole
new playing field we're on right now.
Holy shit. A lawyer?
Should I get my own?
Shane, relax. She's
just advising. All of us.
Detective.
Counselor.
This is detective
shane Vendrell.
Hello.
Welcome aboard.
Someplace private
we can talk?
Sure. Let's go inside.
Hey, Ricky.
Park that for me?
Yeah, no problem.
This make sense?
I think it does.
Private in here.
I was just getting shane
up to speed on our arrangement.
The others, too?
Lem's still wired, so we have
to keep him in the dark for now.
How'd you find out
about the wire?
We were hoopin' in the
back, and I felt it on him.
We got him in here, scribbled a
few notes. Found out it was IAD.
So, uh...
have any luck?
I went digging.
The rabbit hole's deep.
The IAD investigation was
initiated by captain Rawlings
A little over
6 months ago.
Rawlings
set us up?
I don't think it was
a search and destroy.
It was to prove we weren't
crooked. Cover her ass.
Shit. She was trying to
warn me. I didn't listen.
When the chief's staff
saw it in play,
They took it
in another direction.
Yeah, what direction
is that?
The way of politics.
This new chief
wants to move past
The stain
of the last 5 years,
The riots, lawsuits.
He sees the Strike Teams as
a failure of the old regime.
You're a high-Profile
team leader.
Hanging you and your guys
puts a face on that failure.
The brass puts some distance
between then and now,
Buys them their public
cleansing ritual.
And we get screwed
by a history lesson.
What about Kavanaugh?
Closed book. All I found out
is he's way inside.
Looks like he reports
directly to the chief.
Goddamn it.
You need to shift
perception,
Start piling up some
wins in bigger cases.
Make internal affairs look like
they're hurting the good guys.
OK.
Yeah.
That's a huge help.
Thanks.
Looks like I'm on board.
You... you know what that means.
You'll need a retainer.
How much?
I'm a one-Gal shop.
I'll need at least...
10 grand to get started.
If I strike early, I might be
able to make a deal for Lem.
Deals
are for the guilty.
Shit!
You need to know the
financial realities of this.
We'll talking about
legal counsel for 4.
That's a shitload
of man hours.
On cops' salaries,
you guys both have families.
We'll worry about that
later.
No compromises.
We all get cleared.
We all keep our badges.
Nothing less.
OK.
Look that over. Call if
you have any questions.
I'll be in touch.
Thank you.
Thanks.
What's the matter?
Attorney/client
privilege.
It's all inadmissible.
This quasi-Pharmaceutical
shit...
caused an aneurism in your
sister. It stroked her out.
When we find out any of
these drugs were illegal,
We're gonna
arrest you for manslaughter.
You get these
from the clinic?
Clinic charged 45 bucks
for her prescriptions.
That wasn't
cheap enough for you?
I knew they were Russian mob.
Had the same kind of drug.
10 bucks a bottle. I--I
was afraid to tell you.
Where can we find
these guys?
Operate out of
a strip joint on Hensley.
That's Popovich's place.
Popovich stepped in for Tretiak's.
Running the Red Clan now.
Sounds like a guy we
should get to know. Yeah.
Somebody trashed the Gruhani
brothers' trucking office.
Checked the brothers' homes.
Looks like they left in a hurry.
Both Zal and Babak
are M.I.A.
Zal and Babak?!
Yo, Vic!
Hey...
Found these
up your ass.
Hey,
close the door!
Ho! Is that pussy
smilin' at me?
Hey--
Oh, shit!
Come on, girls, you know this
is a patch-the-snatch zone.
Here's your
pink slip, ladies.
Mikula Popovich.
I hear you're
the Czar to know.
You have warrant
to be here?
Violation of pornography laws,
assaulting a police officer.
Probable cause.
Search and seizure, boys.
'Bout a half a dozen of
these in the supply room.
Not much of a supply.
French label. Same shit
we got from the E.R.
You sellin' hangover cures, Popovich?
No. I just like pussy.
Dancing pussy.
Turn around.
Last time I saw you,
you said you were
headed back to Saratov.
Mikula lets me strip.
Better money.
Safer than being whore.
Congratulations
on your promotion.
Your boss is selling bad
prescriptions out of this club.
They're killing a lot
of innocent people.
I need to know where
he keeps his supply.
I just dance. I know nothing about
drugs or gambling or anything.
How 'bout I share
with Popovich
How you ratted out
Tretiak?
Kaboom?
I know they have a garage
on Savanna.
Blackburn auto.
That's a start.
Tough shit, white cop!
I tell you nothing!
You go shit yourself!
Nice tough.
You want to wait
up there?
No. Paramedics are here
if I don't make it.
Fear of gates? Border flashbacks?
Maybe he just likes
a challenge.
Told us he got hit by a car,
knocked him down the hill.
Witnesses saw it different.
Espera que ellos
te ayuden.
Neighbor saw him jump out of
a moving car. A red Infiniti.
Gang retaliation?
Lots of scratches.
No ink.
No, no. Estoy bien.
Tienes que ir
al hospital.
Aah! Estoy bien.
Gracias por la ayuda.
He says he doesn't want
to go to the hospital.
Forearm's
gotta have a fracture.
No ins. No migra.
Esta bien.
Necesitamos ayudarle.
We can't force him.
We can. Trespassing.
Destruction of private property.
You're under arrest.
Take him. Make sure he
gets medical attention.
Fill him in, huh?
OK.
People are going to break
their necks on those wires.
Then tape 'em down.
People gotta eat.
Aw, shit.
Men's toilet's clogged.
Take care of that mess.
Tina talked to Hidalgo
down at Mission Cross.
He wants to tell the truth.
He said he jumped out of the
car because he was scared.
Gave us a description of the woman
driving-- Black, 40s, heavyset.
Picked him up for day work
at the home depot on third.
Drove him out to the Angeles
crest. Made him dig a hole.
Un hueco.
¿Sabes para que?
No enterre a nadie.
Eso es una maldision.
What?
She wanted him
to bury a body.
She must have seen him
getting skittish.
He said she threatened
to report him to the ins
if he didn't
finish the job.
That's when he freaked
and jumped out of the car.
That's really good work.
Both of them.
Absolutely.
Right.
Equinas
cuadradas. Nivel.
Wow. How tall are you?
6'4".
She asked him
to make it this big?
¿La señora, ella lo
queria asi de largo?
Si, si, y hacerlo
mas largo.
Yeah. She told him
to make it longer.
Hey! You guys done?
Yeah, you're done?
Uh, yeah, sorry. Good job.
Clear!
Nothin', man.
There's nothin'.
Think the whore lied?
You mean the stripper.
What the hell is that?
Hey! Jesus, over here!
Holy shit!
Who did this to you?
Vic.
"Zal Gruhani." One of the
brothers owns the trucking company.
Jesus Christ. This is chemo
medicine. Do you have cancer?
No .
Why?
Popovich knew this French
shit was killing people.
So--
He wanted our supply.
Take over...our shipments.
I said no.
He throws me...
in that hole for 2 weeks
and pumps this poison in me.
Until you changed
your mind.
Yeah.
Can't say you're not
committed.
Where's your brother?
Babak runs
our westside office.
But Russians
don't know him.
He's hiding at our mom's.
We hide the drugs
in her garage.
So we pick up the scrips
at the mother's,
charge Popovich
with attempted 187?
Yeah.
Hang on.
Have a seat, Ivan.
Mikula.
Yeah, whatever.
They're back.
What is this room?
This is the room
of endless possibilities.
Away from
the department's cameras.
We have a business opportunity
we'd like to share with you.
You turn it down, it's a
short walk back to the cage.
We know about the garage
and your "cancer" research.
Don't know garage.
Just manage club.
We know.
Dancing camel toe.
I can arrest you
and your guys,
squeeze one of 'em till we
find out where the drugs are,
but... I'm all about
diplomacy.
Raising the iron curtain.
So, uh, you're
talkin' maybe...
relationship?
Just like the way you guys
like to do things back in Moscow.
You like to help folks
who can't afford the...
high cost of medicine.
We appreciate that.
We just wanna make sure your
product doesn't kill anyone.
That's just
bad business.
We'll trade you that French
shit you been dealing...
for all-american
FDA-approved shit.
We'll give you access to
the Gruhani brothers' supply.
You give them 20%.
Why would Gruhani
agree to this?
If he doesn't, we'll
arrest him and his brother.
They'll lose everything.
What's in it for you?
We get bad drugs
off the street.
We also get 10%
off the top
for puttin' you
on the right track.
That's 70%
in your pocket.
Easy half mil a year.
You say yes,
you walk outta here
free and clear.
You say no
or try to burn us,
Perestroika dies.
I can say... yes
to this relationship.
Good.
You bring the bad
French scrips to the garage,
and I'll get Gruhani
and his brother Babak
to bring what he's got
in storage.
We're gonna need a piece
of our fee up front--
Good faith gesture.
$10,000.
You get
a better product.
We track down
the bad drugs.
Everybody gets a win. Huh?
Who says there is never police
around when we need them?
Hmm?
Who says that?
Yeah, who says?
Faster than that, Leo.
Tell 'em it's for me.
What's going on?
We got Mackey making a
deal with the Russians.
Hot prescription drugs. You
know anything about that?
They closed a city-funded clinic
today for doing illegal prescriptions.
People were dying.
He didn't call you
about it,
talk to you about it in one
of his private conversations?
No.
Did you know our boy has hired
a lawyer for him and his team?
Asked around.
Sounded like her.
Rebecca Doyle.
Yeah. You know her.
Met her a few times.
Well, it makes sense. She knows
how to protect career criminals.
Another brother
of a doomed coon mother.
Fill our Persian drug boy in on
the plan. I'll wrangle the big man.
Yeah.
What the hell's going on?
Come on, man. Sofer told
me you released Popovich?
I thought he was the one
pushing these bad meds.
He is. We just don't know
where he keeps his supply.
We couldn't hold him
on the shit we found.
Phillips just drilled me a new ass channel
for my "lack of community awareness."
This bullshit's
gonna totally ding me.
I'm working on something that
might cool your anal burning.
I'll let you know.
Those 2 missing persons over
6' 4"-- Guess who reported one?
Peaches Pyman. Reported a red
Infiniti stolen this morning.
Puts Alex Gardling
missing may, 2004.
6' 5".
Perfect peg
for a very large hole.
You found my car?
Yes, we did.
There's something
I gotta sign?
We just need to ask you
a few questions.
Anyone else have
the keys, Peaches?
Not to the car.
My realtor
has the house keys.
Just sold my house.
Moving out of state?
Nope. Just outta
the hood.
Where were you this morning
when the car was taken?
Sleeping in.
I run a sports bar.
Didn't get to bed
till after 3:00.
While we have you here,
we also need to ask about that
missing persons report you filed.
On Alex?
That was over a year ago.
You just following up
on that now?
Alex your boyfriend?
He was.
He sent me an email
a few months later.
I should have
reported that, I guess.
So he's alive.
No. I don't think so.
He was terminal.
Some kind of
blood disorder.
He didn't want to
put me through that.
He moved to Panama.
Wanted to die
in his boyhood home.
So he emailed me
to apologize and say goodbye.
Had techs plant cameras
and mics in the garage.
Gives us a 360-degree view
of the whole space.
Front row seats to Mackey's
drug swap and cash infusion.
Hey, he's on.
How's our
cancer victim?
He's doin' OK. He's real
worried about his brother.
He should be.
How's your gut?
Same, I guess.
You should stay home
tonight, take it easy.
We can take care
of things.
OK. Um...you hear anything
else about that other thing?
No. We're gonna give our guy a
call, see if there's any movement.
All right, man.
Thanks.
I need
2. 2 more. 2 more unis.
Yeah?
CI's giving us the 20
on those bad scrips.
Thought you might
wanna be there,
spin it
that Aceveda way.
I'll give a call.
You bring the cameras.
It was Mackey.
He wants to turn picking up the
bad drugs into a media event.
After he makes the trade, he
takes the payoff in private.
Steals his cake
and eats it, too.
Look, I got a district
to take care of.
You don't mind sticking
around, do you, councilman?
Why?
Help me get rid of that
bad feeling I got.
You know, Prednisone's
pretty toxic stuff.
How'd you--
You looked
in my desk?
Your drawer was open.
I glanced over.
Unbelievable!
Why don't you talk to me about
this? I just want to help.
It's not about
what you want.
What's going on
here?
Who are you? I live
here! Shonda Cromwell.
Well, we've got a warrant
to search the house.
Oh, my God! What did Peaches do?
Detectives.
What is it?
You're not gonna
believe this.
Is that a...
is that a body?
Damn. He must have
pissed somebody off.
Yeah. Or maybe he was caught
rifling through their drawers.
Or maybe his dying wish
was "dry clean only."
You, uh...
recognize this guy?
Breaking up
is hard to do.
We found him that way.
In your garage.
Oh, my lord!
No! No! No! No!
Alex, baby!
Oh, no!
No!
No! No!
That's not the response
of a woman
who just tried to bury
a guy in the woods.
No, it isn't.
Sit down. Someone'll get
your statement in a minute.
What's that about?
When ya gotta go,
ya gotta go?
Hey, I checked out that email
that Peaches said came from Panama.
Turns out our I.T. guys said it came
from an internet cafe in Burbank.
Long way from the canal.
Thanks. Nice catch on
that Infiniti, by the way.
Oh, sure thing.
Oh--God!
What happened?
- Are you all right?
- Oh, shit.
You want a doctor?
No, really.
It's just stupid.
Just help me up, OK?
I'm sorry.
Are you sure you're OK?
No, I'm fine.
Just...
Who put
the goddamn pole there?
I got it.
How's the head?
I just gave Tina
a whole lecture
on never let 'em
see you cry.
Then I give everyone
a ticket to my...
emotional breakdown.
Christ.
When I was pregnant
with my first,
I trashed the aisle
at Ralph's
'cause I couldn't decide
which disposable diaper to buy.
I just--I don't--
I don't know what
I'm doing here.
None of us do,
sweetheart.
They all need to mind
their own damn business.
You just worry about
what's in here.
Let the rest of us
wade through the sewer.
So how you gonna
handle it
if he makes the deal
with the Russian?
You gonna go in or
wait till you have more?
Gonna use shock and awe
to our advantage.
Take 'em into custody,
separate 'em,
full-court press...
one of them will turn
on the others.
See you later.
Good luck tonight.
Hidalgo was afraid
of being deported.
I told him we weren't
gonna do that.
What else?
Said sometimes people who cooperate
with the police get their green cards.
No wonder he was
so happy to help.
It's true!
Yeah, if you, like,
help bring down a cartel.
But it worked. He's cooperating, right?
He I.D.Ed the first black
woman you put in front of him.
Now their witness
is an illegal
coerced into a statement by a
false promise of citizenship.
Shit.
It seemed like
the right thing to do.
It wasn't.
It'll be OK. Dutchman's got a plan.
Ah, sorry
to keep you waiting.
So, it's OK. Is the
pregnant cop all right?
She'll be fine.
It's a crazy day.
No kidding!
Jeez, I mean, Peaches
killing Alex like that!
I just can't
believe it.
Well, no one can.
What do you mean?
We mean Peaches
didn't kill Alex.
She loved him.
You killed Alex.
And you a crazy bitch,
'cause I ain't killed no one.
Then why did you send
this man to dig a grave
in the Angeles Crest
this morning?
What's the going
rate for day workers?
You also work
2 blocks from the cafe
you emailed his dead John
letter from
so Peaches
would stop looking.
And your shrink-wrapping
skills preserved Alex so well,
we've got your DNA
all over him.
You were trying to move the body
before Peaches sold the house.
Shit.
First rule
of hole digging--
If you're standing
in the hole, stop digging.
So tell us the truth.
One crazy bitch
to another.
All right.
Look...
he was with Peaches.
But then he came on to me.
That's
understandable.
We started having
some fun.
Then he falls all in
love with me and shit.
Wants to tell her
everything.
Peaches owned the house. She
would have kicked my ass out.
He wasn't worth all that.
What happened?
We had sex.
Tch. Started fighting
about Peaches.
I keep a bat
side of my bed.
Shit just happened.
Up against the truck.
Don't you trust us?
Sure.
What makes you think
I don't?
Chh, chh, chh, chh.
When we see
the drugs.
Don't you trust us?
Hey, Vic.
Old French Zocor.
Think I arrested him
once.
That's all of it.
Everything we have.
Open it up. Let's
get the real meds in here.
Be ready.
Go on my call.
Babak,
meet your new boss.
I want to see
merchandise.
Got just what
the doctor ordered.
Show him.
Yes...
you got that tingling feeling like I do?
Here's our good faith.
The 10,000.
Come on. You deserve it.
Just take it.
Yes!
That's bullshit!
He almost killed my brother!
He poisoned him and then
he take over business!
Where'd the gun
come from?
Let it go! Hey! Hey!
Son of a bitch!
Kill me. Go 'head,
I don't give a shit!
Can't let
him walk out of here.
He'll give us all away.
What the hell?
You take care of it.
No. He's your problem.
He's our problem.
Man, come on. There's
gotta be another way.
No other way.
You want relationship,
huh?
Just not in the face.
Do it! Do it!
Go! Let's move!
Vic!
Freeze!
Let me see 'em!
Don't move!
Secure.
We're clear here.
Sir, all suspects
are accounted for.
Vic--What the hell
is goin' on?
IAD just shit
all over our sting!
What's this? What's this!
Detective Baham.
There were blanks
in the guns.
What are you running?
We're trying to establish a
relationship with the Russians.
Knew Popovich wouldn't let the
Persian threat get out alive.
Killing the competition would
have been the blood tie that binds.
Prescription drugs is just
the tip of the iceberg.
This shitbag's got ties
going back to the Kremlin.
Would have been
a huge win for us.
Did you think I was makin'
a deal with the Russians?
That I'd actually
kill someone?
I don't know where you got
your intel, but it's wrong.
He ran the whole operation
by me this afternoon.
I guess IAD'll
spin any kind of fiction
to stain good cops bad.
Uncuff my men. You idiots did
enough damage for one night.
Book him
for attempted murder.
And illegal dancing pussy.
Won't topple the roc, but at least
it'll make a dent in the local machine.
Councilman.
Gannon come out
of retirement?
Hey, if it ain't broke,
it ain't the Barn.
Heard about IAD.
That's bullshit.
Yeah. Typical.
How you feeling?
Well, a little better.
Thanks.
Uh... can I get you
something to eat?
I sorta lost
my appetite.
Right.
Should we talk?
'Bout what?
Well, maybe I can help.
Looks like the dad's
not in the picture.
Yeah, well,
the dad doesn't know.
I think it's better
that way.
I just... I don't think that
he could handle it right now.
I'm gonna do this
on my own.
If you change your mind,
offer still stands.
All right.
Thanks.
I've got lupus.
I've had it for 15 years.
It's just been
flaring up lately.
15 years.
Got my girls.
James.
I've got family.
I just need you
to be you.
Little southern'll
comfort that belly.
I think I'll stick
with the pink.
I like the pink.
Billings wants us
to clean up in here,
make sure there's
no code violations.
Seems someone ratted him
out to the fire Marshall.
Who would do
something like that?
You know what we should do-- Get rid
of some of this shit on the locker.
It's a little too close
to this light.
No! Not the trophy, man.
I went 3 for 4 to win that.
You went 0 for 5,
but who's counting?
Aw, screw it. It's a
cheap piece of shit.
You know what? We'll just
beat IAD again next year.
Hey.
Hey, Dutch.
I just wanted
to thank you.
You keep going
out of your way to help me,
and, well... I just
really appreciate it.
Oh, sure thing.
Any time.
See you tomorrow?
- Night.
Word is IAD
stepped on a big sting
you guys were setting up
on the Russians.
They just keep hurting
the good guys.
Could have picked it up
on Lemansky's wire, maybe,
thought you guys
were making some kind of deal?
Possibility.
There's egg
all over IAD's face.
If this tipped Kavanaugh off
that you're onto the wire,
he's gonna be pissed.
I have Ronnie sweep for bugs every day.
He found one
in the club house.
We knew it had to
be Kavanaugh,
so we spun it our way
just like you said.
Jesus Christ!
You knew the place was
bugged when you talked to me?
You used me, too?
Any part of that
conversation is privileged--
No, you withheld information.
You lied to me.
No, it--
It happened fast.
I--
Look, I'm wingin'
it here.
I'm sorry.
Any move he makes
against us now
just seems like part of an
ongoing misguided vendetta.
I'd better prepare
our next move.
Because Kavanaugh is
going to arrest Lemansky...
and he's going to try to
hurt you by hurting him.
We'll be ready
for that, too.
You know what? We'll
just beat IAD again next year.
You want me to go back to the Barn,
plant another one
someplace else?
Billings wants us
to clean up in here...
don't bother.
You know...
Farmington did beat us
in the semi-finals.
Could have been
talkin' about that.
Thanks, Buzz.
You should get goin'.
No! Not the trophy, man.
I went 3 for 4 to win that.
More like 0 for 5,
but who's counting?
Aw, screw it.
It's a cheap piece of shit.
We'll just beat IAD
again next year.
Subtitles:
FRM-xxy & Lemonhead
www.1000fr.com
www.theshield-laserie.com