Previously on The Shield...
We're talking about
making a case
that puts Mackey
behind bars for a long time,
and I want you
to help me prove it.
OK.
Detective Terry Crowley was
pronounced dead at 2:15 this morning.
No!
We killed a cop.
Get over it
and don't bring it up again.
Stay on Mackey.
All of his guys.
You sure?
I wish I wasn't.
Your captain's been
relieved of duty.
We need someone to cover
in an interim capacity.
What was that about?
He asked me to be the
company yes man jellyfish.
Told him to shove it.
Where's his stash?
It's in there, man.
All right. We find
the dead girl's body,
you get this back.
Those drugs were never
logged into evidence.
Wally called in one of
my colleagues immediately.
We were able to I.D.
Lemansky from her description,
search his vehicle
while he was sleeping,
procured the heroin, and replaced
it with a non-narcotic substance.
Vic likes me
and my boy.
He wants to take care of us.
We can use that.
I thought
you were Vic's C.I.
Whoever's got the money.
Police!
All right,
let's split 'em up.
Hey! Hey!
Goddamn you!
Get out of here!
Get out!
Stay there.
Ronnie, you all right?
Yeah.
Everybody, just be quiet.
Who hit me?
Jesus Christ?
Come on, man. Turn around.
Let me see your hands.
Hey?
Nothing. No blood
on the mexis.
Blacks
are clean, too.
Shit.
Go to the e.r.
Get that looked at.
Get a wagon. Haul in
the grieving families.
Tell the captain
I said to send it.
All right.
Bullshit uni calls.
Better
get used to it.
Sir?
You see
who domed my guy?
Black kid.
Got, like, a blond afro.
I see him hanging out
in front of kwiky's liquor
on my way home.
What the hell's
going on here?
This is, like, the second
black and latino brawl
I've had this week.
Where do you live?
Culver city.
Well, you better learn how to
coordinate your colors, there, westside.
Last week,
some black guy
went hit-and-run
on a Mexican kid.
Crushed his skull.
We couldn't generate any
cooperative witnesses.
Cholos took it
on themselves.
Hunted down the driver
and beat him to death.
Black hood jumped in
and killed two Mexicans.
Went sideways
ever since.
I didn't know.
Yeah. Thanks.
She's got three
punctures in her back.
Who found her?
A Junior. Zellie praza.
She's pretty devastated.
She's in my office.
Do you have any
metal detectors here?
Some of them
don't work very well.
Any other witnesses?
Well, there's 1,500 students
in the school.
I would think so.
Thanks.
Good questions.
Nice work.
Officer, would
you like to see Zellie?
The detectives will. Keep her in
your office until they get there.
Tina?
Hey, Tina!
What?
You're contaminating
the crime scene.
Aw, shit!
Oh!
All right, guys.
Come on.
The captain's gonna address
the troops in the briefing room.
Let's head in.
This should be
educational.
Hey. Hey, come on.
I'm hormonal and
I expedite your paychecks,
so let's move it.
What's going on?
A pep talk.
Yeah, 'cause when I
think pep, I think Billings.
OK.
Thanks for joining me.
Betcha lunch
he says,
"and so forth"
at least twice.
As you probably know,
yesterday, measure 16
on the city ballot failed,
so it looks like
those temporary budget cuts
are now permanent.
That'll be 17%
across the board...
Which means...
which means
we'll have to make do
with the lack of manpower
here in the Barn
and on the street
and so forth.
The chief wants you to know
this is by no means
a reflection
of the fine job that you're
all doing for our city.
Of course not.
Listen, starting next week,
we're going to be going
to single unit patrols.
I know. Which means
if you have more than
6 months on the street,
you're gonna be flying solo.
And speaking of flying solo
at 6 months,
officer Sofer might be mum
on who the daddy is,
but she'll gladly spill the
beans on your new assignments.
OK.
That's all I have.
You guys keep up
the good work. All right?
Hey.
Cheap bastards
don't wanna cough up
a half cent
of sales tax, screw 'em.
Next time somebody bitches
p.d. Didn't show up,
tell 'em that could've
bought 2 cops on time.
Hell, yeah, Vic.
So let's keep showing up.
Everything else'll
even itself out.
That's right.
Everything
always evens out.
And so forth.
Don't hate me
'cause I'm always right.
We need to talk to
the rest of Zellie's class.
Well, the juniors
are at lunch.
The entire class?
We'll be here all day.
Hey! Hey!
Hey!
Come on! Move it!
Gunshots!
Come on! Get out!
Julien!
Tina!
EXTRACTION
we got a full-blown riot at
wellman-Chase high school.
Shots have been fired.
Officers need help.
Tactical alert.
All we got.
Get 'em there now.
Have f.d. And e.m.s.
Stage two blocks out.
Tell 'em it's chaos
on arrival.
Shit!
Go on!
Get out of here!
Get the hell
out of here!
All right, fire it up!
Vic, wilshire east
came through!
Set up a mobile field force.
Come on,
get up, punk.
This was your solution?
Turn the goddamn fire hose
on my kid?
What was I supposed
to do, open fire?
Never stopped
you all before.
Excuse me, ma'am. I'm David
Aceveda, your councilman.
I can assure you that
it was the safest option
to protect
all these kids.
Right.
Let's get
a gurney over here.
Get the labs rats
to lift those prints.
Maybe our knifer?
It's not. Ahem.
Paramedics?
Officer Hanlon. She got a little
bit too close to the crime scene.
I've already
discussed it with her.
You went into the bathroom?
It's my fault.
I should have...
preserving the scene is training
officer 101. That's how...
murderers go free.
I'm really sorry,
detectives.
It won't happen again.
It's OK.
Let's go.
It's a rookie mistake.
She's way too young for you.
I am mature
and distinguished.
A lot of young women
appreciate that.
You really ought to
cut back on the porn.
All right,
please move back.
This shooting related
to our stabbing,
or was this
just for extra credit?
Either way,
he's not graduating.
You OK?
I'm fine.
I can grab
those paramedics.
I said I'm fine.
Let's give that to Vic,
and we'll stick
with the stabbing.
OK.
Parents want to take
their kids home.
Nothing would
make me happier.
Unfortunately,
all the little shitheads
are suspects and witnesses.
They want to talk
to a captain.
And I want more hair.
All right,
you handle it.
It's good mothering practice.
Vic, what do you got?
Armed and dangerous.
A taser.
He was in the cafeteria
when the kid got shot.
All right, listen. Anything you
can do to quiet this shitstorm
and get it off my plate,
it's got my blessing.
You a member of
the varsity taser club, Weston?
Eleven of your classmates
are in mission cross,
some critical, one dead.
And this...
puts you at the top of the most
likely to be tried as an adult list.
A knife and gun
did the damage.
That don't mean shit.
Shit!
That's persuasion by proxy.
I didn't hurt nobody!
Yeah? Well, what do you
use this for, huh?
Toastin' pop tarts?
Protection, man.
Shit's crazy, goin' on.
What shit?
Aah!
Goddamn!
That shit ain't right!
All right, all right,
all right.
There's a kill clock.
Some Mexican's gotta kill a
couple brothers by tonight.
Why?
I don't know the whys,
man, just the what.
Who's the Mexican?
If I knew that, I wouldn't
be carrying the zapper.
That's for being a wise ass.
Claudette, I might know
what your stabbing's about.
Guy in one thinks there's
a kill clock ticking.
Kill clock?
Yeah. Gangs use it
to set a time limit
on an initiation
or a retaliation.
He heard some Mexican's
gonna try to kill two blacks.
Just randomly?
You think
it's legit?
That doesn't matter.
If it stirs up enough fear,
it's real.
Would explain why our
witness isn't talking.
Yeah.
Keep at her. I'm gonna
tap into a C.I. Of mine.
OK.
Hey, that girl
that was stabbed...
caroline tylin,
she just died in surgery.
Sorry.
Hey, how you feelin'?
How do I look?
Great.
Yeah?
Pretty much how I feel.
Thanks for asking.
Bad news, Zellie.
We know about the
black/brown retaliation.
And right now,
you're the closest brown
to our dead black girl.
She died?
Which means you were
involved or you know who did it.
By not talking, you're
interfering with an investigation,
and that's a crime.
All right. I saw him
running out as I came in,
and then I saw her
by the sink,
all bloody and shit.
Who was it?
Lorenzo Lavedra.
All right. This kill clock's
gotta fall gangland.
Vic and I should
follow up on this.
OK. We'll take over
the cafeteria shooting.
I'll tell the captain
we traded cases.
Why confuse him?
That it?
For now.
You'll hear from me soon.
Somethin' else?
No.
Excuse me.
You're here early!
Come in, please.
Come on.
Come on. Have a seat.
I've only got
a few minutes.
How can I help you,
lieutenant Kavanaugh?
You know that I.e.d. Has been
looking into detective Mackey
and the Strike Team he ran
while under your command?
Captain Rawlings began
that investigation.
I was aware of it.
That investigation
still ongoing?
Yes, it is.
Well, what have you got?
What have I got?
We've got Lemansky.
He lifted a brick of tar
off the el Salvadorans.
We've been waiting for it
to spin into something more.
Which means you've got
nothing on Mackey.
His day job's
keeping him busy.
He hasn't had the freedom
to navigate much game.
But we got a C.I. Next to him
and when he jumps dirty,
we'll know.
Until then, I was hoping that
you might be able to help us out.
You've got my
letter.
And I've got
nothing else to add.
Mackey's your problem
now, not mine.
No.
Perception is your problem.
I'm going after Mackey.
And his team.
Now, you can get on board
and be proactive,
or you can sit back
and spectate.
Just like you did when he was
running dirty on your watch!
Hey, I did everything
I could to rein him in.
Don't sit there and
threaten me with bad p.r.
You're right.
I was out of line.
Hey, I'm sorry.
Please, come on.
Sit down.
Mackey's jacket is like
a 20-page cautionary tale.
This is a lawsuit
waiting to happen.
I just want to get him off the
street before he does any more damage.
That's it.
P.d. Is looking for a
poster boy for corruption.
They crucify
one of their own,
the public
will trust the rest.
And next time, that
ballot measure, it passes.
Hmm?
When you were captain,
Mackey and Vendrell
were interrogated
about the shooting death
of a detective Terry Crowley.
From the notes, it's very clear
that you thought Mackey was involved.
And your comrades
ruled it line of duty.
I was hoping you might be able to
shed some light on the specifics.
The rumor has it that the feds
might've been involved with that.
Is that true?
What's my end?
Your suspicion.
This is your letter.
We say you got
the ball rolling.
You followed it through
even after you left the job.
Now, that's the man
that I want to be mayor.
I would vote for that man.
Vic and his guys are tight.
And Lemansky,
he's a soldier.
He'll follow Mackey
anywhere.
But he's also the one
with a conscience.
So you're going to need something to
drive a wedge between him and Mackey.
I need that wedge,
councilman.
I need that wedge.
If I give you this,
I'm done.
I don't want that guy's
stink on me anymore.
My word.
Terry was working with justice
to bring down Mackey,
and I think
Vic had him killed.
What kind of proof
you got?
Detective Crowley's
deal with justice.
That's good.
Can I get the intel
by the end of the day?
Sure.
No, thank you.
This is a fresh pack.
It's juicy fruit.
I said no.
Thank you.
You hold this out
long enough,
some people feel
compelled to take the gum.
It's a sign they'll
crack under pressure.
I know.
Ha ha ha.
Ahh.
Hey, listen...
oh, there he is!
Hey, sebastian,
how you doing?
Look how big
you got.
Oh, wait a minute!
Wait a minute.
How'd that
get in there, huh?
You want that?
Yes.
Here.
You want
anything?
No.
Here on business.
I got a kill clock
ticking.
Mexican on black.
These things usually
start on the inside,
so check with your
prison contacts, OK?
OK.
Good.
Uh... your C.I. Renewal papers
hit my desk.
You need me
to sign them?
Look, I know
it pays the rent,
but C.I. Work,
is a roll of the dice.
We've had
a good 6 months,
but you should get out
before you get hurt.
I need that money, Vic.
What else am I gonna do?
Anything else.
I'll help you find something.
You're worried about us.
I just want this to end
on good terms.
Now tell me
you'll think about it.
OK.
I'll think about it.
Good.
And if you hear anything
about this kill clock...
I'll let you know.
Good.
Was the riot
gang related?
Well, we're still
putting the pieces together,
trying to get
a clear picture and so forth.
Well, what the hell
started it?
We don't have a motive yet,
but we have a suspect.
Good.
I need a minute.
Shut the door.
This about me
hosin' down those kids,
I'd rather have 'em pissed
off and wet than dead and dry.
Ha, what?
You breaking up
with me, Roy?
Got a call from pensions.
Chief's having them
put through your papers.
They want you out
when you hit your 15.
You're puttin' me on the beach?
This referendum failing,
cutbacks are hitting hard.
Anybody near their 20 or
carrying a risky jacket
is getting a push.
At least you'll get a
piece of your pension.
There aren't enough
cops as it is.
It's not personal,
it's policy.
If it's not personal, then why am
I gettin' the news hand-delivered
to me by the chief's
inner circle?
Figured I owed you
a face-to-face.
It's bullshit
and you know it!
It's some suit makin'
a judgment call!
Can't you put in
a good word?
Turn it my way?
I'm not Gilroy.
It's a different time.
Play this smart, Vic.
Don't give 'em a reason
to pull your pension.
Hey, A.C.
Hey.
Uh, kid who did the stabbing,
Lorenzo Lavedra, 17.
Couple misdemeanors,
nothing violent.
No gang ties.
His pops, however, is a...
is doing a dime in chino.
Assault.
Good.
What's up?
Jesus Christ, these are
retirement papers.
Yeah.
Am I missing something?
Department's cuttin'
its liabilities.
Phillips wants me out by the
time I hit my fifteenth year.
That... that's like
in 4 months.
That's crazy!
Um...
but what
are we gonna do?
I'll walk out the front door
on my own
before I'll let someone
push me out the back.
This is between
you and me.
Not a word.
Ha ha ha!
Ha! That's right.
Hey! How's the head?
Intact! Man, nothing
can hurt that cabeza.
Ahh.
Is it sore?
OK, OK. I see it.
I want that asshole
who clubbed me.
Oh, we'll get him.
Hood needs
a little reminder.
You hurt us,
we hurt you worse.
I'll make sure
that measure passes.
We got a clock to kill
first, guys. Let's go.
We're lookin' for Lorenzo.
Haven't seen him
since this morning.
Hasn't been home
all day today?
Don't know.
Just got here.
Was picking up Cisco
from soccer.
Hey, that's our guy!
Stay here!
Hey.
Aw, hell, he went down!
Shit!
Stop!
Asshole's trying
to finish the kill clock.
Can't let him
get out of browntown.
I got it!
Get out now!
You OK?
Give me your keys
right now!
Get down!
Ah, damn it!
Get out of the car!
Hey, get out
of the car!
Hands on your head
right now!
Don't move
or you're dead!
Let me see hands!
Let's go. Let's go!
Come on.
Let me see
your hands, buddy.
Stop struggling.
Got him?
Yeah, I got it.
What are you doing? What are you
doing?! Why are you arresting him?!
He ran a stop sign.
Where's Cisco?
He's downstairs.
The black guy,
the guy with the bible,
is he dead?
He lost a lot of blood,
but he'll live to see
Armageddon.
My son was scared.
He panicked.
He sees what white cops
do to Mexican kids.
Oh, really?
He panic when he stabbed
caroline tylin today?
Got a witness saw him
fleeing from the bathroom.
No. Tell him
you didn't do it, renzi.
What time is it, mama?
You got someplace
you got to be?
I don't feel so good.
I wouldn't feel
too good either,
if I just slaughtered
an innocent girl.
I'm guessing you didn't
download the death photo
with your ring tones.
Oh, Jesus.
Lorenzo.
Oh, Christ.
Take him to the bathroom,
please.
Hey, officer Hanlon.
Got a little job for you.
Anything you need,
detective.
Clean him up.
Get him to the John.
OK.
I'm Mexican.
Why am I gonna be
offin' up some other homes?
Maybe you had
a beef with him.
Maybe it was so crazy
in the cafeteria,
you got caught up
in the rush,
fired off some shots.
I didn't do that.
Sure, you did.
No, I didn't.
Then who was it?
I don't know.
Because you shot him.
Ha ha ha.
Why you keep sayin' that?
'Cause the truth rolls
comfortably off my tongue.
Heard you been braggin'
about the new gun you bought.
Tellin' kids you pack it
for protection.
Well, that was just
me talkin'.
I didn't even
bring it to school.
You snuck it past the
lame metal detectors.
You pulled it out
during the riot
and you shot him
in the back.
It wasn't me!
Fine. Call juvie.
Let him spend
a few weeks in lock-up,
get a taste
of his future.
Maybe a little truth will
seem like a good idea then.
It's Every-Day!
What's everyday,
that you shoot somebody?
Evan Dayne.
Call him Every-Day.
Bangs with the hope hill set.
He can't know it's me
that said anything.
Uggrrhh!
Dutch!
Stop it!
You're killing him!
That's it!
It's over!
Are you OK?
Fine. I'm fine.
Shit.
Goddamn it!
This is a new suit!
Have a wonderful day.
Bye. Bye, guys.
Love you.
Bye.
Hey.
Jon. I'm new here.
Corrine.
Which one's yours?
He's inside already.
Orientation.
Gum?
No, thanks.
Come on.
It's a fresh pack.
Here you go.
Sure. Thanks.
That's your boy?
Yeah, yeah...
and our daughter.
Two?
Wow. That must be tough.
And I'm struggling with
just one autistic child.
It's the challenges
of a single parent, I guess.
Yeah. Doing it alone
is hard.
You, too?
Yeah.
The daddy's not
in the picture?
Uh, he does what he can.
My ex, she doesn't even
acknowledge our child.
I'm sorry.
Sometimes I wonder why
I even married her.
You ever feel like that?
I'll see you around.
Can I call you sometime?
I'm sorry. It's just that
they told me I should try
to get to know some
of the other parents and...
I'm out of my depth.
Uh...
I can talk to you or I
can talk to your husband.
Either one if...
you know, whatever...
uh... OK. Last name's Mackey,
and, uh, you can call me
about the kids or the school.
My husband's not gonna
be much help.
Thanks.
Thank you.
Hi.
Hey, Julien.
You gotta give me
the scoop on Danny's baby.
What do you mean?
The father.
The pool's up to
1,100 bucks.
Of course there's a broker's fee
for any insider-training buzz.
She won't say. Why don't you
guys just leave her alone?
Come on, man.
What's your take?
Oh, I always take shane
in these things.
Not me, brother.
I'm married.
That's means no sticking,
just licking.
Charming.
Besides,
I like my women tiny.
So the dick
fits better?
Oh!
Easy. Easy.
Put me down for 20
on the sperm bank.
I gotta get this organized.
"Tina. 20. turkey baster."
You OK, mijo?
I'll see you later,
darlin'.
I got him.
Are you on drugs?!
I didn't raise
an animal!
You hear me?!
What the hell
is wrong with you?!
Who set
the kill clock?
Don't you touch him!
Vic. Vic.
The little kid who got
run over last week
was a nephew
of a Los mag capo.
Doing 20 in chino.
Los mags are reaching out
to settle the beef.
Chino's where Lorenzo's
pop is stretching.
Hood's been under
the microscope.
Maybe the mags
us a proxy,
make sure no blood blows
back in their direction?
I got a few juvie graduates
in chino.
I'll find out
what pop's story is. Come on.
Shane, give me a minute.
Where's Sebastio?
My mom's watching him.
Here.
It's OK.
I'm... I'm on the clock.
I know how much
gas costs. Come on.
More and more.
Thanks.
Any thoughts about
hanging this up?
Still thinking.
A Los mag cap set
the kill clock from chino.
Same cell block where
your father got caught
helping the black
brethren distribute smokes.
Pissed off
the inked vatos.
Asshole can't even play
by the rules in prison.
My guess is Lorenzo Senior offered
you up as a Junior assassin...
to settle both scores.
Is that true?
Does that bastard have
something to do with this?
Answer me!
Mommy can't help you.
Grow a dick.
Tell the truth.
It's about justice.
He said I could
help the cause.
It's mexl-pride.
Jesus, mother of God!
I didn't want
to hurt no one.
Dad started crying.
Said if I didn't kill
2 dark by 10:00 tonight,
Los mags were
gonna waste him.
It was him you were on
the phone with last night?
I gotta finish it
or he dies.
Why? Why would you
do this for him?
Not for him.
I hate him!
But if I don't do it, it falls on Cisco.
He was on the other
line. Dad told him, too.
He gave us the combination for the guns.
Guns? There's more than one?
Oh, no!
Cisco still thinks my
dad's like a real dad.
He'll do it.
He'll throw it all away
for that asshole.
Paula! Where's the kid that
was sitting in that chair?
Cisco!
What kid?
Shit!
Description
of the shooter
sounds like our
lost brother.
Go!
Hey!
What happened here?
Little spic came
and shot him cold.
I mean, tommy never
saw it coming.
He's gone.
Which way did he go?
Out the back.
Come on, shane.
You know that crazy kid stopped
to take a goddamn polaroid?
I stuck him with
my best pair, though.
You struck him
with your scissors?
Stay here. Let's go!
Go! Go! Go!
Hey.
Yeah.
Easy.
Hey.
Cisco!
Put the gun down, kid!
Put it down right now
or I'll shoot!
I gotta get this
picture to my dad.
Hold it!
All right.
We'll talk about the picture
after you put the gun down.
You'll take it to him?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'll take it
to him myself.
That's it.
Where we can see it.
Good boy.
Go!
Give me the camera.
It really hurts.
Don't! Shit!
Jesus Christ!
Apply some
pressure on it!
Go get those paramedics!
Goddamn it!
Oh, Christ almighty!
Watch out! Go! Go! Go!
All right.
Hurry up, Ronnie!
What happened
in the cafeteria?
I heard those shots and hit
the floor like everybody else.
Anyone else see that?
Don't know.
We all ran for the door.
We got 3 people who saw you
pull the trigger, Every-Day.
Well, then
you got 3 liars!
3 against one.
Those aren't very good
odds for you.
I'm used to it.
We're gonna need a little
more than a bad attitude
to be convinced
of your innocence.
You best tell
pale boy here
to get out of
my goddamn face.
look,
I ain't...
I ain't been playin'
trouble for a while now.
Y'all can
ask around.
We did. That's how
we got the statement.
From who?
Some chill-sitters?
They're killin'
us niggas.
You don't think they want
to put another one away?
That sounds like
motive to me.
Lazy-ass cop.
Hey, I bust my ass
on this job!
Well, your busted ass
suck at it!
Hey. Book him
for murder.
This is wrong, man! I
ain't killed nobody, man!
Come on. It's been
a long, shitty day.
Every day.
The emt says
he's gonna make it.
Gracias a dios.
Well, I wouldn't be
too thankful.
He just killed
an innocent man.
I wanted to kill
their father a dozen times,
and I never did
for their sake!
Los mags should slit
his throat from ear to ear.
Ma'am!
She's right, you know.
That prick should die.
He will.
Just not today.
Look, this isn't the way
I wanted to do it,
but at least it will end
this round of blood.
Talk to your guy
in chino.
Find out where
those pictures go.
We got 2 hours
to get them there...
all right.
Stop the clock.
Get it done.
Got a call from
a teacher at wellman.
He just realized his gun was
stolen out of a locked desk drawer.
Evan dane is any
of his classes?
Homeroom and science.
Now we know where
Every-Day got his weapon.
What ever happened to rappin'
a kids knuckles with a ruler?
Uh, good job. Thanks.
It's, uh...
it's Vic's kid.
I got 50 bucks
in the pool.
That's funny.
'Cause I got 50 on you.
I tried calling.
No one answered.
Something wrong?
I thought maybe I'd...
I'd try to catch them before
they went to bed, say good night.
It's not your usual night.
I know.
Vic, you can't just
show up. I mean...
they have a schedule.
And mine's
always changing.
You want me to ever
see them or not?
These aren't my rules.
It's the custody agreement.
Oh, Jesus.
Is that blood?
Shit. I thought
I got it all.
12-year old.
It's been a shit day.
I just wanted to
kiss 'em good night.
Wash it off
before you see them.
Hey.
Daddy!
Ha ha ha.
Ooh...
aw, my baby.
Heard you already have
a suspect in custody
on that cafeteria
shooting.
Most cases are solved
within the first 24 hours.
After that, the odds of solving
them decrease exponentially.
I'm gonna learn a lot
from you, aren't I?
Could be.
Have a good night,
detective.
You, too.
Relax.
What?
The residue tests came back on negative.
We're sure
about this guy?
He knows when
to wash his hands.
So do I.
We're looking for
a brother.
Blond afro, tall.
Hands might be cut up.
Ain't seen nobody
like that.
We know he hangs here.
And we know this shop's been
hit 9 times the last year.
Twice
last month.
And it took you guys
3 hours to show up
last time I called.
Well, next time...
you call us.
We're your new 911.
We'll make sure that people
don't mess with your shop.
We'll steer that kind of
business someplace else.
You talkin' straight
about keeping my place safe?
I got a badge, don't I?
Darius mcbride. D-mac.
Came in this morning, bought
some band-aids and beer.
Lives over
on belmont green.
Consider your
protection clock running.
Hey!
Anybody, any color,
hits this store,
I will beat them
half dead
and put enough shit on them to
send them away for a 10 stretch.
Spread the word.
Screw up!
Guys like the girly-girls.
Who says you gotta look
like janet reno, right?
You replaced
your breast plate
with lipstick
and tampons?
A place to put your shit,
you know?
Yeah, well,
that's a reprimand.
As well as probably
getting you killed.
Lose those hoop earrings before
someone rips your ears off.
Did I do something
to piss you off?
You know what? You have a
job, sweetheart, all right?
Take it seriously.
You're a cop,
not a kelly girl.
OK, look...
I appreciate you being straight with me.
It's just hard to catch
a break with these guys.
Treat you like
you don't belong.
Yeah, I know.
They talk a blue streak
about equality,
but the truth is the
shit heads just think
we're a bunch of little
girls playing cops.
So we have to
prove them wrong.
Yeah... we do.
Thanks.
It's good to
have some back-up.
Here you go.
You still here?
I thought you were supposed
to be more 9:00 to 5:00.
Thanks. Tell that
to Billings.
Huh. You pretty much
run the place.
Yeah, I'd rather be running
the streets with you.
Hell of a lot easier.
Don't be so sure.
I got my work
cut out for me.
Tina... she ain't
no Danny Sofer.
Well, who is?
Anyway, I wouldn't
write her off too soon.
She's raw, but
she's got potential.
Yeah. Guess I made a few
mistakes out there myself.
Yeah,
you still do.
You're supposed to have
your dfa hours on my desk
before the end
of the shift.
I'll get Tina
right on it.
See? I did
train you right.
Yep.
shit.
Curtis Lemansky.
Yeah. What's up?
Jon Kavanaugh,
I.A.D.
I need you
to come with us.
What about?
Get dressed.
Dyson?
Please.
I'll get dressed.
Halter.
Yeah.
Bye.
Hey.
Come here!
Get off!
About 6 months ago...
we found this kilo
of pure heroin...
in the glove compartment
of your car.
We seized the drugs,
documented it on camera,
and replaced it
with dummy tar.
But you never logged it
as evidence.
So you've been watching me for 6 months?
I don't want you to spin
a story right now. Really.
I just want you to think
about what this means.
Felony theft under color
of authority.
Intent to distribute.
You're a smart guy.
You've been on the
other side of this table
a long time.
You know how that
will play out.
Does that seem fair
to you? Hmm?
Look if you were
arresting me,
we'd be at police one.
You'd be parading me
past o.I.g.
What do you want?
I want us both to do
the right thing, Curtis.
Really?
Why is it that the guy
with the conscience
always has to get caught
holding the bag?
And we never really
want that guy. Do we?
We want the guy that
put him into motion.
The one who is
really dangerous.
Who do you think I want,
Curtis?
Come on, man. Come on.
Who do you think
I want?
Subtitles:
FRM-xxy & Lemonhead
www.1000fr.com
www.theshield-laserie.com