If you could, uh have your
clients walk me through
the house where Terry Crowley
was killed,
that would be great.
Hey!
Terry was
workin' for justice.
Officer Danielle Sofer,
who works here,
if filing paperwork admitting
to a sexual relationship
with Vic over
the last couple of years.
Officer Sofer
is now pregnant.
I need to know everything
you know about these men.
The price is simple.
I help you put away
these fine young men,
you make sure you put
them away right here.
So you can kill them?
I made a life
for myself.
You been missin' me?
Ex-wife.
Ask me
to come back again.
You're here to be
remanded for psychiatric.
And I am
your goddamn wife.
At least we found
his weak spot.
Come on, Jon!
Shit. Go!
Don't leave me,
Jon!
Hey!
You're under arrest
for possession
of heroin
with intent
to distribute!
Yeah.
Come on and have a seat.
I need you to tell me
everything that you know
about Mackey
and his Strike Team.
No deal.
You got your deal!
hey, man.
How's it goin'?
All right.
What's goin' on?
Have we got a plan?
Yeah. Get you the hell
out of here.
Did Mara back off
puttin' up
her and shane's house
as collateral?
We're still
workin' on bail, right?
But Kavanaugh had the irs
freeze our assets,
all of us.
So I'm stuck.
I mean, there's no way
you're comin' up
with $100,000.
I've already filed a motion
to have your bail reduced.
OK. How long you think
I need to hold out for?
You listen to me.
24 hours,
you're out of here.
Tomorrow night,
you sleep in your own bed.
You just gotta stay good
for 24.
All right, man.
All right.
Take the back.
Don't move!
Jeez, stay still!
Don't move, damn it!
Police!
Drop your weapon!
It's OK! Don't shoot!
I said
drop your weapon!
Don't shoot!
I'm a cop!
God damn it drop
your weapon now!
Stop!
Stop right there!
Get on your knees!
Nice work.
Rookie, right?
Look, man, tell your
partner not to shoot.
He's undercover!
I didn't know.
He didn't identify
himself.
His right arm!
It's the color
of the day.
Which makes you
ditz of the month, honey.
Terry went down... here?
Uh, yeah, about
where that chair is.
Uh, two-time
came out blastin'.
Terry went down.
We fired back.
Ballistics gave Vic
the kill shot.
I must've been
a close second.
I was off of my game,
I guess.
Were you off your game
when angie stubbs
got murdered?
Your bullet got
the kill shot on that one.
Gun wasn't
in my hand.
Right.
Angie's death got pinned
on Antwon Mitchell.
Nothing got pinned.
He killed her.
Right.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Uh...
you just watched.
Mitchell ever
give you any money?
Put you
on his payroll?
He was undercover.
It's all documented.
Not all of it.
Not the drug payoffs.
Not the One-Niner pimps
you were shakin' down.
Not the nights and days
that you spent
bein' Antwon Mitchell's
bought bitch.
You think that I
don't know about that?
We are here to talk
about Terry Crowley.
Otherwise,
we'll be going.
Sure.
Hey, stay here.
Why don't you
just relax, asshole?
I'm just coppin'
a squat, all right?
Detective Mackey!
Come on up.
According to you,
Terry entered the room
before it was cleared.
I failed to clear
the bathroom.
I looked, I thought
it was clear...
but two-time must have
been behind the wall.
There were noises, uh,
movements from the
other side of the house.
Shane and I started
that way.
I moved on
before I should've.
I'm gonna
have to live with that.
Soon as I turned around,
about 2 seconds,
I heard the shot...
and Terry fell.
We returned fire.
Now, we can run this
6 more times.
Two-time's always
gonna have the gun,
and Terry's always
gonna be dead.
Right.
You got some kind
of a problem?
Thought you'd remember
Drew from Terry's funeral.
But, no matter.
Drew Crowley...
Vic Mackey.
Doesn't remember 'cause
he never looked
at me or my family
that day.
Formerly officer Drew
Crowley, San diego.
Left the force after
his brother was murdered.
Mothers, you know.
I just wanted
to see your face.
Here, where my brother died.
Of all the underhanded
bullsh...
now I want to know
the truth.
What happened
to my brother?
Tell the truth,
you son of a bitch!
Get him out right now!
Hey, no, no.
If you killed him...
God'll know.
My brother
was a good man.
I'm sorry
what happened to him.
It went down
just like I said.
Come on, Vic.
Let's go.
If you're lying,
God'll have your soul,
and I will give it
to him personally.
SMOKED
All our stories
matched up.
Maybe now he'll give up
this bullshit case.
Move on to shit
we actually did.
All bullshit.
This is about
rubbing our faces
in the intel he's
already uncovered.
Like what?
He knew
all about the pimps
me and army were bleedin'.
Where the hell
did he get that?
I don't know.
Antwon maybe?
No. He'd
never give up anything
for nothin'.
And with his stretch
for double capital,
there's nothin'
to give him.
Army?
No. Halpern.
Maybe Rawling.
No. She didn't know
these kind of details.
Could have been
some One-Niner.
Could be Lem.
Stop that shit.
I'm not saying
it was Lem.
I thought were just listing
the possibilities.
Well, don't.
We gotta stay focused
on gettin' Lem out of there.
This is the last night
he spends in county.
Well, we got
about 700 in cash,
3 frozen bank accounts.
That's it?
Lem's kin is
trailer park trash.
Couldn't spare the money
big powerball
this weekend.
So we gotta find 100
grand on the street.
Just lying around
with Kavanaugh watching us?
He's fixated on the
past, not the present.
You're wrong, we're gonna
end up keepin' Lem company.
We're not leavin' him
in there.
I promised him.
Construction
worker called it in.
Whoa! Talk about
a dump job.
OK, uh...
maybe the murder
occurs around here,
probably in the heat
of the moment.
Killer panics,
sees this as
the best possible way
to dispose
of a body,
hopes it gets carted away
before it's discovered.
What do you think?
Sounds good to me.
Your partner comin' back
anytime soon?
A couple of weeks.
Let's go.
Hey. The kids ready?
I might have to drop 'em
back off early.
My money's been frozen.
What?!
Checking, savings,
debit card.
I can't even buy
groceries.
Shit.
I'm sorry. L...
I just need some time.
Right now,
I can't be around you,
and neither
can the kids.
It's not me,
it's the lawyer.
I was the one who told you
to hire
the asshole, remember?
To protect you.
In order
to do that,
I have to create a pattern
of distancing myself from you.
Listen, it's
only temporary
until you sort
these legal matters out.
Hey, sweetheart. Hi.
You should go.
Please.
Mom's been crying
all morning.
Look. At least let me
give you some cash.
No, Vic. Vic, Vic, Vic,
I can't. I'm sorry.
Look, we're gonna
sort this all out.
We will. We'll figure
something else out.
OK?
If you need me,
I'll be at work.
Hey, captain?
Captain, this is
detective Hoffman.
He had an incident with
officer Hanlon last night.
You got an office somewhere
where I can bitch...
in private?
I like hangin'
with my cops.
We can talk here.
Tina failed to identify Hoffman
as an undercover officer.
First, she nearly
blew my head off,
then she allowed
the perp to escape.
He was clearly wearing
the color of the day.
Julien put a report
on your desk
this morning.
We'll take
all necessary steps
to ensure this doesn't
happen again.
You know,
I live with lowlifes,
smelling
like piss and shit
so guys like you don't have
to get your suits dirty.
I get enough guns
to my head
without barbie
adding to the action!
You expect me
to fire her?
Look, I've tried
with Tina, sir.
So has Julien.
She doesn't get it.
She never will,
until it's too late.
Look, she's a woman,
latina besides.
There's like 3 hoops
to jump through to can her.
OK, well, you know what?
She's gonna land herself or
someone else in a body bag.
Look, your girl
saw this color,
not the color
on my arm.
Right, you handle it
any way you like.
Look, being captain's
about tough choices.
I'll take care of it.
Hey, man.
Hey, Vic.
Any asshole
sightings today?
Not... not yet.
Guess even rats
have to sleep.
Isn't it
your day off?
Uh, my kids got sick.
Wanted to see if you
had anything juicy
I could sink
my teeth into.
Uh, there's, uh,
some new chicken pot pies
in the quick-mealer.
What about that loan shark
over on clinton?
Newman and his team
still set up on him?
Well, he cut a deal.
We got 2 to 6.
Uh, Vic,
there's a girl
who's been waitin' to meet
you or one of your guys.
All right,
give me a second.
What about that dealer
on the decks?
What's his name?
Felonious t.
Intel says he's hangin'
up his dealer hat,
been busy makin'
a documentary
of the streets
or some shit.
I can't wait
to see that, huh?
Yeah.
You lookin' for me?
You Mackey?
Antwon Mitchell needs
a sit-down with you.
That dickhead sent you?
Gave me a message.
Stand up and put your
hands against the wall.
Sh... go to hell.
Your incarcerated old man
wants to fly a kite?
Let 'er rip.
Told me to ask you
what you willin'
to put on the table.
For what?
To keep your boy
Curtis alive.
Stop playing games
or you're gonna get
matching
his and hers cells.
Your cop buddy's
headed for Lompoc.
Gonna be in the same cell
block with Antwon real soon.
Horseshit.
Ask the other cop,
the big brother.
He made the deal
with Antwon.
Kavanaugh?
Even a douche bag
like Kavanaugh
wouldn't jump into bed
with Antwon Mitchell.
God knows what kind
of diseases you'd get.
Ask him.
But do it quick.
Antwon
don't like waitin'.
Said, make sure you know
the offer of protection
ain't out there for long.
Well,
you can tell Antwon
I'll put a bullet in that
fat head of his myself
before I'll let him
kill another cop.
Tell him yourself.
Sounds like it's
just a matter of time
before you follow
your boy inside.
Get the hell
out of here.
Get your hands off!
You just givin' Antwon
more reason
to make it worse
on your boy.
Open it!
What do you got?
Nothing. Huh?
Your face is red.
You're back!
Well, what a pleasure
it is.
The doc said
another 2 weeks.
I can recuperate better
at my desk
than I can in my bed.
What are we working?
Your knee?
Knee, ankle...
the whole shebang.
I fell pretty hard.
What do we got?
Uh... dump job.
Artemis Cooke, 43,
black male,
shot in the face,
stuffed in a dumpster.
And no next of kin?
Uh, mother.
I've got her upstairs.
Come on.
Pick up the pace.
Artemis was always
hard-working.
All sorts of jobs.
Where was he working now?
Ambulance company.
Drove body organs
to canada.
Company paid him
to paint his van up.
Very professional.
Uh... body organs?
You know, they take 'em
just before you die,
give 'em to people
who need 'em.
You mean donor organs?
I guess they have
a big need up north.
You can ask
his buddy, DeKnight.
He helps him
load up sometimes.
Your attempts to drive a
wedge between me and my guys
include
planning a murder?
Just looking
for my salad.
Somebody took it.
Why don't you just
find out who did it,
send him to prison to be
killed by Antwon Mitchell?
What's that make you,
servin' Lem up
to some cop killer?
Just like
you served Terry up?
Terry was a snake,
just like you.
Oh. So you did know that
Terry was workin' for justice.
You told me
about it yourself.
I'm done with cryin'
about him
gettin' killed
by two-time,
no matter how many weepy
relatives you bring by.
Had a conversation
with Antwon Mitchell.
Very illuminating,
especially as it relates
to shane Vendrell.
Is your neck
a little sore?
Excuse me?
From the noose...
tightening.
You send Lem to Lompoc,
it's you that's
the real murderer.
If the 4 of you
come completely clean,
I will let you
pick the prison.
No deal?
Well, I guess you're
not as concerned
for his safety
as you claim.
Anyway, there's
nothing on paper
as to where Lemansky
will end up.
But I'm sure I'll have
a recommendation
when the time comes.
That being said,
any correctional facility
is dangerous for a cop.
Best thing to do
is play by the rules,
and stay out of jail.
Streets can be
real dangerous, too.
Are we leveling
threats, detective?
Just making
random observations,
same as you.
Here's another one.
You're bluffin',
trying to split us up.
You're Mr. Straight
arrow, right?
Couldn't even cut your
poor, sick-in-the-head,
defenseless ex-wife a
break from the rules.
Could ya?
You don't have the stomach
to serve Lem up to Antwon.
I didn't used to.
Excuse me.
I worked for
Artemis at the plant.
That donor thing was
something he got on his own.
Don't know
much about it.
Seems weird.
Usually organs have to be
transplanted within hours.
Take a hell of a lot longer
to drive to canada.
Wouldn't you think
they'd fly 'em?
Maybe it's
low priority organs
like fingers or tongues.
I'm gonna go out
on a limb here.
Artemis was not running
fingers and tongues
back and forth
to vancouver, was he?
Whatever he was runnin'
got him shot in the face.
Shit. He's dead?
Found him in a dumpster
like common trash.
He was runnin'
some cush,
some sort of
super weed.
You get anywhere
near this shit,
the contact high would
knock you out for a week.
He made 8 grand
a run.
And that makes him
invaluable.
He have any beefs
with anyone?
Hell, no.
Everybody loved art.
He drove
that van into L.A.
Full of
the good tree,
it was like Santa Claus
was comin' to town.
We've got a guy upstairs,
needs a ride home.
OK. No problem.
Is she OK?
She says she's 100%.
I'm not gonna
argue the point.
When I get
my 6 weeks,
I'm gonna forget
this place even exists.
Yeah.
Hi there.
Oh, let me guess.
You're here to give me
shit about something.
What? No. I, uh...
these... these have been
floating around.
Thought you should know.
Jesus Christ!
The door was locked.
How'd they...
I barely glanced, just
enough to identify you.
Apparently, some asshole put
a camera in the locker room.
So every jerk-off
in the Barn's
been staring
at my tits?
Hey, you can't let
their high school mentality
get to you.
They'll get their kicks,
then move on to somebody else.
Shit.
I think
I'm gonna get fired.
I screwed up
at a call last night.
That's why
I'm stuck in here.
We all make mistakes.
Even I've been known to make
one or two, occasionally.
I wore those bra
and panties 2 days ago.
The red ones
the day before.
That's something
to go on.
I'm gonna find out
who took these.
I'm gonna see that
every picture's destroyed.
OK.
Thanks for being
such a gentleman.
We're not all neanderthals.
I should
probably keep those.
Stick 'em in a drawer
for evidence.
Oh...
we don't have
anything planned.
I'm resigning my position
as a reserve officer.
So now you no longer
can compel my cooperation
by threatening
to take my badge.
It's all yours.
That's not necessary.
You should also know
that as vice-chair
of the police committee,
I'm launching an investigation
into your investigation.
Really?
Yeah.
And why after tens
of thousands of dollars,
you have nothing more now
than you had 7 months ago.
I got Lemansky in custody.
Yeah, on 7-month-old
charges.
I got 65,000
unaccounted for dollars,
courtesy of Mackey's wife.
I got Mackey's assets
frozen,
along with every member
of the Strike Team.
And I've got
Antwon Mitchell talking.
You're getting Mackey
panicked,
hoping he'll
overplay his hand.
Something I hoped
you could help me with.
Nicely done, by the way,
stompin' in here like that.
That was good.
I liked that.
You're trying to get
Mackey running to me?
What? "the enemy of my enemy
is my friend?"
Well, forget it.
It won't happen.
He and his boys,
they were in business
with Antwon Mitchell.
These guys,
they're desperate.
They're gonna need
a friend in a high place,
like you.
All right.
I'll hold off
on my investigation...
for now.
Walk out angry.
Mackey's watching.
Vic, you got a sec?
Barely.
You ever hear
of a canadian super pot?
What, are you lookin'
to buy a dime bag?
Dump job this morning was
driving vans full of the stuff
down from vancouver.
You know any locals
plugged into that route?
Probably.
You guys have the van?
Still lookin'.
Might be a robbery.
I'm just lookin'
for a few names.
Well, seein'
as you and Claudette's
wonder twin powers
aren't fully activated yet,
I'll do you a favor,
pick up the slack
on this one.
OK, thanks.
All right, let me
shake the One-Niner tree,
see if any 5-pointed
leaves fall out.
That prick cut a deal
with Antwon Mitchell.
Wants to send Lem to Lompoc
if he gets a conviction.
What?
That's why Kavanaugh knows
so much about you and Antwon.
He's hopin' the threat
will get Lem talkin'.
That's not exactly playin'
by the rules.
Means we don't either.
If he puts Lem in
with Mitchell...
I know.
Yo, cuz.
Shit. Let's go.
This 5-o is hitler.
You miss us?
Not especially.
Ha. Antwon's cuttin'
deals over in Lompoc,
shorin' up
the power structure.
If it don't
involve the street,
it don't involve me.
Or maybe you're part of
Antwon's restructuring.
Nice try.
But me and
the big guy's tight.
You really expect
me to believe
he's lettin' you
call the shots out here?
He can't do it.
Somebody's
got to, right?
Antwon know you're recruiting
out of middle school?
Most of the old guard hung
it up after Antwon left.
This is the new regime.
Any of your students runnin'
chronic down from canada?
Let's take a ride.
What, shootin' me
wasn't enough?
Tell me what
we want to know,
or we're gonna be back in
your life again full-time.
All right.
Dude with a fancy
French name,
he runs most of the bud
to the crews.
Best shit in years.
What's frenchy's name?
Dijon.
Get back to class.
Porkchop's stuck
on street duty.
He knows where
the pot comes from,
but Antwon's cut him out
of the inner circle,
the decision making.
You thinking
regime change?
Well, it's somethin'
to keep an eye on.
Dude, sweet pictures.
What pictures?
It's OK. I'm cool.
You think Tina's panties
are regulation?
Just wish we could have
seen her badge.
Just between you and me,
how'd you
pull it off?
Shit, I'm not a perv.
I found 'em
on Billings' desk.
Anyone make copies?
What do you think?
Anyway, thanks
for sharin' 'em with me.
The way you stare
at that chick,
would've been
cruel not to.
You had the irs
freeze my money.
Sorry.
That is unfortunate.
Sorry?
You did it.
Yes.
I did everything
that you asked.
I told you
about the money.
Now I can't
feed my children.
You told me
about $65,000.
Now I'm hearing
there may be more.
A lot more.
Please.
You think I would default
on my children's tuition
if there was more?
I hate that this
is hurting you,
but I'm building
walls around Vic...
to stop him
from slitherin' away,
and you, you're
one of those walls.
I'm not a wall.
I'm a mother.
And... and I'm disconnecting
Vic from my life
and from the kids,
so leave us out of this.
Are you aware
that I arrested
Curtis Lemansky
2 days ago?
He's in county, waiting
for Vic and his friends
to bail him out.
If they don't have
the money,
they can't do it.
And every minute
that Lem spends inside,
I'm just a minute closer
to gettin' at the truth.
That has nothing
to do with me!
My advice is
to go to Vic yourself,
ask him to confess.
You want your life back,
ask him, not me.
What did I do
to deserve this?
You married
the wrong man, Corrine.
Now, I'm not doing this because
that cowboy called me out.
Of course not.
I got 2
of my finest officers
telling me
that Tina's gotta go.
Look, every day
that she's out there,
she's putting people
at risk.
She's just
so damn popular.
I can call
her pba rep.
OK. Get him
down here asap.
Julien, I want a full
report of her conduct.
You're goin'
on the record.
Yes, sir.
Thanks, guys.
What's up?
Shit.
Where'd you get these?
They're circulating.
They were on my desk.
Is nothing sacred?
You're asking me?
Come here.
I put a nanny cam
in the locker room.
People have been ripping off
the vending machines.
I was just trying to catch
whoever was doin' it.
You could've put
a camera in the hallway,
over the machines.
Well, not where
it could be hidden.
And I think whoever's
stealing this grub
is stashin' it
in their locker.
I pulled these photos
and some others
so that they wouldn't
get into the wrong hands.
You know
this only happened,
because I don't have a
goddamn private office anymore.
Do you have any idea what kind
of shitstorm you're lookin' at
when she finds out you're
behind these photos?
She saw them?
You told her?
She had a right to know.
I just promised
to wash her out.
You think he's gonna
take care of that baby?
He's not.
I have no idea what...
you think he's
gonna be a father?
Who the father is
none of your business.
Really? It's
none of my business
that my kids are gonna get
a new brother or sister?
Uh, I'm at work
right now, OK?
This isn't the place.
Right. Come find me
later.
You managed to find
someone to screw at work.
Why not talk
about it here, too?
I'm gonna walk away
from you right now
because you're obviously
not being rational.
Really? Were you
being rational
when you slept
with a married man?
He made that vow,
not me.
Which makes him a cheat,
but that makes you
a whore
and the baby you're
both having a bastard.
You Dijon?
I didn't do nothin',
if that's what you mean.
Nice threads.
We hear you got the best
b.c. Bud in Farmington.
Hey.
What?
White guys can't get
the good stuff?
Or you only sell
to bangers?
That's discrimination.
I got nothin'.
Look around.
OK.
You took
a hit today.
We're offering you
a chance to get it back.
Whoa.
Run that by me again.
Your canadian organ
express got taken down.
Your driver got killed,
supply ripped off.
We can get it
back for you
for a finder's fee.
Why?
Don't worry
about that.
Hundred grand,
no questions asked.
Oh, yeah. That's right.
Only a matter of time before
the detectives on the murder case
follow the phone records
back to you
and your monthly
pot runs.
But... you work with us,
we see to it that the
trail ends with Artemis.
And I keep the rest.
It's a hell of a lot better
than nothin', isn't it?
All right.
The only thing is it wasn't
my shipment that got jacked.
It was my cash.
Artemis was on his way
up to canada.
How much did you lose?
Quarter million.
You get it back,
I'll cut you
the hundred gs in.
Uh-uh. We don't
trust you.
We'll take our fee up
front as a down-payment.
Are you crazy?
I'm out of pocket
on this.
Everything I got
was invested
in that run.
Jesus Christ, man.
This is just a waste of time.
No, it's not.
Deal's a deal.
Put together a list
of every customer,
anybody who would've known
about Artemis's run.
Dirty yourself up.
We need you to play
the ignorant friend
for some colleagues
of ours.
Yo Asher.
Upstairs.
America's
favorite couple
wants to have
a little chat with him.
Sure thing.
I'm tellin' you,
my intel's good.
Artemis was flyin' solo.
His buddy's got some details
about his criminal dealings.
Well, let's see what's up
between these two.
I'll be right up.
Lem?
I finally got
some phone time in,
so, uh,
what's goin' on?
Am I getting
out of here today?
I'm workin' on it.
Hang on.
Hello?
Hey, it's Vic. I'm gonna
put you on with Lem.
Hold on.
All right.
You guys both on?
Yeah.
I'm here.
All right, Lem, you're
talkin' to your lawyer,
Becca Doyle, in case there
are other ears on this call.
Whoa. You can't use me as
cover for anything illegal.
What I'm about to tell Lem,
you need to hear, too.
What is it?
All right,
the good news first.
We got a lead
on some bail money for you.
How?
Callin' in
a few favors.
All right. Look, man,
I know you got my back.
What's the bad news?
Kavanaugh has been
sittin' down
with Antwon Mitchell.
He made some sort of deal
to send you to Lompoc
in case
there's a conviction.
No goddamn way!
That's insane.
He doesn't make those calls.
Look, it's never
gonna get that far.
We're gonna
get you out of there,
then we're gonna get you
out from under this prick.
Do you know this?
Kavanaugh
said those words?
He'd never admit it,
but it's real.
All it means is Kavanaugh
knows he's got Jack shit on us,
and he's gettin'
desperate.
All right, I hear you.
I hear you.
Vic, you comin' or not?
Yeah, hang on.
All right,
listen, I gotta go.
You stay safe,
all right?
OK, yeah.
Dutchman.
Uh, I'm in
the middle of something.
I got it, Dutchboy.
You know I was on the up
and up taking those photos.
Tell the chief.
If Tina makes a stink
about this,
maybe she'll get
a huge pile of cash,
but her career
will be kaput.
You know how
these things wash out.
Well, I don't know what you
expect me to do about it.
I have a plan.
This thing goes away,
everybody wins, including you.
No, thanks.
You can either be
a hero in Tina's eyes,
or you can watch her and
her red bra and panties
march out
that Barn door forever.
He's full of it.
He probably is a member
of the weed ring,
but why kill
your own driver?
I really don't think
he was involved.
If this guy is funding
Artemis's run,
he'll never cooperate.
He'll want to recover
the money himself.
Or Artemis is workin' solo.
Your intel hasn't been
what it used to be.
Fine. I'll see what else
I can squeeze out of him.
What'd I miss?
What the hell did you
bring him into this for?
I thought we could use
a little muscle.
Brains over brawn,
Dutch.
How many times
I gotta tell you that?
Move it, asshole.
Don't need to keep
sellin' it so hard, do you?
Your list of customers
got us nowhere.
The only thing these bangers
want more that ass and cash
is some of your
top grade canadian bud.
They know a good thing
when they smoke it.
Yeah, well, if I
don't find the guy
who knocked
over your van,
you'll be hangin' up
a closed sign.
Who else besides
your customers knows
about the runs?
Just my wife
and my dumbass stepson.
How old is he?
He's 20.
What's his name?
Jaden reid.
He drove the route for me
a couple of times
till I noticed the load
kept comin' back light.
Punk don't know
the meaning of high enough.
Where is he now?
Who knows?
He gonna send his mama
to an early grave.
Does your wife know
where Jaden is?
She got no clue.
You never know.
Blood is thicker
than bong water.
Kid's name
is Jaden reid.
Think he's
our shooter.
Let's pay Jaden
a little visit.
First,
we gotta find him.
Kid's a Burnout.
Now he's got
enough cash
to keep him stoned
for a long time.
And enough cash
for us to spring Lem.
So where do we start?
Unis found
the abandoned van
in a parking lot
in silverlake.
Lots of blood, no cash.
If I had
a bagful of money,
I wouldn't want to walk
too far with it.
Check out
the local weed dealers.
He had the cash,
he'd want to score.
What about Claudette?
We're still a step
ahead of her,
and she seems
2 steps slow.
Let's find this kid before she
figures out anything else, OK?
Yeah. Got it.
Got a hit on the
fingerprints in the van.
Belongs to
a Jaden reid.
Address?
Last known, his mother's,
Tasha Reynolds.
What's up?
Got a suspect...
Jaden reid.
According to the file, he's
your friend Dijon's stepson.
Nice work.
We're gonna check out
an address.
Why don't we let
some unis pick him up?
Well,
they can join us.
Dutch is right.
Why don't you let me and my
guys handle sweep-up duty?
You can join us, too,
if you want.
Mrs. Reynolds, when
was the last time you saw Jaden?
Couple months.
Look, he's a good kid.
There's no way he'd be involved
in anything like this.
Dutch, uh, why don't you have
Dijon show you where Jaden stays
when he's here?
Sure.
Um... lead the way.
Mrs. Reynolds, I know you're
worried about your son,
but he could be
in trouble,
and not just from us.
He wouldn't kill no one.
Then help us find him
so we can clear
this mess up
and keep Jaden
from being hurt.
He has a girl.
I don't like her.
She lives by that
old theater on sunset.
Got an address?
2409 Cole street
by the vista theater.
Jaden's there.
Uh, 2409 Cole.
Yeah, we got it.
How far out are you?
Uh, traffic,
15 minutes maybe. Why?
Because Dutch and Claudette
are on the way over there, too.
Just get inside the house,
find the money,
and get out of there, fast!
Well,
how far are they?
Same as you.
Jesus. What
if they catch us?
I mean, we've got
the day off, remember?
Just get there!
I'll make it work.
OK, park it
and let's go.
Yeah? Where?
Claudette
knows this truck.
Well,
check around back.
Come on, man! Move!
It's locked, man.
I'll get the front.
2 minutes. That's it,
then we're gone.
No arguments here.
God damn it.
Let's forget it.
We're outta here.
Wait, wait, wait.
Wait.
Oh, shit!
Shit. Is he dead?
No. No, it's just
a damn good buzz.
Oh, you gotta be
kiddin' me.
He's sleepin'
on the money.
Oh, shit!
Grab it!
Yeah, we're good.
We're good.
Come on. Let's go.
Hey!
You take him,
I'll clear the back!
Clear.
Looks like
we got our shooter.
Come on, buddy, wake up.
Party's over.
Somebody took my money.
You won't need
any where you're goin'.
He cut me out.
He didn't have to do that.
I didn't want
to hurt nobody.
Hey, you shot him
in the face 3 times.
We should probably
wait until he sobers up.
We can't use anything
he says right now anyway,
his state.
All that money was his.
All that bud, his.
I want to know why you
ain't goin' after him.
Artemis?
You killed him and took the
money belonging to Artemis?
Artemis?
I was drivin'
for Dijon...
it was his shit.
He fired me.
I'm his stepson. What
kind of shit is that?
You really dialed a wrong
number on your street intel.
Still don't have any
evidence against Dijon,
and his hazy memory
ain't gonna get you far, either.
Jaden says somebody broke
into his girlfriend's apartment
and took the money.
What's our next move?
It's my day off.
I helped you
catch the killer.
Finding the money's
your problem.
Hey, Smitty.
Haven't seen
you guys in a while.
It's been nice.
Yeah, well, it's
about to get a lot nicer.
How'd you like
to make 100 grand?
Pass.
Hear us out.
The shit I've done for
you guys for peanuts,
I don't
even want to know
what 100 grand
looks like.
Looks a lot easier
than you think.
Lem's in jail.
You're gonna put up
100 gs for his bail.
You expect me
to just give you 1oo k?
We're gonna
give it to you.
And when Lem shows up
in court,
you're gonna keep it.
And the catch is?
IAD is gonna
ask you about it.
They might want to
look at your books.
You business is
profitable lately, right?
Very.
How'd those leads we gave
you last year work out?
Great. Could always
use a few more.
How many jobs does it take
you to clear 100 grand?
Why you guys always comin'
to me with this shit?
Because you're
the last honest guy we know.
Hey.
We found someone
willing to post bail.
An old friend
came through.
Kavanaugh will be looking
into that old friend.
Nothing to find.
He likes Lem.
I'll see if I can
wake up a clerk,
get things
fast-tracked.
Thanks.
What? What is it?
I'm stuck here.
I don't want to convince
you all to turn on Lem,
and I don't want to
convince him to turn on you,
but that's what
a good lawyer
would be advising all
of you to do right now.
l...
I don't want to see
any of you
going to prison.
Well,
that's nice to know.
Right now, I think
I'd make a better friend
than a lawyer.
Lem...
Lem needs you right now.
And we sure can't afford
to hire someone else.
If you have to make a
choice, you go with Lem.
And advise him
to hurt you? L...
if you can make a deal that has
me switching places with Lem,
you do it.
Just me.
None of my guys.
I want to see you
get your second chance.
Already have.
On behalf
of the entire department,
I'd like to apologize
for the wrong done to you.
The captain learned
about the photos
earlier this afternoon
and came to me.
Did you find
the dickwad, or what?
Unfortunately, no.
The identity of
the culprit's a mystery.
Great. So where
does that leave me?
During the course
of our conversation,
I mentioned
to the captain
thay I've seen you have
some really great instincts,
and he agreed that you have
a lot of potential.
And potential
needs to be nourished.
I've asked
special permission
to take you
under my wing,
show you
the detective ropes
in your spare time.
Unless these photos
have you too upset
to focus
on career advancement.
I see.
So I keep my mouth shut,
I climb the ladder.
Dutch is just offering
an opportunity.
Did you get rid
of the rest of them?
Every last one.
I look forward to working
with you, detective.
Thanks, captain.
Prisoner all clear for release.
Hey, hey!
Told you
we'd get you out!
Hey!
It looks like
your hymen's still intact.
Gonna have to get your own
pussy tonight, though, buddy.
Ahh!
Where's Vic at, man?
He's, uh...
he had someplace
he's gotta be.
He's gonna
meet us later.
Come on, man, let's go
grab a beer. Come on.
- Smitty's buyin'.
- I am?
Yes.
One round.
What are you doing here?
Kavanaugh,
he's out of control.
He's unbalanced.
He's breaking
the rules.
He's threatening
Lem's life.
Hey, IAD is your problem,
not mine.
The look on your face walkin' out
of his office today says otherwise.
He's got screws
in you, too, yeah?
I, uh...
I'm an element
in Kavanaugh's investigation.
Price I pay for having
been your boss.
But I'm hardly in the same
category as you and your guys.
Really?
You think if Kavanaugh's
successful,
I'm gonna go down
quietly?
Ha ha...
I will scorch the earth
covering this whole department,
starting with you.
I can tie you
to every bullshit thing
Kavanaugh's accusing
me of, and then some.
Your stink will smell up every
voting booth in this city.
On the other hand...
you want that little nameplate on
your desk to read "mayor" someday?
We work together.
Make sure that
you, me, my team,
are the last men
standing
long enough to go
our separate ways.
What's your plan?
Subtitles:
FRM-xxy & Lemonhead
www.1000fr.com
www.theshield-laserie.com