Previously on The Shield...
She fainted. She was
out before she fell.
Vic gave me some cash
in a bag.
How much?
$65,000.
I need that money back.
I was talking
to Kavanaugh.
He was wearing
a wedding ring.
He's been divorced
about two years.
Heard of a guy
named Antwon Mitchell?
I know Mackey
and his guys
have some connection
with Antwon Mitchell.
Her body shows up
with bullets in it.
You'll be doing time
for a long, long time.
Waste your time with
these conspiracy theories
and you'll be more lost
than you are now.
About 6 months ago,
we found this kilo.
Pure heroin, in the glove
compartment of your car,
but you never logged it
into evidence.
Why hasn't he arrested
Lem yet?
You think Kavanaugh's going to
try to get Emolia to give you up?
You're not safe.
We got to move you.
Why? What happened?
Possible leaks.
You said Vic
wouldn't find out.
Vic, what the hell?
You didn't return
my calls.
Kavanaugh,
what did you tell him?
That I saw your guy
take the heroin.
Six months you could
have warned me!
One of my men,
maybe all of us,
are going to jail
because of you.
Without you,
IAD's case goes away.
Jesus, it's you.
Antwon Mitchell.
Well,
you're the right color.
For some reason,
I feel that, uh,
you're working on the
wrong side, brother.
Jon Kavanaugh,
Internal Affairs,
Los Angeles.
Really? What part?
Lately I've been
based in Farmington.
Don't tell me
you have officers
stealing ghetto kids'
bicycles
and taking their candy.
Come on,
say it ain't so, Joe.
You recognize these gentlemen, I know.
I need to know everything
you know about these men.
You want everything.
I just need something.
The pope himself couldn't
get you mercy time
on those
two cop killings.
Let's just say I'm trying
to keep hope alive, then.
I can see what I can do about your
accommodations and privileges here.
I run
this goddamn place.
What is it you think
I'm not getting up in here?
Pussy?
I tore some of that shit up
this morning,
and I'm not talking
about the cellmate kind.
You're obviously
no friend of cops.
Here's your chance
to put four of them
in a dark, dark corner.
See, now you're venturing
into an interesting area.
But I can't feed my peeps
with no moral victories.
How do I know you have
shit on these guys?
Shane vendrell.
I could bury this
banjo-playing asshole.
Bitch likes to talk...
the walk,
but if you put
a boot on his throat,
his eyes tear up
like a little bitch.
And bitches, they give up their buddies.
That's what
makes them bitches.
The price is simple.
I help you put away
these four fine young men,
you make sure you put
them away right here.
You want them
to spend their time
here?
That way, every morning
I can see
their smiling faces
when I'm eating
my oatmeal.
So you can kill them.
You got me
all wrong, mister.
Scout's honor.
No deal.
You know my name.
If your brain clears up,
give me a collect call.
Sorry you wasted a drive,
Jon.
What was it...
3, 4 hours?
You forget...
time's on my side.
That's where you're wrong.
You see, me...
I'm just living
one real long day.
You're the one who has the
ticking clock in his ear.
Otherwise,
you wouldn't be here
talking to a man like me.
If you change your mind,
give me a call.
Handle code 3,
1-Tango-10,
roger that.
6-Paul-11 to control, I'm
code 6 at 5029 King Drive.
We're going to need
additional units
for evacuation
and a bomb squad.
You're not going
to believe this,
but someone tossed a bunch of
grenades into a backyard barbecue.
Did you say grenades?
Yeah, live grenades.
Hey, what up?
You here
on IAD business,
or you just visiting
the front?
Just tell me what happened,
all right?
Backyard barbecue.
Somebody tossed 4 or 5
grenades over the fence.
M-26. Vietnam era,
time delay.
That one's a dud.
All clear.
Vic, let's go.
Victims?
Spookstreet Soldiers.
A local black set.
Friends, girlfriends.
Kids.
Hey, I, uh...
found this
in the house.
Already cut, bagged, and weighed.
It's a Spookstreet
distribution crib.
Gang retaliation?
If Spookstreet was beefing
with someone, we'd have heard of that.
Local sets round here don't carry
this kind of heavy artillery.
You might want
to stand back.
There's some real police
work going on around here.
Take this around front?
Sure.
Kyle, thanks, man.
No problem, Jon.
You said you got a call, last week,
from an old salvadorian contact.
Offered you a job
assembling grenades?
Last week you said
I was a liar.
You've been feeding me a lot
of bullshit stories lately,
trying to get out of
testifying against Mackey.
Cut this for her.
Bunch of grenades
went off today.
Maybe now
you'll listen to me.
I need you to tell me
what's going on.
You want information?
Then promise me
I won't have to testify
against Vic or his guys.
We've been
over this already.
You not testifying
against Mackey,
it's not going
to happen.
You're cutting
the pieces too big.
The only thing
keeping you out of jail
and Sebastio out of a
foster home is my good grace.
You tell me what you
know about those grenades
or the next person
cutting this food
is going to be
a social worker.
Owner of the Spookstreet
house that got bombed...
name is Latasha Dunn.
Son's name
is Marcus Dunn.
Street name's
Mc Dunn-Good.
Dunn-Good's
a Spookstreet lieutenant.
You and Ronnie go
scoop him up. All right.
Vic.
My CI has intel.
It's the salvadorians.
I think she can help.
Emolia's friend Maria
contacted her last week.
Salvadorians
were looking for girls
to assemble a large
shipment of grenades.
You heard about this
and didn't share it with anyone?
We've all seen his nose
for quality intel
is not exactly reliable.
She gave me tips
before.
Most of them
were bogus.
Your main witness against Lem
is unreliable?
That's good to know.
All right,
so what now?
My team will set up a meeting
between Emolia and Maria.
We'll work backward
to the grenade tossers.
You're not putting her
in the field.
It's too dangerous.
She just told us there's
another shipment coming in.
You want every night here
to be the 4th of july?
All right.
Your team can run
the investigation.
But any decisions
involving Emolia,
I have the final word.
I make all the calls.
Neither Vic nor his team will
have any unsupervised contact
with Emolia.
They do anything on the sly
to threaten or coerce her,
I'll pull her immediately.
Either myself
or agent Erwin
will be with her
at all times.
All right?
Do it.
KAVANAUGH
Look, we can deal
with other stuff tomorrow.
What's important today is that
we track down these grenades.
Your safety... that's
my number one priority.
You may have
all worked out a deal,
but I haven't.
You want my help,
I want to know
what's in it for me?
What we talked about.
I need $20,000.
For Sebastio
to get help.
Like Vic's kid gets.
Let's talk
about this later.
No... now.
This department's
always looked out for you.
You help us crack this,
there'll be something
there for you.
Maria says the bosses are
shipping grenades into L.A.
They assemble them here,
otherwise they could
explode during shipping.
They're looking
for cutters,
help put them
back together.
Nimble-fingered girls
they can trust.
Why do the salvadorians
need grenades?
They're making a play
to get back into
the drug protection
business.
The colombians
control the drugs.
They use the mexicans
to mule it from Bogota
into the black dealers'
hands in L.A.
The salvadorians
used to protect all of it...
mules, routes,
distribution centers...
until we busted a
general Bonilla last year.
Crippled their
L.A. power base.
Colombians exporting blow
figured
if the salvadorians
couldn't protect themselves,
why pay them
to protect their product?
So they're finding a way
back into the business.
Extortion.
Right.
Hope it's not too late
for you to get that job.
No.
But I need
to call Maria.
Let's set up a meeting.
Lieutenant.
How's your partner?
Getting better.
Getting back soon.
Glad to hear it.
You, uh, finding anything
on the strike team?
Their investigation's
on-going.
You checking into
their finances?
Their money?
If you're not looking,
you should be.
What will I find?
Not here. Later.
And don't talk to me out there
like we're friendly.
Kyle, what's...
What's going on?
Why's Emolia moving?
Emolia's contact made
a last-minute change,
moved the meeting.
Ok, follow her.
Mackey disagrees.
Thinks the contact might
have eyes out for a tail.
Think I care
what he thinks.
She's wired up. She's got
GPS tracking on her cell.
She's got eyes and ears
on her at all times.
I never authorized
the use of a wire.
I know how much
you love them.
Figured I'd try one
for a change.
Give them
a 5-minute head start.
Then we follow.
Oh, great.
Kavanaugh's coming.
Nothing like a large
black man wearing a suit
jumping in your van
to maintain your cover.
Is she ok?
No reason why
she wouldn't be.
This the place
we do the work?
Not yet.
There's someone who
needs to meet you first.
Tejado runs security,
Guardo is in charge.
Come on.
Guardo...
Ready?
Hmm, venga abentro chiquita.
Dejame verte. ¿Eres buena o mala?
I don't use.
I check
every girl I hire.
This isn't the same
as H-cutting.
You need cojones,
quick fingers.
One mistake,
your face is blown off.
First, you reset
the striker.
Then the fuse head.
Attach this spoon.
He's assembling
a live one.
Put the striker
in place,
inserting
the safety pin.
Once you remove the pin
and the handle's released,
you have 5 seconds to put
the spoon and the pin back
before it explodes.
There's a live
grenade in there?
Catch.
Jon, it's ok.
He's bluffing.
That grenade wasn't armed.
You never lost your nerve.
Tejado will call you
with instructions.
Let you know when and
where to start working.
Come on. Let's go.
How did you know
he was bluffing?
Because once
you've pulled the pin,
there's no turning back.
He knew it wasn't live.
Let's move,
make the bust.
It's too early,
we bust them now,
we only got a couple of
players off the street.
There'll still be
grenades out there.
We squeeze Tejado
and Guardo
and then
they give it up.
Fresh off the boat,
salvadorians rarely rat.
They'll take a needle
before they talk to cops.
We follow Guardo.
Let him lead us
to the grenades.
They must be parked
out back.
Hey, hey...
Emolia's still up there.
If I don't move now,
I'll lose them.
Let's go.
We're not leaving
Emolia here.
All right, all right.
Make sure Emolia's
all right.
We'll find Guardo
on the street.
Vic, how'd it go?
They bought her cover.
You'll talk to police.
Wait up in observation.
Marcus Dunn,
aka Mc Dunn-Good.
His mother's house
was hit this morning.
Found a drug store
in his bedroom closet.
Hit the street. Find out
what you can about Guardo.
We'll take
Mc Dumbshit upstairs
and have a little chat.
Let's go.
Lieutenant, you got
a telephone call.
Take a message
for me, please.
They said it's urgent.
Who said?
Says her name's Sadie.
Excuse me.
Sadie?
Detective, I need you
to give me a ride
to the 300 block
of Forestry Street.
What's there?
Crime scene.
You'll be the primary.
I've got work, and you don't
hand out my assignments.
Do I have to remind you
how many rungs
detective falls
before lieutenant
on the department ladder?
You get your ass
out of that chair
and you meet me
in the motor pool
before I open an
insubordination file on you
and put your picture
up on my wall.
Come on!
I was only making sure
I wasn't too friendly to you
on the floor.
Come on, man.
I was just maintaining
your cop cred
with the other IAD haters.
You should be thanking me.
Next time I'd prefer
the silent treatment.
So...
Mackey's finances.
Ever hear of
an armenian money train?
It's a money laundering
operation
in the armenian mob.
I think the strike team
ripped them off.
Dangerous enemies to make.
Not if you
get away with it.
I think we're talking about
a lot of money.
Mackey gave his ex
65 grand in cash
they can't account for.
Corrine had nothing to do
with anything illegal.
This is all Vic.
Can I take a look
at your notes?
Sure.
Thanks.
So, what's this case?
I got a call
from my ex... Sadie.
She was just raped.
Breathe normally.
Jon...
Are you all right?
I don't know.
She was attacked.
Got out of the car, dragged to
the other side of the vehicle,
out of sight
of anyone passing by.
And no witnesses,
either.
We need to get her
to a hospital.
Right away.
I socked him.
I socked him
in the middle.
I fought back
like you taught me.
I hit him...
and I hit him...
and I hit him until he
got off me, and he ran.
I refused to be...
a victim... I know.
That's good.
This is detective Wagenbach.
He's going to be handling
this investigation, ok?
We'll take good care
of you, ma'am.
Did you get a good look
at your attacker?
Mexican.
Mid-30s,
dark eyes.
And a mole...
right here.
I took a picture of him
in my head
when I was fighting him.
I know, I know.
You did great.
These officers here are going
to take you to the hospital,
and they're going
to do some tests
to preserve evidence,
ok?
You're going
to be with me, right?
I'm going to ride with you
to the hospital,
then I got to check
on a few things.
Stay with me.
You need privacy.
You do.
Don't leave me.
Jon...
I'm going to be right back
after the tests are done, ok?
Ok?
You let me
take care of everything.
Look, we can
sit here all day, Marcus,
but that's not going
to change the fact
that you got
a big problem.
Yeah, I know.
The salvadorians
want back in
on the drug
protection business.
Now tell me some shit
I don't know.
Spookstreet's just
gonna sit on their hands
while they blow up
all your drug cribs?
It's time
to make peace.
I told you,
the bosses in Bogota
ain't going
to go for that.
The bosses aren't having
grenades shoved up their asses.
Colombians control the
product. They make the rules.
Ain't shit I can do
about that.
Give me the address
of the other drug cribs
so I can stop them
myself.
Right. How stupid do y'all think I am?
Don't ask a question
you don't want the answer to.
Y'all can keep sending
in the clowns all day,
it won't change shit.
Only one player in this room
has got any juice.
Hmmph.
How'd you get caught
this time, son?
It really matter?
Internal Affairs. It does
if I believe you.
You the one and only man.
Prove it.
District attorney
Eric Zuckerman.
Hello?
Eric, Jon Kavanaugh.
What's up, Johnny?
You hear about that house on
Farmington got hit by grenades?
Yeah, that's pretty
freaky shit, man.
Looks like salvadorian bangers
are planning to hit more.
That's not good.
I got a perp looking at a
possession with intent rap
willing to trade us
addresses and targets.
You let him skate
with just possession?
Write it up.
Send it to my office.
- Do you need any more?
- I trust you.
I'll talk to you later.
I'll be here, Johnny.
My nigga.
Give up the addresses.
Those cribs get busted
off my tip,
you might as well
stick a needle in me.
We'll give you half-hour
to call your homies,
get the merchandise out
before the cavalry arrives.
I use your phone?
Lieutenant.
Mrs. Mackey?
Jon, I helped Sadie
take a rape kit.
And?
Minor tearing and trauma.
Skin under her fingernails?
No, she said she punched
and didn't scratch.
DNA?
She fought him off
pretty quickly.
It's almost like...
Isn't a rape because it
didn't last that long?
No, this guy got
more than he bargained for.
She's a fighter.
Is she ok to come down
to the barn?
I'll have to ask
her doctor,
but I think so.
That way.
No, he had a mole
right here on his cheek.
You're doing good.
Just keep looking.
Yeah, don't worry.
Take your time.
Keep looking.
Hi.
How's it going?
We've been showing her
sexual assault regulars.
Nothing yet.
Can you excuse me
a second?
Just a second.
I'm trying.
You know what?
I'm going to get you
some clean clothes,
and I'm going to take you
to where I work, ok?
To get, you know...
cleaned up and everything.
Sadie, you know
I'm here for you, right?
Where's Emolia?
Inside.
There you are.
Why'd you
bring her here?
Uniforms pulled over a
salvadorian a block away
who fit Guardo's description.
Mackey wanted her here
to make a quick I.D.
She could have been
compromised!
You were off the grid, so
I made a command decision.
To get her killed?
That'd be great for you, wouldn't it?
You with her
every second?
Yeah.
He didn't try
to talk to her?
No.
So, what happened?
Four grenades were thrown through
four windows simultaneously.
The house was hit
on all sides.
A gas pipe exploded
in the kitchen.
Whoever tossed them
wanted to make sure
no one made it out
alive.
This isn't an address
Marcus Dunn gave us.
No, it isn't.
George and Maddie Jackson.
Retired school teachers.
So, it's not a Spookstreet drug crib.
Only drug we found
was metamucil.
Must have been napping when
the grenades came knocking.
So it looks like
killers went by a list?
An old list. We busted
this place last year.
Spookstreeter named Gat
used to bunk here
until Rawlings seized
and put her up for auction.
The salvadorians were protecting
Spookstreet product last year.
They'd know this place.
This is
an old drug crib.
Last year's.
Yeah. Salvadorians are
working on an out-of-date list.
How old a list
we talking about?
About a year.
Maybe two.
Make out as many
as you can remember.
I ain't got
a memory for this.
You can take him.
Sadie id'd a suspect out of
a mug book... Emmanuel Olivo.
Got him
in interrogation.
You seem to be unclear
on the concept
of parole, Emmanuel.
We give you
an early chance at freedom,
you return the favor
by not raping anyone.
Who's he?
Where were you
this morning at 10:00?
Filling out
job applications.
Where?
All around.
It's not that easy.
Got to report my status.
As a registered
sex offender.
Sure you didn't take a
break between references
to rape a woman
in a parking lot
off Forestry Street...
Hell, no.
Remember where you filled out
those applications?
Not the names.
It would help you
with an alibi.
Yeah, but I don't got it.
He's lying.
Can't you see that?
Yeah, but a couple things
bother me.
His previous sexual assaults
were against teenage girls,
not adult women.
That we know about.
Also, Sadie referenced
a mole a couple times.
Olivo doesn't have one.
He's one detail off.
You'll put him in front
of Sadie to make sure?
Yeah, I already
brought her down here.
Listen, about Sadie...
You ready, Vic?
What the... Shit!
Sadie,
I'll be right back.
Get her started,
all right?
Hey, hey!
Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Where are you going?
Emolia's contact
just called us.
They're assembling grenades
above a furniture store.
I used to cut H there.
They want me right away.
We'll drop her off, let
Guardo make the pickup,
then we'll sweep in
and bust this crew.
The list of Spookstreet
drug cribs
Marcus Dunn gave us...
You got that done
already?
Billings
is sending units
to clear out the tenants
that live there
and post cops
in front of each one.
Guardo won't be making
that pickup for hours.
Make sure Emolia
gets in safely.
And give me a call
if anything changes.
Yes, sir.
Someplace important
you need to be?
How are we doing?
Better.
Sadie positively identified
Emmanuel Olivo
as her attacker.
I'm proud of you.
You're so strong.
Can I, uh...
Yeah, excuse me.
Come home tonight.
No.
It's time to come home.
Our bed misses you.
Let me take care of you,
all right?
You got to stop
wearing that.
It doesn't feel
right.
Sadie...
Sadie.
Come home.
Don't keep asking.
'Cause at some point, I'm
going to say yes, and...
you know what kind of
trouble we'll be in.
Lieutenant?
Lieutenant Kavanaugh?
Excuse me for a second.
Can you give me
a minute?
I'm sorry.
Is she ok?
Yeah.
She's great.
Thank you.
Really.
I appreciate you
closing this up for me.
Um...
You don't know
how much I appreciate this.
It's not really closed.
Why didn't you tell me Sadie
has a history of mental illness?
You've been digging up
dirt on her?
Ok, ok. I've been investigating
the claims of a witness.
A victim!
A victim...
right, right.
But we have
no physical evidence.
Because she fought him off.
Ok, ok.
Right...
and we are...
we are all grateful
for that.
But it presents problems
if the case goes to trial.
You see?
She's our sole witness and she's
got a history of mental illness.
It's all in the past.
Ok.
How bad was it?
Years ago.
Had a rough patch.
She, uh...
Paranoia, psychosis.
Depression.
We're talking depression.
Dementia? Difficulty
understanding reality?
She always knew
who she was and where she was.
She just...
She just became...
different.
And now?
We got divorced
and she found some doctors,
they treated her.
She's fine.
She's back.
She's reliable?
Yes.
That's what I'm told.
She saw him?
Yes.
We don't have any
corroborating evidence.
Then why don't you get back
to the goddamn crime scene
with some extra hands
and find the evidence
that you require
to put the man that
raped my wife behind bars?
I have to stay?
Just a little longer.
Go upstairs. There's a
couch where you can lie down.
Go upstairs and lie down,
all right?
First door on your left.
I'll check on you
in a minute.
I'll be there
in a minute, ok?
Mrs. Mackey?
How is she?
She's fine.
Good. This is my attorney Sydney Driber.
Lieutenant Kavanaugh.
I made a promise to return
it, and it's all there.
File this into evidence
for me, please.
My client wishes to cooperate
fully with the investigation.
She never engaged
in criminal behavior.
She seeks immunity
against any prosecution
in exchange for what she knows
about her ex-husband's past.
Swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth...
Yes, yes.
Assuming an arrangement
can be made.
Did detective Wagenbach
arrange or suggest for you
to be the attending nurse
for Sadie tonight?
Either you're telling
the truth or you're not.
He suggested it. Ok?
He said if I helped her, it
might earn goodwill with you.
There is
nothing illegal
about
a registered nurse
caring
for a patient.
No. It's wrong.
Dutch didn't do
anything wrong.
He was trying
to help me out.
I don't have time
to discuss any deal,
even if I was
amenable to one,
which I will have to take
under consideration.
But I do thank you for
bringing in the money.
Kavanaugh. Yeah.
Guardo showed up early.
He's moving the girls
and the grenades.
Where's Emolia now?
Tracking her GPS.
We're all over her.
I want her
out of there.
Turned west on Stanley.
They're stopping.
We bust them now,
they'll tip
the other location.
This is a black hole
we're sending her into.
We know nothing!
Emolia knows how
to take care of herself.
She fooled me
for 6 months.
Are you trying
to get her killed? Huh?
Great. Glad we're
on the same page.
We might have to move in
quick and quiet.
Everyone turn off
their cell phones.
Where's S.W.A.T.?
You said S.W.A.T.
Was going to be here.
Should be here
any minute.
They got MP-5s.
At least two dozen.
Looks like they're planning
to set up shop permanently.
It's a goddamn armory
in there.
How long before back-up
and S.W.A.T. arrive?
10, 15 minutes tops.
Guardo,
we're short a grenade.
Are you sure?
I counted twice.
Stop... stop!
Search her.
Guardo.
I only was going
to sell it for money.
There's so many,
I didn't think you'd care.
What's going on?
It's hard to tell.
Check the others.
They're going
to find the wire.
Go, go! Get out.
This one's
wearing a wire.
You told me
I could trust...
Help me!
Grenade!
Where do you think
you're going?
Ok?
Yeah,
we're all clear.
Clear.
Clear!
Emolia!
Kyle, where is she?
I don't see her.
Emolia!
Mackey!
What did you just
say to her?
I just told her what a good job she did.
What is she doing
back here?
I was getting her
out of harm's way.
Hey, Guardo's gone.
Grab Lem and Ronnie
and set up a perimeter.
Let's scoop him up.
There's no sign
of Guardo anywhere?
My guys
will squeeze his soldiers,
find out
where he likes to hide.
Captain, somebody ripped off
the vending machines again.
Goddamn it. These things
cost a fortune to fix.
Jon.
One of these guys
gets away with murder,
and the captain's
more concerned
with the sandwich machine.
Pick up her son
and her mother.
Don't let anyone know
where she is.
Anyone.
Ok.
Same ol' shit.
Obviously you have
some good cop in you.
You got me out, man.
Let me return
the favor to you.
Quit chasing me and Vic.
Let us do our jobs.
Do you really want
to go to jail for that guy?
Do you think that he would
have picked up that grenade
and saved me?
And save you?
Look,
Vic is a great cop.
He's a great cop,
all right?
A real cop
would see that.
Hear me out, please.
I've giving you
one last chance.
Give me Vic.
Don't throw
your life away for...
What's going on here?
This guy
won't back off, man.
He's threatening
to send me to jail.
This man saves your life,
and you show him
your gratitude
by offering him
jail time?
It's not wonder
you're IAD's MVP.
10 square blocks around
Sadie's crime scene
are plastered with
flyers like that one,
warning the community about a
registered sex crime offender
in their neighborhood.
Note the mole
on his cheek.
At least, it appears to
be a mole at first glance.
It's really an ink stain.
It's on all the flyers.
She id'd him off that,
not because he attacked her.
She works in the neighborhood,
probably saw the flyer.
When he raped her,
the memory came back.
This doesn't change
what happened.
I went back to Olivo, told him
about the rape hanging over his head,
and he came clean.
He wasn't filling out
job applications,
he was at
a local high school
watching the girls' cross
country team run laps.
He didn't tell us before
because it violates his parole.
Of course he admits to that
before admitting to rape.
Coach saw him
hanging around.
We found this bottle
in the nearest trash can
near Sadie's parking lot.
There's vaginal residue,
pubic hair,
all over the mouth
and outside the bottle.
Maybe it was used
in the attack,
but she never
mentioned it,
and she's pointing a finger
at a perverted,
but innocent guy.
Where is she?
Wonder what
that's all about?
I don't know.
Whoever the woman is,
she's got him
pretty shook up.
How long
until I can leave?
Not long.
I'm meeting someone tonight.
How you feeling,
Sadie?
You ok?
Yeah,
I've been good.
Been real good.
I made a life
for myself.
I know you didn't think
I could do that on my own.
The medication
has helped.
Same dosages?
Jon...
Just want to know
which Sadie
I'm talking to right now.
Ask me to come back again.
I'm asking you
for the truth, Sadie.
The truth is,
you've lost some weight.
Haven't you?
Why doesn't it
look healthy though, Jon?
What's going on with you?
You been missing me?
Ex-wife.
But he keeps wearing
the wedding ring.
Sometimes you just got
to let the pussy go.
I just wanted the truth
about this morning.
About the rape.
I want you to kill him
for doing it.
Kill what?
The soda bottle?
I just want to come home...
Jon.
I said yes, I am ready to
come home to our bed now.
I am.
Please, just ask.
You're going
to be charged
for filing
a false police report.
And you're going to be
remanded for psychiatric care.
That's what
I have to do.
I-I-I'm not sick
like I used to be.
I've been taking
my medication.
Now I'm fine.
You took a soda bottle
and you shoved it
up your...
But I knew...
I knew what I was doing.
Listen...
it was wrong.
But I knew...
I wasn't confused.
I just didn't know
how else to talk to you.
Pick up
the damn phone.
You just call me
on the phone.
But I wanted you
to be able to save me.
See, I did it
because I knew...
you wanted to save me.
Jon...
d-d-deserve me again.
Because I want
to come home now, Jon.
I'm ready
to come home now.
So, just...
Oh, God,
just ask me already.
Come on.
You're going
to be charged...
for filing
a false police report.
You're going to be remanded
for psychiatric care.
No... that detective...
he's done everything
you've asked him to do,
so just tell him
that it is a mistake.
I can't.
Yeah, you can.
I won't.
You going to abandon me
again, Jon?
No.
Like the last time...
you're going to leave me alone again.
I'm going to help you.
Take me home.
I can't.
There are rules.
Then break one.
What I do is stop cops
from breaking the rules.
I can't stop them
if I can't stop myself.
Then try bending one
just once.
I'm an Internal Affairs
lieutenant.
That's who I am.
And I am
your goddamn wife.
And when I got sick
you left me alone, Jon!
You shit all over me!
And the rest of the world
shit all over me!
I couldn't
take care of you.
You tell the truth!
You didn't want to!
I was tired.
Of taking care
of your wife.
So you left.
I'm sorry.
You can shove sorry
right up there
with the pop bottle.
Don't say that, ok?
I wasn't worth
taking care of,
and now
I'm not worth shit!
No! I want to go home!
I want to go home...
Jon... please.
Please...
Holy shit.
At least we found
his weak spot.
I...
want to go home...
Everyone sees what I am.
Everyone sees me...
They all see me.
Oh, Jon!
Shit, go!
Don't leave me!
Hey! Hey...
You!
You're under arrest...
for possession of heroin
with intent to distribute.
You're going
to arrest me today?
Give me your badge
and your gun.
You're kidding me.
Give me your badge
and your gun.
No.
Get off me, man.
Get your hands
off him!
Don't talk to me!
You're going to jail!
Hey, Curtis!
Don't be stupid, Curtis!
Give me your badge
and your gun!
Captain Billings, you
take his badge and his gun
now!
Now.
Sorry, man.
Officers,
arrest that man.
You arrest him
or lose your jobs.
Let's go...
let's go, let's go!
Get him printed.
We're out of ink.
You stick him in the cage
until you're ready.
He's a cop.
You don't put him in there.
Clean out
one of the other cages.
Go in there,
right now!
Let's go!
Officer, come over here,
uncuff him,
stick him in the cage.
Let's go!
Yeah, come on
and have a seat.
Here you go, Mitchell.
Inside.
You woke me up
out of my beauty sleep, man.
I can see that.
I need a second
with him.
I need you
to tell me everything.
Everything
that you know
about Mackey
and his strike team.
Like I told you before,
no deal, no info.
Get me back to my cell.
You got your deal.
As long as you give me
what I need to know.
Subtitles:
FRM-xxy & Sapotille
www.1000fr.com
www.theshield-laserie.com