- [Hip-hop]
- [Julien] Get back. Get back now.
- Move.
- [Siren Wailing]
[Man]
What's up with my leg, man?
[Rapping]
[Groans]
My legs ain't movin, man.
I think that's
BettyJohnson's boy.
[Continues]
Hey. Does somebody want to
turn that crap off?
[Continues]
- [Stops]
- [Siren Wails]
[Man]
My legs.
[Helicopter Whirring]
Drive-by in the hood.
That's original.
Well, you know,
if it ain't broke, don't fix it.
The victims are all
decked out Spookstreet.
Driver was gone.
Must have fled.
We found a halfkey of
tar heroin hidden in the backseat.
- [Man Shouting]
- What's with him?
- Just babbling.
Paramedics say he's not gonna make it.
- Witnesses?
Oh, yeah.
They're just falling all over themselves.
See no evil, hear no evil.
[Rock]
- So?
- What are you hearing in
Juvie about Antwon Mitchell?
Besides, uh,
building parks...
and holdin' freedom rallies,
he's movin' tar heroin on the street.
Shane's been cozying up
to the guy lately.
- / think he might be in business with him.
- He's not my problem-
We all have a stake in making sure that
Shane stays out of I.A.D.'s headlights.
He gets in over his head, gets pinched,
we're his best chance of gettin'a deal.
No. Shane wouldn't.
He was ready to go to jail for Mara
when she almost killed Tavon.
He's a father now.
You'd be surprised what you'd do
for your kids.
[Curtis]
/t never goddamn ends.
[Ronnie]
We need to get back close to him.
Make sure if there's a problem
we can fix it before it's too late.
- I haven't talked to him since the shit went down.
- I'll deal with him one-on-one.
Look, I spoke to your C.O.
I want you to ride with
Danny and Julien tomorrow.
They've been assigned to
tap into the One-niners.
If anyone's running their mouth about Shane,
I want to hear about it before anybody else.
[Chattering]
- Carl.
- [Woman] Good morning.
[Chattering]
[Clears Throat]
[Toilet Flushes]
[All Laughing]
[Chattering]
- Morning.
- [Man] Morning.
Um...
I think I've had a chance to meet
and speak with all of you...
but this is my first
opportunity as your captain.
[Applause]
/n the, uh- Excuse me.
[Clears Throat]
In the two-plus years
since this, uh, substation's inception...
the Farmington District has had
its share of successes and failures.
The difficulties
are well-known.
Unfortunately, the successes are mostly
known only in this house.
/ see a lot of wonderful people
determined to make a difference.
I wouldn't have taken
this job if I didn't.
[Clears Throat]
Actually, uh, I'm better one-on-one
than, uh, in front of a big crowd.
[Horn Honks]
They say you should imagine
your audience naked...
but, uh, with this crowd
I wouldn't suggest it.
[All Laughing]
- [Woman] Good one.
- Look.
I know what
it's like out there.
I worked this neighborhood.
You put your life
on the line every day.
The people that you protect don't
thank you enough for that.
So let me thank you
for them.
The problems here
aren't about personnel.
They're about policy,
and that is what /'m here to change.
- [Applause]
- We-
We police a largely
minority district.
They're universally poor.
Most of them don't speak the language.
They look one direction,
see financial skyscrapers.
They look in the other direction,
they see the Hollywood sign.
In between is
the L.A. they know.
Gangs, drugs, fear.
We're not miracle workers.
We don't have any hidden
tricks up our sleeves.
We can't make fathers
want to stay in their kids' lives.
We can't, uh, solve poverty.
We can't take the addiction
out of heroin or cocaine.
Our job is to distinguish between
the criminals and the citizens.
/t's been too hard for the good people
and too easy for the assholes.
And we are gonna change that.
We are gonna turn that around.
- Yes.
- Last night- Last night...
three members of the Spookstreet Souljahs
were killed in a drive-by.
Three hours later, they struck back at
their rival gang, the Farmington One-niners.
Two more dead.
Five hours, five lives gone.
Uh, Steve. You're lead on the case.
What do we know?
Well, not much. We're currently looking for
the owner of the car, but he's AWOL.
- Witnesses?
- [Billings] None that are cooperating.
Starting today...
all drug- and gang-related homicides
will go through Vic Mackey.
/'ve posted a list of
10 detectives and 20 unis...
who will work
directly under Vic.
He'll be leading a task force
designed to learn everything we can...
about the roughly 50 gangs
who operate on our turf.
Their membership,
their businesses, chains of command.
Federal asset forfeiture laws
will now be enforced in Farmington.
A drug dealer uses a car to distribute drugs,
we're gonna seize that vehicle.
A gang sells crack out of their back room,
we're gonna take that home.
Stereo equipment,
plasma TV's.
Everything bought with drug money,
we're gonna take those assets, auction them off.
The D.A.'s office will get a third
to help finance further prosecutions.
A third will be funneled back
into the community...
for better social services, for safe playgrounds,
for after-school programs.
We want these people to know that we are about
more than just throwing their men intojail.
The rest of the proceeds
are gonna be used to help you.
Now, besides the, uh, grand reopening
of the men's room-
[Laughter, Applause]
uh, /'m gonna hire more cops.
/'m gonna authorize overtime when one of you
tells me that you need it to close a case.
I'm gonna purchase equipment
that actually works.
[Woman]
/t's about time.
I'm going to encourage
informants to come forward...
by giving them a cut
of assets we seize.
Citizens whose fear and silence
the gangs depend on...
we are gonna make them
a better deal than the bangers.
/t'll sting at first. People
usually don't like change.
And I still wouldn't expect
any thank-yous...
but we will
make things better.
There's been
another retaliation.
There's one dead and two critical
on Alvarado.
The job is impossible.
I can't do it without you.
- So let's get started.
- [Applause]
- Thank you.
- [Cheering]
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Ends]
/ didn't think you could top
fixing the men's john...
but I gotta give
that speech four flushes.
Don't be too impressed.
I still haven't gotten
my voice mail to work.
A gang war's the last thing
/ need right now.
/'ll serve
all open warrants.
I'll double up patrols in Spookstreet
and One-niner territory...
get as many of these guys off
the street as possible.
What's the average life cycle
of days of rage in the Farm?
/'ve seen them as short as a week,
as long as a year.
Look. Dealing with these
gang beefs can take time.
- They're complicated.
- They're a bunch of kids shooting at each other.
Stop it, so we can move forward.
I don't know.
What do you think?
Sherman's march
through the hood.
Sounds like one step forward,
two steps back.
Aceveda's old office is now our command post,
courtesy of our new captain.
Uh, these all outline
all known gang turf in Farmington.
Each of you has been assigned
a territory to map.
When you're not answering 911 calls,
get to know it like home.
Take a Polaroid with ya.
If you see a shithead, engage him.
Take his picture.
Document his ink.
Get his name, street tag.
Bring it all back here.
Danny, Julien, this little sliver of milk and honey
is Farmington One-niner territory.
[Mackey] Now it's your piece of paradise.
Spookstreet and One-niners are warring.
/ want you to get in their face,
find out what they're fighting about.
Lem's gonna ride with you two today,
get you guys up to speed.
- Thought you were working Juvie.
- Well, half the Niners are under 17...
and I mixed it up with the other
half on the Strike Team.
We're especially interested in an O.G.
named Antwon Mitchell.
Seems like
he's back in action.
/f you hear anything
about him, let me know.
- [Mackey] Everybody clear?
- Got it.
- Hit the road.
- Thanks.
- [Ronnie] Vic.
- What's up?
Owner of the shot-up Escalade's rap sheet.
Street name's Choppa.
We got unis posted at his
apartment and known hangouts.
All right. Put patrols on
his girlfriend's house. Mother's too.
Trouble hits, these assholes always run
one of two ways:
the pussy they're getting into
or the pussy they came out of.
Find Stank.
He runs the One-niners.
- Call me if something pops.
- Yep.
[Hip-hop On Stereo]
Tough getting up in the morning
without a prison guard banging on your cell door?
- Rough night.
- [Mackey] Too busy running a gang war, Antwon?
Too busy trying to find out
what started it.
Shootings scare away
customers, huh?
- Slows down your drug trade?
- Somebody's gotta keep the peace.
Trust me.
I'm on top of it.
I'm sleeping better already.
Why are you here?
To figure out how we're
gonna keep that peace.
/ don't even know what
they're warring about, man.
If I did, maybe I could
stop it, but I don't.
Today's the one day / don't give a shit
whether you're Pablo Escobar or Bishop Tutu.
We both want the same thing.
So, as info pours in,
you let me know.
And I'll let you know
what you can do about it.
[Curtis]
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
[Danny]
Farmington One-niners.
- [Curtis] Hey, what's up, Big Crane?
- [Man]Just walkin
- Yeah?
- Wouldn't bejust walkin'to beef
with Spookstreet, would you?
- Just walkin', homey.
- So what's the word out there?
Word is watch for gats
on the roll, man.
- Mind if we take your picture?
- For what?
For dressing like you're representing.
New policy.
- They're just threads, man.
- Come on, man. Don't make trouble.
[Shutter Clicks]
All right.
Show us the ink.
- All the way.
- [Shutter Clicks]
That's an awful lot of artwork
for someone who's not banging, Big Crane.
- What's your real name?
- You mean my slave name?
- Tremaine Harris.
- Who are you rolling with, Tremaine?
The Vice king strikes again.
- This guy can smell the sin out of a nun's crack.
- I learned from the best.
It's all about intel, brother.
It's how you choose it, how you use it.
Missed you at Gilroy's funeral.
I had more pressing
problems to bury.
I'll send Nancy a fruitcake
if it'll make you feel better.
- Vice keeping you busy?
- Wetbacks making book out of a roach coach.
Good thing I ordered first.
Little, uh, beef, bean and cash burrito.
You want a taste?
- No, thanks.
- Trying to earn that Eagle Scout badge, huh?
Look. This war between the Niners
and Spookstreet's running hot.
Since these things are almost always
drug-related, I figured you'd lend a hand.
Army and I got a full load.
/ had your back with that BlackBerry
you pocketed over at Dead-Eye's the other night.
No professional courtesy
in return?
I'll ask around.
- This Choppa's mom's house?
- Yeah. He went inside 10 minutes ago.
- Yeah.
- We're looking for your son Al.
- His car was involved in an accident.
- He ain't around.
- You know where we can find your brother?
- No talking to him, D.
If you don't tell us, he's gonna go to jail.
You don't want that, do you?
He's in his room.
[Man Laughs]
[Hip-hop On Stereo]
Assume the position, ladies.
Hands on your head right now.
- Hands on your head!
- [Man] Turn around.
- Since when is niggas kickin' it a crime?
- Turn around.
Oh, yeah. That's right.
Since around forever.
Ah, chilling's cool.
Those teeth are a felony though.
Gun.
You plottin'retribution? Huh?
No, man. We got
a circle jerk jumpin' off.
Why don't you grab
some Vaseline and join in?
Who shot up your car and your friends
last night, Choppa?
Don't know.
Wasn't there.
Where are your clothes?
You don't live here.
Come here.
Keep your ass right there.
Stand right there.
Those are my linens.
[Scoffs]
Told you to wash my shirt, Mama.
I started the sheets first.
Always separate your bloodstains
from your delicates, asshole.
Armed robbery with a deadly weapon
at a convenience store on Baxter.
- Victim's at Mission Cross.
- What happened?
- Shot? Stabbed?
- Splashed. With a really hot cup of coffee.
Don't you think it's a waste of time
to give us a case that a uni could handle...
when there's a gang war
going on out there?
I would love to use you both
for more important things.
Apologize to the D.A. yet?
Let me know when you do.
Impressive. Only six months into
our unflinching moral stand...
already the results are
devastatingly effective.
[Choppa] / was at a light. They rolled up
on the passenger side and started blastin
[Mackey]
You see who the other shooters were?
My black ass was out the door
the second I heard the jumpin' off.
So, you running had nothing to do with
the half kilo of tar we found in your car?
That shit wasn't mine.
Belonged to my homeboy,
Shank.
Right. Blame it on the guy
who didn't make it out alive.
Shit's unfortunate.
But /'d do it for him if /'d taken a bullet, so-
[Monica] Come on, Choppa.
You know who shot at you. You told your crew.
How else would they know
who to retaliate against?
Apologize to
the D.A. already.
You made your point.
I deserve out of the doghouse.
- People deserve our expertise
solving serious crimes.
- I'm not apologizing.
- You don't have to mean it.
- [Woman] Rodrigo, tell
the detectives what happened.
I was working the register
when this man came in.
He asked if the coffee was fresh.
I said I just brewed it.
He got a cup.
He gave me a five.
I went to open the register to make change,
and then he threw the coffee in my face.
- He grabbed the cash, and he ran. I don't even-
- [Gunshots]
- Shots fired!
- Call for backup.
- [Shouting]
- Shots fired inside the E.R.
[Shouting]
- [Woman] Help.
- [Woman #2 Groaning]
- [Chattering]
- Room's clear.
[Man]
Shooters took off, man.
- [Groans] Hurts like a bitch.
- You're in the right place.
- Hey. Where's Corrine?
- [Dutch] She was off duty.
- What happened?
- Harold Pinker. Spookstreeter nicknamed "Oink."
He was being treated
for a broken finger.
Nurses say two teens sporting
One-niner colors came to see a friend...
saw Oink,
went right for him.
Rent-a-cop chased the shooters out,
took a slug in his leg for his troubles.
- No metal detectors here?
- They can't afford thermometers.
You want us to
follow up on this?
Vic's on it.
Get back to your case.
We got good news,
bad news and worse news.
- How about a refill on my beverage?
- Oh, sure.
You refreshed?
The bad news is your cousin Oink
was admitted to the E.R.
The worse news is the One-niners
found him there and killed him.
The good news is off the tar we found
in your truck, we searched your apartment...
and found enough hell dust
to earn you stripes in Chino.
These pricks killed two of your friends,
slaughtered your cousin.
Tell us who started this
so we can stop it.
You want me to rat out names so you can stick us
all in the same cage and get me smoked?
You don't, they hit back,
you end up in the same prison anyway.
Nah. Me and my boys gonna handle this
in the streets. Believe that.
- [Door Opens]
- [Shane] Sorry to interrupt, but, uh...
bet you didn't know that
your suspect also goes by "Goldie G."...
bona fide XXX rap mogul.
Oh, you gotta be shittin' me.
Uh, Monica Rawling.
This is Shane Vendrell.
Hear you're making quite a name
for yourself over in Vice.
- Miss our Barn?
- Uh, place wasn't without its charms.
But like they say, uh,
off to bigger and better.
Couple pros at a video shoot saw a hood rat
with One-niner ink...
playing hide the bone
with Choppa.
Thought it might be related to
your gang war out there.
- [Hip-hop On TV]
- Army's looking into who made it.
[Moaning]
Holler if you're with me
I gotta get a Bentley
- [Continues, Indistinct]
- [Moaning]
A lot of brothers with me
A lot of suckers again't me
The boys in the hood
What happened to Ricky
What happened to Tupac
What happened to Biggie, Not me
Never thought of myself
as a prude, but...
might be time
to reconsider.
[Moaning Continues]
You met the guys.
Get ready for their better halves.
Heck of a place for
a mommy and me class.
How you doin, Tanika?
Be a lot better if you brought
this fine brother round here earlier.
- Wouldn't be the baby mama
of some broke-ass nigga.
- [Shutter Clicks]
You know anything
about these shootings?
Just our men getting shot up.
Antwon Mitchell have
anything to do with it?
Nah. Antwon's straight up.
He built this park.
- You know him?
- No. But I know three of his baby mamas.
- How many has he got?
- [Tanika] Why?
You looking
to get knocked up?
- Who's the skank?
- [Moaning]
Caught the booty.
Didn't catch the name.
Bet you caught something else.
You know your, uh, leading lady
is One-niner property?
Why you think I was
claiming my set?
[Mackey]
So, what? All this shooting's over her?
[Choppa]
We don't throw down over bitches.
Look, alls I know is the One-niners shot up
my ride and killed three of my niggas.
- What's with the video?
- /t's a demo.
Y'all always jawin' about getting a job.
That's my résumé.
So, this is gonna
launch your career?
Yeah. Check it out. /'m gonna get
my freak on with this other little ho.
Six people are dead.
Why are you smiling?
You can't buy
this type of street cred.
[Rapping On TV, /ndistinct]
- It takes time.
- I don't have time.
Everyone has
a pressure point. Find his.
You wanted a second chance.
I gave it to you.
Now get it done.
[Phone Rings]
Wow. Looks like fun
to be a cop here.
Pretend this guy isn't
a coffee thrower.
Let's say he killed
three people.
Well, now you're just
getting me aroused.
Okay. Uh, he escaped on foot.
Means he probably lives in the area.
His M.O.'s simple,
yet effective.
I'd say he had priors,
learned from his mistakes.
Okay. Let's start there.
This is Stank. One-niner captain.
Captain Rawling.
Call me Monica. If we're going to do business,
we should be on a first-name basis.
- We didn't start a thing.
- Of course you didn't.
- Do you know who did?
- Come on upstairs.
I got something might
jog your memory.
- [Rapping]
- Oh, here comes the good part.
- [Moans, Laughs]
Who is she?
Just some skank-ass ho.
- He knows the girl.
- /'ll find her.
[Shane]
Uh, hey.
Uh, followed up on that video. A company called
Ghetto Bang Productions made it.
Owner's name is Terrence Ross.
Army and /'ll- We'll track him down for you.
/ appreciate your help, but you're not
under my command. This is our investigation.
- I'll join 'em.
- [Monica] Fine.
- Well, Army and me can handle it.
- I'll back you up anyway.
/f you want to tag along,
tag along.
Terrence Ross?
- Who are you?
- The pussy police.
I'd tell you to spread 'em,
but it looks like she beat you to it.
- [Shane] What's up with that?
- Hung brothers, old mothers.
- /t's the next big thing.
- I'm more interested in Choppa.
Hey, man.
That cat's straight thug.
- / got a family, man.
- You want us going through your hard drive...
checking the I.D.'s of every
chicken-head in your movies?
Choppa needed a demo.
I'm a one-stop shop.
Got the cameras, girls, Viagra.
What? Samuel Goldwyn meets
Seymore Butts?
/ do weddings and confirmations
too if you're in need.
- Who's the One-niner spinner
who was riding bareback?
- Name's Bounce.
She's a video ho, looking to hook up with
the next Nelly, get herself out of the hood.
- Where can we find her?
- She lives in the jungle.
Let's see.
I got her address round here.
Here you go.
Keep it.
/ was looking to hit that, but
after seeing Choppa bust raw...
save myself a trip to the free clinic,
know what I mean?
[Speaking Farsi]
My uncle says that a man came in.
He threw hot coffee in his face and robbed him.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- [Farsi]
Can he give us a description
of the assailant?
[Farsi]
Okay. Calm- Calm down.
This is an investigation,
not a goddamn jihad.
- You might not recognize Bounce
with her, uh, clothes on.
- Oh, but I do.
- / don't do porn. / was dancin
- Tomato, "tom-ah-to."
- Thanks for your help.
- Yeah.
Just like old times, brother.
Yeah. Well, uh,
see you around.
[Monica]
Who gave you your black eye?
I ain't no snitch.
He'll kill me.
You have a newborn, right?
- Ten months.
- You violated your parole.
You do another bid in Chowchilla,
Child Services is gonna take that baby away.
I don't want that.
- I didn't violate nothing.
- It's called consorting with a known felon.
- Peter hit me.
- Who's Peter?
Puppethead.
My baby daddy.
He saw the video.
He gotjealous.
Just 'cause I suck his dick
don't make him my man.
Puppethead's a One-niner?
This war- it's about you?
I guess I'm the bomb, huh?
We're investigating
a convenience store robbery.
I don't do those anymore.
Well, forgive me if I'm skeptical, Kyle,
but, uh, we've got your prints on file.
- We're running them against the coffee cup.
- Coffee cup?
Yeah. Uh, guy threw coffee in the clerk's face
while he was making change...
cleaned out the register.
[Chuckles]
I always used a knife.
- Can I get a moment with you, please?
- Sure.
I by no means meant to offend you,
your ethnic background or your religion in any way.
l- I apologize profusely.
His comments were not reflective
of this department whatsoever.
[Farsi]
- He asks if you caught the guy yet.
- Not yet.
But I assure you. I won't
let him rest till he does.
/f you ever have a problem
in the future, call me directly.
Thank you.
[Farsi]
Borderline racism aside,
I don't have time for this nonsense.
I'm sorry.
I was distracted.
It's- It's not easy being
cut out of all the action here.
It's my first day.
I'm already tired of hearing it.
Puppethead'll be on edge,
worried about Spookstreet retaliation.
- So be careful.
- Got it.
- [Whistling]
- [Ronnie] Spotters.
He's running.
Let's go!
You want to go over?
Go over.
- [Shouts, Groans]
- [Dog Barking]
Puppethead started this war because he didn't
like Choppa inside his woman's cooch.
[Puppethead]
Spookstreet tried to take me out.
Oh, yeah? Where'd they
take shots at you?
I'll send unis over there
to look for bullet holes.
- / saw the video, bitch.
- [Mackey] / know you started-
[Monica]
/s that the guy who shot up your car?
Do you even worry about yourself?
About being killed?
When it's time, it's time.
Well, that's a way
of looking at it.
I got a witness who saw you take the shots.
Help yourself out and cooperate.
Got a witness, huh?
Let me hear what he got to spit.
[Sighs]
What other leverage do we have?
[Mackey]
/ had Ronnie look into Choppa's finances.
He rents an apartment
on Baxter.
But he also owns a house.
- How'd he pay for it?
- Cash down payment.
- Makes the mortgages with money orders.
- Drug money.
- Who lives there?
- His mom and her two other kids.
We don't have
anything else.
His mother know how
he paid for the house?
She knows he's never
held down a job.
Can we make a solid connection between
the house payments and drug money?
You gonna tell Choppa
we're taking his mom's house?
He's tough.
He could call our bluff.
What if it isn't a bluff?
He doesn't I.D. the shooters,
help us stop this, we take the house.
I love it.
How old are the kids?
Young.
Could be a huge
P.R. nightmare.
Tossing two kids out onto
the street is not exactly...
the cleanest example
ofhow / want this to work.
Taking the house is
the only leverage we have.
This policy got a shitload of resistance
when / pitched it to Pol Com.
Chief bit because
nothing else has worked.
The last thing / want is to
give the naysayers any ammo...
to shut this down before
it gets a chance to take off.
[Mackey]
Rise and shine.
- Still playin', huh?
- Who shot at you?
- Last time /'m asking.
- Good.
- 'Cause I'm sick of you barking.
- Okay. Take the house.
- With pleasure.
- What house?
The one you bought
your mother by dealing dope.
Yeah, right.
You can't take shit.
Come with me.
/'ll show you.
[Chattering]
Do you know what
federal asset forfeiture laws are, Choppa?
Skipped that course
at Harvard, huh?
It means any property
bought with drug money...
or used to facilitate
the drug trade can be seized.
- I ain't falling for no bullshit.
- [Mackey] No bullshit.
Unless you prove you bought the house
legitimately, it's ours to put up for auction.
[Monica] We're not required to provide you
a defense either. Wanna fight this?
You gotta hire a lawyer
on your own dime.
Quit clowning.
This is America.
Turns out a One-niner named Puppethead
started this war.
Yeah. His shorty had a thing
for a Souljah's pogo stick.
- That right?
- Yeah. This is all about a jealous boyfriend.
I see my tax dollars
are being well spent.
- What do you want from me?
- I got the guy who started this.
I need you to keep these assholes on the street
from shooting at each other...
long enough for me to show the neighborhood
that things are changing...
that we got things
under control.
- What makes you think they'll listen to me?
- [Chuckles]
/'ve seen you work a room. Even convinced
a few people you're on the straight and narrow.
Feel free to confess
that you're just a piece-of-shit gangster.
Thanks for the help.
- Detective Wyms.
- [Man] Yeah. Thanks for comin
- [Dutch] What happened?
- Guy bought a cup of coffee.
I opened the register to give him change,
he splashed me.
Grabbed my cash and ran.
I'm lucky the coffee wasn't hot.
- Your surveillance camera working?
- Got him on my cell phone.
- [Beeps]
- Didn't you talk to that guy today?
Yeah. He had
a rock solid alibi.
Aw, man. Aw, man.
- This is entrapment.
- [Claudette] How do you figure?
I'm a thief. He's telling me about asking
for change and then throwing coffee.
It's like giving a junkie
a syringe.
I was done robbing until
he put it back in my head.
That's our guy?
Uh, actually, we inadvertently slipped
a few details to one of our other suspects.
Kind of created a copycat.
But we got him.
Still working on
the original guy.
Way to go. You get assigned a simple
robbery, cause a crime wave.
Remind me never to
put you guys on a murder case.
Hope you're happy.
Keys. Thanks.
Hey. Called your dentist.
Paid for your choppers with cash.
- Tooth fairy wants 'em back.
- Man, I ain't giving you my fronts.
Either you take them out yourself,
or I get a pair of pliers.
Thanks, honey.
Vic.
What's up?
One thing we know about Antwon is
he don't like to strap his shit up.
- What'd you hear?
- Guy's fathered a dozen children
from six different mothers.
Even knocked up a couple from behind bars
by sneaking his sperm out.
Oh, shit. You hit up that many women,
you're bound to leave some serious scorn behind.
All right. Let's find out their names.
Anything about Shane?
- No. Not a word.
- All right. Keep listening.
Aloicious? Aloicious,
what've you got us into?
[Choppa] /t's okay, Mama.
They'rejust trying to scare me.
It ain't gonna work though.
/t's workin'on me.
/t's workin'on me, Aloicious.
Are you crazy?
- [Mackey] Can / help you?
- Let go of me.
- Calm down.
- Don't tell me to calm down. Who's in charge?
- Who's putting my babies on the street?
- /'m Captain Rawling.
You did this?
You're taking my house?
/'ve reserved shelter space
for the three of you.
What the hell am I supposed
to do with a shelter space?
The Department of Social and Human Services
can help you find permanent residence.
You wanna help?
You give me my home back.
- / can't do that.
- You got no right throwing
children out of their beds.
All your son has to do is cooperate
with our investigation.
He does that,
he will help us save a lot oflives.
My boy got shot at.
He's innocent.
Your boy bought your home
using drug money.
You knew where that money came from,
and you chose to look the other way.
You don't know what
it's like living here.
You think I can just pick and choose
how to go about surviving?
You don't have children,
do you?
[Shouts]
Do you?
'Cause if you did,
you couldn't do this.
- No mother could do this.
- Six children are dead.
- How do you think those mothers-
- You don't have kids of your own...
so you're throwing
mine out.
Just be glad that all you lost today
was your home and not your son.
Shut up!
You just shut up!
[Door Opens]
These are recruiters.
Newbies just got
their stripes.
They find the next generation
to bring in.
What's up, Lil Bull? Hey, man. I got some people
here want to take your guys's picture.
Gonna make you all famous.
All right? Go ahead, man.
- Just say cheese.
- [Shutter Clicks]
[Julien]
What's your name, son?
Run, stupid. Run.
Come here. When a police officer gives you
an instruction, you listen. Understand?
- I don't want my picture taken.
- Then why are you hanging out with gangs?
- Hey.
- What are you, my mama now?
Go.
[Mackey]
Look. This lawsuit's gonna bury us financially.
But can you afford
not to sue?
The money I'm asking you
to put up for medical tests is peanuts...
compared to what two autistic kids
are gonna need over their lifetimes.
I work at a hospital.
What if I pulled some strings...
and found a way to get
the tests done there?
Well, the doctors I use
are experts.
They're expensive,
but their testimony carries weight.
Well, her friend Gail's
the head of pediatrics.
- That expert enough for ya?
- Talk to her.
If she's willing to testify
and can provide the credentials I need...
- / guess / can live with it.
- Good.
Can I at least
eat dinner in peace?
You know, this isn't about
right and wrong with you anymore.
/t's about pride.
Can't psychoanalyze killers anymore,
so you're giving me the once-over.
Okay. Uh, maybe it's easier to shoot yourself
in the foot and be a martyr...
than to be a captain
and make tough decisions.
You can always get
another partner, Dutch.
I don't want that.
What do you expect me to do?
Y-You're not
giving me any choice.
[Knocks]
Hello.
I thought your shift
ended an hour ago.
/'m just finishing up
some paperwork.
Captain, / wanted to thank you
for including me in all this.
It feels really good
to have a mission...
not just out answering
drunk and disorderlies.
Thank Vic.
He recommended you.
[Woman] There's no reliable evidence to prove
a causal link between thimerosal and autism.
/ won't do the testing
because / won't be a party to this lawsuit.
What about the 300% rise in cases
since they increased the vaccines for children?
Could just mean we're getting better
at diagnosing autism.
There aren't enough
case studies to prove anything.
They're shooting our kids up
with mercury.
You're saying that
it's a coincidence they're sick?
What would you do, Gail?
You love your children for who they are.
Just get out of the suit. Save your money.
Why? 'Cause lawsuits like these
cost doctors like you a few bucks?
- [Corrine] Vic.
- No.
How many shots with thimerosal
have you prescribed to kids?
Saying that they've been
poisoning our kids...
is just like admitting
you've been doing it all along, right?
/'ve devoted my life
to caring for children.
And I'm a cop who
looks out for other cops.
Don't you tell me that doctors
don't look out for other doctors.
You know, helping 'em out, making sure
that they hide the truth from people like us.
The only difference is what / do doesn't
screw kids up for the rest of their lives.
Corrine, please.
Just talk to him.
If you don't want to help us,
we're gonna find someone else who will.
/t's not like that.
This isn't who my children
were supposed to be.
It cost me my marriage,
their future.
And you're wrong.
[Dog Barks /n Distance]
My mom's at work.
I came to ask you
what to do with this.
These pictures, they go up
on a wall in our station house.
Once they're up, they only come down
for one of two reasons:
either you die
or you go tojail.
Do I need to put this up, or will you consider
making some other choices?
- Like what?
- / grew up around here.
There are other ways to go.
Church. Sports.
Nah. I ain't into that stuff.
- What about the Explorer's Program?
- What's that?
We take young men like you.
We teach 'em about law enforcement.
Why do I want to be like you?
Look. When we took
your picture, you ran.
That means you're scared.
You're scared because you know it's wrong.
You need to chill, Oprah.
I ain't never gonna be
no sellout cop.
/ just needed to know
what to do with this picture.
Now I know.
- Hey. Not too bad for day one, huh?
- We're gonna need a bigger room.
I just got off the phone with Central.
Puppethead was bailed out last night.
- He had a quarter of a million dollar bail.
- Antwon Mitchell...
put up 25 grand
cash bond.
- Goddamn.
- Guess you're thinking what I'm thinking.
- Puppethead isn't long for this world.
- Or might be gone already.
[Mackey]
Hey.
- Where's Puppethead?
- People saying he's dead.
- [Ronnie] Clear.
- Who's saying that?
Antwon gave him up to Spookstreet,
so they'd end this war.
I heard they whipped him,
chained him to a back of a car...
and dragged him till
his skin peeled off.
Nothing like that's
been reported.
Well, that's what
they're sayin'.
[Monica]
Antwon got a set to give up one of their own.
- Do you believe that?
- Well...
- we won't know for sure unless a body shows up.
- It'll show.
- He'll want his bail money back.
- Yeah.
ChenilleJenkins never went
to the shelter with her kids.
Taking the house didn't
get Choppa to cooperate.
The war's over.
Why does it feel like we lost?
Well, we did.
Antwon's showed the street
that he's got more juice than we do.
Look. We got our shooters.
We made the peace.
Nothing says you can't give that house
back to Chenille and her two kids.
[Knocks]
- [Baby Coos]
- Surprise.
For your boy.
- Uh, thanks, man.
- Better late than never, huh?
Yeah. Uh-
[Grunts]
Ah, cute kid.
- Yeah. He's got his mother's looks.
- Thank God.
- Nice place.
- Yeah. The last one, uh, barely held two of us...
- let alone a third.
- Hello, Vic.
- [Mumbles]
- I think it's warm enough.
Okay.
- Is she all right?
- Yeah. Just a- a little postpartum. You know.
Still adjusting.
It's, uh-
It's a lot, you know.
So what's up?
Oh, we did pretty good on this thing,
you know. We stopped the war.
- These seizures are real.
- [Baby Cries]
- Farmington's gonna be the place to be-
- Hold on a second.
Hold on, bud.
/t's comin /t's comin
- /s he okay?
- Yeah. He's okay.
- [Crying]
- / know. / know. /t's comin
- If it wasn't warm enough, why didn't you say so?
- /t's okay. / got it.
Come on. Get dressed.
/'ll make you some lunch.
So, what, uh-
Uh, what about the, uh-
the seizures?
I'm gonna need the best people
to make it happen.
Our differences aside,
you're one of them.
I got a good thing on Vice, you know.
My own boss. It's my own way of doing things.
What exactly are you doin'?
- I'm getting what I need done.
- I hope you're using protection.
You lecturing me?
Man, you killed our team, not me.
You're right.
Uh, I made some mistakes. I'll own that.
- I'm past working for you, Vic.
- You wouldn't be.
Uh, / got the watch, but the only person
you'd be taking orders from is the captain.
- You still get to do things your way.
- / got a partner / trust now.
And I really like
running with this guy, man.
Well, I'll try to
bring him in too.
You know, working out of the Barn
will make things easier on the family.
Consistent hours.
Plenty of overtime if you need it.
Shane's doing great
without you.
He's making
a lot of arrests.
Well, you both did
a greatjob with this one.
- He's beautiful.
- Thanks.
Look, I'll, uh-
I'll think about it.
Good.
I don't trust him.
- Hey.
- [Gasps]
It's not about
trust anymore, baby.
It's not.
[Sighs]
[Chattering]
Lady.
Don't throw my peoples on the street.
l- I'll tell you everything.
Too late now. The guy we wanted you to I.D.
is on the loose, probably dead.
So what's gonna happen
to my mama house?
You ain't even sorry,
are you?
- We're done talking.
- You a white bitch!
You threw children
on the street.
- You a cracker-wood ho!
- Hey.
- You hear me, bitch?
- Shut up.
- You a white bitch too.
- Hey. Easy.
- [Man] Be cool, man.
- What you lookin' at?
Can I help you, Detective?
My partner and I have been
on your office shit list for six months.
Oh, I must have
missed that memo.
- It needs to end.
- Well, you need to divorce your partner.
What's it gonna take to get
the D.A. off her ass?
Going into his office, getting on her hands
and knees and begging for his forgiveness.
- She's not gonna do that.
- Then you're both in for a long winter.
- I got work to do.
- Well, what if I, uh-
What if I promise
to control her?
- Are you sure you can do that?
- I wouldn't be here if I couldn't.
She listens to me.
Would that be enough?
This office needs favors
from time to time.
/'d expect you to
deliver them when / ask.
You-You got a deal.
/ was told we're moving this stuff out.
All we need's a signature.
Now this guy inside
says we might not.
What's going on, Captain?
Give me a minute. Okay?
We swept the place. No drugs.
/'m checking the inventory.
Everything's still here.
[Man]
/t's all on the cart right there. Bring it down.
Explain to me why
taking this house...
was the right thing to do yesterday,
the wrong thing today.
Yesterday we had to
stop the shootings.
This house was bought
with drug money.
The mother knew it.
You said it would be
a P.R. nightmare.
Either it works,
or it doesn't.
To make exceptions to put
a prettier face on it...
sounds more like
Aceveda than me.
Take it.
[Truck Reverse /ndicator Beeping]
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Continues]
[Ends]