[Aceveda]
The police department can change...
but trust me,
it's not gonna happen from the inside.
Well, what's that have to do
with the city council?
These property seizures are targeting
my constituents now, someday, yours too.
- That's not our problem?
- You just started, David. Take a breath.
Give yourself a chance
to get settled in.
[Aceveda] This policy's led
to increased corruption in other cities.
Locals fighting for profits,
rises in police brutality complaints.
- What do you want, exactly?
- A leadership position
on the police committee.
/ can steer policy, protect
the council's interests. Look, Bill.
/ know how it works there.
/ know what needs to be done.
I just need the authority
to do it.
[Bill] That's what the other
councilmen are afraid of.
They think you might try
to shove something down their throat.
That won't happen.
/t's how / can serve best.
/tjust makes sense.
I got it.
Thanks.
- I'm Sara.
- David.
You mind?
Havin' a good time?
Just making an effort
to meet people.
But I don't remember
seeing you in here before.
But your friend looked familiar.
I hope, for his wife's sake,
he wasn't a john.
You're a cop.
I need to get
my radar checked.
How's business?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Look, I'm just here to have a cigarette,
not to make an arrest.
So where you from?
Phoenix.
- Been here long?
- No.
Just came out.
I like it though.
There's a lot to like.
It's nice to meet you, David.
You been on vacation, or are you
just workin'on white people's time?
Where the hell is Antwon?
Every cop with a Kodak is hasslin'
brothers, seizin' cars and shit.
- Antwon's shit.
- So?
So you best remember why you here.
Antwon ain't posin'for no po-po.
I told you last time.
I don't deal with scrubs.
Andjust so we're clear, /'m the one
that's supposed to be getting tips.
You're a week behind.
So you tell Antwon to come back himself.
- And don't forget to bring me gifts.
- You trippin'? Huh?
Or you forget just how much
you up in for Antwon?
'Cause itjust takes one anonymous call
to 911. You feel me?
- Oh, yeah, I feel you.
- You better figure out
how to stop the bleedin...
or I'm gonna have to drop
a dime on your ass.
One second.
Come here.
We'll work this out.
He's gonna drop a dime?
Are we involved in some shit...
beyond hookers
that I don't know about?
This is just a little
quid pro quo thing...
only Antwon's a little
slow on the quo.
Hey, this is not a big deal. These guys
always try this once to see if they can own you.
As long as we handle this right,
there's not a problem.
So you just sit
on the other guy, okay?
All right? Okay.
I think I might have
come up with something.
- My nigga.
- [Army] Hey! Hey!
Step back, asshole.
[Groaning]
You gonna drop
a dime on us? Huh?
- [Grunting]
- [Groaning]
Whatcha got in here?
Come here.
Hit him.
Do it, asshole!
- No.
- I told you to do something, you dumbshit!
Harder. Harder.
I thought you two were tight.
[Chuckles]
You know what?
Tell Antwon there's a new scoop law.
Come pick up his dog shit.
It's, uh, safer
if we talk out here.
Whatever. Listen,
/ need you to look at a guy.
A drug dealer named
Maurice Webster.
Claudette and I don't
usually handle drug cases.
From what you've been telling me,
it's a step up.
- I should write this down.
- Stop. I'll send over the file.
Get it from your captain.
This is all we have to do to make things
straight with us and the D.A. again?
No. But it's a start.
Now, my source says
that Maurice is a major player.
See what you and
your partner can whip up.
Hey.
Hey, we've gotta go.
The Realtor's inside.
- She's taking her sweet time.
- They're interested.
Gretchen thinks they're
gonna make us an offer.
Why does Mom have to move?
We talked about that, Cassidy.
/ want to.
What about my friends...
when I'm here?
Can / go to my room?
- We have to go while they're here.
- [Cell Phone Ringing]
- Hold on. Yeah.
- [Mouthing Words]
I'll hold.
- All my stuff is in my room.
- No one's gonna touch your things.
[Sighs]
All right, /'ll be there.
I gotta go to work.
Give me a kiss.
[Sighs]
All right, let's get out of their way.
I appreciate the call,
but rape's not usually my thing.
Fugitive recovery is.
Oscar Ruiz was at
the courthouse this morning...
for a prelim on his three
sexual assault charges.
They think he found
an unlocked window.
[Mackey]
Picked the wrong guy to let escape.
They figure he got loose
around 7:30.
We didn't hear about it
until 9:30 after he raped again.
[Man] Myrna, are you there?
You said it was an emergency.
- [Myrna]Joe-
- Yeah? Yeah, what's wrong?
- / slept with him.
- What? What are you talking about?
- / sucked his dick, and then
he did me from behind.
- What the hell's going on?
He's better than you are.
He's a real man, not a pussy like you.
- Myrna- Myrna, is somebody there?
- He's so big.
- Who's there, Myrna?
- He's the best / ever had.
Myrna, is he
making you say this?
/ want him to do it to me
again in the ass... while you listen.
- Myrna, /'m calling the police.
/'m on my way home.
- [Myrna Sobbing]
[Machine Beeps]
Wanna get this guy?
Yeah.
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Ends]
[Dutch] Oscar Ruiz,
the stay-at-home rapist.
Forcing his victims to call the husband
or the boyfriend was his standard M.O.
Puts a neat little spin
on things.
Come for the rape,
stay for the humiliation.
- That's a list of his friends and acquaintances.
- Anyone interesting?
- He's got a fiancée living in Farmington.
- Talk to her.
So Ruiz left the rape scene at 9:15 with
a handgun and clothes from their closet.
That makes two hours
since anyone's heard from him.
A smart guy would run as far
and as fast as he could.
But he raped again
right out of the box.
Which means he knows we'll catch him.
He's gonna binge until we do.
Ruiz poses as
a flower shop delivery guy.
Then he forces his way in.
I'll get his pictures to the shop owners.
Then I'll talk to his roommate.
"Stay-at-home rapist"?
It's just something I coined.
Well, the women stay at home.
This guy goes out and rapes.
Nicknames are meant
to be catchy, not literal.
You want us to throw in on Ruiz?
[Monica]
No, Vic's got it.
I'm Captain Rawling.
This is Detective Mackey.
- Emily, right?
- Yeah- Emily Mischner.
Thank you for coming in.
I apologize for what happened.
We can put you in a department
safe house until this is resolved.
Until what's resolved?
Why am I here?
Oscar Ruiz escaped
from sheriff! s custody this morning.
Oh, my God. That's what
the commotion at court was about?
We're gonna find him. But
you shouldn't go home alone until we do.
I have been alone. I went home
right after they delayed that hearing.
He already raped me once.
Why didn't somebody here tell me?
The sheriff s department thought they
had him contained in a downtown area.
/t took a couple ofhours before they
realized that he had gotten past them.
- So he's out there?
- We have a lot of resources
dedicated to this thing.
/n the meantime, a couple of officers
could take you home...
and stand guard.
l- I'd, um-
I'd rather stay here...
until you catch him.
Yo. You seen this guy?
- You are Blinky, right?
- In here, I'm Felix. What's goin' on?
Oscar Ruiz, your roommate?
He's in prison.
- He got escaped.
- No shit?
So you don't know that he raped
another woman this morning either?
- What?
- They were about to lay
a life sentence on this prick.
You know what they're gonna do to you
when they find out you helped him escape?
Yo, I didn't help him escape.
All right?
I didn't even know he was out
till he showed up this morning.
When did he get here?
Hey, he was out back
when I got here to work.
Look, he said he was innocent, so / gave
him a few dollars to get to Mexico, and-
l-I just wanted him gone.
He didn't go to Tijuana.
He went out and raped another woman.
He used your money to buy the flowers
that got him in the front door.
Does he know how
to get into your apartment?
He knows where
I keep the spare key.
- Hey, man, I'm sorry.
- Save it.
I'm gonna park your ass right here with
an officer in case Ruiz shows up again.
Antwon Mitchell...
as I live and breathe.
Run on inside, kids.
Man, you got to be crazy
showin'your face around here...
especially after that shit
you pulled last night.
/ didn't wanna play hard,
but your boy was threatening to own us.
The question is,
what's next for us?
Halpern was out of line.
That shit
won't happen again.
That's not good enough, partner.
I don't know if you got a hard-on for jail
or you just like pissin' off cops...
but me and my boy are lookin' at the door
on this unless you convince me otherwise.
Come on.
Shit on 'em, man.
Hey, don't go sideways on me.
Paid in full...
with a little extra
to make everything all right.
Okay, player?
Good.
But I like makin' busts too.
Just step up the tips. I'll make sure
you get by same as before.
Hey, things ain't the same
as before, man.
We got these cops comin'
after us like storm troopers.
Well, I'm your Luke Skywalker.
The seizures-
I'm close to the cop who's runnin' it.
How close you to him?
I'm as close
as I need to be.
- Okay. Get at me then.
- Uh-uh.
You gotta bring me
some news I can use.
Then the clock starts runnin'
on your protection.
- Hey, Captain. Back already?
- City business.
A multiple rapist walked out of the courthouse
this morning, attacked another woman.
- I need to reschedule.
- Anything I can do?
No.
Sorry to inconvenience you.
A lot of people have been talking to me
about these police seizures.
I think we should talk today.
It's important.
- Can you wait a few minutes?
- Yeah, a few.
Beth /nsardi just called. There's a drug dealer
they wanna make a case against.
She specifically asked
for the two of you.
- Really?
- You sure she meant us?
Must be the bottom of the barrel.
- Really?
- You sure she meant us?
Must be the bottom of the barrel.
Doesn't sound it.
His name is Maurice Webster.
He's a big dope fish
in our little pond.
- So try to wrap a net around him.
- [Claudette] Drug sting.
- Isn't that more Vic's rhythm?
- Vic's busy.
So I'd take whatever olive branch
the D.A.'s offering.
Beth says there's a time issue,
so don't waste any.
Maybe they're ready to take
the leash off, huh?
His picture's out there- flower shops,
supermarkets, even the on-ramp slingers.
- [Mackey] Anything on the fiancée?
- No, nothing.
All right, gather around.
This is Ruiz's old apartment.
We'll start from here
and spread out.
Let's hope he's feeling homesick.
Let's go.
Hey, any luck
on your rapist?
Yeah- all his.
You got something to run by me?
I just found a crack
in Antwon Mitchell's family seal.
His oldest son, Donald ///,
has been movin'fake /.D. 's...
out of the back of his van
in the D.M.V. parking lot.
I thought Antwon kept
all of his kids straight.
This one dumped private school
for the family business.
I, uh- Do me a favor.
Don't move on this punk for a day or two.
- Why not?
- I gotta test a theory.
Someone just spotted Ruiz.
Seventh and Vermont.
So, about the seizures?
I understand coming on strong
in the beginning to set a tone...
but maybe
you're pushing too hard.
- You have a suggestion?
- Reach out to the community.
Visit some churches...
community watch programs.
Put on a friendly face.
If these people don't know you,
they won't trust you.
When they see us pulling
bangers off their corners...
I think they'll give us
a second look.
And what they'll see
is you targeting blacks and Latinos.
That's who's here.
We target the criminals.
Most of their victims are black and Latino.
They're smart enough to know the difference.
I'm not trying to kill it.
Maybe with some modifications...
this plan could be a little more
civilian-friendly, that's all.
- This coming from a councilman
or a police captain?
- Both.
And you should know
there's a chance that...
I could be overseeing these seizures
on the police committee.
We don't answer to
the police committee on this.
- Not yet.
- [Phone Ringing]
- Yeah.
- [Mackey] We just missed him.
- What happened?
- Flower shop owner saw him, called it in.
- We missed him by five minutes.
- What do you need?
As many bodies as you can spare.
/ gotta blanket the area.
Okay. Excuse me.
[Julien]
Raga's who our boss is interested in.
Sees the tag in a dozen places
on her way in to work.
He's the main tagger
for the One-niners.
"Raga Paints." "P" is for "Po Boys,"
"ain't," "S" stands for "shit."
"Po Boys ain't shit."
Cute.
So does this have anything to do
with the, uh, territory being disputed?
This is the front line,
which is why Raga keeps hitting this sign.
Raga just gets the word out. But if we can
get him, we can find who's giving the orders.
Look for hoodies or skullies,
and a backpack to carry the paints.
I've been trying to get you guys onto
taggers for a long time. What changed?
We got a new captain. So what's the chance
of this guy hittin'again tonight?
Sometimes, it's hard to tell if ours is
even dried before they're taggin' over it.
- [Woman On Radio] Possible man down.
- That's us. Thanks.
- Have you looked at his file?
- Glanced at it.
- A 60-year-old drug dealer
that's never been arrested?
- Late bloomer?
- There's a possession charge in '89.
- A citation.
We've got unis staking out a guy
who got a ticket for having a joint.
- Maybe he's careful.
- You said he was a late bloomer.
- The D.A. says he's important.
- Yeah.
- I think they're tryin' to jerk us off.
- They requested us.
Because everybody else
is out huntin' a rapist.
Take yes for an answer?
Please?
Ruiz ran out of here
less than 20 minutes ago.
- Where do you want us?
- Start a couple of blocks up
and work your way north.
- Okay.
- Hey, Vic. Ruiz just called his fiancée.
- She tipped him the cops were there.
- Tell me we got a trace.
[Man]
They're gonna take care of you.
I need you with me.
I'll be right behind you.
I promise.
- [Yelling, Clattering]
- [Danny] Sir, come on.
- Calm down.
- It's his house.
[Yelling]
[Yelling, Sobbing]
Neighborhood canvass
came up empty.
- He's got family in Fresno.
- Unis are at the train and bus stations.
- What's your next move?
- I'm on the fiancée and the friend.
And we're gonna expand
the neighborhood search.
Ruiz didn't sling.
He wasn't a member of a gang.
Maybe you should talk to Dutch.
He's a little more plugged in
to this guy's psychology than you are.
[Sighs]
It's time to get creative.
- [Rap]
- [Whistles] Five-O!
Suvuto. How'd you and your thorns
like to play deputy for a day?
God's work
ain't cop's work, homey.
I thinkJesus'll
loan you out for this one.
- [Ronnie] Name's Oscar Ruiz.
- He who persecutes my brother
persecutes me.
Yeah? How about he who rapes
my mother or my sister?
At least five that we know about.
After he's done...
he makes them call their husband or
their boyfriend, tell 'em how good he was.
Ruiz escaped
from your hood this morning.
- We'll check it out.
- Good.
Look for flowers. He poses as
a delivery guy to get in the house.
- All right, homes.
- Someone sees him, I want a call.
Hey. Aren't you gonna
swear us all in?
Blessed is he who delivers
this asshole unto me.
- What do you got, Carl?
- Pulled him over for rolling a stop sign.
- Barely. I mean, come on.
- Hey, somebody tell you to talk?
When he opened the window,
I noticed a strong marijuana odor...
emanating from
inside the vehicle.
- Which gave you probable cause to search.
- Yes, sir.
- We found these.
- Good work, Officers.
Don't you have
anything more important to do?
I'm sorry you don't think buying illegal drugs
is important. Fortunately, the courts do.
Have you heard about the asset seizures
we've been doing around here?
We caught you with illegal drugs.
That means we can take your car.
We find any weed in your house,
you can kiss that good-bye too.
- You can't do that.
- Watch us.
- He's not lying.
- Have you ever been to prison?
- Have you, Slick?
- Of course not.
Forty years old. You really wanna
start down that road now?
Look, it was just a couple
of reefer sticks. Come on.
You've got one chance
to help yourself.
After that, it's out of my hands.
Now who's your dealer?
Maurice. But he's not a dealer.
He's just a friend.
Hooks me up.
Got a few plants in his backyard.
Enough for him and a few others.
- Three plants in his backyard?
- Well, that's just his version.
The D.A.'s office is trying
to make us look like idiots.
- Why would they do that?
- Somebody is lying to somebody.
- Right now, Slick's the only person I believe.
- How was the interview?
Oh, our major drug dealer
is looking a little minor.
Slick's ready to cooperate.
If the D.A.'s willing to pull
you two out of mothballs...
there's plenty
I could use you for.
- Vic talk to you yet?
- No.
He will.
Ooh. Crushing crime
one blunt at a time.
Find what you need?
I've been meeting with people
about staff jobs for my district office.
- / was just checking records.
- Resources are for law enforcement personnel.
Well, I'm a reservist,
so technically I am personnel.
Fell short of your
10-year pension, did ya?
Being a cop
gets in your blood.
So does being a politician
from what I hear.
If I can stay connected to the force
a couple of nights a month...
then I'm happy to serve.
I need some fresh air.
The effectiveness and fairness
of these seizures aside...
you're doing a bad job
selling them.
And you'd like
to be my publicist?
Forcing property forfeitures and asset seizures
on a community that's already decimated?
That's the current spin.
If this is about council getting a cut
of seized property, it's not my area.
I'm just making
a suggestion.
I've been where you are, and
I've learned there's always a compromise.
The policy
still needs time to breathe.
If I set up
a public forum...
where you can present your plan,
answer questions, will you come?
Sure.
You want a tip?
Well, I got one for you.
Heard about some eses
runnin' some wetbacks over the border.
I can eat lunch downtown, trip over
one or two on my way in the door.
Shit. My mom's got half a dozen
sleepin'in the back room any given night.
Yeah, well, these Mexicans,
they check in, they don't check out.
What does that mean?
They gotta find a family member
willing to pay a five grand relocation fee.
I got some credit now?
Yeah...
if the check clears.
Hey!
I heard about that rapist.
- Think you're close?
- I could use a break.
- What are you into?
- Got a line on a coyote farm.
We're gettin' ready to move.
Thought you might wanna hop on.
I could use a break,
not charity.
Peace offering, that's all.
You remember Shane Vendrell. He's got
something brewin' in our backyard.
Got word on a coyote farm,
hopin' maybe you could give us some backup.
- They're housing illegal aliens?
- Until the family can pay to spring 'em.
Just when they think they're free and clear,
boom, the final bill comes due.
All my officers
are tied up chasing Ruiz.
- So I guess we're on our own.
- Let me, uh-
Let me know when you're in position,
see what I can spare.
Thank you.
- Uh, so how's the hunt?
- I got some things worth looking into.
Well, look what the rat dragged in.
Uh- He's got a line on somethin'.
Some One-niner droppin'
stolen air bags at a garage on Third.
Think I'll cut out the back.
- So, what's going on with Webster?
- You tell me.
Are you saying
you don't have anything yet?
No. We hear he's got three
marijuana plants in his backyard.
Oh, well,
three is enough for us.
You said he was
a major drug dealer.
- He's selling drugs, isn't he?
- What aren't you telling me?
I'm not gonna push this
any further.
Webster's about to testify
for the defense in a murder trial...
and we'd like to
undermine his credibility.
You had us target a guy
to keep him off the witness stand?
That's bullshit!
You wanted out of the doghouse, remember?
You came to me.
And you knew if you laid it out for me,
I wouldn't go for it.
- It's not illegal.
- What? Just immoral?
- Not the way I see things.
- My partner doesn't like the smell of it.
Well, fortunately,
you promised to keep her under control.
But if you don't like the way
the deal is anymore...
we can go back
to the way things were.
- So you'll go under with Slick, right?
- Do me a favor.
- Get somebody else.
- It's our case.
- Well, I'd rather not.
- Well, that's great.
That's fantastic.
Hey. Hey, don't you
walk away from me...
not after /'ve had your back
every day for the last six months.
Look.
This is our way
to get back into the rotation.
He'll never buy me in this world.
It has to be you.
- [Yelling, Shouting]
- Get on the sidewalk, now!
[Julien]
Back off! Hey.
Drop it!
- [Mackey] Holy shit.
- [Honking Horn]
Back off!
They think it's the guy.
They just started chasing him. He called 911.
Hey, hey, back off!
Back off!
He's not the rapist!
He's Chinese, for Christ's sake!
[Siren Wailing]
What's wrong with you people?
Hey, what happened
to callin'me first?
They thought they got him.
They got excited.
If he's a Chinaman
driving an actual floral truck...
then feel free to assume
he's not our escaped, Hispanic rapist!
Hey, all you said
was flowers, man.
I asked for eyes on the street,
not a lynch mob.
And trust me, you find him,
he won't enjoy the process.
For Christ's sake!
What happened?
Ah, runnin' down Ruiz
has everyone a little on edge.
On edge? You put
a street gang on payroll?
Look, I was just goin' for intel. These guys
follow the messiah, not Suge Knight.
We're lucky
they didn't kill him.
/t's under control.
/ got the genie back in the bottle.
Maybe you should've asked the genie
for three wishes. About as realistic...
as expecting a street gang
to do your policing for you.
- Yeah, I get it.
- Are you gonna burn me, Vic?
No. I'm gonna catch this guy.
A lot of people warned me about using you.
Maybe I should've listened.
You told me to get creative.
That doesn't always go smoothly.
She's been sitting there all day
because she's afraid to go home.
Talk to Dutch?
Enjoy the show?
Deputizing vigilantes.
I gotta write that one down.
Yeah, well, the point is to find
this prick before he rapes again...
which is the only reason
I'd ask your opinion.
- Shoot.
- Ruiz had a roommate.
- He got a hundred bucks off of him.
- Worked once, it can work twice.
I'm on him.
You know about the fiancée.
- No family in town.
- You watchin' the border?
I got the street stuff covered.
I need you to drop some profile bullshit
on me, preferably something useful.
He used to rape once
every two or three months.
- He's raped twice today already.
As I predicted, he's bingeing.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- You're a genius.
- What else does he binge on?
At the end of the day
these guys are all loners...
and loners become
creatures of habit.
They have to.
Prison's forced deprivation.
Now he can indulge.
So what else does he like besides raping?
Kicking soccer balls, watching
video games, the same porn movie?
Whatever it is,
he's been missing it.
You're welcome, asshole.
[Jazz]
So, uh, Slick says your mama's ill?
I swear I don't know which is worse,
the chemo or the cancer.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
- Weed's the only thing that seems to help.
Wait right here, Claudette.
It's not chronic,
but it is fire.
[Sniffs]
Ahh.
/t's usually $20 a bag, but
the second one for your mama is gratis.
Hey, thanks, man.
That's great of you.
Yeah. God bless.
- I talked to you at the Continental.
- [Sara] I remember.
How did you get
my home number?
I can get any number
I want.
- Look, I'm gonna hang up.
- No, please don't.
I'm interested
in getting together.
But I need to be more careful
than most people.
- There's some precautions we need to take.
- All right.
Why don't you come over to my place
tonight, and we'll talk about them.
Okay.
What did Ruiz like to do
before he went away?
- I don't know.
- Where did he spend his time?
- In his room.
- Doin' what?
- I didn't even wanna know.
- Hey, you know what? I got this. Get out of here.
[Door Closes]
This guy did somethin'
besides raping all day.
- What was it?
- He'd get his takeout and close
his door all day every day.
What kind of takeout?
Chicken pot pie, man.
Same thing, same place.
The chicken pot pie at Clucky's.
Clucky's.
Good.
- I just waited on him.
- This guy?
An hour ago.
Did he do something wrong?
- Did you talk to him?
- Of course. I live off tips.
He seemed nice. He was lookin' for a car.
Asked me what I drove.
He asked me out too,
but I told him I had a fiancé.
- Jimmied.
- Where's your registration?
Glove compartment.
- Well, that's funny.
- Not really.
[Rock]
Vic!
He's off for the street!
[Continues]
Police!
Stay with him.
Stop!
- [Siren Chirping]
- [Tires Screeching]
[Grunts]
- Come! Come!
- Come on! He's close!
[Barking]
[Shouts In Spanish]
- Send him!
- Take him!
- [Barking, Snarling]
- [Ruiz Screaming]
- Should I call him back?
- Not yet.
Ruiz, throw out your gun.
- [Ruiz Shouting, /ndistinct]
- Throw out your gun right now!
- He lost the gun.
- Call the dog back?
This guy raped five women,
two today.
Yeah.
He might still be packin
- [Ruiz Screaming] Get him off of me.
- [Barking, Snarling]
Get off of me.
[Screaming]
[Screaming, Snarling Continue]
- Okay. Sounds like he's ready to give up.
- [Shouts In Spanish]
Emily?
- Yeah?
- We got him.
One of our officers
can take you home now.
- Is he in jail?
- He's in the hospital.
They used a police dog
to subdue him.
Ruptured one of
his testicles.
They say dogs are
a good judge of character.
[Whispering]
It's okay.
Hey, that was
a nice tip today.
Rescued over 80 illegals,
made six arrests.
- That worked out real good.
- No doubt.
Look, /'m not unreasonable. You work
with me, /'m gonna work with you.
Keep both our asses
in the clear.
It's good to give,
but it's nice to receive.
Mackey's got his eye
on this garage on Third...
droppin', uh,
stolen air bags or somethin'.
Yeah, okay.
But the seizure thing, man-
How's that gonna play out?
I'm workin' on
gettin' close for you.
- Good lookin
- I told you.
This could be a beginning thing.
If the check clears.
Man, / don't make trouble.
I don't hurt anybody.
I don't sell to kids.
I keep to myself.
But y'all act like
/'m out there...
killin' people.
I was lookin' out
for your mama, wasn't I?
Now y'all wanna
lock me up...
for three plants.
That ain't right.
[Knocking]
Can I talk to you outside?
Beth is gonna
take over from here.
He's all yours.
- What happened?
- Went by the tire store.
The air bag guy definitely
pulled up stakes and moved on.
Shane tipped them off.
All right. The good news
is we know about it.
So from now on,
watch what you say around him.
- You're a part of this now.
- I got a choice?
- All right, what do I gotta do?
- Shane thinks he knows all our moves.
So let's throw him a curveball.
Pick up Antwon's kid.
Let's let this guy feel the heat.
Which guy, Antwon or Shane?
Both.
[Pop]
You can smoke
if you like.
I might.
/'m glad you wanted
to see me.
I need to work
some things out.
Me too.
/ need you to proposition me,
so / know /'m safe.
I, uh, wanna be with you...
sexually.
I'll pay you.
Just tell me how much.
You're different, David.
I can tell.
/ like you.
Next time, you should bring me a gift
to show me that you like me too.
Anything you want,
but nice.
Six hundred dollars' worth.
/ can't wait to see
what you pick out.
- What are you doing?
- I'm undressing you.
Ow.
- I'll undress you.
- Okay.
That hurts.
You can slap...
but you can't
leave bruises...
anywhere.
No scratching,
and absolutely no blood.
You can pull hair
as long as you don't pull it out...
and you can choke
if it doesn't hurt too much.
/'ll show you a safe signal
in case / think it's going too far.
Didn't we see her before?
Raga's a girl.
Let me see your hands.
Sorry to ruin
your masterpiece.
[Julien] Not worth it. Just come down
the way you went up. Come on.
You've cost this city tens
of thousands of dollars in cleanup.
- Send me the bill.
- We will.
But you tell me who's planning
this war with the Po Boys...
who's giving you these messages,
I can make things better.
Bring her something to eat
while she thinks it over.
- Hamburger and fries.
- Settle a bet first.
What's "Raga" stand for?
"Righteous Angel, Gorgeous Ass."
I don't admire the artwork...
but I gotta admire
the confidence.
- So how's Pops?
- [Mutters] / don't know.
If he's King Asshole,
that make you prince?
I get some juice
on the street...
but I get problems too.
A lot of guys wanna take me down
for bein'his blood.
Hell yeah. You're walkin' around
with a bull's-eye on your chest.
And where's Antwon?
Oh, yeah, that's right.
He's got 10 other kids
to look in on.
/ hardly know the cat.
Just hear the lectures about me
going on the straight and narrow.
He should take
his own advice, right?
I got an idea
how to get him back...
for all those sad
Christmas mornings.
Back up, man.
I don't like the dude...
but I ain't gonna help the
white occupation take him down either.
Look, I heard about the garage.
I passed on the info.
But I'm not gonna
guarantee these things.
Look, I don't give a shit
about that garage.
- Then what in the hell is your problem?
- They busted my son.
You hear about that?
Huh?
They come around here
lookin' for help when they want it.
And then they go
and bust my son?
They bust my kid, man!
You think that shit is just bad luck?
I'll find out what I can.
They're comin' to get me through my blood,
man. That's what this shit is about.
He said he'd look into it.
Well, get it looked into.
'Cause that's what you're here for.
You're startin'to sound
a lot like Halpern.
Maybe you're thinking about
droppin' a dime too.
It's cool, brother.
It's cool.
- [Sighs]
- But I thought you said you were
close to the seizures dude.
- I will be.
- Right.
Then I'm waitin' on you,
white shadow.
You've been holdin'my daughter
all night for a little graffiti?
Your daughter tags for one of
the most violent gangs in the city.
Not my daughter.
Hi, Mom.
So where should we
send the bill?
[Rock]
- Still workin' the garage sting.
- [Door Closes]
Love that.
- So I want back in.
- Really?
Yeah, you're right. With this new captain,
Farm's where the action is.
But I'll need Army too.
We come as a package.
/ can't promise anything,
but /'ll grease the wheels.
Thanks. With that being said,
things are gonna be different now, right?
I'll report to you, but I answer to her
just like we talked about.
I could probably
make that work.
[Door Closes]
Beth /nsardi just called. The D.A. wants
the two of you on a fresh double murder.
Great.
Where are the bodies?
/s the D.A. 's office
assigning cases now?
- I expected a smile or two.
- What did we do to deserve this promotion?
I don't catch your meaning.
Exactly whose agenda
were we servicing...
by targeting and rolling
a three-plant drug kingpin?
- I'm not aware of any agenda.
- Right.
Shane Vendrell?
- The guy who rolled those coyotes.
- Yeah.
/ know we're taking on new personnel.
Truth is...
I could really use someone like him
workin' the drug angle with these gangs.
He made a nice bust today,
but l-
I don't know him very well
other than what's on paper.
A lot of that's bad.
Aceveda hated Shane as much as he hates me.
That's what that is.
Didn't the two of you have
some problems bigger than Aceveda?
- Well, brothers fight. Who do you trust more?
- So you're vouching for him?
Yeah.
He's a great cop.
Okay.
[Man Singing]
[Continues]
[Ends]
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Continues]
[Ends]