[Chattering, /ndistinct]
Hey.
- [Mackey] The Russians are on the move.
- [Man Speaking Russian]
The tall blond guy's Tretiak.
R.O.C. captain.
He's the asshole that Carl and Scooby
slapped with that reckless driving ticket.
[Ronnie]
Who's the girl?
[Curtis]
Must be one of his whores.
- [Groans]
- [Mackey] Oh, shit.
- Oh, this guy.
- Hey.
We got a job to do here, okay?
Yeah, smackin'a hooker around
is not gonna give us any leverage...
to twist this guy.
Why don't we turn over his office,
find something real to pin on him?
Yeah, I got it.
Looks like invoices for
the restaurant over here.
Go through 'em all. Show me
anything that doesn't look aboveboard.
We gotta find something
to hold over this guy's head.
[Man On Tape] Tell Phillip thatJames
and Peter are meeting us at the dance hall.
[Continues In Russian]
- English for Russian dummies.
- Check this out, man.
Looks like a lot
of their shipments...
get delivered to a warehouse
at the Alameda rail yard.
According to this,
he has beef shipped there twice a month.
- So it's a steak and blow job joint.
- A warehouse is for dry goods.
Well, what kind of steak
doesn't need refrigeration?
I usually just order the blow job.
Can we talk someplace?
I'm good here.
The chief s made the decision
to shelf the asset forfeiture policy.
I'm sorry.
It wasn't an easy decision.
You were the eyes and ears
of the chief on this project.
Who's really the one
with his finger on the kill switch?
We have two dead cops, allegations
of corruption and a community on fire.
We said from the start
it would be a trial.
Cops in other divisions
are expressing concerns-
They haven't seen firsthand
how this is working.
Look, l-
I called you out in front of Aceveda,
said some things I shouldn't have.
I apologize.
We know how invested
you are in this policy.
That's why we want you to draft
the department's statement...
explaining why
we're suspending it.
Sell it to the press
however you deem appropriate.
Well, Phillips is hoping
I'll just quit.
He wants you to take
one for the blue.
/'ve been taking one for the blue
for over 20 goddamn years.
When are they gonna
take one for me?
The seizures
are making a difference.
You keep trying to make that case,
but the crime stats say otherwise.
Those stats
are three months behind.
I see a difference
in our caseloads every day.
Less violent crime,
less gang activity.
- Those numbers catch up,
they'll show that I'm right.
- Not if they shut you down now.
Well, it's not a done deal
until Pol Com signs off on it.
They're assuming your committee
will just rubber-stamp it.
The next session is in three days.
I know how much
you've got invested in the Barn.
It's your legacy.
/ also know how you'd like
the city council...
to have more influence
on how the department operates.
Us working together
is the last thing...
that downtown will suspect.
I mean, Mitchell's in jail. We ride out
this rough spot. We keep the seizures going.
Crime goes down.
Revenue continues.
It's a win-win.
Farmington becomes a model
for other districts...
and you get to hang
your mayoral hat on a big success.
And where do we stand
with the murders of Scooby and Carl?
Have you been able to prove
that they're not seizure-related?
- Not yet.
- Well, that would be helpful.
Whoever's behind them
is our main priority.
[Shane] So what do you think's
in the Commie lunch box?
- [Mackey] Coke and a sandwich?
- Yeah, or China white.
It's too milky to be tar.
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Shane]
Looks like the girl's translating.
Hey, the guy with the Russians is drivin'
a pickup that says "Hobalt Construction."
He's alone.
- Did hejust leave the drugs sitting there?
- What's that about, man?
I don't know, man,
but I'm gonna get a closer look.
- Oh, shit!
- What's up?
- Goddamn!
- Christ!
Heads up, dude.
What the hell was that? Jesus Christ.
C-4!
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Ends]
- Hey, can you do me a favor?
- Yeah, what do you need?
I need you to remain silent, 'cause
anything you say might get you shot.
I got behind on my book.
Ponies mostly.
I started paying Tretiak back
in supplies- lumber, cement-
- Explosives.
- The Russians asked me to get C-4.
I told 'em it was too risky. The government
keeps pretty close tabs on that shit.
They threatened to tell my boss.
So / forged the A. T.F. papers...
getting it from a plant
in Arkansas.
- The shipment comes in today.
- What are they usin' it for?
I don't know. They're shipping
a ton of it back to Kamchatka.
Oh, shit. Every one
of those countries is so worried...
about what's getting smuggled in, nobody's
watching what's getting shipped out.
That clay hits Russian soil, R.O.C. can distribute
it to any major terrorist organization.
What size shipment
are we talking about?
A ton.
Tell A.T.F. it went down too fast to call.
We'll let them haul it away.
I'll get SWAT and the bomb crew
to back us up.
- Great. "Us"?
- I'm riding with you and your guys on this.
Hey, wait. This is real
"breach and bang'"stuff.
It's not a great time
to babysit.
In three days, Phillips is gonna
recommend to the police commission...
that they kill
our seizure policy.
We need to prove that these cop killings
aren't seizure-related.
That gives us a lifeline.
What we need is to find everyone who
was involved in killing Carl and Scooby.
Which is why I'm coming with.
[Chattering]
So how you wanna do this?
C-4's pretty harmless without a cap,
but I wouldn't wanna risk any gunplay.
Let them lock up the container. Have the
sharpshooters take point on the bridge.
My guys will be the first wave.
Have SWAT take tactical watch.
- Back us up with unis.
- Okay.
- You find Tretiak?
- He's back at the restaurant.
Guess he didn't like heavy lifting.
He's saving his strength
for the hooker beating.
When we're done here, you two peel off.
Pick up Tretiak and his lieutenant.
And grab the hooker too.
We're gonna need a translator.
I know these Russians. Once they
get into custody, they turn into stone.
I'm tired of our leads dead-ending.
We're gonna bleed Tretiak for everything
he knows about Carl and Scooby.
- Okay, we're all set.
- Us too.
- Hands in the air right now!
- [Voices Overlapping]
- Face down on the ground!
- Let's go, Boris!
- You, buddy, on the ground!
- Get down, right now!
- Goddamn it.
- [Sirens Blaring]
Take your arms out wide!
Let's go!
Cold war's over, boys!
No sign of a struggle. No buckshot
through the hands. He never saw it comin'.
- That better or worse?
- Either way, it's worse.
Sir, a tech found this
and a 12-gauge shell.
Looks like the victim's wallet.
Gill Prue. Local.
Am Ex, A.T.M. card.
About 40 bucks.
If he wasn't robbed,
why get blasted at point-blank range?
Hummer gone bad?
Gang execution?
"Dr. Grohl. Rage management classes.
One-on-one counseling."
Maybe he ran into someone
who flunked that class.
I know a shotgun to the genitals
always brings me to my happy place.
[Muffled Grunting]
He's never gonna hurt you again.
You understand that?
Never again.
This is right?
- You are police?
- Yes, yes. We'll give you protection.
[Shouting, Indistinct]
Relax! Relax.
Take it easy.
I will help.
Good. Now you ask him why
they hired the Nigerians to kill those cops.
[Speaking Russian]
[Russian]
[Screaming, Shouting]
Jesus! We're gonna need
a different plan.
Our victim just got out
of Chino two weeks ago.
It was his third run.
He was a high school phys ed teacher.
Coached baseball.
His latest stretch...
was for nearly beating
a shortstop to death.
It is America's favorite pastime.
Don't let 'em know it's eating you.
They'll never lay off.
Two cops are dead.
You'd think harassing me...
about dating Vic's wife
wouldn't be a priority.
You're the distraction keeping them from
thinking about dead cops. Forget about it.
[Dutch] You were tired
of the life- constant beatings...
embarrassment, ridicule.
He got out of Chino,
came home.
Just couldn't take it anymore.
[Claudette]
Sold your car last week for $8,700.
Maybe you hired someone
to stop Gill from hurting you?
The cash was for a fake I.D.
Forged reference letters.
He knew no school
was gonna hire him with his record.
Is that why he was in that part of town?
Getting a fake I.D.?
- Could've been.
- You didn't go with him?
No. I was at
my 6:30 A.A. meeting.
[Claudette] /s there anyone else
who knew he had the money-
that he was getting a fake I.D.?
What, dear?
I've been sharin' about it
in my morning meeting.
One of the newcomers,
guy in a wheelchair- Bumper-
he caught me in the parking lot
after a meeting.
Told me he-
he knew someone...
could help get Gill the /.D. 's.
- [Muffled Grunting]
- Relax.
Make that look real.
These guys know how that shit works.
Don't worry, Olga. We'rejust
gonna scare the borscht out of your buddy.
Get him a little chatty.
What's the Russian for "all wired up"?
Let's go.
You tell him he's got 30 seconds
to tell us why they hired the Nigerians...
and who else was involved
in killing our cops...
or we blow his boss
to red heaven, and then him.
[Russian]
- [Russian]
- [Muffled Yelling]
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Tell him to relax
or he's gonna flip that goddamn chair.
[Russian]
Vic?
- Jesus Christ!
- [Shouting In Russian]
Shut up! Shut up!
- Holy shit!
- [Curtis] That was loud, brother.
- What the hell are we gonna do?
- Holy shit.
- Oh, my God.
- All right.
Get our shit. Grab the Russians.
Let's get out of here.
Go.
Move.
- Go, go, go.
- Come on! Let's go!
[Man Speaking Russian]
That's far enough!
He says he doesn't know why. Tretiak just
told him to hire Nigerians to kill police.
The black cop gave Tretiak a ticket.
Is that why he killed him and his partner?
[Russian]
He doesn't think so.
Says he was crazy, not stupid.
Oh, shit! Apparently, the only person
who knew anything just blew himself up.
[Russian]
He says there was a young black
with the Nigerians driving.
- A third black guy? Three?
- [Man Speaking Russian]
He says he saw him once before.
He brought language tapes to Tretiak.
- Get her keys to the restaurant.
Go get those tapes.
- Yeah.
You know someplace safe
you can go?
Nina, we're gonna grab some coffee
at Ivid's. Be back in a few.
- This subpoena was just delivered.
- All right.
What is it?
Uh, it's nothing.
Judge wants me to sign some affidavits.
I always get these.
You ready? Huh?
- [Buzzer Sounds]
- [Door Opens]
Glad you could find time to visit.
- Thought you were up in Terminal Island.
- I'm in County this week.
Waiting for the judge
to consider my appeal.
- Appeal? On what grounds?
- [Scoffs] Innocence.
I didn't rob that market.
Three witnesses,
including myself, saw you.
Well, Ricky,
he went in for food.
Next thing I know,
I hear gunshots.
Ran in to see what happened.
You pointed a finger at me.
So your lawyer will actually think that
a judge will buy that bullshit story?
Oh, that's not gonna happen.
They're gonna drop the charges
when you take the stand...
and admit that
you forced my confession.
Otherwise, /'m just gonna
tell the whole courtroom...
what went down with us.
- [Chuckling] I ain't got nothin' to lose.
- No one's gonna believe you.
Well, I got
the picture to prove it.
Oh, you know...
on your knees,
my dick in your mouth.
Shut up.
You forget the 50 ways
that / can screw you...
and your loved ones to death
if you open your mouth?
My grandma-
she died last month.
Had that throat cancer.
My mom, she got tired of wipin'
rich kids' ass and moved back to Mexico.
You don't have a picture...
and neither
does your girlfriend.
Believe what you want.
But you will get on that stand
and say you violated my rights.
Or you will pull some strings
and get me out of here...
power man!
Show me what you can do.
- Show it to me.
- [Buzzer Sounds]
- We found Tretiak.
- Damn!
Must've mishandled
his merchandise.
Our best lead to these cop killers
just got blown to hell.
Well, if he was involved,
it smells like justice to me.
We'll go through the restaurant,
see if it gives us anything.
We traced some of these
books on tape in Tretiak's office...
to the U.C. Northridge
language library.
Checked out by a Jason Porter.J.P.
- Ring a bell?
- Yeah.
Dutch found a J.P. necklace in the sewer
next to Carl and Scooby's bodies.
This kid's a foreign language major.
Spanish, Korean, Russian.
Clean record.
Got his dad's address.
Department head says he's been M./.A.
from classes for the last two weeks.
Since Carl and Scooby were killed.
- [Knocking]
- We're looking forJason Porter.
So am I.
I haven't seen my boy in two weeks.
Come on in.
Look around if you like.
Do you have any idea
where he might be?
He's an adult. Uh, road trips
to Northern California all the time.
Uh, college buddies.
Why are you lookin'for him?
He may know a couple of Nigerians
involved in a shooting.
- We need to talk to him.
- No, it doesn't sound likeJason's friends.
Oh, shit.
Hey, check this out.
That's Jason.
This guy always show up
at your picnics?
Antwon Mitchell,
Jason's half brother.
You're not Antwon's
biological father?
No, Jason and Antwon
share the same mother.
Antwon and I
are no relation.
You were a correctional officer
at Chowchilla, weren't you?
- Yeah.
- Knocked up Antwon's incarcerated mother.
Cost you your job.
Got into security work
and raised Jason on my own.
If you know where your son is,
you need to tell us.
Places he goes, his friends.
Guess I didn't ask enough questions about
where he goes and who he hangs out with.
I'm sorry about that.
/ cross-referenced Bumper
with D.U./. 's.
"Francis Valverde, a.k.a. Bumper."
Various gang stuff.
Took a bullet in a drive-by two years ago.
Left him wheelchair-bound.
He's been clean ever since.
Paula and Carlos
are scooping him up now.
[Laughter]
Well, if the pad fits-
I packed the napkins,
forgot the sandwich.
Hey, uh- Hey, hey.
You find out who's pulling this shit?
- No, not yet.
- Did you ask around, or-
Look, I've been workin' an assault
that's got me spinnin'.
But I'm onto it.
I promise, okay?
You think this kid's capable
of murdering two cops?
Antwon's blood?
It wouldn't surprise me.
He could be hiding anywhere.
How do we find him?
/ got a C./.
who works a pawnshop.
He put the word out on the street
that P.D. never found the necklace-
that it's just
sitting there at his shop.
That's an expensive
piece of ice.
Mm-hmm. I'm hopin' that greed wins out
over smarts, and he comes to claim it.
Listen, man,
/'m the B.N.O.C., brother, okay?
I spread the word
from Crenshaw to Northridge.
If he's in town,
he got the memo.
The video recorders are all on. Just step
on this power strip, they'll all kick in.
You can'tjust sell him the necklace.
You gotta make him prove that it's his.
I'm well versed in
the conversational arts.
Good.
Here's for your education.
- There's another hundred
if you don't screw it up.
- Come on, buddy.
/ call the police, / don't know exactly,
six or seven times a month.
I've stopped keeping track.
Harassment can be hard to prove.
It's random, unpredictable.
It's as if they think it's my fault,
or it's all in my head.
The phone calls, the rotten eggs
on my car, the bleach on my lawn.
Tell me about
the, uh, call today.
/t was from a man
who has called before who says...
I deserve to suffer
the way Will's victims suffered.
Said he was gonna rape you?
Kill you? He used those words?
He said he watched me come home.
He knew what / was wearing.
The police are not
gonna protect me.
I thought you could
help me get a carry permit.
For a gun?
Do you have one?
What choice did / have?
Listen, most of the time,
threats arejust threats.
Somebody trying to feel powerful
by making you afraid.
Well, it's working.
Hey, guys, we haveJoanna Faulks's
phone records from the last month.
- /t's a pretty short list.
- Thanks.
She received, like,
15 calls?
And 11 were from telemarketers.
So much for the
"friends and family" plan.
Aside from the 911, the numbers she dialed
mostly were pizza and Chinese places.
Shit. She left me a message
a couple months ago.
It's been a pretty rough time
around here for all of us.
Yeah. Check the names
of the callers...
against a list
of the cuddler's victims.
- See if there's a connection.
- Okay.
- That's him, buddy.
- [Line Ringing]
Horus' Trade.
- Yo, that's him.
- Come on, man. Let me check it out.
Yeah. Okay.
Will do. Bye.
What's goin' on, brother?
How you livin'?
Heard you got your hand
on a necklace.
- Initials "J.P."?
- Uh, yeah.
No, you know,
l-I keep it locked up, you know?
It's a real fine dog tag here, man.
Ah! Check it out.
- How much?
- Hmm.
You know what? I'm in a charitable mood
today, so I tell you what.
/'ll give it to you on the cheap.
Fifteen grand.
- You smokin' crack, brother?
- Nigger, that is platinum, okay,
with half carats all around.
The necklace is worth 10 G's.
So what, you the-
you the bling king now?
I know how much it's worth,
'cause I'm J.P.
It's mine.
My brother gave it to me.
Listen, a homeless dude came in here.
He told me that he found it in the gutter.
That's where I lost it.
- My brother's Antwon Mitchell.
You want that kind of trouble?
- Go, go, go!
No, I don't.
- Heads up!
- Listen, I have heard of Antwon, okay?
- All I'm saying is-
- Freeze. Police.
[Voices Overlapping]
Shut up.
/ have a receipt
for everything.
What happened?
She came home, found the back door
unlocked. Reported a break-in.
You know where you leave things.
Someone was in here.
Maybe it's possible that you left
the back door unlocked yourself.
Why, with everything that's happening to me,
would I leave the door unlocked?
- You can go, Officers. Thank you.
- Sure thing, Detective.
The carry permit-
I'd still like to get that.
Honestly, I don't, uh-
I don't think it's a good idea.
Uh, listen, I owe you an apology.
You left a message.
- I meant to call you back.
- When Will was arrested, I was angry...
at him and you.
And nothing made sense.
I called because
I thought perhaps...
I could cook you dinner.
My way of apologizing.
Oh. Uh, that's, uh-
that's not necessary.
But, um-
But thanks.
Listen, / have-
/ really have to get back.
I have a murder case.
I'll keep the unis comin' by, checkin' on you.
You're gonna be fine.
Remember me, Mr. Mayor?
Juan's girlfriend.
The one you kidnapped.
Juan says you think we're bluffing-
that we don't have the picture.
I'm sorry.
I don't know who you are.
You can't put your hands-
[Groaning]
What's this?
[Aceveda On Tape]
I don't know who you are.
If you really had a picture, you wouldn't
need me on this admitting one exists.
You'll see it when
Juan shows it in the court.
Or maybe we can
mail it to the Times.
Look. I might be able
to do something...
but it takes time.
So you need to convince
your boyfriend to be patient.
No way.
He's only in County this week...
and he's not goin' back to T.I.
You know whatJuan did to you.
And soon, everyone'll know
unless you get him out of there.
- [Sophia]Jimmy.
- Jimmy.
[Aurora]
Uh-huh.
Now let's make one
for Daddy, okay?
[Sophia]
/t's a flower without petals.
[Aurora Laughs]
- Here.
- /'m gonna draw a Christmas tree.
Okay.
I gotta go finish
some things up.
It's Antwon Mitchell's
half brother.
How did you miss
the connection?
[Monica] The kid's on the dean's list.
No record, no gang ties.
Doesn't seem like the type
to go 187.
Why are you here?
Heard you got a break
on our cop killings.
Jason might be
our Antwon connection.
Which means the murders
are seizure-related.
Uh, we don't know
what it means yet.
[Door Opens]
[Monica] Nice ice.
You should've seen it when we found it...
covered in the blood
of two dead cops.
I lost it on
my way home from school.
Before or after
the dog ate your homework?
- That's the truth.
- [Monica]
We know you were with the Nigerians...
when they killed our guys.
We also know
you have a bright future.
No way you'd be stupid enough
to do something like this...
without your brother Antwon
telling you to.
I barely know Antwon.
These are checks for your tuition
at U.C. Northridge.
- That's Antwon's signature.
- So he pays some bills.
Doesn't mean it's a love fest.
[Mackey]
Antwon paid for your college.
You killin'two cops sounds like
the love bein'paid back in full.
Antwon didn't have anything
to do with that. He's a leader.
A visionary.
His incarceration is a crime against
this community and all people of color.
[Mackey]
Let's stick to your crimes.
You're an accomplice
to the murders of two cops.
We have a Nigerian in custody
who's anxious to make a deal...
and your bling
at the crime scene.
Covering up for Antwon
is gonna do you no good.
Now, if this is about
you cozying up with him at Lompoc...
ain't gonna happen.
I met one of the Russians
at school.
They knew who / was,
thought / might be willin'to help.
/ arranged the deal
with the Nigerians.
That night, I helped
communicate the plan.
I did it to prove to Antwon
that I can play in his league.
He didn't know anything
about it.
So it sounds like
Antwon's clean on this one.
You really think
the Fresh Prince in there...
brokered a high-power deal
between the Russians and the Nigerians?
He admitted to his part in the murders.
Antwon's already in jail.
Sometimes, you have to take
"I did it" for an answer.
That's bullshit.
This kid is Antwon's tool. You know it.
Look, / know pinning this on Antwon
puts these murders on the seizures.
That's a bad thing for us.
I understand.
/ just wanna find out
the whole truth...
wherever it leads.
- [Groaning]
- Jesus!
- [Dutch] Sorry. Sorry.
- Shithead!
Get him up.
Let's get him up. You got it?
[Straining]
Come on.
Okay. We're okay.
We're okay now.
Tell us about Nokey.
Nokey? He's an I.D. guy
I used to roll with.
All puns intended.
Did good work.
I gave Gill his number.
Anything in it for you?
Commissions? Kickbacks?
- Just a chance to be of service.
- You, uh, happen to have
Nokey's number handy?
Sorry.
I lost it.
We'll get it from Gill's house.
- We'll be back.
- I'm not goin' anywhere.
A visitor this late at night?
Must be important.
I've got some friends in Justice
who might be interested in you.
A lot of people
interested in me.
These friends can offer you
witness protection.
You're monitored,
but you're free.
I ain't a rat.
You got loyalties
to the Salvadorans?
The D.E.A. can't make their case,
and they're looking for any help they can get.
Well, if the feds want my love,
why the hell am I talkin' to you?
They know the havoc
you left in Farmington.
They won't push this through
without some local cover, and that's me.
- Now, / can go tell Justice you're interested-
- If what?
If you're willing to give some
serious intel on the Salvadorans.
Now you gotta give 'em
the names at the top, names that matter.
All the locals in charge.
People in Central America
that they answer to.
That's a tall order, man.
Well, that's the only way
this works.
And I assume there's some sort of...
broker's fee for you?
Uh-uh.
Nothing for me.
Huh.
CallJustice.
Tell 'em I'm interested.
I will.
In the meantime,
there's an inmate here in County.
Name's Juan Lozano.
He's due to testify
this week.
It could upset a case
that the D.E.A.'s working on.
This could be your chance
to show that you're a team player.
ConvinceJuan
to miss his court date.
I'll see what I can do.
I'll callJustice.
You do that.
- [Buzzer Sounds]
- [Door Opens]
237. Got it. Thanks.
I'll get back to you.
- [Laughter]
- [Claudette] Are you okay?
They're- They're bringing in Nokey.
Let's talk to him.
Dutch. Come on.
We found Nokey.
/ don't think he likes you anymore.
He confessed to making
the fake I.D.'s.
He said Gill was supposed to come by and
pick 'em up, pay off the $6,500 balance.
Claims he didn't murder him though.
We believe him. Blowing off
a guy's nads and stealing his money-
that's just bad business.
You knew Gill had the cash.
You took him down a quiet alley...
put two rounds
of buckshot in his privates.
/n that chair, you'd have been
face-to-balls with the guy.
And then rolled away
with the cash.
[Sighs]
That's pretty ambitious for a cripple.
You mean a person
with a disability?
I'm a goddamn cripple.
I own that.
You also own
a brand-new handicap ramp.
The contractor just
e-mailed me the work order.
$6,000.
You paid cash this afternoon.
/f / test those wheels, /'m gonna find
shotgun residue and Gill's blood.
I should probably
get a lawyer.
I didn't threaten to rape anyone.
I have a wife and two kids.
But how do you explain the calls made
from your house toJoanna Faulks's?
Maybe one of my kids
dialed the wrong number.
Her husband was convicted of raping
and killing several women last year.
Your mother lives two doors down
from one of the victims- Dory Smythe.
Police interviewed her
at the time of the crime.
And my mom's still scared
shitless because of it.
What does that have
to do with me?
Okay, this asshole did it,
but he's just not gonna confess.
He's actually trying
to pawn it off on his sons.
Uh, take the recording over
toJoanna's house in the morning.
See if she can, uh,
I.D. the voice.
All right, sure.
/ covered your ass last week.
/ ask you for a simple favor.
- Not only do you not help me out, you pile on.
- You gotta unwind a little bit.
All I see is you laughing
right along with everybody else.
Maybe I ought to set an example,
starting with you.
- You don't wanna get into this.
- It's not so funny now? Huh?
What are you gonna do, turn off
the hose and hide behind your car?
Check it out-
Billings and Dutch.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Oh.
- Get him, Dutch-boy.
- I got 20 on the geek!
- That's even money, brother.
Get him around.
Get him around, baby.
[Shouting Continues]
[All Gasping]
How many slap fests
do I have to break up today?
Goddamn it!
[Yells]
Come on.
Let's just finish this.
Come on, asshole.
Let's go! Yeah, you, Vic!
Come on! You too!
You wanna keep ridin' me?
You wanna mess with my chair?
Yeah, let's finish this!
Two of our own are dead.
- [Door Slams Shut]
- [Monica] Rise and shine.
You have to give us
another name.
Apparently, Antwon's lawyer thinks
helping you is a conflict of interest.
- / don't understand.
- It means your big brother doesn't give a shit...
about where you end up,
which makes me wonder...
why you're trying so hard
to protect him.
Antwon's just
lookin' out for me.
Then why'd he make such a big show
about that custom necklace he got for ya?
A couple of his boys
picked it up in a robbery.
The original owner has confirmed
that it was stolen.
Antwon's always got my back,
ever since I was a shorty.
Helps with groceries, covers the mortgage
when my dad's out of work.
Y'all arejust tryin'
to screw me 'cause /'m tired...
get me
to say somethin'stupid.
I'm sure Antwon's briefed you about
the Farmington asset forfeiture policy.
Him being a known drug dealer,
that statement means...
we can get a warrant,
look into your father's finances.
The statement before the one
about you sayin'somethin'stupid.
The mortgage payments
made with drug proceeds?
- We can take your father's house.
- Or you can tell the truth.
Keep your daddy
from movin' into a shelter.
Nobody touches my dad's house.
I don't wanna go
someplace far away.
We can connect you
to the murder of two cops.
You go wherever
we say you go.
Or / can talk to the D. A...
get the death penalty
off the table.
Make sure they put you
into protective custody.
You stay alive:
Dad still enjoys retirement...
rocking on the front porch.
I need to see
the deal on paper.
Then I'll tell you
how it went down.
- This is all your stuff.
- Thanks.
Could we just, uh,
for a minute-
The kids are getting ready
for school...
and, um, I don't want them
to see your face like that.
Listen. When I said before
this started because of Vic...
that's not the only reason.
It's the only one that matters.
See, no, it isn't...
because there's something here.
/ know you wanna
believe that now...
but Vic got under your skin,
and I was a way to get back at him.
Maybe he's still under
your skin?
Maybe you even thought you-
you could get back at him a little?
- Show him you've moved on?
- Men have time for pissing contests.
Mothers don't.
You want me to forgive you?
You're forgiven.
[Chuckles]
Listen, l-I didn't tell you about Vic...
because I was afraid
you wouldn't go out with me.
And then I was afraid to tell you
because things were going so well.
- Being afraid ruined it.
- Yeah, it did.
Well, I'm not afraid anymore.
So at some point...
Iook past my bad start,
give me another chance.
Let me know.
[Door Opens]
Antwon saw
the coming tide.
Black and whites' days
are numbered.
It's all about making peace
with the red, yellow and brown.
He paid for your education,
made sure someone in his organization...
could speak the languages,
so he wouldn't be left behind.
A goodwill ambassador,
only instead ofbrokering peace...
you brokered drug deals,
gang alliances.
How did Antwon get the Russians
and the Nigerians together?
- The Russians had a beef with P.D.
- 'Cause we took down Kozodav?
Antwon was plugged
into that.
He offered Tretiak
the Nigerians as hired help.
Why were officers
Haimes and Miller targeted?
Tretiak's idea.
The black cop
pissed him off...
gave him a speeding ticket.
And you?
I translated, drove...
made sure the Nigerians had
what they needed to get thejob done.
Antwon's emissary.
[Jason]
Russians have an international pipeline.
Need 'em in your corner
if you wanna play outside the States.
Killin' the cops was a handshake.
Antwon knew if they did this, they'd be tied.
There'd be trust.
An oath in blood.
- [Knocking]
- Police.
- Miss Faulks?
- I hear a TV.
[TV, /ndistinct]
Shit. She said the intruder
came through the back the last time.
Miss Faulks, the police!
You in there?
- [Gunshot]
- One-Tango-13. Shots fired.
- Officer down.
- [Groans]
Oh, God!
Let me see your hands.
Put that gun down.
- Put the gun down. Drop it.
- / thought you were-
- Put it down! Down!
- I didn't know! I'm so sorry! l-
Put your hands on your head!
- I heard something outside.
I thought you were-
- Oh, God.
Step down!
Move, now!
- /'m so sorry.
- [Groaning]
Give us a minute, now.
The D.E.A. just requested all
departmental files on Antwon Mitchell.
Shit. Are they thinking
of making a deal?
Witness protection, immunity.
I hear it's done.
What? We've gotta
get it off the table.
- We just linked him to the two cop murders.
- How?
His half brother gave him up.
- Antwon's gonna walk.
You and your boy really did it.
- Me?
And Aceveda.
I know all about the dance...
you two are planning
for the Pol Com session.
You help him navigate
this Mitchell deal?
What the hell
are you talking about?
Aceveda brokered the deal
between Mitchell and D.E.A.?
A woman like you- I figured you'd get to know
your bedmates before you lay down with them.
Oh, shit!
- The deal is off!
- What?
Big brother struck a better one,
which leaves you shit out of luck!
- You can't do that!
- You're gonna take a lethal injection...
for the killing of two cops...
and I'm gonna
be there to watch!
- Put him back in the cage.
- What the hell happened?
Aceveda shit all over us.
Brokered Antwon to the D.E.A.
- Witness protection.
- They're lettin' him go?
Excuse me. The councilman's busy.
You can't go in there-
Where the hell do you get off
cutting a deal for Antwon Mitchell?
Hey, it's the D.E.A. 's deal.
They asked me to approach him.
Antwon ordered the hit
on our cops.
His half brother
just gave him up.
You just set a cop killer free,
you dick!
- The kid said he acted alone.
- That family has a little bit
of trouble with the truth.
- He lied!
- Call the deal off.
I can't. It's in
the D.E.A.'s hands now.
Carl and Scooby were stabbed
over and over again...
probably alive long enough
to feel most of it.
I was there when the bodies were
carried out. I'm the one who found them!
- I'm still a cop!
- Bullshit!
Cops want only one thing-
Antwon executed for what he did.
The D.E.A. cannot make a case
against the Salvadoran cartel.
Mitchell is willing to give up the entire
pipeline, all right? This is huge.
You mean your council buddies
get a few favors from Sacramento.
Do you think I care
about a D.E.A. win?
- Carl and Scooby were my men!
- You're the one who came crawling
to me asking for a lifeline!
- And I was an asshole
to think you were an option!
- Watch it. You still need me.
I need shit from you!
You can take your backroom handshakes,
your D.E.A. cronies...
and your self-serving,
cop-killer deals...
and you can
shove them up your ass.
You're not a cop.
You never were.
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Continues]
[Ends]