Nice to see you, man.
[Car Door Closes]
- How was your week?
- It was okay.
- How was yours?
- Smooth.
Matter of fact,
I hit a trifecta.
Lost a half million dollars
in product in the church seizure.
Six of my top soldiers
got busted.
But the highlight was
the El Salvadorans cut off my supply.
You'll find a new pipeline
to tap.
Yeah, but in the meantime, how are we
gonna get back all that money / lost?
[Shane] You're a drug dealer. Why don't you
consider it the cost of doing business?
So you're saying
my business model's flawed?
Maybe / need a new partner.
Buy-in's 20 grand, cash,
my hands by tomorrow.
I thought you didn't smoke
the shit you sold. Come on, man.
I don't have that kind
of cash lying around.
Look, man,
I know you been skimmin'.
Consider it the cost
of doin' business.
[Sighs]
Plus, one more thing.
What?
- That's Kozodav? Man, he doesn't look all that.
- [Chuckles]
Don't let him fool ya. His enemies
are all fish food in the L.A. River.
- That's Kozodav's car?
- [Mackey] Yeah.
Cover me while I replace
the hard drive underneath.
Dudes are 30 feet away.
Can't we do it later?
The hard drive is full, and Kozodav's
been talkin' about somethin' big.
/f something's on that disk,
we gotta know pronto.
Forget what these guys been talkin'about.
What's Shane been sayin'to Antwon?
Nothing incriminating.
- Have you seen the tapes?
- Ronnie has.
Don't worry about it.
We're watchin
Oh, shit.
Russians are coming.
Hurry up.
[Man Speaking Russian]
- Good evening, gentlemen.
- Can I help you, Officer?
I thought the Moscow Ballet was in town,
and then I saw the ink.
New policy says I gotta get name, rank
and serial number, comrade. Let's go.
Save the shakedowns
for the niggers and spics.
I got a Jew lawyer.
His name is Paul Hirschheimer.
You wanna talk with me,
call him.
- Got a gun.
- Coppin' an attitude, one thing.
Coppin' a Glock is another.
Might be time to get
thatJew on the phone.
He's a bodyguard.
He's got a permit to carry.
[Sighs]
Well, I'm afraid I owe
you gentlemen an apology.
You won't be bothered again.
Video transfer of the hard drive
we pulled from Kozodav's car last night.
He hired someone to torch a building
to pay off an insurance scam.
- Mention when?
- No. But the contract's out.
- Could happen as early as today.
- Know the arsonist's name or the target?
Nothing.
It sounds residential.
Shithead joked there were only
Mexicans living there.
If we arrest him right now,
how bad can we hurt him?
We've got over 10 counts
of extortion, racketeering, grand theft.
- He'll do a minimum 20.
- So we bring him in...
use that as leverage to get him
to give up the arsonist.
I think it's time we shut
this thing down, declared victory.
I'll call the chief.
Get a team together.
Bring him in.
[Exhales Forcefully, Chuckles]
Vic, / had some doubts...
about you handling both the seizures
and the garage sting...
but great work.
/ couldn't have done it
without Ronnie.
Nice work.
Big Chief, Vic needum new
driving machine...
so he can catchum bad guy.
Knew you had some Spanish.
Didn't know you knew smoke signals.
Hey, there's a criminal somewhere
out there drivin' my new ride.
I got two Laker tickets
for the one who seizes it first.
- What do you have in mind?
- Hey, Dutch-boy. What are you driving these days?
- Subaru.
- Anything but a Subaru.
- [Cops Chuckling]
- All right. We'll have you riding in style in no time.
Somethin'fast. / can't take down
these R.O.C. assholes...
goin' zero to 60
in four minutes.
Let's find the big guy
a new car.
So, are we gonna bust
these Russians or what?
Captain's runnin'late.
We can't start without her.
Bringin' him back wasn't my idea. Captain
wanted someone from Juvie in-house.
- Yeah, sure, whatever.
- All right.
You all know your assignments.
Take up positions in 20 minutes.
Hold off, everyone.
- What's going on?
- Change in plans.
[Aceveda] That church
you raided last week?
- [Men Shouting On TV]
- [People Screaming]
Hold it. Muncelle!
[Screaming Continues]
[Shouting Continues]
That is not how it went down.
People were not screaming.
This tape has been edited.
Where's the untouched version?
This is the version
the local news stations have.
- It hits the air tonight at 6:00.
- [Monica] Where did we get it from?
My press secretary had it slipped to him
as a favor by a reporter.
- Does he have the original?
- [Aceveda] / don't think so.
But I'd worry more about
how you're gonna spin this nightmare.
/ have 12 kilos ofheroin in my
evidence room. That's all the spin / need.
Public Relations
is working on our response.
In the meantime, the Organized Crime Unit
is gonna handle the Kozodav sweep.
This is John Sullivan,
their team leader.
Congratulations.
You guys did a hell of a job.
- Put together a great case.
- Yeah. Our goddamn case!
We worked long and hard
on this case, Roy.
We deserve to make this bust.
Getting Kozodav
is a big win for us.
We can't risk tainting it by having
the arresting officer...
and his captain plastered
all over the news the same day.
He has been pissing
on this policy from day one.
Last quarter's numbers. For all
the great work you've been doing...
crime is actually up
four percent in this district.
/ promised my constituents
that / would review...
all of these seizures
on a one-by-one basis...
and I expect full access
to all of your files.
Detective Mackey will get you
up to speed on the op...
provide you any support
you need.
- All clear?
- Crystal.
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Ends]
I'll look into the tape.
Try and track down the original.
We'll get through this.
In the meantime, Shane
brought over a case from Vice.
- Work it with him.
- What is it?
He found a Byz Lat in the state pen
willing to act as an informant...
in return for early release.
Prison Bureau almost
never grants early release.
Yeah, well, the chief went to bat
with the bureau himself.
Shane's informant is banger buddies
with Ernesto Dienta...
Byz Lat contraband king.
Guns, drugs.
You name it, he gets it.
- Not for long.
- Use Lemansky.
I'd like to see how your old
Strike Team works together.
- Great.
- Any progress on Lem's missing girl?
Still working on it.
I'm not feeling a happy ending
to that story.
Captain, / got a call
from Mission Cross.
A little girl was just brought into the E.R.
with burns to her throat and face.
- What happened?
- They think she was forced to drink
some kind of acid.
- Doctors are treating her now.
- How old is she?
According to the foster dad,
seven.
- She's a foster kid.
- Yeah.
Give me a minute.
I'll join you.
This is Hielo Gutierrez. He did
a nickel in Chino for armed robbery.
[Shane] Covered his Byz Lat homies'
asses when he got pinched.
Thanked him by visiting him
once during his stretch.
That's once more than /'ll be seeing
those fools when they're behind bars.
Payback's gonna taste sweeter
than teenage booty.
Hielo's only been a citizen
for a month.
His buddy Ernesto's
integrating him back into the fold.
- You ready?
- Where we headed?
Echo Park. Ernesto and Hielo
have a meeting...
with a busboy who works
on an Indian reservation in Cabazon.
- What's the grift?
- Cigarettes. Indians buy 'em tax free.
Byz Lats turn 'em around for face value.
The tax is pure profit.
Across the state lines.
That makes it a federal beef.
When it comes time to make the bust,
we can R/CO their asses.
Sweep up half
the Byz Lats.
I learned from the best.
Vic and me will ride together.
You ride with Army and Hielo.
Ready?
Let's go.
Look, stay cool.
Play the good soldier, all right?
That guy with Hielo-
that's Ernesto.
He's the Byz Lat
contraband king.
I guess he's gonna have to
run his kingdom from a cell in Chino.
- The other Mexican- that's Garcia.
- [Chattering]
He's the one who works
on the /ndian reservation.
- I've been known to get
my hands on a pack or two.
- I need cartons. Lots of them.
- I can get 300 cartons a month.
- How much?
Ten thousand, in cash,
on delivery.
Got him hooked,
about to get booked.
That was quick. I hope you
didn't mind me calling your cell phone.
Not at all. Corrine Mackey,
this is Captain Monica Rawling.
- Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you. How's the girl?
Joya's unconscious. Her esophagus is badly
burned, and there's stomach damage.
- She's been put on a ventilator.
- Where are the parents?
That's her foster father
over there.
He brought her in.
There are also signs
of a sexual assault.
We're waiting for the results
of the rape kit.
- What did she swallow?
- Some sort ofhousehold cleaner.
Should have killed her.
/t still might.
- Can we see her?
- [Door Opens]
- [Monica] Child Services?
- They're sending over a caseworker now.
Yeah, that'll fix everything.
- Is Joya in a private or a group home?
- [Corrine] / don't know.
Could be an attempt by the rapist
to destroy D.N.A. evidence.
If the sexual assault extended
to, uh, an oral nature.
Thanks for calling right away.
Bring the foster care father to the Barn.
Get his take on what happened.
We'll run by his house,
see what we can learn.
- You're splitting us up?
- I'm just marshaling our resources.
- Hi. Come on in.
- Hi.
- Captain Rawling.
- Claudette Wyms.
- Hi. How's Joya?
- She's suffered a lot of damage.
- /t's terrible.
These children
have so many problems.
- They experience violence, and they get violent.
- Hi.
- Who was home?
- All the kids. We have seven with us now.
Frank was here,
I was out getting groceries...
and he called me
on his way to the hospital.
- Hi. What's your name?
- Bibi.
We need to see
all the children.
Okay. Gather everybody.
Bring 'em back to the living room.
Can you show us where
your husband found Joya?
- Sure. This way.
- [Children Chattering]
Uh, this is the kids'bathroom.
Over here.
Sorry about the smell.
Joya threw up.
You found an empty bottle
of drain cleaner. Where is it?
I'll ask Bibi. She's the oldest.
She looks out for the younger ones.
These meds belong
to all the kids?
Yeah.
They're all taking something.
Like I said,
they have problems.
Why is a padlock
on this door?
Oh, the closet
is our safe place.
[Claudette] Safe for who?
You lock the kids up in here?
[Woman] Yeah. We give them
time-outs on occasion.
Most of them
have behavioral disorders.
This lets them calm down,
keeps the other kids safe.
You realize you've admitted
to child endangerment?
My husband says it's not.
/ mean, people send kids
to their rooms, right?
This is the only space we have.
Any of the kids capable
of attacking Joya?
- Making her drink Drano?
- Take your pick.
- Got an update?
- Yeah. The prelim just came back.
Joya wasn't raped this morning.
The healing looks to be 24 to 48 hours.
- What about the father?
- Definitely a control freak...
so the closet o' horrors
doesn't surprise me.
- Not sure he's a rapist though.
- The files from the foster care kids?
Yeah, Child Services just sent 'em over.
They read like the Marquis de Sade.
One of'em's probably
our liquid plumber.
So, we have six suspects.
- You mean seven.
- I'm not counting Joya.
- Neither am /.
- [Claudette] There were six kids.
- We met them all.
- Not according to these C.S. documents.
Yeah?
Darnell Garry, age 17.
Bipolar.
A history of violence.
So where is he?
Tell us about Darnell Garry.
He was the oldest.
Ran away about three months ago.
- You never called Children's Services?
- / did. Also sent an e-mail.
/ can print it out for you.
They never wrote or called
to check on his status?
No. Trust me, lady...
I've been working
for the county a long time.
- / know how to cover my ass.
- You kept cashing Darnell's checks after he left.
How are you gonna cover your ass
on that one?
My wife handles the books.
We get a lot of checks for these kids.
It's hard to know
the difference.
We caught the mistake last month.
Sent them an e-mail to bill us.
You don't seem too broken up
Darnell took off.
Darnell was uncontrollable.
Belonged in a hospital
or a prison, not my house.
Sounds like your closet therapy
didn't take, huh?
Child endangerment's a crime.
[Monica]
Consider your foster care license gone.
How hard we press charges,
that's in your court.
When was the last time
you saw Darnell?
A couple weeks ago.
Caught him in the house
when he thought Liz and I were gone...
stealing groceries,
other kids' prescriptions.
Any idea where he went
after that?
[Sighs] Try his mom. She's a junkie.
Him too, probably.
The only meds he didn't take were
the ones that actually might help him.
The dad reported Darnell Garry
left months ago.
How come someone didn't file
a missing persons report with us?
There's no record of him
being missing.
This is a copy
of the e-mail he sent you.
He's been gone for three months.
How many visits have you
had there since then?
- Two.
- And you didn't notice
one of the kids was missing?
The checks were never stopped.
Darnell was never flagged for a follow-up.
You know who ends up doing
that follow-up? My cops or the M.E.
Half these kids are gonna
end up in the penal system.
They're time bombs. We shuffle them
around from place to place...
Iose track of them
until they explode.
Look, /'m here as a courtesy.
If you wanna lecture about
the foster care system...
teach an extension class
at UCLA.
I understand the difficulties
and limitations.
I deal with my own,
but we have got to do better.
No, you mean I've got to do better.
/f we got a missing teen, stop taking it
out on me and do something to find him.
In Domestic, I had to watch
you people on a daily basis.
I saw more concern for filling
federally funded beds...
than in helping
reunite families.
We've got tens of thousands
of kids to care for.
- This is one mistake.
- This is a kid!
So's the one in the hospital
with half a throat.
You don't like my job performance,
call my supervisor.
Fine. I'll explain
why you've been arrested.
- Hey! For what?
- Negligence, child endangerment.
You were assigned to that household,
so I'm holding you responsible.
- Officer, take him.
- What's she doing?
- [Man] Hey.
- Standing on her soapbox.
She, uh, have her own,
or you let her borrow yours?
[Rap]
- What's the problem, Officer?
- Your plates are expired, Illinois.
License, registration.
You boys are enjoying the party.
/ smell marijuana.
All right. Get out of the car.
Step out now, all of you. Move it!
[Man] Come on, man.
We'rejust seeing the sights.
- Put your hands on top
of your head and turn around.
- Let's go. Come on. Step forward.
- [Danny] You boys affiliated?
- What?
- Gang ink. You got any?
- Hey.
8th Street. What is that?
Your Boy Scout troop?
We ain't got no business here.
We're just visiting my cousin. That's it.
- Step back.
- I'll let your cousin know
when your visiting hours are.
Danny.
Hey, Vic, / think we got your new official
department-issue ride.
- [Vic] Oh.
- Chicago homeboys with too much narcotics.
You make that stick,
those tickets are all yours.
- Oh, leather seats!
- Fully loaded.
For you,
I'll even throw in dinner.
[Chattering]
- What happened?
- O.C.U. sat on Kozi cabs for two hours.
Half the Russian mob showed,
Kozodav didn't.
Sullivan made the call
to go in anyway.
- Kozodav's in the wind?
- Yeah, Sullivan said he had no choice.
A residential building
was about to be torched.
He figured he'd
press the soldiers...
and use them to give up
Kozodav's location.
They're all asking for lawyers.
Monica got you up to speed?
- She gave me the ABC's.
- Good. We need your help.
I'll get my team together,
start digging into Kozodav's haunts.
- Not for fieldwork.
- What do you want my man for?
To help transcribe videotapes.
You oversaw the operation.
If there's any clue to Kozodav's
whereabouts, we need to know.
Where are you going?
Every second I stay here,
Kozodav gets further away.
My boss just gave you an order.
Follow it.
- You got a minute?
- A building full of people's
about ready to burn down.
- A minute's about all I got.
- Look, I know this church tape...
is a problem for you, but /
should be the one looking for this guy.
- It's O.C.U.'s case.
- Hey, we got years, Roy.
Something's up. All I'm askin' is
you shoot me straight.
Whatever you did to piss off
Aceveda, it worked.
He's got leverage with the chief,
and he's using it.
I'm keeping my nose clean.
I'm doing what I'm told. I'm delivering.
Yeah, you been doing good lately,
but you got a damaged jacket.
- I'm fixing that.
- Do yourself and your family a favor.
Whatever you need to do
to make sure Rawling succeeds, do it.
Because the shot
she's giving you...
it may be the last one
you got in this department.
- [Claudette] We're looking for your son.
- Darnell?
- You with Child Services?
- We're with the police.
There was an incident at Darnell's
foster home. He may be a witness.
Whatever it was,
he probably did it.
- Why do you say that?
- That boy is no good.
He comes around, steals my stuff,
sells it for drug money.
- Where does he score?
- All over.
I can tell you
how he earns his pay.
- [Claudette] He's got a job?
- Just blow jobs.
He sucks fag dick
on 4th Street.
Tell him I say hey.
I didn't mess with Joya
or make her drink anything.
We'd love to take your word for it,
but we're gonna take a D.N.A. sample...
compare it with the semen we
found inside her just in case.
I ain't giving you
permission for that.
Frank is still technically
your legal guardian.
- We have your permission?
- Of course.
I may have done some shit.
But what about him?
- You ain't gonna let him go free, are you?
- So you did rapeJoya?
[Darnell] You see what / gotta do
on the street to survive.
When am I gonna get me some?
When am I gonna get to bust a nut?
- She's seven.
- I hope you fry.
This is his fault-lockin'us up
in a closet and shit.
A few minutes to calm you down,
you animal.
- More like hours!
- Sit down.
[Darnell]
He called it "the hole. '"
Put the oldest one in charge
and make 'em keep order.
Little ones in there cryin'
and wailin'for hours in that closet.
[Sighs]
And as for the Drano,
that ain't me.
Sounds like Bibi
tryin' to keep the peace...
so she don't get locked up
in Frank's hole.
You need to get Ernesto to admit that he's
selling the cigarettes across state lines.
But let him say it.
Don't get overeager, tip your hat.
Don't worry about it, bro.
He thinks of me like a brother.
He won't see nothin' comin'.
Before I went away,
I banged his 14-year-old sister.
Took her virginity. [Chuckling]
Fool didn't have a clue.
/ told him / was helping her
with her history homework.
Try the history
of poppin'cherries.
Why don't you keep it
to yourself, man?
What's the problem, superstar?
If there's grass on the field,
you gotta play ball, right?
- You know what, dude?
- Hey, cut it out, man!
- The guy's a dick.
- Yeah, well, he's my C./.
Okay, this is my run.
So just follow my orders.
First one is to give him
and me a little room.
Okay?
All right.
Showtime, lover boy.
Garcia called with
the drop point for the goods.
[On Wire]
Doin' good, bro.
There's more where this came
from when the smokes get to St. Louis?
/ told you not to push it,
you skid mark.
You should've
emphasized the point.
Relax. Enough business.
[Whistles]
Got you a present
for all your hard work.
Puta's all dressed up
with no one to blow.
Mommy's gonna make papi happy.
[Mutters]
[Monica]
/ looked into the videotape.
The woman who shot it, her nephew works
at Antwon Mitchell's rec center.
You think Antwon edited the tape?
Sent it to the press?
I know it's not an accurate depiction
of what happened there.
Help me bury this.
/ know the press.
You can't unring this bell.
I'll be handing these seizure cases
over to the police committee.
The rest seem fine.
I also looked into
the crime stats.
The numbers are up because you manipulated
yours to make things look better.
I'm getting punished because
I reported mine accurately.
Sounds like now's a good time
to start formulating...
an exit strategy
for this seizure policy.
Only person who could take me
off this is the chief...
and not without one hell
of a fight from me.
Then I'd start training.
I just spoke to him.
He's still blue in the face from having
to explain to the A.C.L.U. lawyers...
why you put a cop like Vic in charge
of such a controversial program.
That's what all this is about-
Mackey.
Starting tonight,
Vic's the face of that church invasion.
Pulling him off the street
might buy you some slack.
He's working.
/ stand by my choice.
- You just won't take help, will you?
- Help from you? Sure.
Orders? No.
If Mackey's off the table, I'm gonna have
to set my sights on the policy in general.
- That was an illegal U-turn, right?
- [Danny] That's right.
/'m sorry. / don't know
this part of town too well.
I've been looking for the 5 Freeway
for, like, 20 minutes.
- /n the rain, it's brutal.
- Yeah, it sucks, doesn't it?
- Yeah, it does.
- Three blocks, make a right on Prince.
- Thank you.
- Let me see your license and registration, please.
- Right.
- Is that an open container?
- No. It's corked.
- /t's been opened. That's illegal.
It's from lunch.
Dude, it's a $400 bottle
of Pomerol.
/ wasn't gonna leave it
for the busboys.
Get out, please.
I had a glass of wine with a client,
like, three hours ago.
- Man, I'm not impaired.
- I said, out of the car, sir.
- l- Do l-
- You heard the officer.
Come on.
Get outta the car.
Step to the back of the car.
Step up against the car, please.
Bootleg DVD's.
Do you intend to sell these?
No. It's for me.
A guy on Olvera sells 'em cheap.
- Are you affiliated?
- What?
With a gang. / see the ink.
Pull up your shirt.
What's your deal, man?
Get your hands off-
Ow! God! Back off, man!
Take it easy!
All right. Look,
I'm sorry, okay? I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Officer.
What the hell
are you doing?
I'm gonna document his ink.
I'm gonna tow his car in.
If his lawyer can't prove that he
didn't intend to sell those DVD's...
we'll seize his vehicle.
That's what we do, right?
Might even get me some Laker tickets.
Hey, Vic,
you need to see this.
- [Mackey] Later, okay?
- No. Now.
Lock the doors.
- [Lock Clicks]
- This surveillance tape's
from Shane's car last night.
- [Antwon] One more thing.
- [Shane] What?
How would you like to get
that little girl's body back?
Your bullets and all.
- How?
- Trade. A body for a body.
Who?
Vic Mackey.
His body for hers.
You've been telling me
he's behind all my misery.
And he ain't gonna stop
comin'after me, so-
- No way.
- I'm offering you a chance at liberation-
freedom from the shackles
that bind you.
You know what?
/ don't give a shit.
- You send her goddamn body to the cops.
- [Engine Starts, Stops]
[Key Alarm Dinging]
- [Dinging Stops]
- Sure you do.
I mean, I send her body to the po-po,
you go to jail.
You go tojail...
who's gonna protect that pretty
little wife and son of yours?
Huh?
A body for a body.
Last time I offer.
Yeah.
Let me know when it's done.
- [Knocking]
- Uh, one sec.
- /t's Captain Rawling.
- Stash it. Nobody does anything...
- or says anything about this until I say so.
- All right.
- [Door Opens]
- [Mackey] /'m sorry.
I didn't know it was locked.
What's up?
Excuse me.
I, um-
I need you to take a step back,
temporarily.
/ can't have you heading up
the seizure policy right now.
- What are you talking about?
- [Sighs]
Well, the church raid
stirred up a shit storm.
So you're offering me up
as a sacrifice?
I'm not taking you off it.
I just need you in
a less-visible role.
I worked hard for this!
- What happened to you having my back?
- I'm protecting the policy.
- Protecting your own ass!
- I am getting us time to regroup.
Aceveda has the chief s ear.
The guy has got it out
for you and-
And you're too much of a coward
to stand up to him?
- Don't make this personal.
- The only difference between you and Aceveda...
is you fooled me into thinking you
actually had a goddamn backbone!
You were the redheaded stepchild
when I arrived here.
I put my ass on the line to give you
a second chance when nobody else would.
I gave you power.
I gave you respect.
So keep your mouth shut
before you lose both.
/ know this is hard, but / need you
to look at the bigger picture.
[Exhales Forcefully]
[Footsteps Approaching]
Hielo's ready to make a buy.
Are you ready
to kick some ass?
Hell, yeah.
Then good. Let's go.
- [Turns Water Off]
- [Paper Towels Rustling]
We found Darnell.
He admitted raping Joya
while you were in charge at the house.
/s that true?
[Claudette]
What happened?
[Monica] /t's okay.
We know about the closet.
- It's not his fault.
- He's not gonna hurt you anymore, honey.
I'm sorry.
l- I tried to stop Darnell.
/ couldn't.
Then Joya was gonna tell.
You poisoned Joya?
Tried to kill her?
She said that she was gonna tell
her teacher at school what Darnell did.
We'd all be pulled out of there,
sent somewhere else.
I couldn't take the chance.
- Chance at what?
- Going someplace worse.
Frank isn't so bad.
Other homes I been at-
At least he doesn't touch me.
- Oh, come on. Take that shit down.
- The guy broke the law.
Yeah, you proved your point.
Not everyone gets treated the same.
Shaking down the white guy might have
evened some intellectual score for you...
but this stunt you pulled this afternoon
doesn't help anyone.
What are we supposed to do?
Sweep everything black and brown
into the same garbage pile?
There was enough drugs in that car
to qualify for an intent to distribute.
They weren't drug dealers.
They were just partying too much.
So being young and stupid
buys them a pass?
No. They broke the law.
They should make restitution.
How many shifts you think this guy had to work
in order to cover the payments on that car?
- Give me a break.
- After lockup, how's he supposed to drive to a job?
So now he
starts selling drugs.
All we did was create
another drug dealer.
If it hadn't been for church,
that would've been me 10 years ago.
The streets have changed a lot
in 10 years.
I can't know how you feel
every time you arrest a young black man.
No, ma'am, you can't.
/ respect the conflict.
But you became a cop, Julien.
It's clear you won't
get behind this program.
At the end of the day, I don't give a shit
about race, color or creed.
Either you're blue
or you're gone.
/'ll put through
the administrative transfer.
Let the brass decide
where to put you.
- [Exhales]
- Ma'am-
[Chattering]
Garcia's van pulled in.
They're ready to make the buy.
All right. Vic and / are going in
to make sure our C./. 's safe.
You and Lem stay with the van.
You keep listening.
We don't know we can trust
this Hielo guy. I'm going in too.
Look, I told you to stay.
It's my operation.
Come on. Let's go.
Ready?
[Men Chattering]
[Chattering In Spanish]
- Cigarettes.
- Three hundred cartons, just like / promised.
[Train Horn Blaring]
Here's the smokes.
Let's see the cash.
Ten G's. /t's all there.
- /t's good.
- [Chattering Continues]
Are you the captain
who arrested my caseworker?
- You must be a supervisor.
- Who the hell do you think you are?
He had nothing to do
with this crime.
His job was to monitor
that family.
These caseworkers are overstretched.
They're not liable.
You don't remember me, do you?
Monica Rawling, Domestic Abuse?
Do you remember
Lisa Rodriguez?
Her father put her mother in the hospital.
Said it was an old boyfriend.
- We worked the case together.
- What's your point?
Do you remember promising me you'd get
the kids out of that house?
Then being overstretched
then too?
I want my worker
released right now.
I promised Lisa that Daddy would never
hurt her again, but you let Daddy go home.
He beat her with a golf club.
Two years later, she's still in a coma.
- Remember now?
- Yeah.
His psych history didn't
come out until after the attack.
- I warned you about him.
- And I had rules and regulations to follow.
You want perfection, clean up your streets
before sticking your nose in my houses.
A raped and poisoned seven-year-old
took me to one of your houses today.
Which had nothing to do with
my caseworker. It wasn't his fault.
- Then whose is it?
- I signed off on his work.
If you've got a problem with him,
you got a problem with me.
Well, there we agree.
I'll release him,
but the next case of neglect I see...
that worker spends
a night in County.
The one after that,
you'll be sharing the cell next door.
Pass it on.
[Train Horn Blaring]
We'll follow the van, set up on the buyers
in St. Louis, and we'll bust 'em both.
This is gonna be a hell of a bust
by the time this thing is through, huh?
No shit. This guy's cold.
Played his pal like
no C.I. I've ever seen.
- We're gonna ride him all the way
to the Vice Hall of Fame.
- [Phone Ringing]
- Drinks on me tonight, fellas.
- Yeah?
Kozodav mentioned a coyote on a tape.
Referred to him as El Callado.
- "The Quiet One"?
- Used him a couple times to ferry
soldiers back to St. Petersburg.
- You tell O.C.U. yet?
- Shit, no.
[Sighs]
Kozodav's coyote have a real name?
- Just use his street tag.
- All right. You give me one hour...
and then you pass it on
to Sullivan.
/'m gonna have to take
a rain check on the cocktails.
- What's up?
- My boss wants me to fill out some paperwork.
- Another time?
- Count on it.
- You need a ride?
- I'm gonna walk.
[Woman Speaking /n Spanish]
- I told you to come alone.
- And I don't know you.
Maybe, but / know...
that a member of your organization
is acting as a criminal informant.
Don't jerk me off,
man, all right?
I'm willing to give you his name,
but I'm gonna need somethin' in return.
- And what's that?
- You know a coyote named El Callado?
I heard of him.
Works for the grandejugadores.
The cartels, mostly.
He's moving a Russian mobster
named Alex Kozodav out of the States.
- I need to stop him.
- This coyote's not Byz Lat.
I'd have to call in a lot of favors
just to get a message through.
How do I know what you're telling
me is worth the shit?
You get him to give me Kozodav...
and I'll give you
the informant's name...
and I'll make sure
that van full of cigarettes...
doesn't get busted
on its way to St. Louis.
- The Russian's at this address.
- Alone or with company?
Alone. Just waiting
to get picked up.
Who's the informant?
- Hielo Gutierrez.
- No. Uh-uh.
You tell me it's Hielo,
I can't believe that.
He's like a brother to me,
all right?
He bragged he popped
your sister's cherry when she was 14.
He said it was so tight,
he thought it was her asshole.
Told you he was just helping her
with some... history homework.
You do whatever you feel
is appropriate with that info.
- I'll make sure it doesn't blow back on you.
- [Engine Starts]
- [Muffled Shouting]
- [Shouts]
[Shouting]
[Cocks Gun]
You hired an arsonist
to torch a building.
I need his name.
I need an address.
What is this?
[Groaning]
If the next word out of
your mouth isn't a name...
I pull the trigger.
Gregor, uh- Gregor Barinat.
[Panting]
- [Ventilator Cycling]
- [Monitor Beeping]
I didn't think anybody'd be here
to look over her.
- Makes two of us.
- Any changes?
They say she's a little better.
You think I lost it
a little bit today.
We've all got burrs
under our saddle.
My, uh...
best friend growing up...
had a father...
who used to knock her around
pretty regularly.
/ knew what was happening...
what she was enduring,
but / couldn't-
I just felt helpless.
It feels worse now.
If you're here to take a second shift,
I've got some, uh...
seizure paperwork I've gotta prepare
for Aceveda's eyes.
- [Door Closes]
- Guess who's here, Alex?
It's Gregor.
[Muffled Grunting]
[Clanging]
You were about to torch those Mexicans
in that apartment, huh?
- Huh?
- [Muffled Speaking]
Jesus Christ.
[Muffled Shouting]
[Muffled]
Don't do it. Don't shoot.
[Sighs]
- [Slow Tempo]
- I'm not a great cook. I'm sorry.
l- I thought it was terrific.
Thanks.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
It's, uh- It's that
little girl, Joya.
I don't know. Y-Y-
Dead bodies-You get used to them.
It doesn't affect you.
But there's something
about a kid...
hanging on, fighting.
Yeah, l- I know.
- [Laughing] Hey.
- Hey.
You want me to read
that to you again?
Come here.
[Chuckling]
Oh.
Big Buddy Bear.
"Buddy was a big brown bear.
A bumbling, stumbling,
sweet-as-honey bear."
- Goddamn it!
- What's up?
I've been trying to get in touch
with Hielo for the last hour.
He's not answering his cell
or at home.
He's probably getting laid.
If I spent five years in prison...
you wouldn't get my face
out of snatch for a month.
The chief already made promises to
the Bureau of Prisons to spring him early.
If this guy ghosts,
I'm gonna look like an asshole.
No worries. He'll show.
- [Monica] Kozodav?
- And the arsonist.
- How'd you track him?
- Some unis responded to a shots-fired call.
These two were there when they arrived,
cuffed and gagged.
I'll take it any way
I can get it.
[Rock]
[Man Singing]
Hey.
- [Continues]
- [Radio Chatter]
I'm a cop, so get that light
out of my face and get out of here.
[Ends]
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Continues]
[Ends]