- [Man] Now, / need you to tell the truth.
- Absolutely.
- [Man] /s your name Shane Vendrell?
- Yes.
- [Man] Are you currently
the mayor of New York City?
- [Chuckles] No.
Have you ever lied to
keep yourself out of trouble?
[Shane]
Yes.
[Man] Have you ever won the gold medal
in women's gymnastics?
[Chuckles]
No.
- [Man] Are you married?
- [Shane] Yeah.
- [Man] Do you have children?
- [Shane] Yes.
[Man] Have you ever been unfaithful
to your wife?
[Shane]
No.
Eatin' ain't cheatin'.
I've been fielding calls all day by people
very angry that we put away Antwon Mitchell.
He confessed to
murdering a teenage girl.
Mitchell's always claimed we were targeting
him: now he's screaming that Vendrell's dirty.
- People think we're trying to cover our ass.
- That's bullshit.
I know. I just
need you to explain it to them.
- I'd be a little nervous.
- [Mackey] Yeah.
- So how we supposed to beat this thing?
- Well, it's easier...
if you're a pathological liar
or a narcissist.
All right. So Shane's safe.
What do we do about Army?
I heard something
about putting a tack in your shoe.
- /t messes up the results.
- [Mackey] Along with your foot.
Tack in your shoe. Bar of soap
under the armpit. No proof they work.
Plus, if they catch you,
they know you're lyin'.
- Come on, Smitty. What do we do?
- All right.
You be the interrogator.
Ask me about some crime you think I did.
- You like little Asian boys?
- Let's say I did.
I'd do what they call a substitution.
I'd replace your question in my mind...
with another question
to which the truthful answer is no.
/ might ask myself,
"Do / have $ 10 million in the bank? '"
And I answer "no." The polygraph
records the response as truthful.
- [Army] And that really works?
- /f you do it right, yeah.
- Oh.
- [Mackey] Got no choice.
Captain's got a spotlight on all of us
until you two pass that lie detector test.
We got a few days to practice.
We can do it.
[Monica] The officer
Mitchell propositioned was undercover.
- We heard he was corrupt.
- [Monica] That was Mitchell's allegation.
- We're investigating.
- [Woman] / was at your first town meeting.
- [Monica] Yes. I remember.
- That councilman said
these seizures breed corruption.
/ have the officers involved
taking a polygraph test.
I will be happy
to make those results public.
We also hear you're trying to blame Antwon
for those two dead police.
- We're investigating all leads.
- Investigate yourself.
Taking people's houses is what got
those cops killed. Now you're trying to hide it.
How much longer
you gonna let these seizures go on?
[Monica] We don't know
what got those officers killed...
but attacking the seizure policy
isn't gonna help us find it.
We're reevaluating the seizures entirely.
This department is not interested...
in any policy that inflames the community
or leads to cops'deaths.
[Onlookers Murmuring]
Here. The files you were lookin' for.
Nailin'Antwon's really
shakin'things up.
- What's the fallout on the street?
- Uh, naturally...
decapitating the One-niners
has created a power vacuum.
Now a few of his sloppy seconds
wanna try on the crown.
So how do we take advantage?
Hit 'em up for info on the two dead cops
before the dust settles.
At least until Antwon sets up shop
in prison, circles the wagons again.
You think Antwon's lying,
One-niners are responsible?
Don't you?
- Hit 'em hard.
- Fine. But I need Shane and Army.
- Not until they clear the polygraph.
- That's not till next week.
I need guys now.
Just let 'em work on who killed Carl
and Scooby, nothin' else.
They only work the cops' murders.
- Anything goes sideways with them, it is on you.
- Got it.
[Rap On Radio]
[Shane]
Looks like Antwon Mitchell...
isn't the only One-niner
on his lawyer's buddy list.
- I knew that shylock was dirty.
- Officer of the court runnin' errands
for Antwon Mitchell?
- Gives us a good card to play with Halpern.
- Yeah.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. What are you doin'?
- Lighting up.
No, no. No, you're not. I finally got something
nice where the A/C actually works.
- Toss it.
- I'll blow the smoke out the window.
Or you could blow me. I want this to smell
like Corinthian leather, not an ashtray.
Come on.
/ heard what happened this morning.
Phillips really threw you to the wolves.
Yeah. He hauled me in front of
Antwon's true believers and promised them...
that he would
reevaluate the seizure policy.
It's a real shame you weren't there
to witness your handiwork.
He's linking it to Carl and Scooby
getting killed. Is it?
[Sighs]
We don't know.
If you can prove the killings had nothing
to do with the seizures-
However it breaks, it breaks.
I'm not suggesting slanting evidence.
I'm offering you an olive branch.
High enough to hang myself from?
I don't like people
capitalizing on cop killings.
/'m willing to talk to the chief
on your behalf, on behalf of the seizures.
- lf?
- /f you agree to a few modifications...
such as no auctioning properties
until the suspects are actually convicted.
That leaves money
in escrow accounts for years...
instead of in the community,
where we need it.
It's an olive branch.
Thanks for your offer.
I think I can take care of Phillips.
And listen.
Anybody gives you shit, you come find me.
- You get on the horn, and you call me.
- Go get your nails done, girls.
We need some quality time
with big papa.
- [Halpern] All right, guys.
- Screw.
What? You already
got Antwon sittin' down.
That deal we were discussin' prior
to your accident? It's back on the table.
What is it with you guys? I look like
I got a pork chop around my neck?
Antwon's lawyer went straight from the men's jail
to a meet and greet with a cat named Weed.
- You know him?
- Yeah.
- [Shane] I thought you were next in line, Halpern?
- White smoke comin'out...
of Antwon's cell, man.
Means he's anointing Weed
as his new pope of dope.
We're tryin' to figure out
whose side we're on.
[Chuckles]
You fools still playin' that dirty cop shit?
- [Chuckles]
- Hey, shithead. We don't wanna
get in business with you.
We're lookin' for the guys
who killed our cops.
I already gave you
the El Salvadorans.
No one specific. All we got to
was that street-level asshole, Pitarrio.
You've been out of I.C. U: you reconnected
to the street. You must've heard something new.
[Mackey] This guy's not a player.
Let's go talk to Weed.
Hold up. Hold up. Hold up.
When Antwon got with the Salvadorans,
he only talked to one guy...
a cat named Gusano.
- Where do I find this maggot, Gusano?
- He deals to Pitarrio.
Now, how you gonna
handle Weed for me, huh?
- You're lookin' at a bunch
of bona fide Weed whackers.
- [Grunts]
[Shane] Hey, Weed.
You wanna hang up the phone, superstar?
- [Mackey] Grab some skull, dickhead.
- You know what's funny, man?
I see your mouth movin',
but I don't hear you sayin' nothin'.
Yeah? Can you hear me now?
Any of you guys smell
the sickly sweet odor of ganja?
Yeah. All right. Come on, man.
This the 21 st century.
That old-school trickery,
it ain't gonna fly in these last days.
You'll be locked up a week
before the judge drops the charges.
Antwon's gone, man.
One-niners are decidin' who's got next.
Can you really afford
to be benched for that long?
Especially with Halpern
on the campaign trail.
Look. Check this out, man.
Quit "beatin' me in my head" conversation.
- What is it y'all want?
- You give us something that
gets us our cop killers...
I guarantee ya Halpern
goes down in the polls.
All right. Word on the street. Some kids
runnin' their mouth 'bout some dead cop's gun.
- Where'd you hear that shit?
- Nigga named Jamani
staying down on Grape Street.
He runs guns
to the street struggle.
So Halpern really wants to squabble, huh?
You got my back, right?
This tip pans out, the street'll be
kissin' your ring before you know it.
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Ends]
- [Chattering]
- I'm going to Giovanni's. You want lunch?
- Chicken parm. You need cash?
- Nah. Get me later.
- What about him?
- Dutch hates Giovanni's.
- I'll pick up some wine on the way.
- [Corrine] I can do it.
- You've got such a long day.
- I don't mind.
- Chardonnay, right?
- My favorite.
I know what you like.
Uh, I gotta go.
I'll see you tonight.
- See ya then.
- Bye.
- Captain.
- Where are you on Scooby and Carl?
We've talked to the neighbors twice.
We've papered the town with flyers.
Latest crime scene reports
haven't turned up anything new.
I want you back
in regular rotation.
You're taking us off the cop killers?
You still can provide support,
but / can't let this trail get any colder.
This case will break. /t may
take six months, : it may take six hours.
- You know that.
- Six months is good enough for you?
Every spare moment you have, work on
Scooby and Carl, but /'ve got Vic looking into it...
so bring him up to speed.
[Rap On Radio]
[Man Shouting /n Spanish]
[Shouting /n Spanish]
[Shouting Continues]
- [Gunfire]
- [Man Shouting]
[Tires Squealing]
[Ignition Starts, Engine Revs]
Aw, shit.
- Hey. What are you doin' here?
- I was on my way home from work...
and I really need
to tell you something.
- Everything all right?
- Yeah.
Actually, /'ve been seeing someone.
Well, I've seen a few people
since the separation. We're allowed.
You kind of work
with this person.
- Who?
- Dutch.
- You're kidding me.
- No.
- How the hell did that happen?
- /tjust did. You just said dating was allowed.
- /t is. Just know that this guy's a first-rate asshole.
- No, he's not.
We're always ridin'this prick.
He's got a bug up his ass about me.
- Hejust wants to get back at me through you.
- That's ridiculous.
I'm just telling you the truth.
You do whatever you want with it.
- I'm not gonna do anything with it.
- Fine.
[Whispering] You didn't tell him
about the money I gave you, did you?
- No. Of course not. I didn't tell anyone.
- Good. Don't.
- / gotta go.
- Wait a minute. You're not
gonna do anything, are you?
- What would I do?
- Please. Don't get in the middle of this.
- Forget we said anything, okay?
- Fine.
- Kiss the kids, will ya?
- Okay. Bye.
Got an address on Weed's tip.
The guy who was braggin' about the cop gun?
All right. Go pick him up.
We'll try to find Gusano.
- We'll trace it back to Antwon.
- Right.
- [Ronnie] Not your most ingenious prank.
- Nah, but it felt good.
- [Banging]
- Police!
Pitarrio, get out here!
- Pitarrio!
- [Woman] / have a gun. /'ll shoot.
- We're the police!
- Bullshit. / know who you are.
We're comin' in! We'll shoot!
- [Woman] Me too.
- Stop!
- [Mackey] Where's Pitarrio?
- Gone.
- Where to?
He lost something he was holding. He knew
the Salvadorans would come to kill him.
[Mackey]
What did he lose?
Heroin. A kilo.
Shit.
Where did he lose this kilo?
Look, we're not here to bust you.
[Sighs] I'm Pitarrio's cut-up girl.
The Salvadorans can't find him...
they'll come after me next.
- / thought you were them.
- Then why'd you come back here?
I thought maybe I could
grab some product or some tools to sell.
Pitarrio left without paying me.
/ got nothing for us.
- Who's gettin' you and Pitarrio so scared?
- [Whimpering]
Dealer named Gusano.
You know where we could find him?
Vic? Vic? Come here.
She was here when I roughed Pitarrio up
and took that heroin as collateral...
so if she's runnin',
it's 'cause of me.
- She see you take it?
- I don't know.
- Come on, man. Let's just get out of here.
- And leave her hangin'? No way.
- [Shane] What do we do?
- Pack a bag. Pack a bag. Let's go.
What exact-
What exactly did you tell him?
- I told him we were seeing each other.
- Yeah? How'd he take it?
He said you two weren't exactly
the strangers you said you were.
Well, we've bumped heads
over a case or two, but you know Vic.
We need to talk about this.
Listen, I hate to do this to you,
but I'm looking at a dead body right now.
- I've gotta go.
- Okay. I'll still see you at 8:00?
Sure. If this case wraps up, sure.
Okay.
[Claudette] Louis Saldera.
Twenty-one. Took four shots at close range.
- Do we know the car yet?
- Saldera's registered owner of a 2003 Honda.
Still wet.
Maybe there's a witness.
Somebody was here recently. You're not gonna
wash your car with a dead body next door.
Don't be so sure.
/'ll post a squad car out front,
but trust me. No one's gonna find you.
Gusano thinks I know
where Pitarrio is or that I have the heroin.
Last woman he thought crossed him,
his man held her down...
stuck a rat in her pussy
till she bled to death.
That's a street fairy tale
cholos have been spinning for years.
Well, something happens to me...
make sure somebody takes care
of my boy.
Nothing's happening.
Let me take care of Gusano.
- After that, things could change.
- I'm out of a job.
I can't exactly
collect unemployment...
and H-cutter don't look good
on no résumé.
You could
clean up your act, start fresh.
I don't see
where you have much of a choice.
I'm helping you this time.
Next time, I'll be arresting you.
Besides, how old's this kid?
Two? Three?
Four.
Four? He seems small.
We take care of ourselves.
But the good news is
this gun guy, Jamani, works alone.
- Come on, dude. Put that shit out.
- This is my car.
Okay. This guy deals in filed-down guns
and sawed-off shotguns.
- You gotta be careful.
- We'll try not to get your hair messed up.
[All Laughing]
- I can't go through with this lie detector.
- [Shane] That's jitters.
We'll get you back to Smitty's,
get you strapped in.
We got three days
to practice.
Are we gonna beat this thing
based off the tips of a goddamn locksmith?
Smitty was Army Intelligence
for 12 years before he got into keys.
Dude, I was in the service.
A.I. just means...
he was carrying extra batteries
for the field radio.
Look, man, Vic put his ass
on the line for us. So did these guys.
- Wejust need to be calm and concentrate.
- Shit.
Answer these questions that we ask ourselves.
We're gonna get through this.
- Bro-
- Don't "bro" me.
This is a team,
and it all comes down to us delivering.
We're not gonna
let these guys down.
Let's go find this asshole
and see what he knows.
[Monica] We hear you fix guns
for Grape Street, Jamani.
Anyone approached you
with a slain officer's gun?
- You got some bad information.
- We found three silencers and a stash...
of unregistered handguns
in your crib.
Unless you wanna
hone your legal skills at Soledad...
you'd better tell us
about the gun you heard about.
African cat stepped to me with it.
Somebody need the numbers
filed off.
- What kind of piece?
- Beretta 92-F.
But / told Kunta Kinte he could
take that business somewhere else.
He came in actin'all arrogant,
high and mighty and shit.
- This dude called me a nigger, like "G-E-R."
- [Monica] What's his name?
- I don't know.
- I need you to look at some mug books.
Nah. Later for that.
I didn't even get a good look at him.
Hey, man, this guy's
great-great-great grandpappy...
sold one of
your ancestors to the man.
You really wanna let him get away
with actin' like he's better than you?
/ heard something loud. / came over
to the window to see what it was.
- What did you see?
- No one's gonna know your name.
I only saw one car.
It was dark blue and old.
This was about a minute
after the shots.
- 1990s? '80s?
- /'m really not good with cars.
Older, I think, like a classic.
We're back from the car wash.
The victim was a Latino.
- He was killed during the carjacking.
- Girl heard the shots.
She didn't see the killer,
but she saw a witness.
"The shooter had Los Mag gang tats.
He drove the stolen car.
Two other Latino males
followed him in a black BMW."
Sounds like your witness called in. Wouldn't
give his name, but he caught a lot of detail.
- [Dutch] 911 get his number?
- No. He called the switchboard.
He knew how to keep his name
and voice out of it.
- What you got?
- Unis papered the neighborhood
for this Nigerian named Ade Achebe.
He lives here.
He was tryin' to clean a cop's gun.
- From the make, it looks like Carl's.
- Any connection to the Niners?
Haven't seen one,
but he's on a Homeland Security watch list.
So is every African
that's entered the country since 9/11.
What's the big deal?
You could fit 'em all in a phone booth.
Ronnie, Army, take the back.
- [Curtis] We got a warrant?
- Just my winning smile.
Anybody else
hear those cries for help?
Police.
- Here we go. Here.
- [Dog Barking Wildly]
[Continues Barking]
- 6-Paul-11. [Echoes]
- Whoa.
- That's another radio. Hit it again.
- [Static Echoes]
- Keep hittin' it.
- 6-Paul-11.
- [Static]
Test, one, two. Test, one, two.
[Echoes]
Hey. Scooby's.
- [Ronnie] Test, one, two.
- Shit.
- So somebody executed our best lead?
- We found Scooby's radio.
- Any guns?
- No.
Well, he could've bought that radio
in a pawn shop.
[Mackey]
Or took it from him after he killed him.
This guy couldn't
subdue Carl and Scooby on his own.
The whole neighborhood knew
we were lookin' for a Nigerian.
Maybe his accomplices heard too
and tried to tie things up.
It feels like it's moving away from Antwon.
Might not even be seizure-related.
I wouldn't rule him out just yet. We haven't
found his Salvadoran hookup, Gusano.
- This reads mob to me.
- The neighbors are screaming "blue justice"...
payback for one of our own.
Let them stick their fingers up his ass.
He's been cold for hours. We just got here.
We just need to get a fix on what direction
this is going. El Salvadorans? Nigerians?
Just get me answers.
We should talk to Vic.
Maybe he could find out...
if our dead guy was beefing
with another gang.
- We can do anything he can do.
- Including dating his wife?
Ex-wife, and we're friends.
You wanna keep secrets,
go ahead...
but when it starts interfering
with our investigations, give it up.
It's just weird timing right now.
Maybe you should be the one to talk to him.
Where you goin'?
Blue classic car,
well-maintained?
- That's a classic?
- /t is to Billings.
- You're not serious.
- Witness knew enough to call the switchboard...
instead of 911.
You're just mad at him
because he took our cases.
Witness with a spot-on knowledge
of gang tattoos.
- Still not there yet.
- That's dried soap.
I thought he was supposed
to be getting you lunch.
So what's up?
[Dutch] We're stuck
on this carjacking murder...
thought you
might be able to help us out.
- Sure.
- Anything you wanna tell us about it?
- What do you mean?
- The anonymous caller
who witnessed the shooting...
provided a lot of detail-
very thorough.
Called the switchboard,
recognized gang tats.
Your car is streaked with dried soap,
like you rushed out without having time to rinse.
Dried soap?
We had Nicole's blood in O.J.'s bedroom,
and look at what good that did us.
- Give me a break.
- We got the bills back from the car wash.
Your fingerprints were
on some of them.
You guys must have broken the world record.
I can't get anything...
back from those lab rats
in less than a day.
So it'll take a day, but when it does
come back, are we gonna find yours?
All right. I was there.
And now I'm here, because I didn't feel
like committin' suicide today.
Come on. / was 15 feet away from two
armed bangers who already had their guns out.
That's not bein' a coward.
That's livin' to fight another day.
- Why didn't you report it?
- I called in and told 'em what I saw, every detail.
- If I didn't care, would I have done that?
- You should've called us instead.
- Why? So the people here could
think I didn't do something to stop it?
- Did you?
I was outnumbered
and outgunned.
Come on. You know you can't
show any weakness in this house.
You saw how they treated Reynolds
when they caught him bawlin' his eyes out...
in the locker room, or Lowe
when his boyfriend threw a hissy fit.
- They still make fag jokes behind his back.
- It wouldn't be like that.
After what happened to Carl and Scooby,
everybody's looking over their shoulder.
They give us this badge and a gun,
and they expect us to act like Superman.
Like I'm not some middle-aged guy who could
use a few more hours a week on the treadmill.
You're both smart.
You got the facts.
I gotta work
with the people here.
Keep me out of this?
- What are you doin'?
- I'm practicin' for the damn polygraph.
Listen, dude.
You're gonna pass it.
And after you do,
you should get out.
- For real?
- Look, this team gets into a lot of shit.
- You're tellin' me now?
- We always say we're through, okay...
but if you're not in 100%,
split while the going's good.
'Cause you're either built
for it or you're not.
- [Door Opens]
- Hey, techies pulled a slug
out of that dead guy's wall.
Ballistics don't match
Carl or Scooby's guns.
I.N.S. gave us his roommate
off an expired visa.
- Idisa Okoye.
- It's "okoye" with me if it's "okoye" with you.
Sponsored by a family
out of Long Beach.
If Okoye executed his roomie, he's gonna need
a place to hide for the next few days...
so grab your swimsuits:
we're headed to Long Beach.
[Birds Squawking]
- Lem, Ronnie, go around back.
- [Curtis] You got it, man.
[Curtis]
Come on, Ronnie. Let's go down the side.
Idisa Okoye? Is he here?
- Is he inside?
- Speak English?
- [Speaking Nigerian]
- [Mackey] Idisa? Idisa?
- [Woman Screaming]
- [Mackey] Get 'em out ofhere.
- [Screaming Continues]
- Army. Army, get these kids out.
- [Mackey] Police.
- [Shane] Come on, buddy. Come here.
- Come on!
- [Screaming Continues]
- [Man Speaking Foreign Language]
- Sounds Russian.
- You ready? Go!
- [Gunfire]
- Cover.
- [Gunfire Continues]
He's empty!
[Grunting]
- [Shane] Don't move.
- [Crying]
- You all right?
[Gunshot]
- [Gun Cocks]
- [Gunfire]
He's down! He's down!
[Groans]
Shit.
- Vic. Hey, thank you.
- Yeah.
[Sirens Wailing, Distant]
- Vic!
- [Sirens Grow Louder]
- [Officer] Don't move!
- [Shane] Hey, hey, man!
- We're cops, Farmington cops.
- You wanna shoot somebody, / volunteer this guy.
[Siren Chirping]
We responded to shots fired, :
we found this guy fleeing from the scene.
He involved in the shooting?
It's Idisa Okoye. Sister lives here.
Yeah, well,
we found this on him.
It's Carl's. Hey, man,
you just snagged yourself a cop killer.
[Chattering]
- Where's your partner?
- He's in the restroom.
/'ve got a murder
/ could use some help on.
/'ll be with you in a second.
I heard you're banging my ex.
- Trying to get my attention?
- No. We met-
/ hope you're
thinkin'that through.
And by the way, we just picked up one
of the guys who killed Carl and Scooby.
- That's great.
- Yeah. Weren't you primary on that?
Well, we're all here
to help each other out, right? Right?
You are in deep shit.
We know
you killed two police officers.
I didn't kill anybody.
Why were two Russians
holding your family hostage, waiting for you?
Let's start with the cops.
Did Antwon Mitchell
hire you to kill them?
- Who?
- Why were the bodies left in a seized house?
Look, I don't know how it works
back home in Lion Country, but here...
you get the needle for killin' cops.
Give yourself a chance,
you start talkin', namin' names.
You say I killed someone:
I say you are wrong.
They found the police radio
in your apartment.
You had one of their guns
on you when they picked you up.
Both were taken off the bodies
after they were killed.
I am tired now.
I am going to take a nap.
Okay. Settle down.
Now, even cop killers
have rights.
Sleeping just
isn't one of them.
This guy doesn't even know
to ask for a lawyer.
You give me the night, I'll get him
to own up to stabbing our guy.
It just doesn't add up.
Why are the Russians involved?
- We'll figure it out.
- Looks like it has nothing to do with the seizures.
- Isn't that a good thing?
- Yes.
The Russian guy from the house
won't say a word...
but I tied him
to Carl and Scooby.
They pulled his boss over a few weeks back,
clocked him doing 50 in a school zone.
They got into some kind of argument,
and they tossed the guy in lockup overnight.
- What?
- Carl liked to get in people's faces.
They got killed
over a speeding ticket?
[Dutch] We need you
to /.D. the shooter on the record.
- [Billings] Why?
- [Claudette] Unis pulled over the stolen car.
- He was Los Mag, long rap sheet.
- So why do you need me?
Because he's not talking. We don't know
who his accomplices are.
- We didn't find a murder weapon.
- You guys are the best detectives here.
Tell him you got 10 witnesses.
Break this asshole and get him to confess.
We tried.
You're our only eyewitness.
- [Claudette] / know you're scared.
- [Billings] Come on.
Can you honestly say you wouldn't
have done the same thing?
/ know /'m an asshole for asking,
but, please, take another crack at this guy.
- I'm beggin'.
- Well, don't.
Ever heard of Andrei Tretiak?
He's Russian organized crime...
same as the comrades who are
holding your family hostage.
You're safe and sound here
in the police station, but what about them?
They already
killed your roommate.
We stopped them before
they raped and tortured your family.
Next time, they'll be quick.
They might let the kids live...
but only if they cut their eyes out
so they can't be identified.
[Monica] But it's over for you. /t was over
the moment you killed our two officers.
But I'm giving you a chance to save the lives
of your sister and the rest of them.
- How would you protect them?
- We'd move them out of state.
But you'd have to give us a statement
and leave nothing out.
- [Mackey] Did Tretiak hire you?
- I can't say.
Achebe arranged everything.
Well, while we're
gluing his brains back together...
you give us something
on these Russians.
- Just did what Achebe asked.
- [Monica] And what was that?
Well, he was given names
and pictures.
We followed them, your officers.
We waited for our opportunity.
Then they went into an apartment,
so we opened a manhole cover.
When they came back,
we told them we heard a child below...
so they bent down to look.
That's when I stabbed the Asian one
in the back of the neck.
He was paralyzed,
couldn't move his arm.
But the other one, the black one,
he fought hard.
So / went to help Achebe.
We stabbed him-
We kept stabbing him,
but he wouldn't die.
And then we heard the Asian one.
He was still breathing...
so I went, took him down
and finished him as well.
Cut him here.
And then we carried them
into the building...
the one you had stolen...
just as Achebe was instructed.
- [Mackey] We straight? Let's go.
- [Knocking]
- Yeah?
- Hey.
I just wanted to say
that it really means a lot to everyone...
that you guys nailed those assholes
who killed Carl and Scooby.
This old team
still has a few new moves.
- Yeah.
- Still gotta get the Russian string pullers.
Also, we got a lead on Antwon's
Salvadoran connection, a guy named Gusano.
You still think
Antwon's involved?
Oh, we think he might be connected
somehow. We're on the way there now.
Shane and Army have other business first.
Polygraph in 10 minutes.
- Gang Central.
- [Mackey] / thought that was next week.
You know the public pressure
we're getting on this.
/f / have to stand up for this team,
/ need assurances, and / need them now.
If you can put it off till tomorrow,
this Salvadoran might fill in some blanks for us.
These two are staying.
Anyway, good work.
Did you have
to get such a pretty tester, Captain?
- Try and relax.
- I'm just saying you got my heart rate up.
Could you take a few points off
for me, darlin'?
I'm gonna ask you a series
of questions first just to make sure...
the machine's working properly.
- Okay.
- Make your answers accurate and honest.
[Machine Beeps]
- Is your name Shane Vendrell?
- Yes.
- [Chattering]
- Gusano.
- What's up, man?
- /'m here to talk about Pitarrio
and his heroin cutter...
Emolia Melendez.
- Cops?
- [Door Opening]
- Yo, man. /t's a friendly visit.
- [Gusano] Since when are cops bein' so friendly?
Pitarrio lost something of yours.
Emolia was worried that you might blame her too.
/ helped her to get it back.
Now /'m helping to make it right.
Here.
[Spanish]
Tell her to relax, :
don't even trip.
As soon as I tell you to stay the hell away
from her and her kid.
Thank you very much.
/t's very nice to meet you.
- Hey, it's not that bad.
- [Monica] Army, let's get started.
- I'm not taking it.
- You're what?
I talked to my P.B.A. rep,
and he said I can refuse to take it.
But we got-
we got nothing to hide.
And I can't get penalized for it either.
He said polygraphs are subjective...
and the results aren't worth shit,
and that's why they're not admissible in court.
- This isn't about covering your own ass.
- [Exhales Sharply]
We have to prove
that we didn't set up Antwon.
If people believe that,
they'll think we framed our cop killer.
- Everything will fall apart.
- I'm sorry. That's not my problem.
It is about everyone in here...
and how people think of us
out there.
You are screwing every single cop
in this building.
This has nothing to do with anybody else.
This is about taking care of me.
- The guy's just nervous-
- No! It's too late.
[Door Slams Shut]
The injunctions are keeping the gangs indoors.
/'m surprised to say it...
but Monica's policies
are really starting to take an effect.
The public sees us
as having our boot on their neck.
- When does the press get good on this?
- We're seeing a difference.
Somebody just has to report it.
- Don't shut it down now.
- [Aceveda] She brought down
Antwon Mitchell, for Chrissake.
- You've been pissing on
her policies. Why the change?
- /'m allowed to reevaluate...
my position,
as long as she's willing to also.
- I really think there's a middle ground
we can be happy with.
- Like what?
No. Compromise, retreat
is the worst thing we can do...
and you'd be abandoning the memory
of those two dead cops and all they fought for.
Christ. Don't play that card with me.
Most people in this town...
still think they were killed
because of your seizure policy.
Well, they weren't.
It seems it was a traffic dispute.
Do we know that for sure? Is there any proof
we can put in front of the people?
I'll find it.
As for the seizures, they stay, or I go.
Then you can tell the brass how you lost
one of L.A. 's two female captains...
because she was too tough
on crime.
[Door Slams]
Hey.
l- Oh.
/ took care of Gusano.
He's not gonna be a threat to you anymore.
You can stay here for a few more days,
but after that...
/ can only
fudge the paperwork for so long.
We'll be fine.
How's this little guy?
- Has he been to a doctor?
- Sure.
What'd they say?
I gotta make him eat,
get him into a preschool.
He used to talk more,
but some of the stuffhe's seen-
I'd keep my mouth shut too.
I'll go pick up a few things,
make you guys a little more comfortable.
Maybe that'll get him
back to talking.
Thanks.
He confessed.
Kept your name out of it.
- Thanks. Really.
- You're welcome.
- How 'bout I buy you both a beer?
- No, thanks.
Can't.
I've gotta be somewhere.
[Chuckles Ruefully]
- Vic's put me through hell, but
never anything this malicious.
- He just said that to hurt us.
- So you're not trying to get close
to me just to get back at him?
- No.
Absolutely not.
Maybe at first a little,
but I really like you now.
Look, / put up with Vic's shit every day,
so is asking you out a perk?
Sure. Vic's an asshole.
He's the father of my children.
That makes him my asshole, not yours.
- It's not where we started: it's where we are now.
- It started with a lie.
I don't even know
where we are now.
- I'm sorry.
- You think this is easy for me, dating again?
I told you it was a bad idea,
but you kept pushing it.
- What about my kids?
- I love your kids.
You weren't honest with me before.
How can I even trust you with them now?
- Or trust myself to you?
- Corrine.
You can leave, okay?
l- l- I am sorry.
It was nothing
you couldn't handle: I told you that.
- I don't have to handle it.
The P.B.A. guy told me that.
- You'd trust him before us?
Damn right! I mean,
he may not be as well-versed in these things...
as an ex-army locksmith,
but I'll take my chances.
- You stupid shit.
- Hey, hey...
your P.B.A. genius,
he gonna get you your next job?
- He's gonna keep me out of court.
- Toss your career if you want...
but you made us all look guilty
when you blew off that test.
- You are guilty!
- Shh.
Who's the one who lost it and shot Halpern?
I know I didn't.
Which makes me guilty too.
Hey, maybe Army's right.
/t's as good a time
as any for him tojump.
No reason we can't leave
as friends.
Captain is right.
You are screwin' people over.
- You're screwin' this team over.
- This team? Look, that bullshit
never worked for me...
when I was pullin' sand out of my ass
in the desert: it's not workin' for me now.
I didn't take a bullet over there: I'm not
gonna take a bullet here, not for you guys.
I appreciate your honesty.
Let's go.
[Exhales Sharply]
- I vouched for him. I'm sorry.
- Don't worry about it.
We have to shake the Russians, figure out
how this all comes back to Antwon.
- You think it does?
- There's only one guy who can
get all the Salvadorans...
Russians, Africans
and One-niners all in the same bed.
- [Curtis] Antwon.
- We just got out from
underneath Antwon's shadow.
- Why shake a stick at a hornet's nest?
- Because anyone...
who had anything to do with killing Carl
and Scooby has to pay.
Plus I got eight missing months
of kickin' ass with you guys to make up for.
[Sirens Wailing, Distant]
[/gnition Starting,
Engine Rewing]
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Continues]
[Ends]