[Carl]... and the guy was just
screamin, so / looked down...
and I see in his hand
his nipple ring-
and his nipple.
[Laughs]
It's all true.
Fortunately, the guy was drunk.
[Danny] Yeah, but sooner
or later you sober up...
and you're still
missing your nipple.
How'd you guys log that
into evidence anyway?
- Oh, shit, with gloves on.
- [Laughter]
I'll be in the car.
[Carl]
Thought he got benched.
His P.B.A. rep appealed.
He's on the street till the hearing.
[Carl] He's pissing a lot of people off,
not being on board with the captain.
[Danny] Come on, look.
He's got a right to take a stand.
He's also got the right
to remain silent.
- Hey, you with me, Scoob?
- Damn straight.
[Radio: Dispatcher] 1-Tango-17, 242 just
occurred. 762 Whitney Avenue. Code 2.
- [Danny] Talk to you later.
- Yeah, / guess second roll call's over.
You had a gun to his head. He's gonna
tell you anything you want to hear.
- It wasn't like that.
- How can you know for sure
what's going on in his mind?
If Shane wasn't telling me the truth,
things would have gone down differently.
- He was never coming after me. I believe that.
- He's been lying for months...
- leaking all that intel to Antwon.
- He didn't get Angie killed.
Her own mother gave her up
to Antwon before she O.D. 'd.
He had to watch Antwon shoot her,
for Christ's sakes.
- He's sick about it.
- Yeah, so sick all he's worried
about is covering his own ass.
I told him he has to come clean with
everything that happened with Antwon.
Will that buy him
some trust?
- We should hear him out.
- Boys.
[Shane]
Once he had us on the hook for Angie...
he twisted us pretty hard.
You've already seen the highlights.
[Sighs]
And after that, everything else just
seemed like small potatoes, you know.
We tipped off the El Salvadorans
in that church raid.
Muled some China white
from San Pedro to L.A.
Antwon was pretty pissed off
you took down those drug dens ofhis...
and to help ease the pain, we, uh, busted
his competitors, gave him half the product.
And that's most of it.
Antwon have any relationships
I should know about?
Not many that work.
Beaners hate his ass.
El Salvadorans are losing faith.
R.O.C., they ignore him.
Asians tolerate him.
Outside the brothers,
he ain't too popular.
These injunctions and seizures are hitting
him harder than he wants folks to know.
- That's why he needed me.
- What about Army?
He follows my lead.
So he won't blindside us?
No. No, he's-
He's down.
Look, I'm sorry
about that little girl.
But it's not too late
to get her back...
to give her a proper burial.
So basically, you need our help.
Right?
He came clean.
Now it's time for us
to do our part.
- [Army] What?
- [Shane] / told them everything.
- What everything?
- All of it.
How about bouncing that shit
off me? I don't know these guys.
I do, and we can't
handle this alone.
All right, banger spotters
are there around the clock.
Lost souls usually shuffle in after dark.
Place closes around midnight.
We'll find an excuse
to roust the muscle.
- We'll bring 'em back to the Barn.
- But they're all One-niners.
- We bust 'em on an injunction violation.
- How you getting Angie's body?
We wait till it's dark. / just
don't know how deep she's buried.
If they planned on having
the shithouse on top...
- probably not very deep.
- We dig her up, extract our bullets-
We find a really
good place to bury her.
Once we have the girl's body, Antwon
doesn't have any more leverage.
- We go in hard. Put him away for good.
- Or we shoot him for resisting.
This is bullshit, man.
- We can do this, just the four of us.
- He's good. Don't worry.
Let's go.
[Radio: Dispatcher]
1-Tango-13, roger.
Respond to 4556 Alexandria Circle,
Apartment 7.
1 -Tango-17 has been Code 6 on
a domestic dispute for a while now.
- They're not responding.
- [Julien] Roger. This is 1 -Tango-13.
We're on the scene.
Ma'am, are you the one
that made the 911 call?
Yeah, but I told them other cops
they missed him.
How long ago did
the other officers come by?
- About halfhour ago.
- Why'd you call?
Gideon Mazell, my ex's kid, he was trying
to break in. Said he was gonna rape me.
Asshole's been trying to get at me
since / dumped his old man.
Did you see where the officers
went after they left?
[Woman]
/ figured they went looking for Gideon.
- [Julien] Excuse me. /'ll take a look.
- 1 -Tango-17, you copy?
Carl, Scooby,
you guys on foot?
- Anything?
- Canvassed the whole area. There's nothing.
- Oh, shit.
- Half the people weren't answering their door.
- The other half were sleeping.
- Can I use your radio?
Staff 9-Tango. I'm Code 6
on Alexandria Circle.
Be advised we have two officers
unaccounted for. Requesting a tac alert.
- All watches will be held over.
- [Dispatcher] Copy that.
We should notify the families.
[Sirens /n Distance]
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Ends]
Carl and Scooby have been missing at least
an hour. I'm on my way there right now.
Could be the same hunt-
Antwon sending a message.
/f that's true,
they aren'tjust missing.
Retribution for not
killing the cop he wanted?
- We know where he likes to bury bodies.
- Jesus Christ.
All right, you, Army
and Ronnie, stick to the plan.
Find our missing cops.
We also gotta get a 20 on Antwon...
so we can scoop him up as soon
as we find the girl's body.
You come with me.
Let's go.
I want you to go to the end of the block,
keep knocking until you wake people up.
- Yes, ma'am.
- [Claudette] Where do you want us?
We're trying to track down Gideon Mazell,
the subject of the 911 call.
Steve Billings is on his way down,
so pass on to him what you find.
Captain, Steve's good at what he does,
but we've got officers missing.
If they're still alive,
they won't be for long...
and your two best detectives
are right here, right now.
You haven't seen our best game
because of the whole D.A. thing...
but this is too important.
Okay. You're the primaries.
We'll contact the sheriff, see if
they can loan us some bloodhounds.
Tracking Gideon Mazell.
Danny talked to the woman he was
threatening, so you guys get together.
- Vic and his people can work the gang end.
- Where is she?
Apartment 7,
right upstairs.
Julien, / want you to be department liaison,
sit with Carl's wife.
I heard what happened.
I want to help.
Tonight your reserve duty?
No, but I'm still
part of this family.
- Who can I ride with?
- I'll see who's available.
Captain, I knew both those guys.
I should be out there looking for them.
I'm more comfortable
if you're at Carl's house.
I don't have time to worry
about whether you follow orders.
Danny, I want you to take
Aceveda on patrol with you.
- /f there are any problems,
/ want to hear about them.
- Absolutely.
You ever consider this might be
Antwon Mitchell's work?
It's his hood, isn't it?
- I sent some unis to pick him up.
- Call 'em back.
- I'm all over it. He's M.I.A.
- With our two cops? That's convenient.
Give me those unis. I'll sweep up some of
his crew. Maybe find Antwon or our guys.
I can only spare
a couple of bodies.
Look, if / wasn't put in the backseat
on this task force...
maybe I could have stopped
this from happening.
[Sighs]
You did what you had to do. I know that.
I just want
to find these guys.
Okay, I'll have Zerkow
call them back...
- and assign them to you.
- Appreciate that.
I'd like to help out.
You got any gaps here?
Yeah. Check with Dutch
and Claudette.
They're up there.
[Helicopters Overhead]
- We want to talk to Antwon.
- Well, he ain't here.
- What do you assholes know
about two missing cops?
- What the hell-
- You know there's an injunction, boys.
- That ain't no violation, man.
Franklin is a citizen.
He ain't claiming.
Really?
Need me to drop
my drawers too, faggot?
- [Grunts]
- [Officer] Hey, Vic.
[Mackey]
Take this piece of shit.
Fuck yes.
Get them inside
and out of sight.
Okay, go to work.
Back in about an hour.
Gideon Mazell's address.
Captain- I mean, Councilman.
It's just officer tonight.
What can we do?
Pick Gideon up,
and take plenty of backup.
Don't worry.
We'll be careful.
[Man]
Detective.
I just talked to a neighbor who called 911
an hour before the other call.
- What was the complaint?
- Homeless man rooting through the trash.
When they tried to run him off
he seemed unstable.
- Threatened violence.
- Get a description. He's homeless. He's not far.
I'll tip it up.
You push it up and over, okay?
Okay.
[Grunting]
- Ugh! Goddamn it.
- That is rank.
You can do the digging.
Okay, fine.
No sign of our cops,
and the girl's body wasn't there.
- What do you mean?
- Shallow grave, empty. Somebody moved her.
- Halpern tipped Antwon.
- No way. We've been taking turns
watching that place...
- around the clock since he showed it to us.
- Halpern lied?
Then maybe the body
was never there.
- No, he moved it and didn't tell him about it.
- [Army] Now what?
Can't find the don,
you go visit Fredo.
- Yo, what're you working?
- Same as you.
Captain talked to Dutch and Claudette.
Put 'em onto Antwon.
- They got me tracking him down.
- You hear something, give us a heads-up.
Yeah.
Look, I'm trying.
You're not making it easy.
Keep trying.
Why you got me locked down?
Officers who brought you in
said you got a little... physical.
'Cause / didn't do nothin'
to deserve this.
Twice arrested for intent
to distribute steroids.
That your One-niner
connection?
You and a couple of them run into
two of our police officers tonight?
- Shit no.
- Maybe you went over to Lydia Quall's place...
- looking to get a little physical too.
- Lydia?
- She the one trying to get physical with me.
- With you?
- Yeah.
- She's dating your father.
Left him, thinking she
could have the 2005 model.
- / told her / was straight.
- If she's the one chasing you...
how come she's calling 911 trying
to stop you from breaking into her house?
- What you talking about?
- Officers respond, they go missing.
Take somebody pretty strong
to corral the two of them.
- What time we talking?
- Few hours ago.
No, no, no. I was over
at Greg Hockler's place all night...
- shooting up with stanozol.
- Steroids?
Got fresh track marks
on my ass to prove it.
[Scoffs]
Looks like you could use a little juice...
buddy.
- You lied to us, Lydia.
- We have two officers missing.
So we don't have time
for goddamn liars.
Gideon was nowhere near
your place when you called 911.
You lured those officers there.
You told them some bullshit story
about some guy harassing you...
and when you left your place...
- there was somebody else waiting for them.
- No!
Where are they, Lydia?
We are gonna lock...
that fat ass of yours in a cage
for the rest of your life...
- unless you tell us right now.
- / didn't lure no one.
I was just trying
to set up Gideon.
Figured if I got him
into some trouble with the law...
then he'd have
to talk with me...
and I'd drop the charges if he got
a little friendlier, you know?
I was looking to get the man in my bed,
not mess with no cops.
Thank you. We'll return the favor
if you ever need it. Good-bye.
Sheriff s office is sending over
six more officers.
- What'd you get upstairs?
- Bodybuilder and his paramour weren't involved.
- So we're back to square one.
- We've ruled some people out.
- We have to rule some people in.
- We knew whoever did this...
had a reason for being
on that block.
Mm-hmm.
Statements from neighbors?
Oh, yeah. Look, I've been over this.
Nothing stands out.
- / was gonna go through them again.
- [Monica] Do it in person.
Knock on the doors yourself.
We might have something.
Well, like I told the other
law enforcement agents...
uh, one was tall...
uh, African-American.
Uh, the shorter of the two
appeared white initially...
then I realized...
he was Asian.
[Laughs]
Marco Polo.
Did you see the officers
go into the apartment building?
Yes, ma'am.
- [Dutch] Did you see them come out?
- [Clears Throat]
[Claudette]
Can you answer the question, Roger?
May / see a badge number,
please?
[Claudette] Did you see the officers
come out of the building, yes or no?
I am going to need
one of those...
before I can be debriefed
in the category.
Civilians don't have badges.
When I get my badge...
all things will be made known...
peace officer to peace officer.
- Hey, Corrine.
- Hi.
- What's going on?
- We're looking for a black banger, 20s...
- came in here last night.
- This tied to those missing cops?
It might be. You got any
gunshot wounds in here?
- Only about 100.
- Check for a Halpern White.
Gimme a sec.
Gunshot wound to the shoulder.
Lost lots of blood.
Stabilized this morning.
Moved to the fourth floor.
- Talking?
- On a morphine drip.
He's happy. Not sure how much
talking he's doing.
So, any word
on those missing men?
Uh, no, but we could use
a favor with that.
That felt creepy.
- It's for a good cause.
- Thank you. Thank you.
Hey, I see you got
that lift to the E.R.
- What the hell you want?
- Did you say Angie's body was
under the goddamn outhouse.
- It is.
- No, it ain't. We looked.
Antwon must have
hauled it out.
- [Groans]
- Question is, where to?
Same place he's stashing
the two cops?
- What cops?
- You'd best be coming up with some answers...
or a copy of this C.I. contract
you just signed...
gets nailed to the door
of Antwon's community center.
- [Groans]
- Next time you sign insurance waivers...
you should read
the fine print.
Some paper, signed or not, ain't gonna
make my clique turn against me.
- [Groans]
- You just took a bullet. Almost died.
I hear you found Jesus,
saw the error of your ways.
- Started giving it up to Mr. Man
to get a fresh start.
- [Coughing]
You know the thug code-
"Trust no one.
Kill your buddy
before he kills you."
That's what separates us
from you.
Antwon wouldn't use his own crew
for that kind of shit.
He farms it out. They got a contract
with the El Salvadorans.
With you laid up,
who would he reach out with?
I doubt he went direct.
I don't know who
he'd use as a middleman.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
You won't be able
to make any phone calls...
but you won't care.
Uh, would you do...
the honors?
What happened after the officers
came out of the apartment building?
[Clears Throat]
Uh-
The officers in question were
approached by a series of individuals.
[Claudette]
How many?
Three to seven.
Difficult to say with accuracy.
Low luminous environment.
- Where were you in relation to the police car?
- /'d say, uh...
forty meters east southwest.
[Claudette]
What were you doing there?
Routine surveillance.
Uh, monitoring bursts
of non-visible light...
in the 800-angstrom range.
High dispersion and so forth.
Roger, I need you
to be honest with me-
detective to detective.
Did you have anything
to do with this?
No, sir, I did not.
What happened
to those police officers?
Hmph.
[Dutch]
These men have families...
that are very worried
about them.
We all have a level three
clearance here, correct?
No. I'm still at level two.
Roger.
Level three.
Foreign operatives are
using the fault lines...
to destabilize
the gravity shelf.
9/11 all over again.
So these people you saw,
they were, uh...
foreign agents?
Uh, they, uh-
They travel along the fault lines...
to evade detection.
There are easier ways
to knock down a skyscraper...
than flying aircraft into it-
Uh, subduction,
uh, slip strike manipulation...
mantle failure and so forth.
That building is coming down.
- /t's coming down, all right.
- Got it. Got it.
Officer, deploy the swing shift
without roll call- everyone on the street.
And no petty busts. I don't want anybody
holed up with paperwork here.
- So, did he give us anything?
- Hmm.
Alien abduction in the hood is more
plausible than anything he had to say.
He studied string theory
before going off the deep end.
Send him to County
for observation.
The one thing we do know is he saw
our cops. We should keep him here.
- The man's psychotic.
- He's our only witness.
- When does /.N.S. send your ass back?
- Supposed to be three days ago.
Behind schedule. Why?
I can keep you off that bus-
keep you in the U.S.
Two cops have gone missing.
/.N.S. is helping the police.
- What do you need me for?
- /nformation. Antwon Mitchell.
If he wanted to grab some cops,
who'd he use from your set?
You could really
get me out of here?
Free pass comes
right from the top.
Chief signed it himself.
Name's Pitarrio.
Knew Antwon in prison.
- He's his go-to on all the ugly shit.
- Where can I find him?
I need to look for him.
You need to stay here
in case Carl calls.
You know, he's been
coming home...
every night...
talking about how things
are more dangerous out there.
I mean, what did your captain
think would happen?
You push people long enough,
they push back.
Things weren't
working before.
She's just trying
something different.
Things were working fine
before.
Carl came home every night.
He's out there.
Alive.
- I can feel it.
- Then we'll find him.
What's up, Queenie?
Daddy, am I glad you here.
Ducked in the alley for a quick bowl.
You know,
take the edge off.
Dude grabs me from behind,
puts a knife to me...
- tell me to dime po-po and give y'all an address.
- What is it?
Sister need to be
about her paper.
That blade on this pretty face
scared my ass to death.
Here.
- 2711 Heliotrope.
- What am / gonna find there?
- Didn't say.
- What's the guy look like?
Told me if / turn around,
he's gonna cut out my implants.
- Did he sound black or white?
- Honey, / wasn't trying to know.
I just finished paying
for my new kitty cats.
Another dub buy you
some bomb-ass skully.
You know I'm gonna take care of your piece
better than any other female.
I'm gonna have to take
your word for it.
Go.
Oh, Jesus. Oh, Jesus!
[Flies Buzzing]
[Man Groans]
Everyone outside
until the detectives get here.
[Officers Murmuring]
Stay behind the line.
[Man] Officer, can you just
tell us the names-
They were killed somewhere else
and dumped here.
Yeah. Forensics'job just got harder by half.
Gotta find the murder scene.
- We seized this house last month.
- Somebody's certainly making his point.
Antwon Mitchell's
hit the hardest.
He partnered
with the Salvadorans in Lompoc.
Likes to use them
for the dirty stuff.
You remember that Salvadoran broker,
Spider, from the church bust?
- I had a chat with him.
- The I.N.S. hasn't sent him
back to El Salvador yet?
They're not the most efficient bunch.
But anyway, he put me onto a guy
who does dirty work for Antwon.
- Let me know.
- Yeah.
[Whispering]
It's a foursome.
Easy way to wash drug money.
The bottles come in the front,
the big faces come out the back.
- Go around.
- Yeah.
[Men Chattering,
/ndistinct]
Freeze! Hands on the table!
Don't move!
[Mackey]
Which one of you is Pitarrio?
Pitarrio!
Pitarrio.
- [Groans]
- Pitarrio!
Talk!
- Cabrón.
- Get out. Get out.
- Who paid you to kill the cops?
- I didn't kill no cops.
- [Groans]
- Antwon Mitchell gave you the order.
- No, I didn't do no cops, man. [Groans]
- Spider says you did.
[Panting, Groaning]
/ was at the movies last night.
Ticket's in my jacket.
Sylmar.
8:30 show last night.
Shit.
- No.
- [Groans]
You didn't kill the cops,
but you did something for Mitchell.
What was it?
- What?
- The body.
- Antwon told me to move a body.
- Cops?
- No. I think it was a girl.
- Where?
- [Groans] Griffith Park, man.
By the horses.
Need to interview the suspect
Billings brought in.
Psst.
Psst. Psst.
Surveillance has been
nonproductive thus far.
/ have been monitoring
the chatter and so forth.
Sorry to hear
about those two officers.
They deserved better than
getting dragged down like that.
Why don't you start
without me?
What do you mean,
"dragged down"?
Hey, I need you
to really concentrate...
on everything you saw
last night.
See it in your mind
like it's a movie...
and you're looking at it
one frame at a time.
- Can you do that for me?
- I'll try.
I've got one of those brains
that skips around a lot.
Uh, and my condolences
to the Marco Polo family.
[Laughs]
In a cavern
In a canyon
Excavating
For a mine
Dwells a miner, forty-niner
and his daughter
Clementine
- /'m in a hurry, so / won't waste your time.
- I'll do the same.
People say not a lot happens on your block
if you don't sign off on it.
I look after my peoples.
We had two cops murdered and dumped
in a house on your street.
- That had to have been outsiders.
- Really?
You and your neighbors
weren't pissed off...
- the police seized that house on your street?
- Wasn't my house.
Owners cooked meth.
Street's been safer
since you done it.
[Officer]
Just keep it back.
We need to do another canvass
of this whole area.
Figure out how
Carl and Scooby disappeared.
- What are we looking for?
- I'm not sure.
But it may involve a geological anomaly
in the Earth's crust.
Just something to keep in mind
as you do your search.
Vonda,
/'m Captain Monica Rawling.
He's dead.
/'m so sorry.
He believed
in what you're doing.
- He was proud to put on his uniform every day.
- He was-
But what you're doing here in Farmington
is what got him killed.
You need to know that.
Carl was a hero.
I need you
to leave now.
Both of you.
Please, just-Just go.
Hey, uh, give me
a hand with this.
Here.
Yeah, Southwest. That's cool. We'll pick
him up. Thanks, man. We owe you one.
Was that about Antwon?
- Well?
- Yeah. That was, uh, Walon Burke, Decoy-
I know Walon.
What did he give you?
An F.B./. pal ofhis in Westwood
just got a hit on Antwon's credit card.
He charged a plane ticket from Vegas.
Due into L.A.X. at 7:30.
- Southwest.
- /'ll send some unis to pick him up.
- Nice work.
- [Dutch] / got something.
Found it at the bottom of a manhole
near our original crime scene.
There's blood everywhere
down there.
How do you get two cops
in the sewer?
"Officer, my daughter just fell down there.
Can you help me?"
Blinged out dog tag the hip-hop kids wear.
Initials "J.P."
Found it in the blood. It's too
untarnished to have been down there long.
Get the owner, got a killer.
So how many guys
you think it took...
- you know, to get Carl and Scooby down there?
- A few.
There's a lot of anger
about what's going on.
Yeah, well, they're angry
because it's working.
A lot of us
are behind the captain.
That's understandable.
Sometimes street level isn't
the best vantage point to really see-
[Sharp Sounds]
- [Brakes Screeching]
- What the hell was that?
Holy shit.
This look familiar
to you, Yancy?
- Don't think so.
- It was ripped from the neck...
of one of the people
who killed two cops last night...
whose bodies were found
on your block.
- You're hip-deep in this shit.
- You're the mayor on that block.
- You either did it, or you know about it.
- Don't come near me with that.
So you're saying you've
never seen this jewelry before.
Name's Yancy Backus.
Remember?
"J.P." belongs
to somebody else.
So it belongs to one of your friends
you did the killing with.
Y'all took my cell phone
downstairs.
Check my friends and family.
Or you could check
with LeimertJewelers-
The people who made this.
See who
they sold it to.
[Whispering]
Stupid-ass-
- [People Clamoring]
- [Man] We didn't do nothing.
[Siren Wailing]
[Man]
What's wrong with you?
- [Officer] Who wrote this?
- Man, he ain't seen nothing.
He was out back,
loading the truck.
- That's bullshit.
- What's bullshit-
Brothers out here dying,
none of you turning over the street.
- One of these cops was a brother.
- A cop ain't a brother.
- Maybe you saw something then, huh?
- Man, get the fuck-
- Hey, come here. Get your ass over here.
- [Groaning]
[Clamoring Continues]
You okay?
You know, you might
want to get that x-rayed.
I got the wind
knocked out of me is all.
Comes with the territory.
- Along with getting shot at.
- Don't single yourself out.
- Three other officers
got their cars fired on today.
- Everybody okay?
Thank God.
Not that you're asking,
but I've lost cops under my command.
/t's easy to shit your pants,
but it accomplishes nothing.
- I wasn't going down that road.
- What /'m saying is...
a thing like this- especially if there's
no good news right away-
can paralyze you.
Those people out there
need to feel your confidence.
Vic. You're empty-handed.
Where's the guy who does
all of Antwon's dirty work?
He had an airtight alibi.
Well, it's going around. Antwon just
happened to be in Vegas last night.
Got his flight info. / have some unis
posted at L.A. X...
to grab him when he gets
off the plane.
- Some good news, finally.
- Yeah, well, conversations with Mitchell...
tend to go around
in circles.
I don't want to keep the community
waiting while I find...
a straight line.
Dutch and Claudette
have come up empty too.
Maybe it's time to, uh...
bring in a person
of interest.
- Lay it off on someone?
- Just a couple of days.
Give us a chance to try to squeeze
the truth out of Antwon.
Makes people think twice
before they take a shot at a uni.
- You have anyone in mind?
- No.
Just as long
as he fills the bill.
One unsympathetic asshole
coming right up.
Captain's arranged a welcome wagon for
Antwon. He's flying into L.A.X. tonight.
So I hear.
You knew?
What part of us getting information first
didn't you understand?
Captain was standing right there
when I got the call. I had to tell her.
- She doesn't have anything on Antwon.
- No.
But he's got plenty
on them.
If we haul in Antwon,
push the wrong buttons...
how long you think it's gonna take him
to point a finger at me and Army?
I'll make sure it takes long enough
for us to get our leverage back.
Look, we gotta find a goat
to pin these murders on-
- calm the streets before another cop gets killed.
- This captain won't go for that.
It was her idea.
All we need is a face and a name.
Anyone in Antwon's circle
fit that bill?
Well, there is this young cat. Earned his cred
by supplying clean guns to the black sets.
Whatever he was doing
last night, it wasn't legal.
- Guppy got a name?
- Street name's Urkel.
- [Man Snickers]
- Swear to God.
[Laughs]
All right, good.
You and Ronnie go pick up
our cop killer.
- Now you want us to haul in an innocent guy?
- He'll have a car full of guns.
Bring him in for that.
We'll figure the rest out later.
Let's go.
- Rise and shine, big pimpin'.
- [Gasps]
Get ahold of our thick friend.
Give him a heads-up.
- About what?
- Our captain likes him for killing those cops.
She's sending a blue crew
to L.A.X. to pick him up.
He needs to fly into Burbank instead.
We'll surprise him there.
Tell him how to play this out
with our bosses.
What makes you think he's
gonna drop his black ass...
- into whatever jackpot you got planned?
- No more games, no more threats.
We want to stop beef and start
doing business the right way.
This guy wants you dead.
He ain't getting into a car with y'all.
He's not gonna have a choice.
Now make the damn call.
[Line Ringing]
- Hell yeah, that's my shit.
- So you're admitting...
- you were present at a crime scene
last night, Jamal?
- Crime scene?
- Those two dead cops.
- [Dutch] Friends of ours, actually.
- No, I was not there.
- But your necklace was?
- How do you explain that?
- Necklace got itself stolen.
[Laughing]
Right.
- When?
- Six, seven months ago.
- They took the TV too.
- You, uh, report it?
I spent three G's getting
this thing custom made.
You best believe your ass
I reported it.
- Go check your records.
- Police have any idea who took it?
I kept trying to check back
with you cops every couple weeks...
see if they heard
anything new.
No one seemed real interested.
Y'all real interested
now though, huh?
Dutch.
Need you to come up, please.
So the trail just stops?
Well, even with the necklace stolen,
we're thinking...
it probably ended up in the hands
of somebody with the initials "J.P."
[Monica]
That's reaching. What else do we have?
No witnesses,
but we're waiting for lab work.
So that's the plan? We just get lucky,
something falls in our laps?
- /t's only the first day.
- Every day will just get harder.
Meanwhile, I've had
four different squad cars shot at...
two brawls with civilians
and officers...
and one instance in which
my own men lost control.
It's got to stop.
Vic and his guys have
brought in a suspect.
Great!
What do we have on him?
Carload of stolen guns.
Our guys were stabbed.
He's a gang member.
We've got him on weapons charges.
- But nothing related to our murders?
- / want you to make the press...
- believe that we have a killer in custody.
- [Dutch] Oh, you're kidding.
- You want us to lie?
- Save your high and mighties for a time...
when the lives of my cops
aren't at stake.
- You've had a chance to solve this.
- It's only been one day.
And you've been doing your best,
but we're not far enough.
We tell the community that we
have a killer, it sends the message...
that there's a price to pay
for coming after us.
Makes whoever
really did it cocky...
gets them laughing with their friends
about what idiots we are...
and if they tell
their friends-
- Their friends tell someone who tells us.
- You wanted the case...
so take the bad
with the good.
[Antwon]
So 5-0 was waiting for me at L.A.X.?
How is this an improvement?
My little gift to you,
running interference.
I didn't know
I made your Christmas list.
We want a truce.
You know, there's a much bigger upside
for you, me being alive and kicking.
[Antwon]
/ don't see it.
Truth is, my captain's made
a serious dent in your business.
How long before someone in your
organization decides to play King of the Hill?
Nobody's taking me down.
- Not without my backing.
- You been stepping on my game since day one.
That earns you dead.
Yeah? That didn't happen.
[Scoffs]
My boys saw you gaffing me
up at the airport, so-
Now what?
You back off of me and mine,
Shane and his family.
We work out fair percentages.
You get to do business uninterrupted.
That's the deal.
Either you smoking crack
or you think I am.
Our captain pulled him off lead
on the gang task force.
He lost his pay bump.
There's no up side for me
to play by their rules anymore.
I got two sick kids.
I gotta earn.
And I ain't got time to hear no more
of this crackerwood bullshit.
I know you been looking
for a new tar importer...
ever since you lost that cul-de-sac,
the El Salvadorans.
[Mackey] / got a hookup with
a Jamaican crew out of Miami.
They call themselves
the Splash Posse.
Yeah, I heard of them niggas.
They're looking to move weight
out of the West Coast.
I'm their broker.
We need a retail outlet.
So you a baller
all of a sudden now.
Always was.
/ just took a step back
from the game for a little while.
So what's your captain
gonna sweat me on, huh?
These dead cops?
I don't kill for no reason...
and I don't know nothin'
about merkin' no police.
[Shane]
They got nothin'on you.
They'll hold you
for a few hours...
- and then cut you loose.
- [Mackey] /'ll be in the room.
I'll steer the questioning away
from anything sensitive.
That is...
if we're working together.
You're lucky your boy
got mad love for you.
Oh, yeah.
We're all about mad love.
The suspect's name
is Donzell Prince.
[Man] You've arrested him for the
murders of Officers Haimes and Miller?
Currently, he's only being
held on weapons charges...
but we're confident
we have our man.
[Man] /f you're so confident,
why don't you file on murder?
We don't want to make any mistakes.
No one wants to take chances.
[Man]
Do you believe he acted alone?
Doesn't the crime itself suggest
that there were multiple assailants?
I really can't go into our theory
of the crime at this time.
Has the suspect indicated
any accomplices?
I can't talk about the specifics
of what the suspect revealed.
All / can say is,
our investigation is bearing fruit...
and we'll have more for you
in the coming days.
- Thank you.
- [Reporters Shouting Questions]
- Danny. Bring him up to one?
- [Danny] Sure.
- We frisked him. He's clean.
- [Danny] All right.
He gave us the slip at L.A.X.
How did you find him?
One of his crew told us
he got a heads-up.
Figured he only had one
of two choices left, Burbank or L.B.
- We got him at Bob Hope.
- Nice.
Don't know what
we're gonna throw at him yet.
I've got a couple aces
up my sleeve.
- See you up there.
- [Mackey] Yeah.
Help yourself.
All known city gang members
with the initials...
"J" and "P."
Hope you got a four-leaf clover
in your pocket.
- We should start with One-niners.
- In Farmington.
- You want some dinner?
- I had dinner- four hours ago.
Yeah. I mean another dinner.
Whatever you want's
fine with me.
We have nothing
to charge Antwon with.
Means we can only hold him
for 12 hours.
She's buried in Griffith Park, somewhere
near the horses, in three holes.
- Christ.
- [Mackey] All right, /'ll tie up Mitchell.
Make sure he doesn't
dime anyone to move her again.
You three have to find
the graves.
[Curtis]
/'ll do it too.
Look for fresh digging.
Let's find her.
Don't need that.
Thanks for coming in, Antwon.
[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
[Continues]
[Ends]