- Previously on The Shield.
- Sir, what's the problem?
- [Man] My dickl Pleasel
- You're caught in a rattrap.
I've got lupus.
Had it for 15 years.
[Dutch]
Claudettel
- Oh, my Godl
- [Billings] Don't move her. Call the paramedics.
Why didn't you tell me that Sadie
has a history of mental illness?
I made a life for myself.
You been missin' me?
- Ex-wife.
- I wasn't worth taking care of,
and now I'm not worth shit.
- I wanna go home!
- At least we found his weak spot.
- Shit! Go!
- Hey!
You! You're under arrest...
for possession of heroin
with intent to distribute.
The price is simple.
I help you put away these fine young men...
you make sure you
put them away right here.
You send Lem to Lompoc,
it's you that's the real murderer.
- Had a conversation with Antwon Mitchell.
- You're bluffin'.
You don't have the stomach
to serve Lem up to Antwon.
I didn't use to.
- [Man Sniffles]
- [Siren Wailing In Distance]
[Sniffles, Grunts]
[Retching]
[Flushes]
[Water Running]
[Knocking]
- Oh, shit.
- [Door Opens]
Mornin'.
- [Curtis] You gotta be kiddin'me.
- Welcome home.
- You don't look so good.
- [Curtis] I'm not talking to you.
[Kavanaugh]
It's a social call.
You're lucky havin'
a friend like Mr. Hovis.
Smithland Hovis, your good buddy
who posted your bail.
- Smitty.
- It's funny.
- He doesn't remember you that well either.
- Just get out, man.
You know, when I find out how Vic
and the other two got that bail money...
they're gonna wish that they had a friend
like your friend Smitty.
- Jesus. Is that blood?
- [Retching]
- [Grunts]
- Do you need a doctor?
Just get the hell out!
Just get out!
- [Groans]
- [Door Closes]
Heard you had a rough week, so I told Jon
I'd stop by and check in on you.
Sun'll rise in the west the day that man
cares whether I live or die.
Well, he did the same thing
for me with my ex.
Did more for her
than he did for me.
Sounds like
you guys are close.
We've been spending a lot of time together
actually, on account of the job.
ButJon's kinda tough
to figure out.
You know, I.A.D. Cops are
a different kind ofbreed.
Consider yourself fortunate.
He didn't tell me.
Uh, you have kids?
Family wasn't
on Jon's "to do"list.
Just as well. Easier to move on.
You want coffee?
Uh, water's fine.
So, how does it work,
you and the ex?
Good and bad. But I look out for her,
make sure she gets what she needs.
At least you guys
have a connection.
For better or worse.
You're not what I expected.
Truth is, I didn't have a clue what sort
of woman Jon would've married.
Neither did he.
Still doesn't.
Just like him to send
somebody else over...
to, uh, carry
my emotional baggage.
Tell the prick I'm great.
Hey, it's tough
to be a cop's wife.
Jon's wife is the job-
what keeps him warm at night.
And he's a coward
for not coming himself.
Is there some other message
you'd like me to give him?
Sure.
Whoa, whoa.
[Chuckles]
Uh, wh-what aboutJon?
When Jon left me,
he made his choice.
I'll make mine.
[Door Closes]
Hey. Where you been?
I had an ex-wife thing.
What'd you need us here for?
Not her. Me.
I'm gonna take a deal.
Now just listen.
If I plead guilty to the heroin thing,
this all seals off.
I mean, without me,
Kavanaugh's got nothin' else.
- He's got nothin' on you guys.
- We're not feeding you to Antwon.
Lompoc's an idle threat. The judge'll most
likely place him in a medium-security facility.
Kavanaugh's not gonna let you
skate with some cush deal.
He's got Emolia's testimony, man.
He wants years.
- He's got the brass behind him.
- [Rebecca] Not anymore. O.I.G. And the chief...
they're losing confidence
in Kavanaugh's investigation.
- D.A. 's receptive.
- I plead guilty to theft under color of authority.
- They'll drop the intent to distribute charge.
- No.
[Rebecca]
Five years. Up for parole in 18 months.
[Curtis]
Yeah.
[Mackey]
Man, you plead guilty, it's your badge...
it's your pension.
We're talkin' prison.
Eighteen months isn't a week.
I know.
Don't do it. Don't do it, man.
We're fighting this, man.
[Curtis]
I don't wanna fight anymore.
I don't wanna
fight anymore.
All right, if you were in
my place, you'd take the hit...
to protect me, the team.
To protect me, the team.
I know you would.
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Ends]
Look, no matter what we do, end of the day,
Kavanaugh's still got a brick of tar.
He's still got Emolia's word.
You heard Becca. The chief's losing faith.
I'm working on discrediting this guy.
So I.A.D. Brings in someone else.
They still have the same brick.
I'm doin' time no matter what.
This way I got some control.
Look, I'm just so tired of not
knowing what's gonna happen...
worrying about
the rest of you.
I gotta see an end.
Jesus Christ, man.
Look, I gotta get back inside
and talk to Becca.
- [Mackey] Let us know if anything breaks.
- All right.
For him to get out in 18 months,
he's gonna have to be a model inmate.
That's not gonna happen.
Protective custody's a joke.
He's gonna be fightin' for
his life the full five years.
What the hell is he thinkin'?
Well, between Kavanaugh spinnin' doom
and Becca sellin' him a rose garden...
the poor guy doesn't know
what end is up.
Or he's taking the deal because he knows
eventually Kavanaugh's gonna get him to crack.
I'm off to Lompoc.
- [Prison Door Buzzing]
- [Man On P.A., Indistinct]
[Antwon Chuckles]
I was beginning to think that you
didn't have love for me anymore.
I was getting a little jealous, you spending
so much time with another cop.
Oh. Yeah, Kavanaugh's
an intense cat, isn't he?
Shame about Lemansky, man.
But you do know that blondie
will end up in my backyard.
We don't know anything yet.
And if Lem does do time,
he's not gonna land here.
I've got a real big backyard.
And wherever he lands...
I decide his quality of life.
But that's why you're here.
You need something,
same as I do.
Otherwise you wouldn't have
sent that little black breezy to find me.
[Chuckles] Truth is, Antwon Mitchell's
the answer to all your prayers...
Lemansky's guardian angel.
See, we have a relationship,
you and me.
That relationship's had its ups and downs,
but it's still a relationship.
You make me drive out here for couples
counseling, or you got something to say?
The Niners have taken a serious
hit since my incarceration.
Halpern's been running 'em
under the radar...
until this black-brown
shitstorm plays itself out.
Look, that cranky black bitch
is afraid of his own goddamn shadow.
I've got some serious
old-school weight comin'in.
Kern Little.
I knew Kern's rap career
was in the dollar bin.
I didn't know he
was back in colors.
Eventually,
they all come home.
And Kern, he's eager to help me
with my cash flow problem.
I've got to hand out a lot of
turkeys at Thanksgivin'.
There's a warehouse
on Ridge Road...
place where they're storing what's left
of the seized assets.
You want me to rip off
a P.D. Warehouse?
Of course not. Kern's already
put together a team for that.
You just gotta come up with a plan
on how and when to get my guys in.
Walk Kern and his second,
Moses, through it.
That's more than an escort.
That's a hooker and a hand job.
Hey, that's the price for my guarantee
that Lemansky stays alive.
- Stand back. Nothing to see here.
- [Siren Wailing]
Ah, Jesus, his dick's gone.
Somebody find it.
[Julien]
Detectives, another glory hole.
- Jogger called it in. No I.D.
- Gunshot?
- Shit.
- [Julien] No.
There's a rattrap in one of the stalls.
I was real careful not to disturb the crime scene.
Good thinking. You wanna get that on ice.
Send it with him to the hospital.
[Man] Not gonna matter if we don't
get him stabilized. We need to move.
Let's get a canvass going.
The same M.O. As that attack
a couple of weeks ago.
Suspect was male,
Caucasian, 30s.
Well, let's not rule
anyone out yet.
In a world of men, the thought's
even crossed my mind.
Serrated teeth,
interlocking, no less.
This is a lot more gothic than
the last glory hole attack.
- Did you, uh, talk to the hospital?
- The victim's still unconscious.
He sustained a head injury when he passed out.
He's in pretty rough shape.
So we have no way
of knowing if and when...
- he'll be able to communicate.
- Canvass turn up anything?
- Nothing so far.
- So we got dick. Which is more
than I can say for the victim.
[Claudette]
We need to get the word out.
Bookstores, bathhouses, bars,
anywhere this sort of activity goes on.
Uh, we need to reinterview the victim
in the first glory hole attack.
- What was his name?
- He gave us everything that he had.
- He never talked to a detective.
- It's Alarico Trujillo.
- I'll write his address down.
- This Trujillo guy, he's married, kids.
I told him I'd keep his name out of it
if he cooperated. He held up his end.
This has escalated way beyond a twisted prank.
He's our only conscious witness.
- We'll be discreet. Thank you.
- Okay.
[Train Whistle Blows]
Is this thing
even remotely safe?
We make sure it is
'cause we got no choice.
- Antwon's the devil we know.
- Well, what if it's the other devil?
Kavanaugh laying a trap?
He's been cuttin' deals with Antwon. Maybe
this is his last stab before Lem seals us off.
[Ronnie] This place is wide open. We could
spot a surveillance unit a mile away.
If Kavanaugh was plannin'a sting,
this wouldn't be the place.
- He knows we would think that.
- [Mackey] We sniff out every inch of this thing.
Triple-check every last detail.
We get one bad whiff, we bail.
- ##[Rap On Car Stereo]
- Hey, why don't you crank it up?
Might still be some cops in
Long Beach who can't hear it.
Why don't you relax, teeth?
I was hoping I'd never
see you in purple again.
I never took it off.
You know how that goes.
Yeah, I do.
- This my boy Moses, man.
- Check 'em both.
Looking for this?
No. We've had a little
bug problem lately.
What you think,
we work for the white law?
[Mackey]
White law, black power, it's all the same shit.
Just wanna make sure
our visit stays anonymous.
- They're clean.
- No shit, Captain Cracker.
That's clever. Can't understand why that
rap career didn't take off.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Easy, easy, easy.
Now what's
your goddamn problem?
Times change, man.
I don't trust you or your ghost squad.
Well, the lack of love
is mutual.
Yeah, I see that.
You and Antwon.
- Nothin' like karma.
- Hey, the favor I have to do!
- Taking mouth shit from "M.C. Has-Been" I don't!
- Come on, come on, fellas.
Now let's just put this history on hold
and get this shit done. Okay?
- Let's go over it.
- Let's.
Okay. There's one guard, spends most
of his shift at the gatehouse here.
Guy of ours says the warehouse
is wall-to-wall cameras.
They feed into a bank of monitors back
at the gate. The seizure locker's here.
Can't miss it, right past a Hummer.
There's antiques, TV's and a safe. A big one.
[Shane] Mitchell was right.
We checked the inventory.
- There's over 500 grand in watches and jewelry.
- Yeah, and that's all we go for.
No one drives out of there
with a Hummer or a flat screen.
- [Cell Phone Rings]
- Yeah.
- Where are you?
- [Mackey] Why?
- We need to talk.
- [Beeps]
Kavanaugh's covering his bets in case
the criminal case against you doesn't make.
- [Toilet Flushes]
- What do you mean "in case"?
Surprised this clown hasn't
gotten the hook already.
By acknowledging you failed to clear
the room when Terry was shot...
Kavanaugh's trying to characterize
your earlier statements...
as false and misleading.
That's bullshit.
I've told the truth since day one.
Nothing I've said has changed
because the facts haven't.
Well, then he's doing a good job
of twisting your words.
It's not inconceivable that he could
cost you your retirement.
- Where'd you hear that?
- Your case was referred to the police
committee for review.
You let him try
to take my pension.
- P.B.A. Reps will have his head on a pike.
- I wouldn't be so sure.
You know, Kavanaugh could get this
as a face-saving way to end his investigation.
Never mind prying a cop with a sketchy jacket
off the taxpayers' tit.
Anyway, we said we'd share.
Thought you'd want the heads up.
- Thanks.
- Wait a minute.
Is Kavanaugh making any noise
around here about me?
All's been quiet
as relates to you.
- Undermining him is a priority.
- For both of us.
- [Speaking Spanish]
- [Clucking]
[Knocking]
We'd like to speak
to Alarico Trujillo.
About a car accident he
witnessed a couple weeks back.
[Speaking Spanish]
Uh, we had a few more questions
about that accident.
- I told you people everything.
- You didn't tell me about no car accident.
- I got nothing more to say.
- There's been another driver
that's been seriously injured.
- It's important you come with us.
- Someplace private.
Look, man...
just-just leave me
alone, okay?
We can do this another way
if we have to.
[Men Chattering]
Pretty soon this is gonna be a lonely room
filled with empty lockers, huh?
You and me are the only ones on the way out.
I just cut a deal with the D.A.
It's sittin' on his desk,
waitin' for his signature.
He'll be out on parole
before the blood rushes back to your face.
You don't mind if I check the facts
before I pack my bags, do you?
[Curtis]
I don't give a shit what you do.
Yeah. Thanks.
The chief's office hasn't even
seen Lemansky's deal yet.
His mouthpiece's feeding him a Happy Meal
to keep his spirits up.
Speakin'of Happy Meals,
did Vic bite on that intel...
about me, uh,
goin' after his pension?
- What, you didn't see the steam
comin' off his bald head?
- Beautiful, man. [Laughs]
And I so want there
to be trust between you two.
[Knocking]
- We need to use your office.
- [Kavanaugh] Of course.
- Anything I can do for you?
- No. It's a police matter.
Mi casa es su casa.
Excuse me.
Gave us all a scare,
that spill you took.
[Sighs]
Well, if you got one of these,
there's plenty of bounce to the ounce.
Let me get to the point. I've been made
aware you that have a serious medical condition...
one that could compromise your
ability to perform your duties.
You needed to disclose
a disease like lupus.
- You didn't.
- Because it was a personal matter.
Suppose you had
taken that header out in the field?
- You could've put other officers at risk.
- But it didn't happen.
And I'm not here because
of how I knock down doors.
I'm ordering you to see a city physician
for a full medical review.
Until then, you're
assigned to desk duty.
Then let's get it done A.S.A.P.
I've got plenty of cases to clear.
I'm responsible for the health and welfare
of everyone working here.
Then maybe you ought to do something
about the epidemic bullshit in this place.
Claudette, don't let
your frustration-
Don't interrupt. This man Kavanaugh that
you've just given the place over to-
I understand he's got
an investigation to run...
- but have you any idea
what he's doing to morale?
- She's got a point there.
I.A.D. Is arrogant and intrusive.
It's the nature of the beast.
But this man takes intimidation
to a whole other level.
He's got every officer
in this place spooked.
They spend more time
looking over their shoulders...
- than they do doing their jobs.
- It's a fair assessment.
Our last captain
had unpopular policies.
So you stuck us with an interim jellyfish
that won't rock the boat.
Then you cut resources that we need to do
the job. Talk about putting people at risk.
Crime stats are down
since I took over.
Look, if you aren't out
to lunch, passing the buck...
or leaving every day at 4:00, you'd know
that our citizens aren't reporting half...
of what's going on out there because they
know that we can't or won't do anything.
If you want me to go pee in a cup,
I'll be happy to fill it...
but I'm not your problem.
[Door Slams]
Pretty loopy.
Maybe that's why they call it lupus.
I've been here too long as it is.
My wife's gonna get suspicious.
You have a perfectly plausible cover story.
If you'd like me to call and explain-
- No, please.
- [Claudette] Dutch.
I just want to go home.
Give me a second.
Sit down.
- [Dutch] What'd the assistant chief want?
- I'm trying to comprehend...
why you felt the need to inform
the department that I have lupus.
What? L- I did
nothing of the kind.
- The chief's office is certainly up to speed.
- Well, not from me.
- You're the only one who knew.
- Obviously not.
- Because of you, I'm riding a desk.
- Okay, Claudette.
You're not hearing me. L- I have not
spoken to anyone about this.
You went to the D.A.'s office before to make
a separate peace behind my back.
- Remember?
- Oh, come on.
- You don't believe me?
- If you didn't tell them directly...
then somebody you told did.
Maybe that little Latina
wet dream you've been pushing up against.
You gave her a little gossip so you could
show how plugged in you are.
Hold on. You've crossed the line
into wholesale character assassination.
Career assassination
is a lot worse.
[Door Slams]
This is good.
This helps a lot.
I'll have an officer
give you a ride home.
I'll take a bus. I don't wanna be getting
out of a police car in my neighborhood.
- [Man] Captain?
- [Billings] What can I do for you?
Art Gadwah, Los Angeles
Gay Men's Initiative.
I'd like to talk to whoever's in charge about
recent attacks on members of our community.
Julien, come talk to this guy about the rattrap
glory hole business, will ya?
This is Officer Lowe.
He's been with this since the beginning.
Yeah, um, we've been
interviewing witnesses.
In the meantime, we're asking anyone
with any information to contact us.
So, basically, you're waiting
for this sadist to turn himself in.
That would be
a wrong perception.
Well, your captain couldn't wait
to shuffle me off onto you.
- It's clear you'd rather be
anywhere than talking to me.
- Here you go.
Instead of playing
the blame game...
why don't you help us get the word out
and distribute these?
I'm sure you people know where
the glory holes are better than we do.
Are you aware there are at least a half a dozen
attacks we know of haven't even been reported?
Well, maybe those people knew
what they were doing was wrong.
Adults engaging
in consensual sex?
In public,
which is a crime.
Thank you for coming down
and registering your concern.
I need your name
and badge number.
You need to keep
your hands off me.
You and your buddies in blue
can hate all you want to.
We're here.
You need to get used to it.
[Police Chatter On Radio]
Did a five-mile sweep. No R.F.
Or infrared readout anywhere.
Nobody's transmitting
any voice or video.
We've been up and down
the dial. No coded chatter.
[Grunts]
- Oh, Christ!
- Don't move. You don't fight, you don't die.
- No fightin', man. Whatever you want.
- Shut up.
- Whatever you want.
- Walk.
Man, come on.
Don't.
- Jesus!
- Open up. That one and that one.
- Hold his gun.
- [Door Opens]
[Door Closes]
You get the safe.
I'll get the jewels.
Come on.
[Guard Coughing]
- Please, I got a family. Just let me go, okay?
- [Kern] Shut that bitch up.
- I won't say anything.
- Shut up.
Jesus.
Don't forget the tools.
Jesus Christ!
What the hell are you doing?
Just finishing the job.
Antwon's orders. Kern had to go.
Holy shit. Turn around against
the fence right nowl Right nowl
- [Ronnie] He's gone.
- [Shane] What about Kern?
- Shit! This was not part of the deal!
- Sure, it was.
- Part Antwon didn't tell you about.
- Holy shit.
It's done.
- [Grunts]
- Kill me, you lose favor with Antwon.
And your boy end up facedown in
a pool ofblood and blow juice.
Hey. Hey.
[Mackey]
Get upl
Get the safe and get out.
- [Shane] You heard him. Let's go.
- Get out!
Go!
- [Door Closes]
- What the hell do we do here?
Goddamn it.
- Give me a hand.
- Shit.
- [Grunts] I don't get it.
- [Mackey] Kern was no backseat banger.
Antwon had him taken out
before Kern took over.
[Ronnie] Why not just whack him
when he's in the hood?
[Mackey] Word got out that
Antwon took out Kern...
street would
take it as a weakness.
Gang without a leader,
brothers jump to other sets.
Kern goes down in the line of duty,
gets the Niners street cred.
Moses takes over, pushes
Antwon's agenda.
Goddamn it.
Goddamn it, man.
Let's go.
[Kern Groans]
You gotta be shittin' me.
- These brothers can take a bullet.
- Oh, God. What now?
Vic, get me help.
Get me help.
- Please.
- Let's go.
- Vic, come on, man. We can't-
- 911 will take 20 minutes to get here.
He's gonna be dead in 10.
We'll wait.
Then we leave, call it in.
- You sure about this?
- [Mackey] Kern's dead.
We can still save Lem.
Jesus.
No. No.
[Kern Whimpering]
[Kern]
Mackey. Mackey, please.
Mackey, please.
- [Dumpster Bangs]
- Police.
We're cutting the lock. On my command,
you stand, hands on your head.
- [Lock Clangs]
- Sorry I spaced on the combination.
There's a glory hole over there
and a couple of rattraps.
Yeah, the owner said he put 'em out.
Tough to prove whose whose.
Stand slowly.
Hands on your head.
We helped you catch him.
I expect you to hold up your end.
What do you suppose would happen
if someone snapped this on someone's dick?
You're sick.
You know that?
I didn't make this up.
This one here- serrated teeth.
The guy who got caught in this
is gonna pee sitting down, ifhe survives.
Aren't you glad it wasn't you?
Be a hell of a secret you'd have to live with.
Something personal and embarrassing
that affects your ability to function.
Not something you'd want
a lot of people to know about.
Okay, you wanna do this,
you can talk to him.
I'll come back later.
So, Jarrod, what have you got
against gay folks?
That some sort of tactic?
You pretend to pick a fight
and then you do the whole tag team thing?
Just answer the question.
- He give you anything?
- Nope.
- We need to put this guy in a lineup.
- He's all yours.
Tina, we need to bring
Trujillo in again.
I'll tell him to meet you
down the block from his place.
- Keep up appearances.
- Got it.
- Alarico Trujillo on Lattimer Ave.?
- Yeah.
Unis just responded to a domestic
at his address that got ugly.
You should run with it since you're
dealing with him on the other thing.
- Okay. Come on.
- I got balls in the air on a big 211
that just got called in.
I'm gonna check in
on it personally.
We got here, he was standing
over her with a baseball bat.
We took it offhim, but not before
he got a few whacks in.
I got this.
What happened?
We got married, priest told her everything
I'd done before with men was in the past.
Tried to stop,
but she knew what was up.
You people started
coming around asking questions.
She knew why.
She started calling me a fag
in front of my kids, so...
- I beat the shit out ofher.
- [Siren Wailing]
- [Man Shouting, Indistinct]
- [Police Chatter On Radio]
[Shane]
What the hell is he doing here?
- [Mackey] Pretending to be a cop.
- [Billings] You call this in?
Yeah. We got a tip
the One-niners were hittin' this place.
We got stuck in the van on a stakeout,
couldn't make it back here in time.
- What's the damage?
- Looks like the guard took out one of'em...
before he got
his head blown off.
Detective Mackey,
do you know him?
It's Kern Little.
Old-school One-niner.
Went back to the street game
once his hip-hop career hit the skids.
Why don't you inventory what's missing,
and we'll start turning over One-niner rocks.
Familiar scenario, this.
[Chuckles]
How so?
Come on.
You don't see it?
A dead cop killed by the gun
of a dead bad guy.
You two,
innocent bystanders.
We were on the other side
of Farmington, asshole.
- Anybody see you?
- Wouldn't have been much
of a stakeout if they had.
You know what? You should
start eating again, man.
Malnourishment's startin'
to screw with your logic.
[Kavanaugh] Lemansky's going to prison.
You need to protect him.
You reach out
to Antwon Mitchell.
For some reason, he needs
his, uh, crew leader dead.
Bad blood, internal beef,
whatever.
So you kill him-
your end of the deal.
He keeps Lem alive-
his end of the deal.
How's that logic
sound to you?
Let me remind you
of a few things you seem to have forgotten.
I didn't kill Terry.
You've lost your leverage
with Lem.
And your ex-wife's pussy...
tastes like sweet butter.
What do you want?
- Sadie, you gonna let me in?
- I'm in the middle of something.
I just need to know if you, uh-
You seen this guy?
Yeah, he came through.
Are you okay?
- What do you care?
- Sadie, did he hurt you?
You're the only one
who ever hurts me, Jon.
That's not gonna
happen again.
I just- Can you just...
tell me what he did.
Just tell me what happened.
Just what did he do?
What'd he do?
Um, he made me come.
That's what he did.
[Chuckles]
- No, he didn't.
- Oh, yeah.
Twice.
Do you know who-
who this guy is,
Sadie?
Your friend...
who you sent
to check up on me.
Well, he did.
What is wrong with you?
Huh?
You need to go.
Move your arm
from the door, Jon.
Now.
Or I will call the police.
What's up?
- What are you doin' here?
- The chief's office just signed off on the deal.
Look, I report for processing
tomorrow morning.
It's okay, man.
It's over.
[Sighs]
Thank you, man.
[Curtis]
It's all right. It's okay.
- Yeah.
- [Ronnie] We got your back.
All right.
I know. I know. I know.
- You're gonna be taken care of. You understand?
- Right.
I had nothing
to do with this.
If you're asking if I think these perverts
deserve to be punished-
Look what they're
doin' to our country.
Yeah, seducing our kids, spreading Al DS.
You gave us your spiel.
A moment of your time.
- Where are we with this freak?
- He's guilty, just not prosecutable at the moment.
The problem is the evidence is circumstantial
and threadbare at best.
He matches the witness's
description.
There's no way the D.A.'s gonna indict
off a wife beater's say so.
Well, let's put him on the tour. Lose him
in the system for a couple days, buy some time.
With I.A.D. Bivouacked in my colon?
You out of your mind?
If you can't close him,
lose him.
Oh, uh, Claudette, chief's here.
He wants to see you.
Hey, I tried to keep it
copacetic with you and Phillips.
Detective Wyms, I got a preliminary report
back from the city physician.
- You are medically fit to resume your duties.
- I could have told you that.
- You'll be required to have quarterly checkups.
- Your nickel.
Understand you unloaded
with both barrels on my number two here.
Sometimes happens I see red.
Changes have to be made. For starters,
I've decided to appoint you captain.
What makes you think I want
that revolving door?
You know this place better
than anybody in the department.
Which is why you don't see me
jumping at the offer.
My predecessor made a mistake slapping
you down with that D.A. Nonsense.
But you and I can find a way
to work together, right?
For starters, I would need a guarantee
that I would run the Barn.
Not in theory.
In fact.
No one can do
the job with-
Sorry to interrupt, but I just confirmed
some very disturbing news.
Did you- Did you sign off
on a deal with Lemansky?
- I did.
- I thought we agreed, no deals.
The only way to get Mackey
is to leverage his guys.
- We're in the middle
of something here, Lieutenant.
- So am I.
And it just got derailed
because you guys backed down.
It's over, Jon.
Sending Lemansky to jail sends a message.
We all move on now.
And Mackey skates clean.
[Chuckling]
This guy-This guy is just pissing-
just pissing all over us...
- and we just smile and lick it up?
- [Phillips] That's enough.
Vic Mackey kills cops!
He- He deals drugs!
He beats suspects!
You know what
he did yesterday?
He-
He screwed my ex-wife...
with the sole purpose...
of making this investigation
seem like a personal vendetta.
He may have assassinated
a gang leader.
And that's just
all in one day.
I wonder what
he's gonna do today.
he's gonna do tomorrow.
This guyl
This guy is just pissingl
He's pissing all over us!
He's pissing on you!
What-
What does it taste like?
Chief, what does it taste like?
'Cause, you know what? It tastes like piss to mel
You have 48 hours to
tie up the loose ends.
And find someplace else
to do the paperwork.
Captain Wyms
needs her office.
[Door Opens, Slams Shut]
We'll sneak the whole cow
in to you, man.
Hey, Lem, I'm sorry.
I'm glad it's over though.
That's okay.
Thanks. Thank you.
Hey, you'll be a little thinner
the next time I see you.
[Chuckles]
Yeah.
Thanks. Hey, I gotta get some things in order.
I'll see you guys at the party.
- All right, man.
- Here you go.
- What's that?
- That's the paperwork for the 211
you called in last night.
E.M. T.'s found a ton of jewelry in the pocket
of the dead banger.
Shitheads shot an innocent guy
and walked away with almost nothing.
- Which means-
- The goddamn safe was empty?
So Antwon's not getting
his money.
- That's gonna screw the whole deal.
- Holy shit.
I gotta talk to Antwon.
These fags who choose a life of sin
and suffering get what they deserve...
but I'm the one in handcuffs.
- Hey.
- Stand up.
Does his family deserve to have their lives
ruined because of what you did to him?
- Men's room on Alvarado.
- Look, I've never seen that guy before.
But if he's bein' punished for his wickedness,
then it's God's will.
- You're his spokesman now?
- That's right there in the Book.
"You shall not lie with a male
as one lies with a female."
It's an abomination.
I mean, come on.
- Hey, hey!
- Leviticus 18:22.
- What are you doing? I don't have to talk to you.
- I know.
Hey, hey!
Where do you go to church?
Christ Bethany.
What is this?
So then you know thatJesus
lived a perfect life of truth...
and he was crucified for it.
What do you suppose happens to
someone who lies in his name?
Who passes judgment on other
people in his name?
Psalm 71, Verse 4.
- "Deliver me, O my God,
out of the hand of the wicked.
- Hey, stop!
Out of the hand of the
unrighteous and the cruel man."
- Stop!
- You wanted to look at a man down there.
You wanted to touch it. Thought about it
for a long time, maybe all your life.
You just never did it 'cause
you knew that it was wrong.
No, no, no!
[Yelps]
So you convinced yourself
that you were doing God's will...
gave yourself an excuse to find out
what another man's penis feels like.
No. I would never do something
so repulsive and disgusting.
You're no different
than the men you prey on.
- You're a homosexual.
- No, no, no.
Homosexual.
- No.
- You're just too weak and afraid to admit it.
That's a lie!
That is a lie.
I am a Christian,
and they are vermin.
I did it because
they are vermin.
Why would any man want
to touch another man down there?
I did it to punish them.
[Knocking]
What, no muffins?
You shouldn't have
taken that deal, Curtis.
You weren't supposed to get
the worst of this thing here.
That's all you did from the minute
you picked me up, is threaten me with jail.
That's all it was.
It was just a threat.
You threw me in County.
You arrested me.
I knew you'd make bail,
just not so soon.
It was just a strategy, man.
A wedge to get you to turn.
Cops always give it up
with the threat of jail.
Always. But not you.
Not Curtis Lemansky.
I can't believe
you're doing this.
You're gonna take
the hit for him?
- For them?
- Well, believe it.
Sorry I didn't, uh-
that we didn't
become friends sooner.
Maybe, uh, I could've pulled this in another
direction, if I just- if I just made a-
Any man would be lucky
to have you in his corner.
Good luck, Curtis.
Hey. Hey.
It's over.
I know.
Take care of yourself,
all right?
Things went south.
Dirty South?
Alabama South?
Yeah, well, if I had all the information going in,
we wouldn't be sitting here.
But here we are right now...
big blue and his
little black puppet.
What the hell are you
talking about?
Kavanaugh dimed me, man.
Told me you been braggin' about how
you were playin' me against him...
how you manipulated me into protecting
Lemansky to shit all over his leverage.
That's bullshit.
He's jerkin' us off.
What do you care?
He can't get to you in here.
No, but he can touch
everyone around me.
That crazy-ass nigga, he initiated a full-scale
D.O.C. Investigation of this place.
The heat is on. And soon I won't be feelin'
all the comforts of home.
Look, I'll figure out
a way to get you your cash.
I'll look into
this D.O.C. Thing.
You've done enough.
- The deal and this conversation are over.
- Jesus Christ.
I took care of that
little thing for you.
Now you're gonna tell me that
doesn't buy Lem some time?
That buys you one more dead cop.
I got Niners in every pen in the state.
So wherever he touches down,
it will happen.
And you can set your watch
to that inevitability.
One of your crew so much
as hard looks my guy...
my reach will
get you shivved.
You got reach like that? So why you sittin'
down here talkin' to me, gray boy, huh?
Hey! Hey! That's enough!
That's enough!
[Antwon]
It's okay. It's all right.
That's just Detective Mackey's
way of saying good-bye.
- [Door Buzzing]
- [Man On P.A., Indistinct]
I cut you a break for that
meltdown in front of Phillips...
on account of your medical
problems and so forth.
- Then I find out it's part of
your campaign to steal my job?
- I didn't go after this.
Why did you do me like this?
I thought you and me were good.
We are good,
and I didn't "do" you.
Letting Kavanaugh loose in this place,
they set you up to fail. It's not your fault.
I didn't fail.
Is that what
people are sayin'?
I'll need you to help me
pick up the pieces.
I'm supposed to stick around after getting
shanked in the back like this?
No. I got some pride,
you know.
Why don't you
give it a few days?
When you're ready to talk,
my door is open.
- ##[Pop On Stereo]
- [Chattering]
[Shane]
You better get a good look.
Hey. The "entertainment"
just showed up.
I figured it was
time for me to leave.
Right. Uh, this is not
the safest hood.
I'll get you to your car.
Oh, my.
I see what you mean.
I'm taking him to the courthouse
9:00 tomorrow morning.
Officially surrender.
- You doing okay?
- Yeah.
We did the right thing, Vic.
Thank you for helpin' him.
You're a good friend.
He's lucky to have you.
[Sirens Wailing In Distance]
Hey, what's going on?
Listen, I gotta tell you
something... about Lem.
What?
I hear we got a confession
out ofTrapperJohn.
He and Julien
reasoned together.
Congratulations
on your promotion.
Thanks. I didn't know
it was public.
I wanted you to hear
that from me.
Ah, you know how things
spread around here-
like herpes
at a swingers party.
While you were stretched out on the floor over
there, paramedics found prednisone in your purse.
They called your doctor to find out
what you were being treated for.
Billings overheard
and reported to Phillips.
He just told me.
He thought lupus was
an emotional disorder.
I'm sorry.
Well, you can't un-ring that bell.
You don't trust me.
- I made a mistake.
- You made a choice- to think the worst about me.
I'll need your support.
I've got my work cut out for me.
You'll do fine.
Whoever sits up there has to
have an active mistrust...
of everyone and everything
in this place.
I can't imagine anyone
better suited to the job.
[Curtis Chuckling]
Who-Who were they?
Look, you guys, I hate to step
on the pussy and laughs...
but we gotta talk
about a change of plans.
- What change?
- You're not goin' to prison.
- What are you talkin' about?
- Look, we made a deal with Antwon
to get you safe passage inside.
It went bad.
The thing at the warehouse?
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Kavanaugh's launched a Department
of Corrections investigation of Lompoc.
- He's gonna make Antwon's life
hell, and Antwon's blamin' me.
- [Shane] Oh, goddamn it.
- But I won't end up in Lompoc.
- Word gets out Antwon's got a beef...
any prison, any protective custody-
best-case scenario, you bust enough heads...
- to stay alive.
- Which means I can kiss early release good-bye.
Worst-case scenario, you're
gonna kiss everything good-bye.
- What am I supposed to do?
- Lay low until I figure out a way...
- to get Antwon back.
- You're puttin' him on the run?
- I can't run anymore.
- We're out of options.
- I do not wanna do this.
- Do we have a plan?
- I'm working on one.
- Where's he gonna go?
I don't know!
Now, you're gonna hide...
while I find
Gilroy's contacts.
Mexico?
No. No.
Lem, it's only temporary.
What about my deal?
If I run, they're gonna throw it out.
- They'll have all new charges.
- It's better than the alternative!
Lem, right now this
is about keeping you alive.
[Curtis Panting]
Lem, I promise you.
I promise you, man. I promise you,
we're gonna make this work.
[Curtis Groans, Sniffles]
[Groans]
[Chattering]
- ##[Man Singing Rock]
- [Indistinct]
[Danny]
Hurry up.
Oh, God, Julien. Shit.
[Groans]
Goddamn it.
Oh, the baby's coming. Oh.
[Knocking]
Can I talk to you
for a second?
Just-
Just one second, okay?
##[Continues]
##[Ends]
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Continues]
##[Ends]