Previously on The Shield.
- I have an attorney for you.
- I'm Becca Doyle.
[Rebecca] If everything hinges on her,
I'd be a fool to give up that hammer.
Just like you were foolish
for letting me know...
how important she is
to making your case.
- You lookin' for more business?
- Right now I'd like to go home
and wash this place off.
Has anyone from the department
come around askin' any questions?
Someone has been asking questions.
He said he was the parent of an autistic child.
- That him?
- Yeah.
Pitarrio, where's your stash?
About six months ago, we found...
this kilo of pure heroin
in the glove compartment of your car...
but you never
logged it into Evidence.
Lem got picked up by I.A.D.
Got him wearin' a wire.
I'm goin' after Mackey and his team.
And I'm gonna be right here
to make sure you don't blow it.
We got a C.I. Next to him,
and when he jumps dirty, we'll know.
- Here.
- It's okay. I'm- I'm on the clock.
- I thought you were Vic's C.I.
- Whoever's got the money.
[Curtis]
Check. One, two. Check. One, two.
Good.
That's good.
Hey. I need admissions from Mackey and
the others on crimes they committed, all right?
Hey, man.
Questions make cops suspicious.
You walk out every time he opens his mouth
to say more than "good morning"I
- You think I haven't noticed this?
- I'm just doin'my job.
All right, Vic and I
aren't attached at the hip.
Well, then get attachedl
'Cause draggin'this out...
tryin'to... have it both ways-
You're torturing yourself.
You made a choice.
[Kavanaugh]
It was the right one.
And now you gotta
start livin' with it.
Hold on a second, okay?
Wait a second.
L-l- I know it's your birthday.
You mentioned that you're a fly-fisher
on one of the tapes.
Thanks.
We're gonna be workin' together for a while.
I just thought, you know-
I know this is tough.
But we're both...
gonna make our way
through all of this.
All right?
[Scoffs]
Would've pegged you
for a corner office.
First time a police officer
stepped foot in here.
- I've got a case that'll interest you.
- My schedule's full.
- I've been finding my own cases since I was 30.
- Not like this one.
Five minutes.
Everything I'm about to say
falls under attorney-client privilege.
Yeah, but it doesn't
obligate me to take your case.
I.A.D.'s launched an investigation
into one of the guys on my Strike Team.
I don't represent cops...
especially corrupt ones.
We're good cops.
This is about the system
turning its back on four of its own.
- You'd be better off going somewhere else.
- You shuffle gangbangers...
in and out of jail all day.
This is a chance for you
to take a shot at the big boys.
What do they have on him?
They claim they found a brick
of tar in his glove compartment.
- It's bullshit.
- What else?
The only thing I know
is they're goin' after my whole team.
Guy named Kavanaugh is in charge.
I'd dig into it myself, but it would
raise too many red flags.
Now there's the first
real truth I've heard.
You wanna keep your knowledge
of the investigation secret...
and no one would suspect
I'm working for you.
So we agree that you work
for me then.
I've got an old boyfriend
in the City Attorney's office.
I'll ask a couple questions.
But that's it.
[Woman Sobblng]
I just came In, and he was laylng there.
You know, Fiji, Barbados-
all those tropical vacation places-
you're talkin' typhoons!
- Just lookin' out for ya.
- Look out for the tape.
Tape?
- Angle looks car-to-car.
- Bumper's got a dent Could be fresh.
So maybe there's an incident out on the road,
someone in the other car shoots...
victim veers offhere.
Oh, Christl
Get additional units down herel
- Tell Danny I said now!
- Right awayl
Umbilical cord.
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Ends]
Checked the goddamn AMBERAlert
requirements. We don't have enough to file.
Somebody cut that baby out
of the woman's stomach.
Then get me a witness, a description
of the other car, something.
If they wanted the child, why risk
pumping the mother with bullets?
Someone wanted it to look random.
Maybe the boyfriend.
- [Billings] What do we know about him?
- Works nights in a machine shop.
Hasn't been home since the murder.
I've got unis stationed at the house.
Vultures are gathering.
- I'll get rid of'em.
- Wait, wait. No, no, no.
Let's use 'em.
Somebody knows something.
- We just need to pull the right heartstrings.
- All right, good.
Uh, you keep working.
I'll do it.
Wilshire's not giving us any
bodies for the search team.
- Not if we can't prove the baby's alive.
- That's bullshit. Call again.
No, I'll call.
Who would do something like this?
- What'd the ex have to say?
- Absolutely nothing.
And I called a couple ADA's
I went to school with.
- Quiet on all fronts.
- Good.
Not good.
None of them offered to look into it for me.
Which means they know
something major's in motion.
What haven't you told me?
- David Aceveda's name come up with your friends?
- The city councilman?
He's assisting Kavanaugh
with his investigation.
Why?
Because he used to be
captain here. Had me, uh...
pushing the legal line
a couple times when it meant...
gettin'a killer off the street,
making him look good to the voters.
Overseeing the investigation means
he can steer it away from himself-
make me and my guys
play the heavies.
Starting to get
your blood runnin' yet?
I'm interested in the true story
of this heroin they caught Lemansky with.
- What does he say about it?
- Haven't been able to ask him.
I.A.D.'s got him all wired up,
listening to our every word.
Well, they wouldn't make that move unless
they had a witness or corroborating evidence.
- I'll find out what I can.
- Good.
Me too.
[Door Buzzes]
So the kid's about, uh...
well, here, right?
The knife goes in, goes straight down-
gotta be careful about the depth.
I'd say it's intuitive.
You wouldn't need medical training at all.
So I tell the newshounds we're not looking for
Einstein, just a garden-variety psychopath...
- possibly a woman?
- [Dutch] Usually it's a woman...
who's recently lost a baby,
or who's been claiming to be pregnant.
- I'm never gonna sleep until I have this kid.
- I'm here.
You're not gonna get
any sleep then either. Thanks.
911 received a call
at 5:17 this morning...
from a pay phone
one block from the scene.
- They hung up.
- All right, that could be our line to the baby.
- So how we gonna find 'em?
- You've got to convince them to come to us.
- Need another cup?
- Two should do it.
- [Door Opens]
- Hey, we on that missing baby yet?
[Mouthing Words]
[Mackey]
No, Dutch and Claudette are handlin'it.
[Shane] Captain wants us
available to round up all the, uh...
other miscellaneous sickos.
Listen, man. I'll be back
in a few. I gotta take a dump.
Smells like you already did.
All right, we got five minutes to hear
what's going on with Kavanaugh.
- Every detail.
- He suspects I'm protecting you.
All right?
I've been helpful, but not too helpful.
- Nothing he can check out.
- Any chance he's got a witness?
- Someone who saw you take that tar?
- Shit. Pitarrio.
- Or Emolia. I mean, she was in the house too.
- No, no.
L- I got a six-month
relationship with her. She's solid.
Pitarrio's the one
with an ax to grind.
If they got Pitarrio, man,
I'm screwed.
- We don't know that yet, but we're gonna find out.
- He puts that heroin in my car...
makes I.A.D.'s case, what then?
You're a first-time offender,
you'd do what?
Five years max, probably less?
- Shanel
- Look, I'm just- I'm just sayin'.
Worst-case scenario-you refuse to wear
the wire, you let Kavanaugh arrest you.
We'll work behind the scenes
to undermine him...
and you'll seal us off
from this, right?
- Look, the shit you've done,
and I'm the one going to jail?
- Nobody's going away.
- Hasn't been a jam yet
we haven't slipped out of.
- There hasn't been a witness...
or an I.A.D. Cop wiring one of us.
Nobody jumped ship when Antwon
had your balls in a sling.
And I was willing to put a bullet into Antwon
to keep it off the rest of you, remember?
We got you out of that before
you had to go through with it.
Which is exactly what we're gonna
do for Lem. But if we can't...
you're gonna look out for us, right?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Okay.
We're gonna get you clear of this.
Ronnie and I'll track down Pitarrio,
and we'll squeeze his balls.
- I hate this.
- Don't worry. We got you.
Let's get the wire back on.
What kinda person cuts a baby
out of its mother's stomach?
The kind that
should've been an abortion.
- There's the man. Gimme a sec?
- For what?
Aceveda's been updating me
on a few things.
Be right back.
Councilmanl
A moment of your time.
What is it?
## [Pop Blaring]
Some asshole dumped a few couches over
on Benton, I got a La-Z-Boy over on Scott.
Bums find that out, it's a Motel 6.
You screeched up here to talk
to me about trash pickups?
[Police Radio]
6- Paul-11, 6-Paul-11. This is Dispatch.
Billings is too squirrelly to ask
the city for an extra dime.
- Someone's gotta do it.
- [Curtis] Hey, we got a 187!
Anyway, Farmington's garbage
is your area.
That's a little below my pay grade.
Call someone in Waste Removal.
Okay. But I'd hate to see
your entire district become a fire hazard.
- Get what you need?
- Yeah. He was very helpful.
- The car was headed south down there.
- Hank Preminger.
Green Explorer came around the corner,
started blasting at him as he exited the diner.
- [Shane] Nice piece.
- Let this be a cautionary tale.
- You find our heroin dealer?
- Pitarrio cleared out of his house. He's a ghost.
Only sign oflife was a couple
of squatter crackheads.
Hey. Telephone worker
got a bird's-eye from the pole.
- He get a plate for the S.U.V.?
- No, but he gave unis a partial plate on a witness...
who had a better view-white guy,
jumped in his ride after the shooting...
- took off.
- All right.
You guys work your angle.
Lem and I'll figure out who's got a problem...
- with the Hair Club for Men.
- [Curtis] All right, man.
[Billings] That baby is still out there.
This disgusting crime...
occurred at approximately
5:15 a.m. This morning.
- So we beg you...
- [Beeping]
While the baby can still be saved...
please call if you have any information
about the traffic altercation...
that led to the heinous murder
of Isabelle Arrington.
We need you to call our tip line.
- Time is of the essence.
- I pulled the records of every person...
who worked with Isabelle Arrington.
So far just petty stuff.
Here's our grieving boyfriend.
Your neighbor told us Isabelle
was screwing somebody else.
- That's bullshit.
- Baby probably wasn't even yours.
Don't you say that,
you goddamn liar!
If the baby's alive, tell us.
Oh, God.
- Please let him be alive.
- [Claudette] It's a boy?
You notice that when you
cut him out of Isabelle's stomach?
We did one of those scans.
[Laughs]
We saw his stuff.
You gotta believe me.
Okay. Uh-We'll get somebody
to give you a ride home.
Stay by the phone.
I may have more questions.
You accuse me of slicin'my baby
outta my girl's stomach...
and now you want me
to go home and wait on you?
- We're sorry for your loss.
- I don't want your damn apologiesl
I want you to find out
who did this to her...
and where my baby is!
Victim did a stint in Lompoc eight years ago.
Been clean ever since.
No family, but coworkers at the pet store
said he's got no enemies.
These matches to the partial
plate on the witness?
I've ruled out 50 of'em.
Got about a half dozen possibles here.
Pitarrio hasn't been
arrested in six months.
That's the longest he's gone
since he turned 18.
He's off the grid.
If the feds picked him up and he
made a deal to give up Lem...
that arrest
wouldn't show up on his record.
Check this out. Leon Frankel- lives
in the same building as our victim.
Turns out they both got
their G.E.D.'s in Lompoc.
Well, let's find out
why Hank's study buddy...
didn't stick around
to talk to the police.
[Shane] We lookin'at this guy
as a coward or suspect?
Whichever jacket fits.
Hold on. Hold on.
- Is that Leon Frankel?
- That's me.
We were just on our way out
looking for him. What did he do?
We were canvassing on that baby. He threw
a bottle at the car, cracked the windshield.
- Then he asked if he could smell my sweet spot.
- Even Shane stopped usin' that.
Pretty stupid way
to get yourself arrested, Leon.
[Leon]
I had a bad day.
That bad day include seeing your
pal Hank Preminger shot dead?
A friend of mine was in trouble,
I'd do everything I could to help him out.
Sit down.
I was scared, I heard shots, I ran.
Hey, look.
Maybe if I sit here for a while...
something will come to me.
You're walkin' down the street
with your enemy-free friend, Hank.
Shots go off, he's dead. But you know
those bullets were meant for you.
Now you're not safe.
You're too damn cheap
to spend 20 bucks on a fleabag motel.
You get yourself arrested, 'cause
it's safer in here than it is out there.
- Only we're not your goddamn bodyguards.
- [Mackey] Who did it?
L- I don't know.
Get out.
- What?
- Get out!
Get the- Get out!
No.
W-Wait a second.
I remember a green S.U.V.
Great!
Think of anything else, give us a call.
I'm releasing Leon on his own
recognizance.
- Wait a minute. He's supposed to post bail.
- I'm overriding bail.
- Buzz him!
- Jesus, you're gonna get me killed out there.
- That's a chance I'm willing to take.
- Okay, okay. Come on. Please.
Couple days ago, I had a client
fell behind on his payment.
Awesome pool player.
Now, I knew this guy, right?
He did me a solid back in the day.
We used to hang out at Gary's Tavern...
- little place on Sunset-
- Cut to the part where someone wants to kill you.
My boss, Gus, wanted me to take
a crowbar to his right arm.
If I did that,
his break would never be the same.
So I gave him an extra 24 hours.
Most loan sharks don't take too
kindly to independent thinking.
Yeah, Gus never would've known.
But this ungrateful prick...
disappears
with the 40 large he owes.
Now Gus thinks we split the money,
and he wants me dead.
And your friend Hank
takes the hit meant for you.
- Aw, I feel like shit about that.
- Who shot at you?
I'll bet ya anything it was that
little ass-suck works for Gus.
He's always tryin'
to hone in on my business.
- What's his name?
- I don't know.
I just call him ass-suck.
[Knocking]
Excuse me while I get a Kleenex
for the rest of this sob story.
It's a protection game. See, I got
all these young guys comin'up behind me.
It's like no one
wants Leon to get ahead.
- Jesus, what took so long?
- I had to track Pitarrio through I.N.S.
Miguelez Construction registered...
his Social Security number
with payroll two months ago.
- Scumbag got a real job?
- He's workin' at a site over on Hillhurst.
If Pitarrio's breaking a sweat,
we know he's in with the feds.
- Let me wrap this up.
- Okay.
Hey.
You're early.
So am I.
[Chuckles]
- How's Andy?
- He's good actually.
He's inside.
Um, I was wondering.
How old was Andy when he was diagnosed?
Around three.
There's an Andy at this school,
but he's not your son.
What's going on? When were you
planning on telling me you're a cop?
- Who told you that?
- Nobody.
I was married to one.
I see them every day in the E.R.
You all walk the same.
[Chuckles]
Yeah, we do.
I'm a lieutenant- I.A.D.
You'd make a good detective, Corrine.
I don't know what you want or why
you've been lying to me, but stay away.
Ms. Mackey, I need you to know that your
husband and his team are under investigation.
So what?
I was his wife, not his partner.
I don't know what
your involvement is yet...
but you and I are gonna do
a lot more talking.
And you mention anything to him
about me or this investigation...
and it's obstruction of justice.
So, I find out that you told him...
that he learned anything
about this case, it's on you...
and that's prison.
We'll talk later.
I wouldn't be here if it wasn't
a baby, just so you know.
It's very generous of you to come in.
Could you tell us what you saw?
That pregnant lady decided she
had to turn all of a sudden...
almost drove into that other car.
Other car-
think it was white-
goes honking,
gets crazy, starts shootin'.
911 put me on hold-
5:30 in the morning-so I hung up.
You said you saw something on a car?
Something that could help?
The white car had one of those
decals on the back window.
- What did the decal say?
- "Jevontrey."
I have a nephew named Devontrey,
so I remembered the decal.
It was one of those RI P ones.
- [Curtis]... stomach?
- [Mackey] Kind that should've been an abortion.
- There's the man. Gimme a sec?
- For what?
Aceveda's been updating me
on a few things.
Be right back.
Councilman, a moment of your time.
- [Aceveda] What is it?
- ##[Radio: Music]
- [Knocking]
- [Turns Recorder Off] Come in.
You said you have an update?
Lemansky's birthday's today.
His pals, they either don't know
or just don't care.
That's the update?
My best friend forgot my
birthday, I'd be pissed.
This could be a way in.
[Scoffing Laugh]
- Anything interesting happen with you today?
- Like what?
Like... visitors?
- Mackey?
- He came by the office.
- What about?
- Some bullshit sanitation complaint.
I think he just wants to shove it in my face
that he's de facto running the Barn.
You didn't call him- don't have regular
sit-down meetings with him or anything?
Just trying to figure out which uniform
you're wearing, Councilman.
Well, it sure as hell isn't Mackey's.
Sorry for getting you down here.
Next time I have a birthday alert,
I'll just call you on the phone.
- [Knocking]
- You're not safe here anymore.
- I'm taking you. We gotta go. Gotta move.
- Why? What happened?
Got a couple possible leaks. Get your stuff.
Whatever Sebastio needs, okay?
- You said Vic wouldn't find out.
- I'm not saying that he has.
Either way, he calls, you don't answer.
He comes by, you're not gonna even be here.
The volume on this thing
just got turned way up.
Let's go.
- Pitarrio. Where is he?
- Well, as far as I know...
he's right over there.
- [Mackey] Pitarriol
- Sí.
Yes. I am Pitarrio.
- Nice try, dickwad. We know the guy.
- [Grunting]
Where is he?
- Gimme your papers.
- Let's see 'em!
Let's see it.
All right, you got a job off this.
- What'd Pitarrio get for his papers?
- He- He got dead.
- Dead?
- What? You sure he's not laying low...
takin' a cut off
your hard-earned money, huh?
No. Three months ago...
we were down in El Salvador
doing a heroin deal.
And La Sombra Negra, he got to him.
And sliced his neck in half.
[Shane]
Look, you gotta consider Emolia.
They might have some other kind
of corroborating evidence against Lem.
Man, she's got a messed up kid.
She's got no job.
Look, I.A.D. Offers her a deal,
she could've jumped at it.
I spent time with this girl and the boy.
- She's not gonna turn on me.
- Well, just call her then.
Check in.
Emolia!
Sir?
Have you seen the woman who lives here?
- ¿Qué?
- Niño. Mujer.
Se fue.
Hace como dos horas.
Se metió en un carro
con un negro.
Gracias.
Thanks. I've got every decal place
in town checking special orders.
Meantime, I need an extra pair of eyes.
Three years of death in L.A. County.
Holler if you see a Jevontrey.
[Ringing]
- Wagenbach.
- Dutch, it's Corrine.
- You there?
- Hey.
- What's, uh-
- I need to ask you some questions.
Oh, l- I ca- I can't right now.
Please.
I'm pulling up now. It's important.
Sorry.
I didn't know who else to call.
I can't stay long.
What's going on?
Promise this stays between us, okay?
Promise that you're gonna give me straight
answers no matter what you think of Vic.
- Of course. What is it?
- Some I.A.D. Guy's been coming
to the kids' school...
trying to get me to say
things about him.
I.A.D.'s into Vic?
I wonder what they got on him?
- I mean, probably, take your pick.
- Listen, I don't know.
But he threatened to send me to jail
if I said anything or if I don't cooperate.
I need to know
if he's bullshitting me.
I mean, can he send me to jail?
A lot of times, the person who goes down
didn't have anything to do with the original crime.
They found out about it
afterwards, lied, covered it up.
Well, what about spousal privilege?
They can't force you to talk,
but if they can prove...
you knew about any of Vic's actions,
makes you a coconspirator.
What's gonna happen to your kids
if something happens to you? You see?
You're their best leverage
against him.
- But I don't know anything.
- Well, then take away their leverage.
Be completely up front and honest.
L-l-I'm sorry.
I've really gotta go.
Hey, um, why would
someone take prednisone?
I don't know,
a lot of reasons- arthritis, lupus...
uh, asthma, Crohn's disease.
It's a common anti-inflammatory.
Thanks. I'm sorry.
You don't have to memorize every picture.
Just flip.
- Flip it, man.
- You want me to make a mistake?
Hey, cut the guy some slack, all right?
He's got a target on his back.
Emolia, it's me again.
Got a Salvadoran thing goin' on.
It's kinda time-sensitive, so call me back.
- I need some air.
- I'll come with.
That's the guy that works for Gusl
- That's ass-suck, right there.
- [Curtis] Justin LaMott?
Emolia's gone.
Neighbor saw her leave with a black guy.
- Kavanaugh.
- You call her cell?
- Three times, including just now.
- You're her paycheck.
When's the last time she didn't
call you back in five minutes?
Hey, if Kavanaugh got to her somehow,
it's nothin'I can't turn around.
He's probably got her stashed
at a safe house somewhere.
Come on.
Had to start with Pitarrio. I.A.D. Flips him.
Shithead ends up dead.
They've got nothing.
They go to Emolia, twist her against her will.
What does she know about
besides the heroin?
Nothin'. I've kept her clean.
Is there any chance Lem's
really workin' with these guys?
See, that's what Kavanaugh wants,
for us to doubt each other.
This guy's usin' every angle.
Prick talked to Corrine at our kids' school.
This guy's chattin' up your ex?
- You think you might've mentioned that?
- I just did.
Warn Mara. Ronnie, you tell
whatever you're bangin' this week...
don't talk to strangers.
All I need is five minutes with Emolia
to coach her on what to say-
let her know that
we're there to help her.
Trust me. We find her,
this whole thing goes away.
Well, how are we gonna find her?
Hey, we got an I.D. On our shooter-
Justin LaMott, vehicle matches.
Yeah, better luck than we're havin'.
We're gonna need to stick Leon
in a safe house until we make the arrest.
All right. I got a list
of available HUD houses.
All right, let me see.
Uh, these are for captains
and above only.
Captain, we found the baby.
Won't leave your office.
[Woman] The bones in his chest
are essentially pulverized.
- Pulverized? How?
- I'd say a fist.
- Somebody punched a newborn?
- Stepped on him, maybe.
There's a variety of trauma-
skull fracture, knife wound on the left leg.
- I'll know more later.
- Thanks for the rush.
On this one- anything you need.
[Claudette] A typhoon in Fiji's
looking pretty good right now.
- Did we even have a chance?
- Crime Scene says he died hours ago.
It's a special kind of monster.
Yeah, and that monster's
name's Tevares Glade.
Just got a call back
from a decal place on Pico.
Two years ago,
Tevares placed a special order there.
- "R.I.P. Jevontrey."
- In honor of a dead uncle. Pulled his record.
- Tevares drives a white Monte Carlo.
- And has six arrests...
all for violent crimes,
four of'em with a Sean Deeks.
Why do two men cut a baby out of a woman's
stomach just to beat him to death?
There were more than two
of them. Look. In the blood.
Fingerprints.
Jesus, he's covered in them.
The big one's Tevares Glade or Sean Deeks.
Maybe both.
- But the little ones-
- You think maybe there was a girl here too?
[Police Radio Chatter]
Ass-suck, 12:00.
Outta six rounds, this dude manages to get
four in the wall, two in the wrong guy.
Loan shark should've
hired a professional.
- Some shit to be dealing with on my birthday.
- It's your birthday?
- We should get wasted, man.
- Yeah.
- Hey, buddy. You, uh-
- Hey.
- You Justin?
- Why?
Why? Gus sent us. He's a little pissed off about
the way things went down this morning.
- What you talkin' about?
- You shot the wrong guy.
I didn't shoot the wrong guy.
I seen the prick hit the ground.
No, you saw his friend hit the ground,
and you just confessed to murder.
You wanna spare yourself the needle,
tell us where to find Gus.
- Gus!
- All right. All right.
Justin I.D.'d the loan shark.
Got 'em both.
- You tell Leon he's in the clear?
- Yeah, freak tried to hug me.
But you insisted on the blow job.
[Laughs]
I must've ate something this morning.
Third time I gotta shit today.
Be sure to inform us of number four.
All right, look. Pitarrio's a dead end-
literally.
We think Kavanaugh's gonna try
to get Emolia to give you up.
- I don't even think she saw me take the "H."
- Good.
Meantime, Vic's convinced
a little T.L.C. Puts her on our side.
Look, Kavanaugh finds out
we got to her, this blows up.
- We even know where she is?
- Ronnie and I checked out the safe houses.
Came up empty.
But her son has occupational
therapy twice a week.
Emolia won't let
Sebastio miss those.
I chased down
this therapist's unfaithful wife...
in exchange for a couple of sessions
for Emolia's kid.
- All right, what do you want me to do?
- Just put on your wire...
head home,
kick back your feet, have a beer.
Kavanaugh's turnin'up the heat.
We think, uh-
We think he might be planning
to formally arrest you.
That happens,
we'll be ready to bail you out.
Hey.
Okay.
All right.
Hey.
Uh, I need you two guys.
This old man here-
He's been waiting here for hours.
Apparently, some asshole's been movin'
around the hood in a camper-trailer.
The guy sets up streamers, flags-
whole thing's very patriotic.
He's selling care packages and bogus
body armor to our troops in Iraq.
Grandpa here paid 300 bucks
for a state-of-the-art vest.
His grandson called from Iraq
when he got it in the mail-
- [Tina] Let me guess. Piece of shit.
- Yep.
Go pull a car.
- Glad to see you two kids are workin' it out.
- Uh, yeah.
Your P.R. Instructor said
you weren't in class the other night.
Yeah, well, somethin' about almost
having to blow a van full of skin peddlers...
made me want to go home
and drink a bottle of wine.
I wasn't up for baton training that night.
So you missed the class
with no valid excuse.
I took three classes already.
And when, exactly, do you lay off?
When I feel safe riding with you.
There's our patriot.
- ##[Trumpet]
- [Police Radio Chatter]
[Julien]
Put him in the cage.
All right, Officer.
What's a little bit
like you doing being a cop?
- [Fence Clatters]
- Put your hands on top of your head.
What'd he do?
He a murderer?
Hey. Listen. I know we're
shorthanded and everything...
but do you think
I can get reassigned?
- What you want, a different T.O.?
- I've tried with Julien, I really have.
- There's murderers in here...
- But he doesn't know the difference...
- between teaching and bitching.
- And rapists and shit.
Look, I can't be in here
with murderers!
I've taken three baton classes,
and my instructor thinks I'm doing great.
- It's justJulien-
- Gotta have a room or something.
We don't have-We don't have a room.
This isn't an inn.
All right, this guy's
in here for resisting arrest.
This guy's in here for
scamming grandpas into buying...
bogus body armor for
their grandkids over in Iraq.
No murderers.
So don't get your panties up in a bunch.
Same goes for you.
We found your fingerprints on the baby,
Tevares, dried in the mother's blood.
Sean and Tevares killed that lady,
so you could have the baby.
And then what?
He got too much for you to handle.
He cried too much.
So you let them beat him to death.
We also have your friends.
We've got their fingerprints.
Pretty soon, one of'em's
gonna start to talk.
Good defense attorney just says
they found the baby in the Dumpster.
Fingerprints mean
they tried to revive it.
- Think the girl's the way to go?
- She's our best shot.
- You want me to give it a run?
- I've got someone else in mind.
[Danny]
Okay, I feel him, like, right here.
It's his foot.
You wanna touch it?
You know, I didn't even
ever really want a baby.
But now-
I guess you're too young to know
what I'm talking about, huh?
All those maternal feelings and all?
Which is why I'm thinking
that you did the cutting.
- No.
- Oh, come onl
Those idiots you're hooked up with- they
wouldn't even know how to make a baby...
much less cut one out of somebody.
You feel it?
That man lost his baby son...
- his girlfriend.
- Bitch brought that on herself.
Is that why you wanted that baby?
You didn't think
she'd be a good enough mother?
Shit, we didn't even know
she was pregnant.
- When you shot her?
- She almost ran us off the road.
My man don't stand for that.
She almost killed us,
so shooting her was like self-defense.
Right?
We didn't see the belly till she got
out the car and started tryin' to run.
They was just gonna drive off, but I said,
"No. We gotta save the baby."
They was thinkin'
they was gonna sell it...
but my sister, Myesha, she had
two abortions when she was my age.
Now she wants a baby...
but those doctors messed up
something in there and so-
I thought maybe, she could take him.
But then the baby
wasn't breathin' right.
So we did the stuff
you see on doctor shows.
We cleared out his mouth
and turned him upside down.
But that didn't work, did it?
So I made Tevares do that C.P.R. Stuff...
and... the minute he pressed down...
we heard everything crack.
That's enough.
- We was just tryin' to save him!
- You know what, just-
just stop talking.
They've given this Kavanaugh
carte blanche to work your case.
Any resources he needs.
What's Kavanaugh
trying to nail you for?
Because this isn't
about some misplaced heroin.
Aceveda and the department need
a poster boy for corruption...
to sell their softer, gentler force
to the voters.
Why pick you as a scapegoat?
You're a push-the-envelope
kind of lawyer.
- I'm a push-the-envelope kind of cop.
- Which Aceveda sanctioned.
This really does go to the top.
Those are some pretty
high-powered cages to rattle.
So you'll represent us?
- Just you.
- No.
We're a team.
Four of us come as a package.
I've seen these things go down.
Everyone eventually needs
to look out for themselves.
You don't understand.
We're not the typical lowlifes
that you represent.
We're a family.
We're surviving this together...
or we go down together.
Hey! Hey! Shit!
I need some officers in here, quick!
[Grunting]
- Helpl Helpl
- [Attacker Shouting, Indistinct]
- [Commotion Continues]
- Stand back!
- What the hell are you doing?
- What?
- You took your gun into the cage!
- Get off me!
Someone could've
grabbed your weapon!
Do you see all these people
around you, huh? Look at me.
You trying to kill one of them,
or you trying to kill one of us?
[Prisoner]
Hopefully one of you. [Cackles]
[Derisive Chatter Continues]
[Prisoner #2]
Where you going, pretty thing, huh?
Where you goin'?
You got a nice swing, you know?
[Sobbing]
Sh-
[Sobbing Sigh]
You know why you're dangerous?
'Cause this isn't real for you yet.
So you're gonna get on me too?
If you wanna be a cop, you
gotta recognize your mistakes.
Learn from 'em.
All I've done is try to be nice to you-
to everyone.
You got a problem with me,
it's because of your own shit.
See, you're used to being
the queen bee around here...
but you don't get much attention
with those stretch marks.
So you're gonna
make my life miserable.
Every cop here has made mistakes,
including you.
And I bet you anything all of
you got cut more slack than me.
If you go out of this room with
that sniffly nose and those red eyes...
those guys will
never ever respect you.
So you pull your shit together!
Jesus, it's bitches like you
that make the job hard for the rest of us.
Hey, man. Where is she?
She hasn't come out yet.
[Mackey] She should've been
out of there 10 minutes ago.
- You sure you saw her go in?
- Yeah, man, unless she went out the back.
Okay, here we go.
[Kavanaugh]
Get in.
[Shane]
She getting an I.A.D. Escort?
Hey, hang loose.
He might be watching.
[Watch Beeping]
[Pills Rattling]
- You're not going on vacation, are you?
- Haven't decided where yet.
No, um, you're sick.
How sick?
Dutch, I was here yesterday,
I'm here today, I'll be here tomorrow.
I don't know what that means.
I'm your partner.
Look, all that stuff I said about you
not being committed, checked out-
- I'm sor-
- Dutch.
It's okay.
I gotta go take these pills.
Anybody shows up, you call me.
[Knocking]
- Vic. What the hell?
- You didn't return any of my calls.
I got worried.
This dealer
was givin' me a hard time.
- I had to get away.
- Sebastio asleep?
Those sessions take it out of him.
What's up with you?
- When did I.A.D. Approach you?
- What?
Kavanaugh.
What's he trying to get you to say?
No, I don't know a Kavanaugh.
Why you lying to me?
I'm sorry, Vic.
What happened?
Did he come to you, threaten to put
you in jail if you didn't cooperate, huh?
- Because there's a way out of this, you know.
- [Shudders]
What did you tell him?
That I saw your guy take the heroin.
That's it.
All right. It's okay.
Soon as we get you out of town,
your statement won't mean anything.
No, l-l-I can't leave!
Whatever Kavanaugh's squeezing
you with, I can make it go away.
- I'm gonna pack your shit.
- But Sebastio-
I'm gonna take him to your mother's.
I'll make sure he gets back
with you once you get settled.
Vic.
I didn't know you then.
What?
You've been behind this all along?
You tipped I.A.D. About the heroin.
If I had to do it
over again, I'd have said no.
You been good to me and Sebastio.
You didn't- You didn't say anything?
You never warned me?
All this goddamn time?
- I told him that-
- Shut up!
[Whimpers]
- [Huffs]
- Oh, God.
[Gasps]
He checks in on me, Vic.
He'll be here.
- What else did you tell him?
- Nothing. I swear.
Six months. Six months
you could've warned me!
- God-
- [Frightened Yelp]
One of my men, maybe all of us,
are going to jail because of you.
- I was scared.
- I helped your son!
- I tried to get you out of this life!
- [Gasps]
- I'll leave... tonight.
- And go where-
- to a phone booth to call Kavanaugh?
- No.
- Without you, I.A.D.'s case goes away.
- [Whimpering]
You knew what I was when you
started running with me.
I report on people for money, Vic!
That's what I do!
- Till now.
- [Sobbing]
[Frustrated Scream]
[Cell Phone Rings]
- I found you once. I can do it again.
- [Ringing Continues]
[Ringing Stops]
Come here.
- Who did you call today?
- What?
On your cell phone-
who did you call?
Only my cousin.
Few hours ago.
You called her to get a message to her
to tell me how to find you.
- Got it?
- [Door Opens]
Poli-
Oh, Jesus. It's you.
Detective Mackey.
What are you doin'here?
[Laughs]
It's my C.I. What the hell are you doing here?
Emolia's helping us
with a Salvadoran drug ring.
I.A.D.? Vice?
You're a jack-of-all-trades.
I'm sorry. Did I miss something?
Why is it that you're here?
I got spooked.
Called my cousin.
She called Vic for me.
Next time you hide
one of my C.I. S, put a car out front.
This isn't safe.
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Continues]
##[Ends]