Previously on The Shield.
[Aceveda] We're talkin'about a case
that puts Mac behind bars for a long time.
- And I want you to help me prove it.
- Okay.
[Gunshot]
Detective Terry Crowley.
He was pronounced dead 2:13 this morning.
- [Shouts]
- We killed a cop.
Get over it
and don't bring it up again.
Stay on Mackey, all of his guys.
- You sure?
- I wish I wasn't.
Your captain's been relieved of duty.
We need someone to cover in an interim capacity.
- What was that about?
- He asked me to be the company yes-man jellyfish.
I told him to shove it.
- Where's your stash?
- It's in there, man.
All right. We find the dead girl's body,
you get this back.
Those drugs were never logged
into Evidence.
Emolia called in one
of my colleagues immediately...
and they were able to I.D. Lemansky
from her description.
Searched his vehicle while he was sleeping,
procured the heroin...
and replaced it
with a non-narcotic substance.
Vic likes me and my boy.
He wants to take care of us.
We can use that.
- I thought you were Vic's C.I.
- Whoever's got the money.
[Screaming, Shouting]
[Screaming, Shouting Continue]
[Shouting Continues]
[Woman]
Stop itl Stop itl
[Chattering On Police Radio]
[Screaming, Shouting]
- Hey!
- Stop! Police!
- Police!
- All right. Let's split them up.
Hey, hey!
Come on, Joe.
In the other room!
- Get outl
- [Groans]
Get in the other room.
Get him out ofhere.
Get in the other room right now.
Get out of here. Get out!
- [Mackey] Ronnie, you all right?
- Yeah.
- [Shane] Everybody just be quiet.
- Who hit me?
Jesus Christ?
Come on, man. Turn around.
Let me see your hands.
- Anything?
- Nothing. No blood on the Mexis.
- [Curtis] Blacks are clean too.
- Shit.
Go to the E.R., get that looked at.
Get a wagon.
Haul in the grieving families.
Tell the captain I said to send it.
- All right.
- This is bullshit uni calls.
Better get used to it. Sir.
You see who domed my guy?
Black kid. Got, like, a blond Afro.
I see him hanging out in front
of Kwiky's Liquor on my way home.
Look, what the hell's going on here?
This is, like, the second black
and Latino brawl I've had this week.
- Where do you live?
- Culver City.
Well, you better learn how to coordinate
your colors there, West Side.
[Chuckling]
Last week some black guy went hit and run
on a Mexican kid. Crushed his skull.
We couldn't generate
any cooperative witnesses.
Cholos took it on themselves.
Hunted down the driver and beat him to death.
- Black hood jumped in, killed two Mexicans.
- Went sideways ever since.
I didn't know.
Yeah. Thanks.
[Man]
She's got three punctures in her back.
- Who found her?
- Ajunior-Zellie Praza.
She's pretty devastated.
She's in my office.
Do you have
any metal detectors here?
- Some of them don't work very well.
- Any other witnesses?
- There's 1,500 students in the school.
I would think so.
- Thanks.
Good questions. Nice work.
Officer, would you like to see Zellie?
The detectives will. Keep her
in your office until they get there.
Tina? Tina.
- Hey. Hey, T-Tina!
- What?
You're contaminating the crime scene.
Oh, shit!
[Sighs]
All right, guys. Come on.
The captain's gonna address the troops
in the briefing room. Let's head in.
This should be educational.
Hey. Hey, come on.
I'm hormonal, and I expedite
your paychecks, so let's move it!
- What's going on?
- Captain's calling a pep talk.
[Shane] Yeah, 'cause when I
think pep, I think Billings.
[Billings]
Okay.
Thanks for joining me.
Bet you lunch he says
"and so forth" at least twice.
As you probably know...
yesterday Measure 16
on the city ballot failed.
So it looks like those temporary
budget cuts are now permanent.
Uh, that'll be 17% across the board.
Which means-
Which means we'll have to make do...
with the lack of manpower here in the Barn
and on the street and so forth.
Uh...
the chief wants you to know
this is by no means a reflection...
of the fine job that you're
all doing for our city.
Of course not.
Listen, starting next week, we're gonna
be going to single-unit patrols.
I know. Which means, if you have
more than six months on the street...
- you're gonna be flying solo.
- [Woman] What?
That's bullshit.
And, uh, speaking
of flying solo at six months...
Officer Sofer might be mum
on who the daddy is...
but she'll gladly spill the beans
on your new assignments.
[Chuckling]
Okay. Um, that's all I have.
You guys keep up the good work.
All right?
Hey!
Cheap bastards don't wanna cough up
a half a cent of sales tax, screw 'em.
Next time somebody bitches
P.D. Didn't show up...
tell 'em that could've
bought two cops on time.
[Man]
Right on, Vic.
So, let's keep showing up.
Everything else will even itself out.
That's right.
Everything always evens out.
And so forth.
Don't hate me 'cause I'm always right.
We need to talk
to the rest of Zellie's class.
- The juniors are at lunch.
- The entire class?
- We'll be here all day.
- Yeah.
[Screaming]
Hey, hey!
Heyl
[Tina]
Get downl Get downl
Hey!
Come on. Move it!
Get downl I said, movel
[Gunshots]
- Get on the floorl
- [Girls Screaming]
- Come on! Tina!
- Julien!
Tinal
[Girl]
Oh, my Godl
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Ends]
We got a full-blown riot at Wellman-Chase
High School. Shots have been fired.
Officers need help.
Tactical alert. All we got.
Get 'em there now.
Have F.D. And E.M.S.
Stage two blocks out.
- Tell 'em it's chaos on arrival.
- [Danny] Got it.
[Screaming]
[Shane]
Move it! Let's go!
Hey, get off him. Hey! Back off!
Get off! Get off!
- [Woman Screams]
- [Horn Honks]
Shit! Go on! Get out of here!
Get the hell out of here!
Let me borrow that! Give it to me.
All right. Fire it up!
[Horn Honks]
[Siren Wailing]
Vic, Wilshire East came through!
Set up a mobile field forcel
Come on. Get up, punk.
This was your solution?
Turn a goddamn fire hose on my kid?
What was I supposed to do, open fire?
Never stopped you all before.
Excuse me, ma'am.
I'm David Aceveda, your councilman.
I can assure you that it was
the safest option to protect all these kids.
- Right.
- [Man] Let's get a gurney over here.
Get the lab rats to lift those prints.
May be our knifer.
It's not.
Paramedics?
Officer Hanlon. She got a little bit
too close to the crime scene.
- I've already discussed it with her.
- You went into the bathroom?
It's my fault. I should've-
Preserving the scene is Training Officer 101.
That's how murderers go free.
Murderers go free.
I'm really sorry, Detectives.
It won't happen again.
- It's okay.
- Let's go.
- It's a rookie mistake.
- She's way too young for you.
I am mature and distinguished.
A lot of young women appreciate that.
You really ought to
cut back on the porn.
Please move back.
This shooting related to our stabbing,
or was this just for extra credit?
Either way, he's not graduating.
- You okay?
- I'm fine.
- I can grab those paramedics.
- I said I'm fine.
Let's give that to Vic,
and we'll stick with the stabbing.
Okay.
- [Danny] The parents
want to take their kids home.
- Nothing would make me happier.
Unfortunately, all the little shitheads
are suspects and witnesses.
- They want to talk to a captain.
- And I want more hair.
All right. You handle it.
It's good mothering practice. Vic.
- What do ya got?
- Armed and dangerous. Taser.
He was in the cafeteria
when the kid got shot.
All right. Listen.
Anything you can do to quiet this shitstorm,
get it off my plate, it's got my blessing.
[Door Closes]
You a member of the Varsity
Taser Club, Weston?
Eleven of your classmates are in
Mission Cross- some critical, one dead.
- And this-
- [Crackling]
Puts you at the top of the
most-likely-to-be-tried-as-an-adult list.
A knife and gun did the damage.
That don't mean shit.
Shit!
- [Shane] That's persuasion by proxy.
- I didn't hurt nobody.
Yeah? What do you use this for, huh?
Toasting Pop-Tarts?
- Protection, man. Shit's crazy going on.
- What shit?
- [Crackling]
- [Groaning]
[Panting]
Goddamnl That shit ain't rightl
All right, all right, all right.
There's a kill clock. Some Mexican's
gotta kill a couple brothers by tonight.
- Why?
- I don't know the whys, man, just the what.
- Who's the Mexican?
- If I knew that, I wouldn't be carrying the zapper.
That's for being a wiseass.
Claudette, I might know
what your stabbing's about.
- Guy in 1 thinks there's a kill clock ticking.
- Kill clock?
Gangs use it to set a time limit
on an initiation or a retaliation.
- He heard some Mexican's
gonna try to kill two blacks.
- Just randomly?
- You think it's legit?
- That doesn't matter.
If it stirs up enough fear, it's real.
- Would explain why our witness isn't talking.
- Yeah.
Keep at her.
I'm gonna tap into a C.I. Of mine.
That girl that was stabbed, Caroline Tylin?
She just died in surgery.
Sorry.
Hey, how you feeling?
- How do I look?
- Great.
Yeah? Pretty much how I feel.
Thanks for asking.
- Bad news, Zellie.
- [Dutch] We know about
the black-brown retaliation.
And right now, you're the closest brown
to our dead black girl.
She died?
[Claudette] Which means you were
involved or you know who did it.
[Dutch] By not talking,
you're interfering with an investigation.
That's a crime.
All right.
I saw him running out as I came in.
And then I saw her by the sink,
all bloody and shit.
Who was it?
[Sighs]
Lorenzo Lavedra.
All right. This kill clock's
gonna fall gangland.
Vic and I should follow up on this.
- Okay, we'll take over the cafeteria shooting.
- Yeah.
I'll tell the captain we traded cases.
Why confuse him?
That it?
[Man]
For now. You'll hear from me soon.
Somethin'else?
Uh, no.
[Knocks]
Excuse me.
You're here early. Come in, please.
Come on. Come on. Have a seat.
I've only got a few minutes.
How can I help you,
Lieutenant Kavanaugh?
You know that I.A.D. Has been looking
into Detective Mackey...
and the Strike Team he ran
while under your command.
Captain Rawlings began that investigation.
I was aware of it.
That investigation still ongoing?
Yes, it is.
- Well, what have you got?
- What have I got?
We've got Lemansky.
He lifted a brick of tar
off the El Salvadorans.
We've been waiting for it
to spin into something... more.
Which means you've got nothing
on Mackey.
His day job's keeping him busy.
He hasn't had the freedom
to navigate much game.
But we got a C.I. Next to him,
and when he jumps dirty, we'll know.
Until then I was hoping that you
might be able to help us out.
[Chuckles]
You've got my letter,
and I've got nothing else to add.
Mackey's your problem now, not mine.
No, perception is your problem.
I'm going after Mackey and his team.
Now, you can get on board
and be proactive...
or you can sit back and spectate...
just like you did when he
was running dirty on your watchl
Hey, I did everything I could
to rein him in.
Don't sit there
and threaten me with bad P.R.!
You're right. I was out of line.
Hey, I'm sorry.
Please, come on. Sit down.
Mackey's jacket
is like a 20-page cautionary tale.
This is a lawsuit waiting to happen.
I just want to get him off the street
before he does any more damage. That's it.
P.D. Is looking for a poster boy
for corruption.
They crucify one of their own,
the public will trust the rest.
And next time that ballot measure,
it passes.
When you were captain,
Mackey and Vendrell...
were interrogated
about the shooting death...
of a Detective Terry Crowley.
From the notes, it's very clear
that you thought Mackey was involved.
And your comrades ruled it line of duty.
I was hoping you might be able
to shed some light on the specifics.
The rumor has it that the feds
might've been involved with that.
Is that true?
What's my end?
Your suspicion. It's your letter.
We say you got the ball rolling.
You followed it through
even after you left the job.
Now, that's the man
that I would want to be mayor.
I would vote for that man.
Vic and his guys are tight.
And Lemansky, he's a soldier.
He'll follow Mackey anywhere.
But he's also the one with a conscience.
So, you're gonna need something to drive
a wedge between him and Mackey.
I need that wedge, Councilman.
I need that wedge.
If I give you this, I'm done.
I don't want that guy's stink
on me anymore.
My word.
Terry was working with Justice
to bring down Mackey...
and I think Vic had him killed.
What kind of proof have you got?
Detective Crowley's deal with Justice.
That's good.
- Can I get the intel by the end of the day?
- Sure.
- No, thank you.
- Come on. This is a fresh pack.
It's Juicy Fruit.
I said no. Thank you.
You hold this out long enough...
some people feel compelled
to take the gum.
It's a sign they'll crack under pressure.
I know.
[Chuckling, Sighs]
Hey, listen. Oh, there he is!
Hey, Sebastio. How you doing?
Look how big you got.
Oh! Oh, wait a minute. Wait a minute.
How'd that get in there, huh?
You want that?
[Chuckles]
You want anything?
No. Here on business.
I got a kill clock ticking.
Mexican on black.
These things usually start on the inside,
so check with your prison contacts, okay?
- Okay.
- Good.
Uh, your C.I. Renewal papers hit my desk.
You need me to sign them?
Look, I know it pays the rent,
but C.I. Work is a roll of the dice.
We've had a good six months,
but you should get out before you get hurt.
- I need that money, Vic. What else am I gonna do?
- Anything else.
I'll help you find something.
You're worried about us.
I just want this to end on good terms.
Tell me you'll think about it.
- Okay. I'll think about it.
- Good.
- And if you hear anything about this kill clock-
- I'll let you know.
Good.
Was the riot gang related?
Well, we're still putting the pieces together,
trying to get a clearer picture and so forth.
Well, what the hell started it?
We don't have a motive yet,
but we have a suspect.
Good. I need a minute.
Shut the door.
[Sighs]
This about me hosing down those kids?
Rather have them pissed off and wet
than dead and dry.
[Chuckles] What?
You breaking up with me, Roy?
Got a call from Pensions.
Chief's having them
put through your papers.
They want you out
when you hit your 15.
You're putting me on the beach?
This referendum failing-
Cutbacks are hitting hard.
Anybody near their 20 or carrying
a risky jacket is getting the push.
At least you'll get
a piece of your pension.
- There aren't enough cops as it is.
- It's not personal. It's policy.
If it's not personal,
then why am I getting the news...
hand delivered to me
by the chief's inner circle?
Figure I owed you a face to face.
It's bullshit, and you know it!
It's some suit
making a judgment call.
Can't you put in a good word,
turn it my way?
I'm not Gilroy.
It's a different time.
Play this smart, Vic.
Don't give 'em a reason
to pull your pension.
Hey, A.C.
Hey. Uh, the kid who did the stabbing-
Lorenzo Lavedra, 17.
Couple of misdemeanors,
nothing violent. No gang ties.
His pops, however,
is, uh, doing a dime in Chino.
- Assault.
- Good.
What's up?
Jesus Christ.
These are retirement papers.
- Yeah.
- Am I missing something?
Department's cutting its liabilities.
Phillips wants me out
by the time I hit my 15th year.
That-That's, like, in four months.
That's crazy.
Um-
What are we gonna do?
I'll walk out
the front door on my own...
before I'll let someone
push me out the back.
This is between you and me.
Not a word-
- [Door Opens]
- [Laughter]
That's right.
- Hey. How's the head?
- Intact.
- Man, nothing can hurt that cabeza.
- Is it sore?
- Yeah. Okay, okay.
- Let's see that.
- I want that asshole who clubbed me.
- We'll get him.
Hood needs a little reminder-
you hurt us, we hurt you worse.
We'll make sure that measure passes.
We got a clock to kill first, guys.
Let's go.
[Whispers]
Wow.
[Knocking On Door]
- We're looking for Lorenzo.
- Haven't seen him since this morning.
Hasn't been home all day today?
Don't know. Just got here.
I was picking up Cisco from soccer.
- [Small Engine Revving]
- Hey, that's our guy!
Stay here!
Hey!
[Tires Screech]
Whoa! He went down!
[People Screaming]
- Oh, Godl
- [Gunshot]
Asshole's trying to finish the kill clock.
- Can't let him get out of browntown.
- I got it.
[Horn Honks]
Get out of there or I'll shoot.
- [Shane] You okay?
- Hey, give me your keys right now!
[Lorenzo]
Get outl
- [Tires Squeal]
- Ah, damn it!
Get out of the car! Hey, get out of the car!
Hands on your head right now!
Don't move, or you're dead!
Let me see hands!
Let's go. Let's gol Come here.
Let me see your hands, buddy.
Stop struggling.
- Got him?
- Yeah, I got him.
What are you doing? What are you doing?
Why are you arresting him?
He ran a stop sign.
- Where's Cisco?
- He's downstairs.
The black guy- the guy with the Bible.
He dead?
He lost a lot ofblood,
but he'll live to see Armageddon.
My son was scared. He panicked.
- He sees what white cops do to Mexican kids.
- Oh, really?
He panic when he stabbed
Caroline Tylin today?
Got a witness saw him fleeing
from the bathroom.
No. Tell him you didn't do it, Renzi.
What time is it, Mama?
You got someplace you gotta be?
I don't feel so good.
I wouldn't feel too good either
if I just slaughtered an innocent girl.
I'm guessing you didn't download
the death photo with your ringtones.
Oh, Jesus.
- Lorenzo!
- [Mackey] Christ.
Take him to the bathroom, please!
Hey, Officer Hanlon.
- Got a little job for you.
- Anything you need, Detective.
Clean him up.
Get him to the john.
Okay.
I'm Mexican. Why am I gonna be
offin'up some other homes?
[Dutch]
Maybe you had a beef with him.
Maybe it was so crazy in the cafeteria, you
got caught up in the rush, fired some shots.
- I didn't do that.
- Sure you did.
- No, I didn't.
- Then who was it?
- I don't know.
- Because you shot him.
[Laughing]
Why do you keep saying that?
'Cause the truth rolls
comfortably off my tongue.
Heard you were bragging
about the new gun you bought...
telling kids you pack it for protection.
Man, that was just me talkin'.
I didn't even bring it to school.
You snuck it past
the lame metal detectors.
- You pulled it out during the riot,
shot him in the back.
- It wasn't me!
Fine. Call Juvie. Let him spend a few weeks
in lockup, get a taste ofhis future.
Maybe a little truth
will seem like a good idea then.
- It's Every-Day.
- What's every day? That you shoot somebody?
Evan Dayne. Call him Every-Day.
Bangs with the Hope Hill set.
He can't know it was me
that said anything.
[Growling]
Get him- Get him off!
Dutch!
- [Mrs. Lavedra] Stop itl You're killing him.
- Dutch! That's it.
- It's over. That's it.
- [Gasping]
[Dutch]
Are you okay?
Fine. I'm fine.
Shit. Goddamn it! This is a new suit.
Have a wonderful day.
Bye. Bye, guys.
Love you. Bye.
Hi.
- Jon. I'm new here at the school.
- Ah. Corrine.
Uh, which one's yours?
He's inside already. Orientation.
- Gum?
- Uh, no, thanks.
Come on. It's a fresh pack.
Here you go.
Sure. Thanks.
- That your boy?
- Yeah, yeah. And our daughter.
Two?
Wow, that must be tough.
I'm struggling
with just one autistic child.
- It's the challenges of single parenthood, I guess.
- Yeah.
- Doing it alone is hard.
- You too?
Yeah.
- The daddy's not in the picture?
- Uh, he does what he can.
My ex, she- she doesn't
even acknowledge our child.
I'm sorry.
Sometimes I wonder why I even married her.
You ever feel like that?
I'll see you around.
Can I call you sometime?
I'm sorry.
They told me that I should try to get
to know some of the other parents.
I'm out of my depth.
Um-
I could talk to you or I could talk
to your husband. Either one. Whatever.
Okay. Last name's Mackey.
And, um, you can call me
about the kids or the school.
- My husband's not gonna be much help.
- Thanks.
Thank you.
Hi.
Hey, Julien, you gotta give me
the scoop on Danny's baby.
- What do you mean?
- The father. The pool's up to 1,100 bucks.
Course, there's a, uh, you know,
broker's fee for any insider trading, buddy.
She won't say. Why don't you guys
just leave her alone?
- Come on, man. Help a brother out.
- [Tina] Who'd you take?
- Oh, I always take Shane in these things.
- Not me, brother. I'm married.
- That means no stickin', just lickin'.
- Oh, charming.
Besides, I like my women tiny.
So your dick fits better?
Ohl Easy.
Easy.
[Tina]
Put me down for 20 on the sperm bank.
I gotta get this organized.
Tina, 20, turkey baster.
You okay, mijo?
See ya later, darling.
[Kisses]
I got him.
Are you on drugs?
I didn't raise an animal.
You hear me?
What the hell is wrong with you?
Who set the kill clock?
Don't you touch him!
Vic. Vic.
Little kid who got run over last week was
a nephew of a Los Mag capo doing 20 in Chino.
Los Mags are reaching out
to settle the beef.
Chino's where Lorenzo's pop
is stretching.
Hood's been under the microscope.
Maybe the Mags use a proxy, make sure
no blood blows back in their direction.
I got a few Juvie graduates in Chino.
I'll find out what pop's story is. Come on, man.
- Shane, give me a minute.
- Yeah.
- [Door Closes]
- Where's Sebastio?
- My mom's watching him.
- Here.
It's okay. I'm- I'm on the clock.
- I know how much gas costs. Come on.
- More and more.
Thanks.
Any thoughts about hanging this up?
Still thinking.
A Los Mag captain
set the kill clock from Chino.
Same cell block
where your father got caught...
helping the black brethren
distribute smokes.
Pissed off the inked vatos.
[Shane] The asshole can't even
play by the rules in prison.
My guess is Lorenzo Sr.
Offered you up...
as a junior assassin...
to settle both scores.
Is that true? Does that bastard
have something to do with this?
- Answer mel
- [Bangs Hand On Table]
Mommy can't help you.
You grow a dick. Tell the truth.
It's about justice.
He said I could help the cause.
It's Mexi pride.
Jesus, mother of God.
I didn't want to hurt no one.
Dad started crying.
Said if I didn't kill two dark by 10:00 tonight,
Los Mags were gonna waste him.
That was him you were
on the phone with last night?
I gotta finish it, or he dies.
Why? Why would you
do this for him?
Not for him. I hate him!
But if I don't do it, it falls on Cisco.
He was on the other line.
Dad told him too.
He gave us the combination
for the guns.
Guns? There's more than one?
- [Mrs. Lavedra] Oh, no.
- Cisco still thinks my dad's like a real dad.
He'll do it. He'll throw it all away
for that asshole.
Come on.
[Mackey] Paula, where's the kid
that was sitting in that chair?
- [Mrs. Lavedra] Ciscol
- What kid?
- Shit.
- [Whimpering] No, no, no.
- Description of the shooter
sounds like our lost brother.
- Go.
- Hey!
- Whoa, whoa!
- What happened here?
- Little spic came in, shot him cold.
- Tommy never saw it coming.
- He's gone.
- Which way did he go?
- Out the back.
- Come on, Shane.
- That crazy kid stopped
to take a goddamn Polaroid.
- I stuck him with my best pair though.
- Stuck him with your scissors?
- [Siren Wails]
- Shit. They're here. Let's go. Go, go, go.
Hey.
Yeah.
Easy.
Hey!
Cisco? Put the gun down, kid!
Put it down right now, or I'll shoot.
- I gotta get this picture to my dad.
- H-Hold it! All right.
We'll talk about the picture
after you put the gun down.
- You'll take it to him?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I'll take it to him myself.
That's it. Where we can see it.
Good boy. Go.
All right. Give me the camera.
Good boy.
This really hurts.
Don't! Shit. Oh, Jesus Christ.
All right. Hold on.
- Keep pressure on it.
- Go get those paramedics!
- Goddamn it.
- Aw, Christ almighty! Here we go. Watch out.
- Got it?
- Watch out. Go, go, go.
All right. Hurry up, Ronnie!
[Claudette]
What happened in the cafeteria, Evan?
I heard those shots,
hit the floor like everybody else.
- Anyone else see that?
- Don't know. We all ran for the door.
- We got three people who saw you
pull the trigger, Every-Day.
- Then you got three liars!
Three against one.
Those aren't very good odds for you.
I'm used to it.
We're gonna need
a little more than bad attitude...
to be convinced of your innocence.
You best tell pale boy here
to get outta my goddamn face.
Look, I ain't- I ain't been playing trouble
for a while now. Ask around.
We did.
That's how we got the statements.
From who? Some chili-shitters?
They killing us niggers.
You don't think they wanna
put another one away?
- That sounds like motive to me.
- Lazy-ass cop.
Hey, I bust my ass on this job!
Well, your busted ass suck at it.
Hey, book him for murder.
This is wrong, man!
I ain't kill nobody, man!
- Come on. It's been a long, shitty day.
- Every day.
The E.M.T. Says he's gonna make it.
- Gracias a Dios.
- Yeah, I wouldn't be too thankful.
He just killed an innocent man.
I wanted to kill their father a dozen times,
and I never did for their sake.
Los Mags should slit his throat
from ear to ear.
[Man]
Ma'am.
She's right, you know.
That prick should die.
He will. Just not today.
Look, this isn't the way I wanted to do it,
but at least it'll end this round of blood.
Talk to your guy in Chino.
Find out where those pictures go.
- You got two hours to get them there.
- All right.
- Stop the clock.
- I'll get it done.
Got a call
from a teacher at Wellman.
He just realized his gun was stolen
out of a locked desk drawer.
- Evan Dayne in any of his classes?
- Homeroom and science.
Now we know where Every-Day
got his weapon.
Whatever happened to rapping
a kid's knuckles with a ruler?
Uh, good job. Thanks.
It's, uh- It's Vic's kid.
I got 50 bucks in the pool.
That's funny, 'cause I got 50 on you.
[Doorbell Rings]
I tried calling. No one answered.
- Something wrong?
- I thought maybe I'd-
I'd try to catch them before they
went to bed, say good night.
- It's not your usual night.
- I know.
Vic, you can't just show up.
I mean, they have a schedule.
And mine's always changing.
You want me to ever see 'em or not?
- These aren't my rules. It's the custody agreement.
- Ah, Jesus!
Is that blood?
Shit. I thought I got it all.
Twelve-year-old. It's been a shit day.
I just wanted to kiss 'em good night.
Wash it off before you see them.
- Hey!
- Daddy!
Hmm! Ah, my baby.
Heard you already have a suspect
in custody on that cafeteria shooting.
Most cases are solved
within the first 24 hours.
After that, the odds of solving them
decrease exponentially.
- I'm gonna learn a lot from you, aren't I?
- Could be.
- Have a good night, Detective.
- You too.
Relax.
What?
Gun residue test came back
on Evan Dayne- negative.
We sure about this guy?
He knows when to wash his hands.
So do I.
[Bell Dinging]
We're looking for a brother.
Blond Afro. Tall.
Hands might be cut up.
- Ain't seen nobody like that.
- We know he hangs here.
- We know this shop's been hit nine times last year.
- Twice last month.
And it took you guys three hours
to show up last time I called.
Well, next time... you call us.
We're your new 911. We'll make sure
that people don't mess with your shop.
We'll steer that kind of business
someplace else.
You're talkin' straight
'bout keeping my place safe?
I got a badge, don't I?
Darius McBride. D-Mac.
Came in this morning.
Bought some Band-Aids and beer.
Lives over in Belmont Green.
Consider your protection clock running.
Hey!
Anybody, any color, hits this store...
I will beat them half dead
and plant enough shit on them...
to send them away for a 10-stretch.
Spread the word.
Screw.
[Bell Dings]
Guys like the girlie girls.
Who says you gotta look
likeJanet Reno, right?
You replaced your breast plate
with lipstick and tampons?
No place to put your shit, you know?
Yeah, well, that's a reprimand...
as well as probably getting you killed.
Lose those hoop earrings before
someone rips your ears off.
Did I do something to piss you off?
You know what?
You have a job, sweetheart. All right?
Take it seriously.
You're a cop, not a Kelly Girl.
Okay, look.
L-I appreciate you
being straight with me.
It's just hard to catch a break
with these guys.
- Treat you like you don't belong.
- Yeah, I know.
They talk a blue streak about equality,
but the truth is...
the shitheads just think we're
a bunch of little girls playing cops.
So we have to prove them wrong.
Yeah, we do.
Thanks.
It's good to have some backup.
Here you go.
You still here?
I thought you were supposed
to be more 9:00 to 5:00.
Thanks. Tell that to Billings.
[Laughs]
You pretty much run the place.
Yeah, I'd rather be running
the streets with you. Hell of a lot easier.
Don't be so sure.
I got my work cut out for me.
Tina? She ain't no Danny Sofer.
Well, who is?
- Anyway, I wouldn't write her off too soon.
- [Door Buzzes]
- She's raw, but got potential.
- Yeah.
- I guess I made a few mistakes out there myself.
- Yeah, you still do.
You're supposed to have your D.F.A.R.'s
on my desk before the end of the shift.
I'll get Tina right on 'em.
See? I did train you right.
Yup.
- ##[Man Singing]
- [Knocking On Door]
[Whispers]
Shit.
Goddamn it.
##[Continues]
Curtis Lemansky.
Yeah. What's up?
Jon Kavanaugh. I.A.D.
I need you to come with us.
What about?
Get dressed. Guys?
Please.
I'll get dressed. Leave me alone.
- Walter.
- Yeah.
##[Continues]
Bye.
- Hey.
##[Continues]
Get down.
- Come here!
- [Grunting]
Enough.
##[Continues]
- ##[Ends]
- [Siren Wailing]
About six months ago...
we found this kilo of pure heroin...
in the glove compartment of your car.
We seized the drugs...
documented it on camera...
and replaced it with dummy tar.
But... you never logged it
into Evidence.
So, you've been watching me
for six months?
I don't want you to spin a story
right now. Really.
I just want you to think
about what this means.
Felony theft under color of authority.
Intent to distribute.
You're a smart guy.
You've been on the other side
of this table a long time.
You know how that will play out.
Does that seem fair to you?
Hmm?
Look, if you were arresting me,
we'd be at Police 1...
and you'd be parading me past O.I.G.
What do you want?
I want us both to do
the right thing, Curtis.
Really?
Why is it that the guy
with the conscience...
always has to get caught
holding the bag?
And we never really want
that guy, do we?
We want the guy...
that put him into motion...
the one who is really dangerous.
Who do you think I want, Curtis?
Come on, man. Come on.
Who do you think I want?
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Continues]
##[Ends]