Previously on The Shield.
[Claudette] Kleavon Gardner.
Questioned in four separate homicides.
Kleavon is not a killer. I'm his sister.
- Believe me, I'd know it.
- We're releasing your brother.
[Dutch] Deep down, you know we're right.
There's something wrong.
- You just don't wanna see it.
- Now that you know, things will add up.
About six months ago,
we found this kilo...
of pure heroin in the glove compartment
of your car.
But you never logged it
into Evidence.
Lem got picked up by I.A.D.
They've got him wearing a wire.
Kavanaugh might be planning
to formally arrest you.
That happens,
we'll be ready to bail you out.
- You hired a lawyer?
- You need to shift perception.
Make Internal Affairs look
like they're hurting good guys.
I got Mackey making a deal with
the Russians. Hot prescription drugs.
Here's our good faith.
- Yes.
- [Man] Do itl
- Freeze!
- [Shouting]
Vic, what the hell is going on?
- [Mackey] I.A.D. Just shit all over our sting.
- What's this?
[Billings] Don't know where
you got your intel. It's wrong.
He ran the whole operation
by me this afternoon.
I guess I.A.D. Will spin any kind of fiction
to stain good cops bad.
- [Truck Beeping]
- [Man] Keep comin'.
All right.
Gonna be tight.
Is there another way in?
- [Billings] Nah, this is it.
- [Man] All right. Down here, guys.
Oh! Watch it.
Delicate machinery, people.
- Al, hang on.
- Careful, guys.
Watch the turn. Watch the turn.
[Claps]
Coming through.
Heads up.
- [Man] Heads up?
- [Chattering]
[Billings]
Watch your back, Dutch-boy.
- You gotta be kidding me.
- [Billings] No.
Hey, guys, just be careful
on the landing, all right?
I don't want you
to scratch the leather.
Huh? After our
big pharmaceutical bust...
the brass put through some of my
purchase orders they've been sitting on.
- Well, now you'll be sitting in style.
- Anything for us?
- [Clunking]
- Careful. Come on.
[Door Buzzes]
I give that couch two weeks
before we're movin' it down here.
- I'm not wired.
- You're what?
- Look, I'm not wired.
- I don't get this guy. What did Kavanaugh say?
I can't find him. I went by the motel,
it's empty. I called his cell, office.
- There's no answer.
- Why hasn't he arrested you?
[Shane]
Maybe he never had a solid case.
- [Mackey] Think he's packing it in?
- Pulled the plug...
- on the investigation?
- Till we're sure...
we act like it's still on.
- But I like the feeling I'm getting.
- [Knocking]
Vic, I hate to start your morning with this,
but multiple gang homicide.
Beautiful.
Better than a strong cup of coffee.
[Siren Wailing]
- Set trippin'?
- [Julien] Drive-by.
Male victims affiliated Bop Street,
judging by the ink.
That's what happens
when you cross enemy lines.
This turf's been gang-neutral
since Antwon's crew slithered out of Dodge.
- Any witnesses?
- [Tina] Yeah.
Friends of the deceased.
And about as helpful.
[Mackey]
Yo.
- You two see anything?
- Yeah, brothers having courage.
My boys went down wet like real G's.
- You know who did this?
- Some hater.
They almost capped me and Moni, too.
Beyond that, I couldn't say.
- Did you get a good look at the car?
- We didn't see nothing.
Well, you better start
searching your memory...
or you're gonna get a good look
at our car on the way to the station.
So me and my breezy almost catch
hollow points, and po-po got his foot up my ass?
Ain't that some
toy white cop bullshit.
Better check your color, honky.
- Chair over here, all right?
- Yeah. All right.
You getting rid of that chair?
You know, the stuffing in this one is shot.
My ass dies a daily death.
- Yeah, well, sorry. It's headed back to surplus.
- You can send this one back.
- Inventory's expecting that one.
- [Door Buzzes]
Well, well, well.
Pretty ballsy showing your face around here.
I get to officially
notify you that Internal Affairs...
is investigating all four members
of your former Strike Team.
Well, you got burned trying to make
that case already. Why don't you move on?
Since all the Strike Team's files...
all your files on them, are here...
I'm gonna be setting up shop
in the Barn until my investigation's complete.
- You're kidding me, right?
- [Chuckles]
Most of the time.
Just not this time.
And where exactly do you think
you're gonna drop anchor?
I need some privacy, and I don't
want to restrict any of these officers...
from using
the interrogation rooms...
so the easiest thing for me
to do is to use your office.
Excuse me, Lieutenant.
- Are you forgetting that I'm captain here?
- Acting captain.
And that entitles you to a work space
and a phone, not a private office.
But I understand the last captain
did very well...
right here on the killing floor.
I'm sorry for the inconvenience.
Scott?
- Hey.
- Yeah?
Get that stuff- Put it over there.
- [Man] All right.
- Till I can work this shit out.
I didn't see nothing.
I don't know nothing.
I got nothing to say,
except thank the Most High my man's okay.
Your man?
He's a kid and you're not.
- How's that work?
- He laces me with nice shit and got a big dick.
- It's all good.
- You're a deep one.
See, what I'm having
a hard time understanding is...
aside from the ghetto speak,
is why some evildoers...
lit up on your peace posse
for no good reason.
It's the curse of the Fu Manchu.
Arrogant little prick
for only being 19, Preston.
That's my government name.
- The homies call me Kasper.
- The famous Kasper?
You been making quite a name for yourself
these last few months moving rock.
You must have me confused
with some other cat.
I hear you been
working with the rival sets.
Black, brown,
One-niner, Spookstreet.
- You're an equal opportunity dope dealer.
- I don't know about that.
But, see, when you white
in Farmington, you don't fit in.
So you gotta
make friends everywhere.
It'd make it easier if we put our heads
together on this.
Yeah, it would be.
But, see, I ain't no cheese-eating rodent.
Looks like you been gnawing on
something nasty to me.
- [Cell Phone Rings]
- Yeah.
Vic, we got issues here.
What the hell are you doing?
I know this'll come
as a big surprise to you...
but you and your team are the subject
of an I.A.D. Investigation...
which I am heading up.
You already lost face in front of the brass
blowing our Russian bust.
- How's this play helping you?
- I appreciate your concern,
but let me worry about that.
Don't expect any cooperation
from those folks down there.
- They're a home crowd.
- I wouldn't want to do anything to upset them.
Last thing I want to do
is rock the boat.
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Ends]
[Grunts]
Man, if he'd arrest me already...
at least then he'd have
to lay out what he's got.
- [Knocking]
- Goddamn it.
Come in.
- Hey.
Lem, Ronnie, you remember Becca Doyle
from the Crawford case.
- Yeah, sure.
- Well, she's representing us now.
Protecting us legally against
this nut job upstairs.
- You lawyered up?
- [Shane] She's helping out all of us.
For just such an occasion,
you're taken care of.
Well, your boy Kavanaugh's
quite the loose cannon.
Even his I.A.D. Buddies
are surprised by this move.
He's made it personal,
which helps me make the case...
- that you're being unfairly targeted.
- [Door Opens]
Oh. This looks like
attorney-client privilege.
- Yes, it is.
- Ms. Doyle, is it?
- Yes.
- Jon Kavanaugh.
I'm representing all four
of these detectives.
Make sure your communications
with them go through me.
Oh, be my pleasure.
I'm looking forward to working with you.
- You just let me know when you're ready, okay?
- All right.
Thank you.
All right, we gotta
concentrate on doing our jobs.
Let her worry about what other
bullshit charges he's trumping up.
The last thing we want is him getting
at you through some side door.
Throws you off your game.
He comes at you on competency issues...
or some mistake
you make on the street.
We got some dead kids
to account for.
Kasper and his squeeze gave us zip.
What's the next move?
The dead bangers are Bop Street.
It could be their own set whacked 'em
for breaking ranks, working with white folks.
- That's a tree worth shaking.
- All right.
- Appreciate what you're doing.
- Yeah, thanks.
##[Speakers: Rap]
[Gate Buzzes]
[Knocking]
Step off, ho.
You got nothin' to trade.
I been flossin' and pussy-tossin'.
Hand it over.
Aw, shitl
Out the backl
Whoo.
- [Coughing]
- [Curtis] Policel
On the ground.
- [Mackey] Couple of your crew
caught dirt naps today.
- [Coughing]
I'm thinking you Bop Street boys
are policing yourselves.
- You're trippin', man.
- Then why were they rolling with Kasper?
We all right with Kasper... mostly.
As in you wanted him
and his crew "mostly" dead?
Or you beefin' with some other set?
- I don't know.
- This guy's rank and file.
[Ronnie]
Look what I found.
We been letting Bop Street run game
as long as you kept it low-key.
Truce is over. You tell Gunsmoke
I'm gonna shut down a Bop Street rock house...
every two hours
until I get that shooter.
Your clique,
rival set, doesn't matter.
- We want a name.
- Nice touch. Crack vials.
- That's old school.
- [Mackey] A name by the end of today.
Or Bop Street can start filing
for Chapter 11.
[Coughs]
Uh, no.
Thank you.
Well, what do you know?
Robbery-Homicide.
Seems they're sniffin' around the Dutchman,
want to set up an interview.
That's impressive.
Elite of the elite.
Well, it's not a total surprise.
We've closed some big ones,
the whole business with the D.A.'s behind us.
I guess we've got some buzz.
You anyway.
Hey, isn't that, uh-
Fatima Gardner.
It's Kleavon's sister.
Yeah.
You all were pretty sure Kleavon
killed that girl back when.
Lana Gregory.
Her and several others.
- We just weren't able to prove it.
- I've been doing what you said.
Watching and listening.
And I found this while I was
cleaning his room.
It's Kleavon's.
[Dutch]
That's a lot ofblood.
We'll, uh-
We'll check this for D.N.A.
I don't know
if he's noticed it's missing.
He hasn't mentioned cutting
himself, or an accident.
If there's nothing to it, he never has
to know you were here.
I don't know how to look at him anymore.
My own brother.
Just go home,
keep doin'what you're doin'.
Don't be nervous.
Don't give him any reason to think twice.
You know, she says
not to seem nervous.
How am I supposed to do that?
I just- I just don't know
if I can take this.
If we searched your
brother's room, for evidence.
It's your house. You have every
legal right to let us inside.
Kleavon been, uh, keeping odd hours?
Being secretive?
[Fatima] Nothing out of the ordinary,
except the shirt.
His room's this way.
All the furniture's mine.
Only thing he brought
was, uh, the mirror.
Kleavon do anything else
with his time besides work?
Reads a little.
Watches TV. Like everyone else.
- Dear Lord.
- [Door Opens And Closes]
[Gasps]
Oh!
Tima? Tima?
- Oh.
- Tima?
Hey. Changing the sheets.
I thought you were at the track.
Ah, bum day.
They only needed me an hour.
- Let me help. Then make me a grilled cheese.
- I got it. It's okay.
It's all right.
It's already done.
- You all right?
- Of course.
Come on, I'll make you some lunch.
[Kleavon] Can you believe all that time
and effort just to get across town...
then they send me home
after an hour?
[Fatima Chuckles]
Want some pickles?
- Sure.
- Okay.
What about that-
that other job you were looking into?
Oh, manager told me
to call back next week.
- Oh, baby, something will turn up.
- Yeah.
[Kleavon]
You going to Bible study tonight?
Just curious.
Hey, you know, we need some paper towels.
[Dog Barking]
Huh?
[Mouths Words]
- Where the hell's our door?
- The other one too.
[Ronnie]
That son of a bitch.
Thought you might like
a little fresh air.
- Let a little sunshine in.
- Pretty cheap stunt.
I assume you guys have got
nothing to hide, right?
Anyway, with all
the confusion last week...
I never did get a chance
to congratulate you on that bust.
Nice work, even if
it was a little unorthodox.
[Chuckles]
But back to business.
I need to see you in my office.
- Not without my lawyer.
- Becca Doyle, huh? Good call.
Let me know when she gets here.
Vendrell, you got a sec?
Or do you, uh, need a lawyer too?
- No, I'm good.
- Shane.
I'll answer
whatever questions you got.
I see you just bought,
uh, a new house.
L.A. Real estate's bananas.
You doing a little moonlighting,
security work on the side?
Mara's a Realtor.
Between our two salaries, we make do.
Reason I'm here is
I want to nail shut the Terry Crowley file.
I see that.
That happened over two years ago.
I.A.D. Cleared us.
Or didn't you hear
the squeaks in your rathole?
Wonder if you'd mind
taking a look...
at a transcript of your interview
after the, uh, shooting.
See if it jars anything new loose.
I've been looking at your jacket.
Wow.
Pretty effective cop.
Gotten yourself into a couple
of sketchy situations along the way.
Black mark or two.
You were on your own
for a while last year.
Vice. What made you come back
to the Strike Team?
I would think that you would want to make
a name for yourself flying solo.
All the same,
living in Mackey's shadow all the time?
You don't feel that he was trying
to get you back into the fold...
so that he could
get a leash on you, do you?
What's here is how it went down.
So there was just you, Vic...
Terry and Two-Time in that room?
Just me and Vic.
No Lemansky, no Gardocki?
It was true then.
It's true now.
Thanks so much for your help.
Uh, I'm gonna need you
to sign a document...
confirming that you know that we
are reopening the Terry Crowley case...
and you are under investigation.
Blow me.
- [Dial Tone]
- I've talked to every precinct in the city.
No recent bodies
matching Kleavon's M.O.
You gonna do something with that?
Just got off the phone
with Robbery-Homicide.
Turns out they didn't just find me.
A "veteran detective"
recommended they review my file.
I'm gonna check
Missing Persons again.
- You tryin' to get rid of me?
- I thought Robbery-Homicide was your dream job.
I didn't need your help.
There is buzz.
Hey, you guys have a Fatima Gardner
sign in to see you this morning?
- Yeah.
- Her brother just reported her missing.
- Yeah?
- Uh, Captain left a few things up here.
- He asked me to get them.
- Sure.
Anything you need.
I pulled this
off the wall downstairs.
Pretty demeaning, don't you think?
Doesn't really bother me.
It's just boys being boys.
A lot of money
on Vic being your baby's daddy.
Everybody's got an opinion.
Heard a lot of rumors
about the two of you.
Are you saying that
they aren't true?
Look, I'm sure you won't blame me...
when I don't discuss stupid gossip
about my personal life with I.A.D.
When I don't discuss stupid gossip
Sexual relationships between department
personnel need to be divulged in a timely manner...
according to the employee handbook.
Failure to do so
can result in suspensions...
even demotions.
You just got a pay bump
recently, didn't you?
Ah, come on. There's no relationship
between me and Vic.
Should I make this official?
Because I can do that-
widen my investigation.
[Sighs]
Vic and I had a thing, okay?
It's in the past.
When was that?
- Eight or nine months ago?
- You want to get a court order
to draw blood, go right ahead.
But this is none of your business.
You still have to disclose
your relationship with Mackey.
Fill out the forms today, and
I'll overlook the tardiness.
Hey, Vic. Checked out our next
Bop Street target on Hoover.
- Doors and windows are fortified.
- All right, have Ronnie get a door knocker.
- Flash bangs too.
- All right, man.
- [Mackey] Hey. Hang on.
- Over there.
Gunsmoke, we're just about to pay a visit
to another one of your crack palaces.
Look, man, I don't know
who capped my peoples.
But I tell you straight up,
it wasn't no Bop Street niggas.
After Hoover, we're gonna
stop by your Temple Street smokehouse.
That'll bring your
one-day loss to what, 12K?
You know what it does to my street cred
even walking into this pig farm?
- Oink when you get something we can use.
- Hold up, hold up.
Come here.
Tell him.
I'm chillin' at homegirl's round the way,
hear shots, see these two vatos drive off.
- What'd they look like?
- Vatos.
You know, shaved heads,
white tees.
Guy driving had "L.A."
Tattooed all up in here.
But I didn't get a good look
at the dude shooting.
- What kind of car?
- Old, I don't know.
But they was riding on gold anodized
100-spoke D's.
- I know my wheels.
- So we straight now?
Not yet. How's a punk-ass wigger like Kasper
get respect from a crew hard as Bop Street?
I thought he was a poser myself
for a minute.
White boy got business skills.
Split 50-50 off top,
so folks are gettin' paid.
Come with these names
for the product...
"Pink Yo," "Yellow Fever."
Same old shit, only
different colored caps.
You were moving Kasper's product outta
the place we took down this morning?
Look, man, fiends want
what Kasper's selling.
Can't argue with the free market.
Lookin' forward
to that truce again, fellas.
- [Danny] Hey, Vic, you gotta sec?
- I'll get on those rims.
- What's up?
- Uh...
That guy from I.A.D. Got all over me
about department policy...
disclosure of personal
relationships on the job.
- None of his business.
- Yeah, well, he's pushing me really hard, okay?
I can't take a suspension
or a pay cut right now.
I gotta notify Billings.
I just wanted you to know.
When was the last time
you saw your sister?
Lunchtime. Said she was gonna run out
for some soda, never came back.
Family drinks a lot of soda.
I seem to remember you were "out for soda"
when Lana Gregory was killed.
[Claudette]
It's only a few hours. Grown woman.
- Bit premature to call the police.
- I know my sister.
She say she'd be back,
she'd be back.
- Mind if we look around?
- Wouldn't have called you if I did.
[Claudette]
I'll take her room, you take his.
Fatima's room's clean.
Back door's unlocked. What do you have?
It's what I don't have.
Kleavon's death kit.
Latex gloves, knife, duct tape-
It's gone.
I was- I was- I was here earlier.
- What?
- The spur of the moment.
Fatima gave her consent.
You searched a murder suspect's
house without backup?
What if Kleavon showed up?
I hid in the closet.
He didn't see me.
- I slipped out the back door.
- Jesus.
- If you're wrong, and he
confronted her after you left-
- I shouldn't have come alone.
But I wasn't sure you were up to it.
Stress is a trigger.
- I saw you were hurting this morning.
- I am fine.
We got a neighbor that says he saw
a prowler exiting the backyard this morning...
wearing what he called
a "$100 suit."
I'll deal with the neighbor.
If you think I'm up to it.
Take Kleavon to the Barn,
get a statement.
I paid over $300 for this suit.
[Kavanaugh]
Hey.
Who's this?
It's Terry Crowley.
He was one of my guys.
- Killed by a drug dealer a couple of years go.
- That is one version.
Terry was working forJustice,
investigating allegations of a relationship...
between drug dealers
and your clients.
- You have a different version?
- Detective Mackey...
either acting alone or with other members
of his team...
killed Detective Crowley or put him
in a position to be killed.
Just like that Russian I was gonna murder
before you blew our sting?
Any evidence,
or are you all attitude?
In due course.
These theatrics
why you wanted to see us?
I'm sure the three of us
have better things to do.
Yes.
I'm officially informing you, you are under
investigation for the death ofTerry Crowley...
and other allegations of corruption.
You have a right to a P.B.A. Rep,
a lawyer.
I see you already got one.
And a good one.
Please, could you get him to initial here
and here, his signature there.
We'll cooperate fully so you can stop wasting
everyone's time, Lieutenant.
I suppose you want a statement?
Actually, if you could have your clients
walk me through the house...
where Terry Crowley was killed,
that would be great.
Arrange it soon.
Oh, and take down these photos
or I'll file for harassment.
Becca.
I thought the headline in this case
was David against Goliath.
Or did this murder charge
slip your mind?
- I can't talk about this right now.
- This is a big goddamn deal.
It's all a lie.
I'm sorry, I'll call you later.
- What the hell's going on?
- He told them to bring me in.
- Can you take the kids?
- You don't have to talk to him, remember?
- I want this over with.
- He can't compel your cooperation.
If you feel uncomfortable
at any time, you just leave.
- Okay.
- Corrine.
Thanks for coming.
The children, they could, uh-
they can wait inside.
- I can take care of my own kids.
- Okay.
This way. Upstairs.
Hey.
- Dad, what the hell's going on?
- Don't talk like that.
He's a cop, right?
Did Mom do something wrong?
No, never.
Come on, honey.
Vic. I, uh, caught a 187 times two.
- Need you to get on it.
- What's 187 mean?
It means Dad's gonna find you guys a ride.
Come on, kids. Let's go.
You need anything?
Can I get you something? Coffee or water?
Just ask your questions.
You told me that, uh...
it's really difficult
to make both the tuitions.
Yet, Vic, he seems to be able to come up
with the money all the time.
How do you think he does that?
Overtime.
Yeah, I've checked those pay stubs.
He always has been a good provider,
wouldn't you say?
I guess that might
change now that...
you have to split the pie
four ways instead of three.
I don't understand.
Oh, maybe you're not aware.
Officer Danielle Sofer,
who works here...
is filing paperwork admitting
to a sexual relationship with Vic...
over the last couple of years.
When did you get divorced?
- Last year.
- Right.
Officer Sofer is now pregnant.
Is this another imaginary child
like Andy?
What kind of a man says he has
an autistic child...
to a woman who has
two ofher own?
- How sick is that?
- You know, I didn't really like doing that.
I'm-I'm sorry. I just needed to know
what kind of woman you are, Corrine.
Really. I mean,
this is not about me.
This is about Vic.
It's about you.
It's about the kids.
It's about this new baby.
How we got to this place and
where we're gonna go from here.
Please.
Have a seat?
[Dogs Barking]
[Mackey]
"L.A.," Cali-for-nye-ay.
- Same caliber as the Bop Street hit.
- Yep.
It's gotta be the shooter
from this morning.
- Payback's a bitch.
- Yeah, and karma's a whore.
Amado Alvaro. His place.
No sign of forced entry.
- What about ass-boy over there?
- No I.D. Yet.
Neighbor called 911,
saw Alvaro's car driving away...
a little while after
she heard the gunshots.
Hooptie?
Gold rims?
Yeah.
'69 Olds Cutlass. Black.
- Run Alvaro's registration,
put an A.P.B. Out on the car.
- Got it.
Squad, let me get a run on
a '69 Olds Cut-
[Man On Radio] The vehicle should be
rolling up to you right now, Detective.
- You see it?
- [Mackey] We got it. Nice work, Larry.
- Say hello to whoever killed L.A. And ass-boy.
- Who's the Chinaman?
I don't know.
But we're gonna find out.
- [Tires Squealing]
- [Horn Blaring]
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- [Tires Screeching]
- Heyl Get back herel
- Heyl
[Curtis]
Stop! Goddamn it.
Go!
Stop! Hey!
Whoa! Hold it!
Hey, stop, dumb-ass.
It's a barbed wire fence.
- What the hell is he doing?
- [Screams]
[Grunts]
I didn't do nothing.
- Except a double homicide.
- That's crazy. Amado's my main man.
Funny how you know exactly the murders
we're talking about.
We've got you fleeing the scene of a murder
in the victim's car.
You take one last look
at the outside world.
- Where'd you put the murder weapon?
- They were dead when I got there.
- I swear.
- All right. Search the car.
He was into me for 10 grand.
Some white guy named Kasper's
coming by to drop off money.
- [Mackey] Amado was meeting Kasper?
- I wasn't supposed to know.
Kasper was coming by to pay him for some work
he did. When I saw bodies, I bounced.
We gotta take another run at Kasper.
- Remember Terry Crowley?
- Sure. He was on Vic's team.
Do you remember any change in Vic's
behavior leading up to Terry's death?
No. Uh, but he was
pretty torn up afterwards.
- We all were.
- I'm sure it was, uh, terrible.
Terry was working forJustice...
investigating your
ex-husband's team for corruption.
Planting evidence, extortion, kickbacks-
a laundry list of things.
When Vic made Terry
as working for the feds...
we believe that he and Shane Vendrell
murdered him.
- Vic's a lot of things, but he's no killer.
- [Scoffs] Vic is a survivor.
He'll do whatever
it takes to protect himself...
his team and his family.
Are you really trying to tell me that
after 12 years of marriage...
you don't think that that man
is capable of pulling the trigger on someone...
who's trying to take away
everything from him?
- Everything?
- You need to stop this, okay?
Don't cry!
I don't want to see you
shed one single tear.
'Cause tears imply
that you didn't know.
And don't you sit here and tell me
that you didn't know, Mrs. Mackey.
Twelve years you shared his bed.
You knew. He paid your mortgage,
he paid your bills...
and now he's paying
for private schools.
You always knew what he was capable of.
Just like you knew about the other women.
Don't you sit here
and-and-and cry...
and tell me that he's a good man.
Because we both know
that's bullshit.
You left him because you knew.
And yet, you protect him.
You protect him and you lie.
You lie to me.
Don't you dare
sit here shedding tears.
You can only do that
if you've earned that right...
if it was all a surprise.
But it's not a surprise to the woman who knew
him better than anyone else on this Earth.
Is it?
- [Knocking]
- Police. Open up.
[Man] I can'tl
[Sobs]
Please, help me!
Please.
- Sir, what's the problem?
- [Crying]
Something's got me.
My dick. Please.
Jesus. Please.
- Hurry, please.
- All right, sir, just relax. I'm gonna try to-
- No! No! No! No!
- Shit.
Oh, God.
[Crying]
Oh, please.
- Please, hurry up.
- You're caught in a rattrap.
- Oh, God. Get it off me, pleasel
- Call the paramedics.
1- Tango-Bravo requesting paramedics
for male Hispanic, mid-30s.
[Screams]
Lacerations to his groin.
Sir, it's okay.
Paramedics are on the way.
Damn.
Ouch. Meanwhile, this I.A.D. Guy's
got my nuts in a waffle iron.
- You say this happened at a glory hole?
- Yeah. It's pretty sick, huh?
Yeah. Guy's lucky
his schlong wasn't cut off.
Well, I figure the perp
only let it snap halfway.
Otherwise, it would've- No question.
Anyway, we're reinterviewing the victim
as soon as he gets back from the hospital.
Price tag. Check out
the hardware store that sold it?
Yeah, it's one of 20 in the same transaction
two days ago.
That's why my T.O. Thought you'd want
to put detectives on it.
I can't spare any,
so you guys run with it.
It's right upJulien's alley. It's the kind
of case he can really sink his teeth into.
You and Fatima had a fight. She was nagging you
too much, invading your privacy?
Lady, I came to you. Now y'all want to pull me
in here about this thing?
- You're wasting time. My sister's missing.
- We're trying to find her.
Then why ain't you talkin'
to that neighbor about the man he saw?
- We're following up on that.
- We want to help find your sister.
You have to start answering questions.
You gonna cooperate or not?
Anything for her.
Give us a minute.
Anyone else, I'd say he's
genuinely concerned about her.
Given that he's a homicidal sociopath,
who knows?
When we get this guy,
I want to administer the needle myself.
- Wow, he's really under your skin.
- I wish I could get under his.
Okay, maybe we hit Kleavon
with the bloody shirt, the missing death kit.
- We get him rattled.
- We've already exposed Fatima enough.
I don't want to blow her cover.
She could still be out there, alive.
You know, he could've realized
the bloody shirt was missing...
figured out Fatima turned on him,
even if he didn't see me.
Great. Now that we've covered your ass,
you help me figure out what to do.
[Shane]
4:00 this afternoon, where were you?
4:00 this afternoon? I was at Moni's crib.
Hittin' skins and smokin' endo.
Don't believe me, ask the girl.
- You know an Amado Alvaro?
- No.
Shot and killed in his home,
along with a buddy.
- Pretty messy.
- Rest in peace.
Matches the description of someone we're
looking for in the attack on you and your peeps.
Well, like the book says:
"No hand raised against me shall prosper."
[Door Opens]
The other D.B.'s Adair Zeborio.
Vegas P.D. Was looking at him
on a murder for hire. Case didn't make.
Professional hit. He didn't get the whole job
done, wigger got the last word.
This punk?
Unlikely.
Hey, Gilligan's still
half-baked on chronic.
- Let's keep him yapping, see where it gets us.
- All right.
- Am I done here?
- [Shane] No, you're not.
Not until you tell us what you were doing
at Amado Alvaro's apartment today.
You all are buggin'.
I was at my homegirl's.
And how I'm gonna try and kill
somebody I never even heard of?
How long before
you piss off the wrong Mandingo...
and he wastes your pasty,
wigger ass as reparations?
Man, the street's got nothin' but love for Kasper,
long as I'm puttin' money in their pockets.
One bad month and you'll be danglin'from
a balcony just like Vanilla Ice.
Another great, white wannabe.
Next thing you know...
we're gonna hear about some shitty rap album
you're gonna wanna put out.
Why you trippin' on this black-white shit?
Color ain't a thing.
Oh, come on, man.
This is just us glacier monkeys.
We both know
white is right and black is whack.
Which is why you're rolling
with the pretty white lady.
You might talk like a brother,
but you hang with your own.
Not that the sisters
would show you love anyway.
I get more black ass
than a bus bench in Compton.
- Ya heard?
- [Chuckles]
Hard for me to imagine you holding it down
with some Nubian mattress-monster.
Well, then you need
to ask somebody, one-time.
Taneisha's my go-to girl.
She'll let me tear her fat ass
and sugar walls up any time I want.
White ho's only around
'cause she swallows nut...
and I can take her home
to Moms without any drama.
Word.
L.L. Douche Bag's
starting to piss me off.
Yeah, well, he gave us enough to put
his alibi to the taste test.
Pick up the girlfriend.
I'm gonna stick around.
[Julien]
You must've seen something.
The assailant had to walk past you
to leave that bathroom.
- I really didn't get a look at him.
- Get a booking slip going.
- I need you to stand, hands behind your back.
- What?
- Stand, hands behind your back.
- [Groans] You're arresting me?
- Public indecency, lewd conduct.
- I'm not the one who did anything.
You think maybe I've suffered enough?
I have a wife and daughters.
If they find out- Oh, Jesus.
Look, I don't normally
do this sort of thing.
- Just once or twice to work stuff out.
- In the cage.
Please, don't do this.
It'll ruin my marriage.
- Come on, sir. Come on.
- Please.
I don't have to say anything to you.
We were married, and I'm protected
under spousal privilege.
[Scoffs] He told you
to say that, didn't he?
'Cause it protects him.
You know you can waive
that right any time you want to, right?
Which is why he probably didn't even tell you
to get an attorney, did he?
You know he's got his own lawyer?
Maybe you saw her downstairs?
She's real pretty, dark-haired.
[Scoffs]
Such a good provider.
And yet, he's covering his ass,
he's covering his guys' ass...
and he leaves you
just hanging out there.
You know why?
'Cause he doesn't want you listening
to anybody else but him.
Your lawyer would, uh,
be looking after your interests.
And that doesn't help him.
That hurts him, in fact, so-
Your lawyer would advise you
to cooperate.
Tell me the truth.
Tell me what I want to know.
But you're here all alone.
You want to know what I see?
I mean, just looking at you?
I see a mother of three
going away for obstructing justice...
protecting a man
she knows is a criminal.
What are your two autistic children
gonna do when you're, like...
Iocked away and you're serving
your sentence? What are they gonna do?
- How are they gonna be in foster care?
- Stop it. Stop!
Tell me what I want to know.
I'm just asking you to tell me what-
Vic is not going to take care of those kids
when you're gone.
Vic gave me some cash
in a bag a little while ago.
That's it. I don't know anything else.
There's nothing else.
- How- How much?
- 65,000.
- Where'd it come from?
- I didn't ask. L-I never asked.
- And where is it?
- I spent most of it on tuition and on therapists.
There's-There's only-
There's only about $5,000 left.
I need that money.
I need that money back.
Now.
Now you can cry.
[Shane] You might want to rethink this
alibi you're handing Kasper.
'Cause we can put him in the crib where
Amado Alvaro got his brains splashed.
That's, uh-That's the guy who shot at you
and, uh, killed your friends.
If you're lying to cover
for your man-boy-toy...
we can get you on conspiracy
to commit murder.
[Shane] It's like pulling
the trigger yourself.
You'll be old and in the way
by the time you see the sky again.
I've got nothing to say.
Period. Point blank.
Kasper's got plenty
to say about you.
I get more black ass
than a bus bench in Compton.
- Ya heard?
- [Mackey Chuckles]
Hard for me to imagine you holding it down
with some Nubian mattress-monster.
[Kasper] Well, then you better
ask somebody, one-time.
Taneisha's my go-to girl.
She'll let me tear her fat ass
and sugar walls up any time I want.
White ho's only around
'cause she swallows nut-
- You all right?
- Don't talk to me.
- What happened?
- Not now. Just let me go.
- Corrine.
- [Shane] Vic?
Corrine, I'll call you.
Vic, Moni gave up
our friendly ghost.
What's wrong?
Hey, come on, man.
Let's go.
[Mackey] You know
the thing about women?
And it doesn't really matter
what color they are.
When they get pissed off, watch out.
Moni just threw your
pink-ass cheeks to the curb.
- You had the smarts, the business model.
- The stripper girlfriend.
What you didn't have was the street cred.
Not really.
Not like some hard-ass brother.
You're only a true baller
when somebody wants you dead.
And if the bullets miss you,
makes you immortal to the street, right?
So you hired Alvaro and Zeborio to shoot up
your friends. Make you look like the target.
Market yourself as some bad-ass dude
instead of a punk-ass white boy.
Man, you been smoking crack.
Your girl Moni
just gave us the key...
to her locker at the Cheetah,
where she stashed...
the TEC-9 you did
the two hit men with.
Shooter out of the way, you don't have
to pay for the hit, right?
The businessman in you saw
a way to save a buck.
Instead, it's gonna cost you
three to five dimes in the state pen.
Bitches ain't shit.
Your sister's a churchgoing woman.
You grow up that way?
Jesus is my savior.
That's what you mean?
That's what I love about the church.
No matter how bad
you are, how often...
forgiveness is always there.
All you gotta do is come clean.
- What's that gotta do with finding her?
- I don't know.
Maybe she started looking at you funny
after you murdered Lana.
Maybe she wanted to ask about it
but was too scared.
And then one day it all came out.
But you couldn't have that.
So you had her killed...
and reported her missing
so you could make yourselflook innocent.
Nol I didn't kill my sister.
That's my blood.
They're all somebody's blood,
Kleavon.
Didn't stop you then.
Why would it this time?
- Don't talk to me like that!
- I'll talk to you any way I goddamn please.
You can't arrest me, and you're not helping me.
I'll find her myself.
I'd be willing to make these charges go away
on two conditions.
- Anything you want.
- You never do this type of thing again.
- My word.
- And you help us I.D. The guy who did this.
[Chuckles]
Then I'll be involved in a court case.
I know how this works, my brother's a lawyer.
Either way, it's all public.
I'll keep your name out of this. But I cannot
get this guy and his 19 other rattraps...
off the street without your help.
The bridge ofhis nose is right,
but his cheekbones were higher.
Hey. You've decided
to cut him some slack?
Yeah. Lesser of two evils.
Gets the kook off the streets.
- You think we're looking for a vigilante?
- Ah, don't know.
Julien, you and I got off
to a rough start.
But I feel like things are
starting to make more sense.
Good.
Look, man, I grew up with my gay uncle
living with us...
so it's no big deal to me.
But I saw what he had to go through.
I honestly just didn't
get your situation.
I'm not sure what
you're trying to say.
All I'm saying is that I understand.
And it's between you
and your wife anyway. So I'm cool.
You're cool with what? That I'm the T.O.
That should've washed you out weeks ago?
You don't understand anything.
I know why you recommended me
for Robbery-Homicide.
There's no need to thank me.
You're getting sicker, and you
can't bear for me to see it.
A woman may be dead
because you wanted to protect me.
I shouldn't have done
the search without you. I'm sorry.
I do not let my illness
get in the way of my job.
You do.
That's dangerous.
I'm-I'm not leaving you.
Detectives? You wanted to be notified
of any black female dump-jobs.
Late 40s.
Probably strangled.
That's not Kleavon's M.O.
That's his sister.
Uni says it looks like rape.
His own sister?
It's not Fatima.
Who is it then?
Look at this.
- He chopped her hair off.
- Yeah.
Not with scissors.
Probably a knife?
You recognize the haircut?
Looks like I got
under Kleavon's skin after all.
Hey. Thanks for swinging by.
- I wanted to finish this in person.
- Me too.
If you didn't before, now you can see how
out of control Kavanaugh is.
I need to decide if I want to represent you.
Any of you.
First, you're a sacrificial lamb to appease
angry voters after that referendum tanked.
- We're the good guys in this.
- Only not that good.
Because then you tell me Aceveda
had you doing dirty work for him...
and is setting you up
to take the fall.
Today I find out this is about
capital murder on a cop.
Becca, it's a put-up job.
Right now, I have no clue about
who the hell you really are.
How can I help you with that?
I actually had a kernel of faith...
that you could take the guy down.
Now it just seems
like you've lost your senses.
You're under investigation,
Councilman.
- For what?
- Your connection with Mackey.
I don't understand how you could
be so gung ho to get this guy...
and yet be in his pocket
at the same time.
Something I gotta look at.
What? You still think that I helped Vic set you up
with that Russian sting?
Man, he got to you.
Playing us against each other.
You-You may as well fold up your tent
and go home.
One thing I know for sure:
When you sat in this office,
you could've put an end to him, but you didn't.
Now it's my turn.
You seriously think this little display
of yours is gonna work?
I need you to initial here, here...
and I'd really like
your signature here.
You're still a reserve cop, right?
I do have authority over you.
You walk out that door,
I'm gonna take your badge...
and I'm gonna tell
every reporter in town why.
Then you may as well add insubordination
to your list of bullshit allegations.
You want any paperwork signed,
you send it to my office.
- I'll have the City Attorney take a look at it.
- Fine.
I'm chairman
of the police committee.
This is a fight you don't want.
I didn't want any of it.
But I'm here...
and I'm staying.
Corrine, call me.
Kavanaugh's upstairs with Aceveda.
What the hell's going on?
It's almost 8:00
and he's still at it.
What do we do?
Just leave for the night?
- ##[Rock]
- ##[Man Singing]
##[Ends]
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Continues]
##[Ends]