Prevlously on The Shield.
Claudette.! She falnted.
She was out- Claudette.
- Vlc gave me some cash In a bag a whlle ago.
- How much?
- 65,000.
- I need that money. I need that money back.
When I was talkin' to Kavanaugh,
he was wearing a wedding ring.
He's been dlvorced, Ilke, two years.
You ever heard of a guy
named Antwon Mitchell?
I know that Mackey and his guys, they have
some connection with Antwon Mitchell.
- [Gunshots]
- If her body shows up with bullets in it...
from your two gats,
you'll be doin' time...
for a long, long time.
Waste your time with these
conspiracy theories...
and you'll find yourself
more lost than you are now.
About slx months ago, we found thls kllo of pure
heroln In the glove compartment of your car.
- You never logged it into Evidence.
- Why hasn't he arrested Lem?
We think Kavanaugh's gonna try
to get Emolia to give you up.
- You're not safe here anymore.
We gotta move you.
- Why? What happened?
- Got a couple possible leaks.
- You said Vic wouldn't find out.
- Vic! What the hell?
- You dldn't return any of my calls.
Kavanaugh,
what did you tell him?
- That I saw your guy take the heroin.
- Six months!
You could've warned me.!
One of my men...
- maybe all of us, are goin' to jail because of you.
- [Gasping]
Without you, I.A.D.'s
case goes away.
[Door Opens]
Oh, Jesus.
It's you.
[Man On Radlo]... reported today
that Saudl Arabla has offered...
- a proposal to Syria-
- [Radio Clicks Off]
[Brushlng Teeth]
[Teakettle Whlstllng]
[Whlstllng Stops]
[Brushlng Teeth]
[Ticking]
- [Door Buzzes]
- [Chatter]
- Antwon Mltchell.
- Well, you're the rlght color...
but for some reason
I feel that...
you're working on
the wrong side, brother.
Jon Kavanaugh, Internal Affairs,
Los Angeles.
- Really? What part?
- Lately I've been based in Farmington.
Don't tell me you have officers stealing
ghetto kids' bicycles and taking their candy.
Come on.
Say it ain't so, Joe.
You recognize these
gentlemen, I know.
Need to know everything
you know about these men.
You want everythlng.
I just need somethlng.
The pope hlmself couldn't get you
mercy tlme on those two cop kllllngs.
Let's just say I'm trylng
to keep hope allve, then.
I could see what I can do about your
accommodations and your privileges here.
I run this goddamn
place, man.
What Is It that you thlnk
I'm not gettlng up In here, huh?
Pussy?
I tore some of that shit up this morning,
and I'm not talking about the cell mate kind.
You're obviously
no fan of cops.
Here's your chance to help me put four
of them in a dark, dark corner.
See, now you're venturlng
Into an Interestlng area...
but I can't feed my peeps
with no moral victories.
How do I know you even
have shit on these guys?
Shane Vendrell?
I could bury thls
banjo-playln'asshole.
Bitch likes
to talk the walk...
but if you put a boot
on his throat...
his eyes tear up...
like a little bitch.
And bltches,
they glve up thelr buddles.
It's what makes 'em bitches.
The prlce Is slmple.
I help you put away these...
four fine young men...
you make sure you put them
away right here.
- You want them to spend their time here?
- Yes. That way every morning...
I can see their smiling faces
when I'm eating my oatmeal.
So you can kill them, huh?
You got me all wrong, mister.
- Scout's honor.
- No deal.
You know my name.
If your brain clears up...
glve me a collect call.
Sorry you wasted
that drive, Jon.
What was It?
Three, four hours?
You're forgetting-
Time's on my side.
That's where you're wrong.
You see, me-
I'm just livin'
one real long day.
You're the one who has
the tlcklng clock In hls ear.
Otherwise,
you wouldn't be here...
talking to a man like me.
You change your mind,
give me a call.
[Radio: Dispatcher]
Handle Code 3, 1 -Tango-10, roger that.
[Mackey On Radio]
6-Paul-11 to Control.
I'm Code 6
at 5029 King Drive.
We're gonna need additional units
for evacuation and a bomb squad.
You're not gonna belleve thls,
but someone tossed a bunch...
- of grenades Into a backyard barbecue.
- [Woman] Dld you say grenades?
- Yeah. Llve grenades.
- Stay right there. Hey.
[Slrens Walllng]
[Man]
There's a hostage.
- Hey. What happened?
- You here on I.A.D. Business or
you just visiting the front?
Just tell me what happened, all right?
Backyard barbecue. Somebody tossed
four or five grenades over the fence.
M-26.
Vietnam era, time-delay.
- That one's a dud.
- All clear.
Good.
Let's go.
- Victims?
- Spookstreet soldiers.
They're a local black set.
Frlends, glrlfrlends, klds.
Hey, l-
Found thls In the house.
Already cut, bagged
and welghed.
- It's a Spookstreet distribution crib.
- Gang retaliation?
If Spookstreet was beefing wlth someone,
we'd have heard about It.
Yeah, local sets around here don't
carry this kind of heavy artillery.
You mlght want to stand back. There's some
real pollce work golng on around here.
- [Curtls] Take thls around front?
- Sure.
2-nothing.
Kyle, thanks, man.
No problem, Jon.
You said you got a call last week
from an El Salvadoran contact...
offered you a job
assembling grenades?
Last week you said
I was a liar.
You've been feeding me bullshit lately,
trying to get out of testifying against Mackey.
Cut this for her, will ya?
A bunch of grenades
went off today.
Maybe now
you'll Ilsten to me.
I need you to tell me
what's golng on.
You want information? Then promise me
I won't have to testify against Vic or his guys.
We've been over this already. You not testifying
against Mackey- It's not gonna happen.
You're cutting the pieces
too big.
The only thing keeping you
out of jail...
and Sebastio out of a foster
home is my good grace.
So you tell me what you know
about those grenades...
or the next person cutting his food
is gonna be a social worker.
Owner of the Spookstreet house that
got bombed Is named Latasha Dunn.
- Son's name Is Marcus Dunn.
- Street name, "M.C. Dunn-Good."
Dunn-Good's a Spookstreet Ileutenant.
Why don't you and Ronnle go scoop hlm up?
- All right.
- Vic-
My C.I. Has intel. It's the Salvadorans.
I think she can help.
Emolia's friend Maria
contacted her last week.
The Salvadorans were looklng for glrls to
assemble a large shlpment of grenades.
You heard about this and you
didn't share it with anyone?
Yeah, well, we've all seen his nose for
quality intel is not exactly reliable.
She gave me tlps before.
Most of them were bogus.
So your maln wltness agalnst Lem's
unrellable. That's good to know.
- All rlght, so what now?
- My team will set up a meet
between Emolia and Maria.
We'll work our way backwards
to the grenade tossers.
You're not puttlng her In the field.
It's too dangerous.
She just told us there's
another shipment coming in.
You want every night here
to be the Fourth ofJuly?
All right.
Your team can run the investigation,
but any decisions involving Emolia...
- I have the final word.
- I don't run an op without making all the calls.
Neither Vic nor his team will have any
unsupervised contact with Emolia.
And they do anything on the sly
to threaten or coerce her...
- I'll pull her Immedlately.
- [Laughs]
And either myself or Agent Irwin
will be with her at all times, all right?
Do it.
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chatterlng]
##[Ends]
Hey.
Look, we can deal with other
stuff tomorrow.
What's important today is that
we track down these grenades.
Your safety, that's my number
one prlorlty.
You may have all worked out
a deal, but I haven't.
Now you want my help, I want
to know what's in it for me.
- That's not what we talked about.
- I need $20,000...
for Sebastio to get help,
like Vic's kid gets.
- Let's talk about this later, okay?
- No. Now.
This department's always
looked out for you.
You help us crack this, there'll be
something in it for you.
Maria says the bosses are
shipping grenades into L.A.
They're assembllng them here.
Otherwlse, they could explode
durlng shlpplng.
They're looking for cutters,
help 'em put them back together-
Nimble-fingered girls
they can trust.
- Why do the Salvadorans need grenades?
- They're making a play...
to get back into the drug
protection business.
The Colombians control the drugs. They
use the Mexicans to mule it from Bogotá...
into the black
dealers' hands in L.A.
Now the Salvadorans used to protect all of it-
mules, routes, distribution centers-
Till we busted their general, Bonilla,
last year, crippled their L.A. Power base.
Colombians exporting blow figured if
the Salvadorans couldn't protect themselves...
why pay them to protect
their product?
So they're bombing their way
back into their business? Extortion.
[Mackey]
Rlght.
Hope it's not too late
for you to get that job.
No.
But I'll need to call Maria.
Let's set up a meet.
Lleutenant.
- How's your partner?
- Getting better.
- Nasty fall.
- She'll be back soon.
I'm glad to hear it.
You, uh, finding anything
on the Strike Team?
- That investigation's ongoing.
- You checking into their finances?
Their money? If you're not
looking, you should be.
- What do you think I'd find?
- Not here. Later.
And don't talk to me out there
like we're friendly.
Kyle? What's-What's going on?
Why's Emolia moving?
Emolla's contact made a last-mlnute change,
moved the meet.
- Okay, follow her. Maintain a visual.
- Mackey disagrees.
Thlnks her contact mlght have
eyes out for a tall.
I don't care what he thinks.
Let's just move.
Look, she's wlred up. She's
got G.P.S. Tracklng on her cell.
She's got eyes and ears
on her at all times.
I never authorized
the use of a wire here.
Well, I know how much you love 'em,
I figured I'd try one for a change.
Give 'em a five minute
head start, then we follow.
- Oh, great.
- Kavanaugh's comlng.
Nothing like a large black man
wearing a suit...
- jumping into your van to maintain your cover.
- Is she okay?
- No reason why she wouldn't be.
- [Emolla On Radlo] Thls
the place we do the work?
[Woman] Not yet. There's someone
who needs to meet you first.
Tejado runs securlty.
Guardo Is In charge.
Come on.
Guardo.
- Who are they?
- [Man On Radlo Speaklng Spanlsh]
- I don't use.
- I check every glrl I hlre.
This isn't the same
as H-cutting.
You need cojones,
qulck fingers.
One mlstake, your face
gets blown off.
First, you reset the striker
in the fuse head.
Attach the spoon.
- He's assembling a live one.
- Lock the strlker In place
by Insertlng the safety pln.
You know,
once you remove the pln...
and the handle's released,
you have five seconds...
to put the spoon and the pin
back before it explodes.
There's a live grenade in there?
Catch.
No, no, no. It's okay.
He's bluffing.
[CIIcks]
That grenade wasn't armed.
[Laughs]
You never lost your nerve.
Tejado will call you
with instructions...
let you know when
and where to start working.
Come on.
Let's go.
- How'd you know he was bluffing?
- Because once you pull the pln
there's no turnlng back.
- He knew it wasn't live.
- Let's move.
- Make the bust.
- No. It's too early.
We bust them now, we only get
a couple of players off the street.
There'll still be
grenades out there.
We squeeze Tejado and Guardo, and then
they glve It up. That's what we do.
Fresh off the boat
Salvadorans rarely rat.
- They'll take a needle before they talk to cops.
- We follow Guardo.
- Let him lead us to the grenades.
- He must be parked out back.
Hey, hey.
Emolia's still up there.
They bought her cover. She's fine.
I don't move now we're gonna lose him.
- Let's go.
- We're not leaving Emolia here.
All rlght, all rlght.
Make sure Emolla's all rlght.
We'll find Guardo
on the street.
- How'd It go?
- They bought her cover.
They're gonna call wlth
a tlme and place.
In the meantime she'll wait up
in Observation.
Marcus Dunn-
A.K.A. M.C. Dunn-Good.
Hls mother's house was hlt thls mornlng.
Found a drugstore In hls bedroom closet.
You and Ronnie hit the street.
Find out whatever you can about Guardo.
- We'll take M.C. "Dumb-shit"
upstairs, have a little chat.
- Come on, let's go.
Uh, Lleutenant,
you've got a telephone call.
- Can you take a message for me, please?
- They said it's urgent.
- Who said?
- She says her name's Sadie.
Excuse me.
Sadie?
Detective? I need you to give me a ride
to the 300 block of Forestry Street.
- What's there?
- A crime scene.
- You're gonna be the primary.
- I've got work, and you don't
hand out my assignments.
Do I have to remind you
how many rungs...
detective falls below lieutenant
on the department ladder?
You get your ass out of that chalr
and you meet me In the motor pool...
before I open an insubordination file on you
and put your picture up on my wall.
Come on!
I was only making sure I wasn't too
friendly to you on the floor.
Come on, man. I was just maintaining your
cop cred with the other I.A.D. Haters.
You should be thanking me.
Next time, I'd prefer
the silent treatment.
So? Mackey's finances?
You ever hear of
an Armenian money train?
It's a money launderlng
operatlon of the Armenlan mob.
I think the Strike Team
ripped them off.
- Dangerous enemies to make.
- Not if you get away with it.
And I thlnk we're talklng
about a lot of money.
Mackey gave his ex 65 grand in cash
they can't account for.
Corrine's got nothing to do
with anything illegal.
This is-
This is all Vic.
Can I get a look at your notes?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
So what's this case?
I got a call from my ex,
Sadie.
She was just raped.
Is that too tlght?
Breathe normally.
Jon.
Are you all right?
I don't know.
What happened?
She was attacked
as she got out of her car...
dragged to the other side of the vehicle,
out of sight of anyone passing by.
And no witnesses yet.
We need to get her to a hospital
right away. Do a kit.
I stopped him. I stopped him
in the middle.
I fought back
like you taught me.
I hit him
and I hit him and...
I hit him until he got
off of me and he ran.
- L-l-I refused to be the victim.
- The victim. I know.
That's good. This is
Detective Wagenbach.
He's gonna be handllng
thls Investlgatlon, okay?
We're gonna take
good care of you, ma'am.
Did you, uh, get a good
look at your attacker?
Mexlcan.
Um, mld-30s.
Dark eyes
and a mole.
Right here.
I took a plcture ofhlm
In my head when I was...
fighting him 'cause you,
you always said-
I know. I know. You did great.
You did great.
Next thing is these officers
here, they're gonna-
they're gonna take you to the hospltal,
and they're gonna do some tests...
to preserve evidence, okay?
You-You're gonna
be with me, right?
I'm gonna ride with you
to the hospital...
and then I just gotta
check on a few things.
Stay with me.
You need privacy.
You do.
Don't leave me.
- Jon.
- I'm gonna be right back after the tests are done.
Okay? Okay?
You let me take care
of everything. Okay?
Look, we can sit here
all day, Marcus.
That's not gonna change the fact
that you got a big problem.
Yeah. I know.
The Salvadoreans want back in
on the drug protection business.
Now, tell me some shlt
I don't know.
So Spookstreet's just gonna slt on thelr
hands whlle they blow up all your drug crlbs?
It's time to make peace, man.
I told you. The bosses in Bogotá
ain't gonna go for that.
Well, the bosses aren't having
grenades shoved up their asses.
Colombians control the product. They make
the rules. Ain't shit I can do about that.
Then give me the addresses of the other
drug cribs so I can stop them myself.
Yeah, rlght. How stupld
do y'all thlnk I am?
Never ask a questlon
you don't want the answer to.
Y'all can keep sendln'In the clowns all day,
aln't gonna change shlt.
I'm the one player In thls room
who's got anyjulce.
- [Scoffs]
- How'd you get scratched up, son?
- It really matter?
- Internal Affairs. It does if I believe you.
You the one and only man?
- Prove it.
- [Beeping]
- District Attorney Eric Zuckerman.
- [Line Ringing]
- [Man On Phone] Hello?
- Eric. Jon Kavanaugh.
- What's up, Johnny?
- You hear about that house In
Farmlngton got hlt by grenades?
Yeah. That's some
pretty freaky shlt.
Looks like Salvadoran bangers
are planning to hit a couple more.
[Zuckerman]
That's not good.
I got a perp looklng at
a possesslon wlth Intent rap...
willing to trade us the addresses
of possible targets...
- if we let him skate on just possession.
- Wrlte It. Send It to my office.
- You need to hear any more?
- I trust you.
- All rlght, cool. I'll talk to you later.
- I'll be here, Jon.
- My nigga.
- All right. Give up the addresses.
Those cribs get busted off my tip,
you might as well stick a needle in me.
We'll give you a half hour to call your homies.
Let 'em get the merchandise out...
before the cavalry
arrives.
Can I use your phone?
[No Audible Dialogue]
Lieutenant.
- Ms. Mackey.
- Jon, I helped treat Sadie. Took a rape kit.
- And?
- There's some minor tearing and trauma.
- Skin under her fingernails?
- No, but she sald she punched
hlm and dldn't scratch, so-
- D.N.A.?
- She fought him off pretty quickly.
- It's almost like-
- What, it's not a rape because
it didn't last that long?
No. I was gonna say that thls guy
got more than he bargalned for.
- She's a- She's a fighter.
- She okay to come down to the Barn?
I'll have to ask her doctor,
but, um, I think so.
- She's that way.
- Excuse me.
- Sure.
No. H-H-He had a mole.
- Right here on his cheek.
- You're doing good.
- Just keep looking.
- Yeah. Don't worry. Take your time.
- Keep looking. Okay.
- Hi.
- Hi. How's it going?
- We've been showing her our
sexual assault regulars.
No hits yet.
Guys, give me a second?
Just a second.
- I'm trying-
- You know what?
I'm gonna get you
some clean clothes...
and I'm gonna take you
down to where I work, okay?
Why don't you get
cleaned up and everythlng?
Sadie, you know I'm here
for you, right?
Jon Kavanaugh.
- Emolia? Where's Emolia?
- Inside.
There you are.
Why'd you bring her here?
Uniforms pulled over a Salvadoran a block
away who fit Guardo's description.
Mackey wanted her here
to make a quick I.D. It wasn't him.
- What if somebody saw her?
She could've been compromised.
- You were off the grld...
- so I made a command decision.
- What, to get her killed?
That'd be great for you, wouldn't it?
You been with her every second?
- Yeah.
- He didn't try to talk to her?
- No.
- So, what happened?
Four grenades were thrown
through four windows simultaneously.
The house was hit on all sides.
A gas pipe exploded in the kitchen.
Whoever tossed them wanted to make
sure no one made it out alive.
- This isn't one of the addresses
that Marcus Dunn gave us.
- [Mackey] No, It Isn't.
George and MattieJackson,
retired schoolteachers.
So it's not a Spookstreet
drug crib?
Only drug we found was some Metamucil
in the medicine cabinet.
- Must've been taklng a nap
when the grenades came knocklng.
- So, what? Marcus Iled?
- Gave us a bad list?
- An old list.
We busted this place last year.
Spookstreeter named Gat
used to bunk here...
untll Rawllng selzed It,
put It up for auctlon.
Salvadorans were protecting Spookstreet
product last year, they'd know this place.
This was an old drug crib.
Last year's.
Yeah. The Salvadorans are
workin' on an out-of-date list.
- How old a list we talkin' about?
- About a year-
Ayear. Maybe two. Write down
as many as you can remember.
I'll do my best, but
I ain't got a memory for this.
You can take hlm.
Sadie I.D.'d a suspect
out of a mug book.
Emmanuel Olivo. I've got
him in Interrogation.
You seem to be unclear
on the concept of parole, Emmanuel.
See, we give you an early chance at freedom,
you return the favor by not raping anyone.
- Who's he?
- Where were you thls mornlng about 10::00?
- Filling out job applications.
- Where?
All around. It's not that easy.
Gotta report my status.
As a registered sex offender.
You sure you didn't take
a break between references...
to rape a woman in a parking lot off
Forestry Street this morning?
- Hell no.
- You remember where you
filled out those appllcatlons?
- Not the names.
- It would help provide you with an alibi.
Yeah, but I don't got it.
- He's lying. Can't you see that?
- Yeah.
It's just a couple things
bother me.
His previous sexual assaults were against
teenage girls, not adult women-
- Assaults that we know about.
- Yeah.
Also Sadie referenced a mole
a couple of times. Olivo doesn't have one.
That's one detail off.
All the others match though.
- You gonna put him in front of Sadie to make sure?
- Yeah.
I already brought her
down here.
Llsten, about Sadle-
- You ready, Vlc?
- What the- Shit.
Can you hold on a second?
Sadie, I'll be right back.
Get her started, all right?
Hey, hey!
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
Where-Where you-
Where you going?
Emolia's contact
just called us.
They're assembling grenades above
a furniture store. I used to cut "H" there.
- They want me rlght away.
- We're gonna drop her off.
Let Guardo make the pickup,
and then we'll sweep in and bust his crew.
And the list of Spookstreet drug cribs Marcus
Dunn gave us? You got that done already?
Billings is sending units to clear out
the tenants that live there...
and post cops in front
of each one.
Guardo won't, uh- He won't be making
that pickup for another couple hours.
Make sure Emolia gets in safely, and you give
me a call if anything changes.
- Yes, sir.
- Someplace important you need to be?
- How we doing?
- Better.
Sadle posltlvely Identlfied
Emmanuel OIIvo as her attacker.
I'm proud of you.
So strong.
- Can I, uh-
- Yeah.
Uh, excuse me.
- Come home tonlght.
- N-No.
It's time to come home.
Our bed misses you.
- Let me take care of you for now, all rlght?
- You gotta stop wearing that.
It doesn't feel rlght.
Sadie.
Sadie, come home.
Don't keep askin'...
'cause at some point
I'm gonna say, "Yes," and...
then what kind of trouble
are we gonna be in?
[Dutch]
Lleutenant.
Lleutenant?
Lleutenant Kavanaugh?
Excuse me for a second.
- You can't give me a minute? I just need-
- Yeah. L-I'm sorry.
Sh-She okay?
Yeah. She's great.
Thank you. Really.
I appreciate you
closing this up for me.
You don't-You don't know
how much I appreciate it.
That's the thing. It's not-
It's not really closed.
Why didn't you tell me that Sadie
has a history of mental illness?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Jesus Christ!
- You've been digging up dirt on her? Huh?
- Okay, okay, okay.
- I've been investigating the claims of a witness-
- A victim!
A victim.
Right. Right.
- But we have no physical evidence.
- Because she fought him off.
Okay, okay.
Right, and we are-
We are all grateful
for that...
but it presents problems
if the case goes to trial.
You see? She's our sole witness
and she's got a history of mental illness.
It's all in the past.
O- Okay.
How bad was it?
Few years ago
she had a rough patch.
She, uh-
Paranoia. Psychosis.
Depression.
- We're talkin' depression.
- Dementia?
- Difficulty understanding reality?
- No.
She always knew who she was
and where she was. She just-
Shejust became dlfferent,
all rlght?
- Okay. A-And now?
- We got divorced, and she went
and found some doctors.
They treated her.
She's fine.
- She's back.
- She's reliable?
- Yes. That's what I'm telling you.
- She's solid?
- Yes.
- 'Cause we don't have any corroborating evidence.
Then why don't you get back
to the goddamn crime scene...
with some extra hands
and find the evidence...
that you require to put the man
who raped my wife behind bars.
[Door Slams]
- I have to stay?
- Uh, just a little bit longer.
Room upstalrs. A couch
where you can Ile down.
Go upstairs and lie down,
all right?
Left at the top, first door
on your left.
I'm gonna check on you
In a mlnute.
I'll be there
in a minute. Okay?
- Ms. Mackey.
- How is she?
- She's better.
- Good. This is my attorney, Sydney Driber.
Lieutenant Kavanaugh.
The money I promised to
turn in. It's all there.
Log this into Evidence for me, please.
My cllent wlshes to cooperate
fully wlth your Investlgatlon.
She never engaged in any
criminal behavior...
she seeks only to secure Immunlty
agalnst any prosecutlon...
In exchange for what she knows
about her ex-husband's past.
You ready to tell the truth, the whole truth,
nothin' but the truth, so help you God?
- Yes, yes.
- Assuming an arrangement can be made.
Did Detective Wagenbach arrange or suggest
for you to be the attending nurse for Sadie today?
You're here to tell
the truth or you're not.
He suggested it, okay?
He said that if I helped her, it might earn
goodwill with you. Is that wrong?
There is nothing illegal about a registered
nurse caring for a patient.
- No. Wasn't wrong of you.
- Dutch didn't do anything wrong.
- Sorry.
- He was trying to help me out.
- I don't have time right now to discuss any deal...
- [Rlnglng]
Even If I was amenable to one, whlch
I wlll have to take under conslderatlon...
but I do thank you
for bringing in the money.
- Kavanaugh. Yeah.
- [Door Buzzes]
Guardo showed up early.
He's moving the girls and the grenades.
- Where's Emolla now?
- Tracking her G.P.S. We're all over her.
- Pull her over. I want her out of there.
- Turned west on Stanley.
- They're stopping.
- We bust them now, they'll tip the other location.
Look, this is a black hole we're sending
her into. We know nothing.
Emolia knows how to take care of herself.
She fooled me for six months.
Are you-Are you trylng
to get her kllled?
- Huh?
- Good. Great. Glad we're on the same page.
Shit.
All rlght, Ilsten, we mlght have
to move In qulck and qulet.
- Everyone turn off their cell phones.
- [Beeplng]
[Speaking Spanish]
- Where's SWAT? You sald
SWATwas gonna be here.
- Should be here any minute.
- They got MP5's?
- At least two dozen.
Looks Ilke they're plannlng
to set up shop permanently.
It's a goddamn
armory In there.
How long before backup
and SWAT arrive?
- Ten, 15 minutes, tops.
- [Man On Radlo] Guardo, we're short a grenade.
- Are you sure?
- I counted twice.
Stop. Stop.!
Search her.
Guardo.
[Gasps] I only-
I only was gonna sell it for money.
There's so many,
I didn't think you'd care.
- [Clicks]
- [Gags]
- What's going on?
- It's hard to tell.
[Guardo]
Check the others.
- They're gonna find the wire!
- Go. Go, go. Get out.
This one's wearing a wire.
- You told me I could trust this puta.!
- Vic! Help me!
[Shouting, Clamoring]
Get 'em up! Up!
[Shouting, Indistinct]
On the ground.!
Rlght now, on the ground.!
- [Grunting]
- [Shouting]
[Grunts]
[Man]
Okay. I glve.
- Grenade.!
- Down.!
Where do you think
you're going?
- [Glass Shatterlng]
- Okay?
Yeah.
We're all clear.
- Clear.
Emolia!
Kyle! Where is she?
I don't see her.
You take hlm.
Emolla.!
Mackey!
- [Whispering] As long as you do-
- Emolia!
What dld you
Just say to her?
I just told her
what a good job she did.
And what Is she dolng
back here?
- I was getting her out of harm's way.
- Hey, Guardo's gone.
Grab Lem and Ronnie
and set up a perimeter.
Let's scoop him up.
There's no slgn
of Guardo anywhere.
My guys will squeeze the soldiers, find out
who he is, where he likes to hide.
Hey, Captaln, somebody rlpped off
the vendlng machlnes agaln.
Goddamn It. These thlngs
cost a fortune to fix.
Jon.
[Laughs] No wonder these guys
get away with murder.
The captaln's more concerned wlth
the sandwlch machlne than wlth personnel.
Plck up her son
and her mother.
Don't let anyone know where she is-
Anyone.
Okay.
- What's up?
- [Indlstlnct]
I always knew you had
some good cop in you.
You bailed me out, man.
Let me return the favor to you.
Quit chasing me and Vic.
Let us do our jobs.
Curtis, do you really want to
go to jail for that guy?
Do you think that he would've
picked up that grenade and saved me?
- That he would save you?
- Look, Vic is a great cop.
He's a great cop,
all right?
- Curtis-
- A real cop would see that.
Hear me, please.
I'm giving you one last chance.
- Give me Vic. Don't throw your life away for him.
- What's golng on here?
Man, this guy just won't
back off, man.
Keeps threatening
to send me to jail.
Thls man saves your Ilfe...
and you show him your gratitude
by offering him jail time?
It's no wonder
you're I.A.D.'s M.V.P.
Ten square blocks around
Sadie's crime scene...
are plastered with
flyers like that one...
warning the community about a registered
sex crime offender in their neighborhood.
Note the mole on hls cheek-At least
It appears to be a mole at first glance.
It's really an ink stain.
It's on all the flyers.
She I.D.'d him off that,
not because he attacked her.
She works in the neighborhood.
She probably saw the flyer, when he
raped her, the memory came back.
- This doesn't change what happened.
- I went back to Olivo...
told him about the rape hanging over
his head and he came clean.
He wasn't filling out job
applications.
He was at a local high school watching
the girls' cross-country team run laps.
He dldn't tell us before 'cause
It's a vlolatlon ofhls parole.
Of course he's gonna admit to
that before admitting to rape.
The coach saw him
hanging around.
We, uh, found this bottle in the nearest
trash can near Sadie's parking lot.
There's vaginal residue,
pubic hair...
all over the mouth
and outslde of the bottle.
Now maybe it was used in the attack,
but she never mentioned it...
and she's polntlng a finger at
a perverted but Innocent guy.
Where is she?
- I wonder what that's all about.
- I don't know.
Whoever the woman Is, she's
got hlm pretty shook up.
How long till I can leave?
Not long.
L-I'm meeting someone tonight.
- How you feeling, Sadie? You okay?
- Yeah, I've been good.
Been real good.
L-l- I made
a life for myself.
- I know you dldn't thlnk
I could do that on my own.
- Same medications?
Same- Same dosages?
- Jon-
- I just wanna know which Sadie
I'm talking to right now.
Ask me to come back again.
I'm asking
for the truth, Sadie.
The truth is you've lost
some weight...
haven't you?
Why doesn't It look healthy,
though, Jon?
I mean,
what's going on with you?
Have you been missing me?
- Ex-wife.
- But he keeps wearlng the weddlng rlng.
Sometlmes you just gotta
let the pussy go.
I'm asking for the truth
about this morning.
About the rape.
- I want you to kill him for doing it.
- Klll what?
A soda bottle?
Ask me to come home, Jon.
I'll say, "Yes." I am ready to come home
to our bed now.
I am.
Please, just ask.
You're gonna be charged with
filing a false police report...
and you're gonna be remanded
for psychiatric care.
That's what you have to do.
I'm-I'm-I'm not sick
like I used to be.
No, l- No, I've been taklng
my medlcatlon. No, I'm fine.
Sadle, you took a soda bottle
and you shoved It up yourself-
But I knew what I was-
I knew what I was doing.
No, listen. No, listen.
No, it was wrong...
but I knew.
I wasn't confused.
L- I just dldn't know how else
to talk to you.
You pick up the damn phone.
- You just call me on the phone.
- Yeah, but I wanted you to be able to save me.
See, I did it
'cause I knew...
you want to save me...
Jon.
To de- deserve me again.
Because I want
to come home now, Jon.
I'm ready.
I'm ready to come home now.
So, just-
God, just ask me already.
Come on.
Jon.
You're gonna be charged...
with filing
a false police report.
You're gonna be remanded
for psychiatric care.
No.
That detective...
he's done everything
you've asked him to do.
So you just tell him
that it was a mistake.
- I can't.
- Yeah, you can.
I won't.
- You're gonna abandon me again, Jon?
- No.
Like-Like the last time?
You're-
You're gonna leave me
alone again?
- I'm going to help you.
- Then take me home.
I can't.
There are rules.
- Then break one.
- What I do is I stop cops from breaking the rules.
I can't stop them
if I can't stop myself.
Then you try bending one
just once.
I'm an Internal Affairs
lieutenant. That's-
- That's who I am.
- And I am your goddamn wife...
and when I got sick...
you left me alone, Jon!
You shlt all over me...
[Sobblng] and the rest of the world
shlt all over me.!
- I couldn't take care of you.
- You tell the truth.
- You didn't want to!
- I was...
- tired.
- Of taking care of your wife?
- So you left.
- I'm sorry.
You can shove "sorry"...
right up there
with the pop bottle.
- Don't say that, okay?
- [Sobbing] I wasn't worth taking care of...
- and now I'm not worth shit and you-
- It's okay.
- No! I wanna go home!
- I want to go home. No.
- Shh.
L- Please?
- Please?
- Holy shit.
At least we found
his weak spot.
[Sadle Sobblng]
I wanna go home.
It's all right.
- [Sobbing]
- It's okay.
Everyone sees what I am.
Everyone sees me.
[Sobs]
They all see.
- Well, Jon-
- Shit! Go!
- [Sadle] Don't leave me.!
- Hey!
Hey.
You.
You're under arrest for possession
of heroin with intent to distribute.
Today? What, you're gonna
arrest me today?
- Give me your badge and gun.
- You're kidding me.
- Glve me your badge and gun.
- No. Get off me, man.
- Get your hands off him.
- You touch me, you're gonna go
in the jail cell next to him.
Hey, Curtls.!
Don't be stupld, Curtls.
You give me your badge
and your gun!
Captain Billings. You take his badge
and you take his gun now!
Now.
- [Phones Ringing]
- [Pollce Radlo, Indlstlnct]
- It's okay.
- Officers, arrest that man.
You arrest him or you're gonna
lose your jobs.
[Man] You gotta be klddln'me.
You gotta be klddln'me.
[Man]
Do It In publlc? Wow.
Let's go.
Let's go. Let's go!
- Get him printed.
- We're out of ink.
You stlck hlm In the cage
untll you're ready.
He's a cop.
You don't put hlm In there.
- Clean out one of the other cages.
- No. He's going in there.
Right now. Let's go.
Officer, come over here, uncuffhlm,
stlck hlm In the cage.
Let's go.!
Yeah. Come on.
Have a seat.
[Door Buzzes]
Here you go, Mitchell.
Inside.
You woke me up out
of my beauty sleep, man.
Yeah, I can see that.
I need a second with him.
[Door Buzzes]
I need you to tell me
everythlng-
Everything that you know about
Mackey and the Strike Team.
Llke I told you before...
no deal, no info.
- Get me back to my cell.
- You got your deal.
As long as you give me
what it is I need to know.
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chatterlng]
##[Contlnues]
##[Ends]