- Previously on The Shield.
- It's Terry Crowley...
one of my guys killed by a drug dealer
a couple years ago.
That is one version. If you could have your
clients walk me through the house...
- where Terry Crowley was
killed, that would be great.
- Hey!
- [Groans]
- [Kavanaugh] Terry was working forJustice...
investigating allegations of a relationship
between drug dealers and your clients.
Officer Danielle Sofer
is filing paperwork...
admitting to a sexual relationship
with Vic over the last couple of years.
Officer Sofer is
now pregnant.
- I need to know everything
you know about these men.
- The price is simple.
I help you put away
these fine young men...
- you make sure you put them away right here.
- So you can kill them, huh?
I made a life for myself.
You been missing me?
- Ex-wife.
- Ask me to come back again.
- You're gonna be remanded for psychiatric care.
- I am your goddamn wife.
- At least we found his weak spot.
- Oh, Jon!
- Shit! Go!
...leave mel
Hey! You're under arrest...
for possession of heroin
with intent to distribute!
I need you to tell me everything that
you know about Mackey and his Strike Team.
- No deal.
- You got your deal.
[Door Buzzes]
[Man #1]
Bell, Brown, off to the dayroom.
[Man #2] What you lookin'at
with your punk-ass?
[Man #1]
Menendez, Wilson.
[Chattering]
- [Man Speaking Spanish, Indistinct]
- [Laughter]
[Man Speaking Spanish,
Indistinct]
- [Man #3] Yeah.
- [Man #4] Yeah. What happened?
[Door Buzzes]
[Man Speaking Spanish]
- [Man #5] Ten minutes.
- [Door Slams]
- [Sighs]
- How's it going?
I'm all right.
Wh-What's goin' on?
- We got a plan?
- Yeah. Get you the hell out of here.
Did Mara back off putting up her
and Shane's house as collateral?
- We're still working on bail.
- Right.
But Kavanaugh had the I.R.S.
Freeze our assets, all of us.
So I'm stuck.
I mean, there's no way you're coming
up with a hundred thousand dollars.
I've already filed a motion
to have your bail reduced.
Okay. How long do you think
I need to hold out for?
You listen to me. Twenty-four hours,
you're outta here.
Tomorrow night, you sleep in your own bed.
You just gotta stay good for 24.
All right. All right.
[Police Radio, Indistinct]
Take the back.
[Man]
Don't move. Stay over there.
- Don't move, damn it!
- Policel
- Drop your weapon!
- It's okay. Don't shoot.
- I said drop your weapon
or I'm gonna shoot! Goddamn it!
- I'm a copl
Drop your weapon nowl
Stopl Stop right therel
- Get on your knees! Get on your knees!
- Nice work.
Rookie, right?
- Tinal
- Man, tell your partner not to shoot.
- He's undercover.
- I didn't know.
- He didn't identify himself.
- His right arm!
- It's the color of the day.
- Which makes you "Ditz of the Month," honey.
- [Car Alarm Blaring]
- [Police Radio, Indistinct]
- Terry went down here?
- Uh, yeah.
About where the chair is.
Uh, Two-Time came out blastin'.
Terry went down.
We fired back.
Ballistics gave Vic
the kill shot.
Well, I must've been
a close second.
Off my game, I guess.
Were you off your game when
Angie Stubbs got murdered?
Your bullet got the kill shot
on that one.
Gun wasn't in my hand.
- Right. Angie's death got
pinned on Antwon Mitchell.
- Nothing got pinned.
- He killed her.
- Right. I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Uh, you just watched.
Mitchell ever
give you any money?
- Put you on his payroll?
- He was undercover. It's all documented.
Not all of it.
The drug payoffs.
Not the One-niner pimps
you were shaking down.
Not the nights and days that you spent
being Antwon Mitchell's bought bitch.
- You think that I don't know about that?
- We are here to talk...
about Terry Crowley-
Otherwise, we'll be going.
Sure.
- Stay right here.
- Just relax, asshole.
- I'm just coppin' a squat, all right?
- Detective Mackey.
Come on up.
According to you, Terry entered
the room before it was cleared.
I failed to clear
the bathroom.
I looked.
I thought it was clear,
but Two-Time...
must've been
behind the wall.
There were noises, uh, movements
from the other side of the house...
Shane and I started
that way.
I moved on before I should've.
I'm gonna have to
live with that.
Soon as I turned around,
about two seconds...
heard the shot.
Terry fell.
We returned fire.
Now we can run this six more times,
Two-Time's always gonna have the gun.
- Terry's always gonna be dead.
- [Man] Right.
You got some kind
of a problem?
Thought you'd remember Drew
from Terry's funeral...
but no matter.
Drew Crowley, Vic Mackey.
Doesn't remember 'cause he never
looked at me or my family that day.
Formerly Officer Drew Crowley,
San Diego.
Left the force after
his brother was murdered.
- Mothers, you know.
- I just wanted to see your face...
- here, where my brother died.
- Of all the underhanded...
- bullshit!
- I want to know the truth.
What happened to my brother?
- Get him out. Right now!
- Tell the truth, you son of a bitchl
- Hey. No, no.
- Lf you killed him, God'll know.
My brother was a good man.
I'm sorry what
happened to him.
It went down
just like I said.
Come on, Vic. Let's go.
Let's get out ofhere.
If you're lying,
God will have your soul...
and I will give it
to him personally!
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Ends]
All our stories matched up. Maybe
now he'll give up this bullshit case.
- Move on to shit we actually did.
- All bullshit.
This was about rubbing our faces
into intel he's already uncovered.
- Like what?
- He knew all about the pimps
me and Army were bleeding.
- How the hell he get that?
- I don't know.
- Antwon maybe?
- No. He'd never give up anything for nothing...
and with his stretch for double capital,
there's nothing to give him.
- Army?
- No.
- Halpern.
- Maybe Rawling?
- No. She didn't know these kind of details.
- Could be some One-niner.
- Could be Lem.
- Stop that shit.
I'm not saying it was Lem. I'm just-
I thought we were just listing possibilities.
Well, don't. We gotta stay focused
on getting Lem outta there.
This is the last night
he spends in County.
- Well, we got about 700 in cash
and three frozen bank accounts.
- That's it?
- Yeah.
- Lem's kin is trailer park trash.
Couldn't spare the money.
Big Powerball this weekend.
So, we gotta find a hundred
grand on the street.
Just lying around?
With Kavanaugh watching us?
He's fixated on the past,
not the present.
You're wrong. We'll end up
keeping Lem company.
We're not leaving him in there.
I promised him.
Yeah.
- Construction worker called it in.
- Whoa.
Talk about a dump job.
Okay.
Uh, maybe the murder occurs around here,
probably in the heat of the moment.
Killer panics, sees this as the best possible
way to dispose of a body.
Hopes it gets carted away
before it's discovered.
- What do you think?
- Sounds good to me.
- Partner coming back anytime soon?
- Couple of weeks.
Let's go.
[Sighs]
Hey, kids ready? I might have
to drop them back off early.
- My money's been frozen.
- What?
Checking, savings, debit cards.
I can't even buy groceries.
Shit! I'm sorry.
I just need some time-
I can't-I can't be around you,
and neither can the kids.
- It's not me, it's the lawyer.
- I was the one who told you
to hire the asshole, remember?
- To protect you.
- In order to do that...
I have to create a pattern
of distancing myself from you.
Listen, it's only temporary until
you sort these legal matters out.
- Hey, sweetheart. Hi.
- You should go.
Please. Mom's been
crying all morning.
- Look, at least let me give you some cash. Here.
- No, Vic.
Vic, Vic, Vic, I can't. I'm sorry.
Look, we're gonna sort this all out.
We will. We'll figure
something else out.
Okay?
If you need me,
I'll be at work.
[Indistinct]
Hey, Captain? Captain,
this is Detective Hoffman.
He had an incident with
Officer Hanlon last night.
You got an office somewhere
where I can bitch in private?
I like hanging with my cops.
We can talk here.
Tina failed to identify Hoffman
as an undercover officer.
First, she nearly blew
my head off...
- then allowed the perp to escape.
- He was clearly wearing the color of the day.
Julien put a report
on your desk this morning.
We'll take all necessary steps
to ensure this doesn't happen again.
You know, I live with lowlifes,
smelling like piss and shit...
so guys like you don't have
to get your suits dirty.
I get enough guns to my head
without Barbie adding to the action.
- You expect me to fire her?
- Look, I've tried with Tina, sir. So has Julien.
She doesn't get it. She never will
until it's too late.
She's a woman, Latina besides. There's, like,
three hoops to jump through to can her.
Well, you know what? She's gonna land
herself or someone else in a body bag.
Look, your girl saw this color,
not the color on my arm.
All right, you handle it
any way you like.
Look, being captain's about tough choices.
I'll take care of it.
- Hey, man.
- Hey, how you doin'?
- Any asshole sightings today?
- Not yet.
- Guess even rats have to sleep.
- [Laughs]
- Isn't it your day off?
- My kids got sick.
Wanted to see if you had anything
juicy I could sink my teeth into.
There's some new chicken potpies
in the Quick-Mealer.
What about that loan shark over on Clinton?
Newman and his team still set up on him?
He cut a deal.
We got two to six.
- Shit.
- Uh, Vic, there's a girl...
- who's been waiting to meet
you or one of your guys.
- All right. Give me a second.
What about that dealer on the Decks?
Uh, what's his name-
- Felonious T?
- Intel says he's hanging up his dealer hat-
Been busy making a documentary
of the streets, or some shit.
- Can't wait to see that.
- Yeah.
- You looking for me?
- You Mackey?
- Antwon Mitchell needs a sit-down with you.
- That dickhead sent you?
- Gave me a message.
- Stand up and put your hands against the wall.
[Scoffs]
Go to hell.
Your incarcerated old man
wants to fly a kite? Let 'er rip.
Told me to ask what you're
willing to put on the table.
- For what?
- To keep your boy, Curtis, alive.
Stop playing games or you're gonna
get matching his and her cells.
Your cop buddy's headed
for Lompoc.
- Gonna be in the same cellblock
with Antwon real soon.
- Horseshit.
Ask the other cop,
the big brother.
- He made the deal with Antwon.
- Kavanaugh?
Even a douche bag like Kavanaugh wouldn't
jump into bed with Antwon Mitchell.
God knows what kind
of diseases you'd get.
Ask him- But do it quick.
Antwon don't like waiting.
Said make sure you know, offer
of protection ain't out there for long.
You tell Antwon I'll put a bullet
in that fat head of his myself...
- before I'll let him kill another cop.
- Tell him yourself.
Sounds like it's just a matter of time
before you follow your boy inside.
- Get the hell out of here!
- Get your hands off!
You just giving Antwon more reason
to make it worse on your boy.
[Chuckles]
- Open it!
- [Door Buzzes]
- What do you got?
- Nothing. Huh?
- Your face is red.
- You're back.
- [Sighs] And what a pleasure it is.
- Doc said another two weeks.
I can recuperate better at
my desk than I can in my bed.
- What are we working?
- Your knee?
Knee, ankle-
The whole shebang.
I fell pretty hard.
What have we got?
Uh, dump job.
Artemis Cooke, 43, black male.
- Shot in the face, stuffed in a Dumpster.
- And no next of kin?
Uh, mother.
I've got her upstairs.
Oh.
Come on. Pick up the pace.
Artemis was always
hardworking.
All sorts of jobs.
- Where was he working now?
- Ambulance company.
Drove body organs to Canada.
Company paid him to paint his van up.
Very professional.
- Uh, body organs?
- You know, they take 'em...
just before you die, give 'em
to people who need 'em.
- You mean donor organs?
- I guess they have a big need up north.
You can ask his buddy, DeKnight.
He helps him load up sometimes.
Your attempts to drive a wedge between me
and my guys include planning a murder?
I'm just looking for my salad.
Somebody took it.
Why don't you just
find out who did it...
send 'em to prison to be
killed by Antwon Mitchell?
What's that make you, serving Lem
up to some cop killer?
Just like you served Terry up?
- Terry was a snake, just like you.
- Oh.
- So you did know that Terry
was working forJustice.
- You told me about it yourself.
I'm done with crying about him
getting killed by Two-Time...
no matter how many weepy
relatives you bring by.
[Sighs]
Had a conversation
with Antwon Mitchell.
Very illuminating, especially
as it relates to Shane Vendrell.
Is your neck a little sore?
Excuse me?
From the noose tightening?
You send Lem to Lompoc,
it's you that's the real murderer.
The four of you come completely clean,
I will let you pick the prison.
No deal?
Well, I guess you're not as concerned
for his safety as you claim.
Anyway, there's nothing on paper
as to where Lemansky will end up...
but I'm sure I'll have a recommendation
when the time comes.
That being said, any correctional facility
is dangerous for a cop.
Best thing to do is play by
the rules, stay out of jail.
Streets can be
real dangerous too.
Are we leveling threats,
Detective?
Just making
random observations.
Same as you.
Here's another one-
You're bluffing.
Trying to split us up.
You're Mr. Straight Arrow,
right?
Couldn't even cut your poor,
sick-in-the-head, defenseless...
ex-wife a break
from the rules, could ya?
You don't have the stomach
to serve Lem up to Antwon.
I didn't use to.
Excuse me.
I worked with Artemis
at the plant.
That donor thing was something he got
on his own. Don't know much about it.
Seems weird. Usually organs have
to be transplanted within hours.
Takes a hell of a lot longer
to drive to Canada.
Wouldn't you think
they'd fly 'em?
Maybe it's low-priority organs,
like fingers or tongues.
I'm gonna go out
on a limb here.
Artemis was not running fingers and tongues
back and forth to Vancouver, was he?
Whatever he was running got him
shot in the face.
- Shit. He's dead?
- Found him in a Dumpster, like common trash.
He was running some cush,
some sort of super weed.
You get anywhere near the shit, the contact
high would knock you out for a week.
- He made eight grand a run.
- That makes him invaluable.
- He have any beefs with anyone?
- Hell no.
Everybody loved Art. He drove that
van into L.A. Full of the good tree...
it was like Santa Claus
was comin' to town.
We got a guy upstairs,
needs a ride home.
No problem.
She okay?
Says she's a hundred percent.
I'm not gonna argue the point.
When I get my six weeks,
I'm gonna forget this place exists.
Yeah.
- Hi there.
- Oh, let me guess.
You're here to give me shit
about something.
What? No.
I, uh-
Th-These've been
floating around.
I thought you should know.
Jesus Christ.
- The door was locked. How'd they-
- I barely glanced.
Just-Just enough
to identify you.
Apparently some asshole put
a camera in the locker room.
So every jerk-off in the Barn's
been staring at my tits?
Hey, you can't let their
high school mentality get to you.
They'll get their kicks,
then move on to somebody else.
Shit. I think
I'm gonna get fired.
I screwed up at a call last night.
That's why I'm stuck in here.
We all make mistakes.
Even I've been known to make one or two-
Occasionally.
I wore those bra
and panties two days ago.
- The red ones the day before.
- That's something to go on.
I'm gonna find out who took these.
I'm gonna see that every picture's destroyed.
Okay. Thanks for being
such a gentleman.
We're not all Neanderthals.
I should probably keep those,
stick 'em in a drawer for evidence.
Oh. We don't have
anything planned.
I'm resigning my position
as a reserve officer.
So now you no longer can compel my
cooperation by threatening to take my badge.
It's all yours.
That's not necessary.
You should also know that
as vice-chair of the police committee...
I'm launching an investigation
into your investigation.
- Really?
- Yeah.
And why, after tens
of thousands of dollars...
- you have nothing more now
than you had seven months ago.
- I got Lemansky in custody.
Yeah, on seven-month-old
charges.
I got 65,000 unaccounted for dollars,
courtesy of Mackey's wife.
I got Mackey's assets frozen...
along with every member
of the Strike Team.
And I've got Antwon Mitchell
talking.
You're getting
Mackey panicked...
- hoping he'll overplay his hand.
- Something I hope you could help me with.
Nicely done, by the way, stomping
in here like that. That was good.
- I like that.
- You're trying to get Mackey running to me?
What, the enemy of my enemy
is my friend?
Well, forget it.
It won't happen.
He and his boys, they were in
business with Antwon Mitchell.
These guys, they're desperate.
They're gonna need a friend...
in a high place, like you.
All right, I'll hold off
on my investigation-
For now.
Walk out angry.
Mackey's watching.
- Vic, you got a sec?
- Barely.
You ever hear of a Canadian
super pot?
What, you lookin' to buy
a dime bag?
Dump job this morning was driving vans
full of the stuff down from Vancouver.
You know any locals
plugged into that route?
Probably.
You guys have the van?
Still looking. Might be a robbery.
I'm just looking for a few names.
[Door Slams]
Well, seeing as you and Claudette's Wonder
Twin powers aren't fully activated yet...
I'll do you a favor,
pick up the slack on this one.
- Okay. Thanks.
- All right, let me shake the One-niner tree...
see if any five-pointed
leaves fall out.
That prick cut a deal
with Antwon Mitchell.
- Wants to send Lem to Lompoc
if he gets a conviction.
- What?
That's why Kavanaugh knows
so much about you and Antwon.
He's hoping the threat
will get Lem talking.
- That's not exactly playing by the rules.
- Means we don't either.
- If he puts Lem in with Mitchell-
- I know.
- Yo, coz.
- Shit. Let's go.
- This 5-0 is Hitler.
- You miss us?
Not especially.
[Laughs]
Hear Antwon's cutting deals...
over in Lompoc, shoring up
the power structure.
If it don't involve the street,
it don't involve me.
Maybe you're part
of Antwon's restructuring.
Nice try, but me
and the big guy's tight.
You really expect me to believe
he's lettin' you call the shots out here?
He can't do it.
Somebody's got to, right?
Antwon know you're recruiting
out of middle school?
Most of the old guard hung
it up after Antwon left.
- This is the new regime.
- Any of your students running
chronic down from Canada?
- Let's take a ride.
- What? Shooting me wasn't enough?
Tell me what we want to know or we're
gonna be back in your life again full-time.
All right.
Dude with a fancy French name who runs
most of the bud to the crews.
- Best shit in years.
- What's Frenchy's name?
Dijon.
Get back to class.
Pork Chop's stuck
on street duty.
He knows where
the pot comes from...
but Antwon's cut him out of the inner circle,
the decision-making.
- You thinking regime change?
- Something to keep an eye on.
- Dude, sweet pictures.
- What pictures?
It's okay.
I'm cool.
You think Tina's panties
are regulation?
[Chuckles]
- Just wish we could've seen her badge.
- [Laughs]
Hey, between you and me,
how'd you pull it off?
Shit, I'm no perv.
Found 'em on Billings's desk.
Anyone make copies?
What do you think?
Anyway, thanks
for sharing them with me.
The way you stare at that chick,
would've been cruel not to.
You had the I.R.S.
Freeze my money.
- I'm sorry. That isn't-
- Sorry?
- You did it.
- Yes.
I did everything that you asked.
I told you about the money.
- Now I can't feed my children.
- You told me about $65,000.
Now I'm hearing there may be more-
A lot more.
Please. You think I would default
on my children's tuitions if there was more?
I hate that this
is hurting you...
but I'm building walls
around Vic...
to stop him from slithering away and you,
you're one of those walls.
I'm not a wall,
I'm a mother.
And I'm disconnecting Vic
from my life and from the kids.
So leave me out of this.
Are you aware that I arrested
Curtis Lemansky two days ago?
He's in County, waiting for Vic
and his friends to bail him out.
If they don't have the money,
they can't do it.
And every minute that Lem spends inside, I'm
just a minute closer to getting at the truth.
That has nothing
to do with me.
My advice is to go
to Vic yourself...
ask him to confess.
You want your life back,
ask him, not me.
What did I do to deserve this?
You married the wrong man,
Corrine.
- Now I'm not doing this because
that cowboy called me out.
- Of course not.
I got two of my finest officers
telling me that Tina's gotta go.
Look, every day that she's out there,
she's putting people at risk.
- She's just so damn popular.
- I can call her P.B.A. Rep.
Okay. Get him
down here, ASAP.
Julien, I want a full report of her conduct.
You're going on the record.
- Got it.
- Thanks, guys.
What's up?
Shit! Where'd you get these?
- They're circulating.
- They were on my desk. Is nothing sacred?
- You're asking me?
- Come here.
I put a nanny cam
in the locker room.
People have been ripping off
the vending machines.
I was just trying to catch
whoever was doing it.
You could've put a camera
in the hallway-
- Over the machines.
- Not where it could be hidden.
And I think whoever's stealing this grub
is stashing it in their locker.
I pulled these photos and some others so
that they wouldn't get into the wrong hands.
You know, this only happened because I don't
have a goddamn private office anymore.
Do you have any idea what kind
of shitstorm you're looking at...
when she finds out
you're behind these photos?
She saw them?
You told her?
- She had a right to know.
- I just promised to wash her out. [Sighs]
You think he's gonna take
care of that baby? He's not.
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
You think he's gonna
be a father?
Who the father is
is none of your business.
Really? It's none of my business that my kids
are gonna get a new brother or sister?
I'm at work right now, okay?
This isn't the place.
Right.
Come find me later.
You managed to find someone to screw
at work. Why not talk about it here?
I'm gonna walk away from you because
you're obviously not being rational.
Really? Were you being rational when
you slept with a married man?
- He made that vow, not me.
- Which makes him a cheat...
but that makes you a whore and the baby
you're both having a bastard.
You Dijon?
- I ain't do nothing, if that's what you mean.
- Nice threads.
We hear you've got the best B.C.
Bud in Farmington.
- Hey.
- What?
- White guys can't get the good stuff?
- You only sell to bangers?
- That's discrimination.
- I got nothing. Look around.
Okay.
- You took a hit today.
- We're offering you a chance to get it back.
Whoa.
Run that by me again.
Your Canadian organ express
got taken down.
Your driver got killed,
supply ripped off.
We can get it back for you,
for a finder's fee.
- Why?
- Don't worry about that.
Hundred grand,
no questions asked.
- [Scoffs]
- Oh, yeah. That's right.
Only a matter of time before the detectives
on the murder case follow the phone records...
back to you and your
monthly pot runs.
But you work with us, we see to it
that the trail ends with Artemis.
- And I keep the rest?
- It's a hell of a lot better than nothing, isn't it?
All right.
The only thing is, it wasn't my shipment
that got jacked, it was my cash.
- Artemis was on his way up to Canada.
- How much did you lose?
- A quarter of a million.
- [Sighs]
- Get it back, I'll cut you the hundred G's then.
- Uh-uh.
- We don't trust you.
- No, man. We'll take our fee
up front as a down payment.
Man, you crazy?
I'm out of pocket on this.
- Everything I got was invested in that run.
- Jesus Christ, man.
- This is just a waste of time.
- No, it's not.
A deal's a deal. Put together
a list of every customer...
anybody who would've
known about Artemis's run.
Dirty yourself up. We need you
to play the ignorant friend...
for some colleagues of ours.
Yo, Asher, upstairs.
America's favorite couple wants
to have a little chat with him.
- Sure thing.
- I'm telling ya, my intel's good.
Artemis was flying solo. His buddy's
got some details about his criminal dealings.
- Let's see what's up between these two.
- [Cell Phone Ringing]
I'll be right up.
- Lem?
- I finally got some phone time, man.
So what's going on?
Am I getting out of here today?
I'm working on it.
Hang on.
[Beeping]
- [Ringing]
- Hello?
Hey, it's Vic. I'm gonna put you
on with Lem. Hold on.
- [Beeps]
- All right. You guys both on?
- I'm here.
- Yeah.
- All right, Lem...
you're talking to your lawyer, Becca Doyle,
in case there are other ears on this call.
Whoa, you can't use me as cover
for anything illegal.
- What I'm about to tell Lem, you need to hear too.
- What is it?
The good news first.
We got a lead on some bail money.
- How?
- Calling in a few favors.
All right. Look, man,
I know you got my back.
- What's the bad news?
- Kavanaugh has been sitting
down with Antwon Mitchell.
Made some sort of deal to send you
to Lompoc in case there's a conviction.
- No goddamn way.
- [Becca] That's insane.
- He doesn't make those calls.
- Look, it's never gonna get that far.
Gonna get you out of there, then we're
gonna get you out from under this prick.
Do you know this?
Kavanaugh said those words?
He'd never admit it,
but it's real.
All it means is Kavanaugh knows he's got
jack shit on us and he's getting desperate.
All right. I hear you.
I hear you.
- Vic, you coming or not?
- Yeah, hang on.
All right. Listen, I gotta go.
You stay safe, all right?
- Yeah.
- Okay. Yeah.
- Dutchman.
- I'm in the middle of something.
I got it, Dutch-boy.
You know I was on the up-and-up
taking those photos.
[Scoffs]
Tell the chief.
LfTina makes a stink about this,
maybe she'll get a huge pile of cash...
but her career will be kaput.
You know how these
things wash out.
- I don't know what you expect me to do about it.
- I have a plan.
If this thing goes away,
everybody wins, including you.
No, thanks.
You can either be a hero in Tina's eyes,
or you can watch her...
and her red bra and panties march out
that Barn door forever.
[Scoffs]
He's full of it.
He probably is a member of the weed ring,
but why kill your own driver?
- I really don't think he was involved-
- If this guy's funding...
Artemis's run,
he'll never cooperate.
- He'll want to recover the money himself.
- Or Artemis is working solo.
Your intel hasn't been
what it used to be.
Fine. I'll see what else
I can squeeze out of him.
- What did I miss?
- What the hell'd you bring him into this for?
- I thought we could use a little muscle.
- Brains over brawn, Dutch.
How many times I gotta
tell you that?
Move it, asshole!
You don't need to keep sellin'
it so hard, do you?
Your list of customers
got us nowhere.
The only thing those bangers want more than
ass and cash is your top grade Canadian bud.
They know a good thing
when they smoke it.
Yeah, well, if I don't find the guy
who knocked over your van...
you'll be hanging up
a "closed" sign.
Who else besides your customers
knows about the runs?
Just my wife
and my dumb-ass stepson.
- How old is he?
- He's 20.
- What's his name?
- Jaden Reid.
He drove the route for me couple times
till I noticed the load kept comin' back light.
- Punk don't know the meaning of"high enough."
- Where is he now?
Who knows? He gonna send
his mama to an early grave.
- Does your wife know whereJaden is?
- She's got no clue.
You never know. Blood is
thicker than bong water.
Kid's name is Jaden Reid.
Think he's our shooter.
- Let's payJaden a little visit.
- Well, first we gotta find him.
Kid's a burnout. Now he's got enough
cash to keep him stoned for a long time.
- Got enough cash for us to spring Lem.
- So where do we start?
Our unis found the abandoned van
in a parking lot in Silver Lake...
lots of blood, no cash.
If I had a bagful of money, I wouldn't
want to walk too far with it.
Check out the local weed dealers.
Lfhe had the cash, he'd wanna score.
- What about Claudette?
- We're still a step ahead,
and she seems two steps slow.
- Let's find this kid before
she figures out anything else.
- Okay.
Yeah. Got it.
Got a hit on the fingerprints in the van.
Belongs to a Jaden Reid.
- Address?
- Last known, his mother's.
- Tasha Reynolds.
- What's up?
Got a suspect.
Jaden Reid.
According to the file,
he's your friend Dijon's stepson.
- Nice work.
- Gonna check out an address.
- Why don't we let some unis pick him up?
- They can join us.
Dutch is right. Why don't you let me
and my guys handle sweepup duty?
You can join us too
if you want.
Mrs. Reynolds, when was
the last time you saw Jaden?
- Couple months.
- Look, he's a good kid.
There's no way he'd be involved
in anything like this.
Dutch, why don't you have Dijon show you
whereJaden stays when he's here?
Sure.
Um, lead the way.
Mrs. Reynolds.
I know you're worried about your son, but
he could be in trouble and not just from us.
He wouldn't kill no one.
Then help us find him so we can clear this
mess up and keepJaden from being hurt.
He has a girl.
I don't like her.
- She lives by that old theater on Sunset.
- Got an address?
2409 Cole Street, by the Vista Theatre.
Jaden's there.
Uh, 2409 Cole.
Yeah, we got it.
- How far out are you?
- Uh, traffic, 15 minutes maybe. Why?
Because Dutch and Claudette
are on the way over there too.
Just get inside the house, find the money,
and get out of there fast.
- Well, how far are they?
- Same as you.
Jesus!
What if they catch us?
I mean, we've got
the day off, remember?
Just get there.
I'll make it work.
- Okay, park it, let's go.
- Yeah, where? Claudette knows this truck.
Check around back.
Come on, man.
Move.
It's locked, man.
- I'll get the front.
- Two minutes, that's it. Then we're gone.
No arguments here.
Goddamn it.
- Let's forget it. We're out of here.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait.
- Oh, shit.
- Hold on. Hold on.
- Shit, is he dead?
- No.
- [Snoring]
- No. It's just a damn good buzz.
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
He's sleeping on the money.
[Cars Approaching]
- Oh, shit.
- Grab it. Grab it.
Oh, yeah. We're good.
We're good.
Let's go! Go, go, go.
Hey! You take him.
I'll clear the back.
[Mouthing Words]
- Clear!
- Looks like we got our shooter.
- Come on, buddy, wake up. Party's over.
- [Sighs]
- Somebody took my money.
- You won't need any where you're going.
- He cut me out. He didn't have to do that.
- [Man] There you go.
- I didn't want to hurt nobody.
- You shot him in the face three times.
We should probably wait
until he sobers up.
- Can't use anything he says right
now anyway, his state.
- All that money was his.
All that bud, his. I don't know why
you ain't going after him.
Artemis? You killed him and took
the money belonging to Artemis?
Artemis?
I was drivin' for Dijon.
It was his shit.
He fired me.
I'm his stepson.
What kinda shit is that?
You really dialed the wrong
number on your street intel.
Still don't have any evidence
against Dijon...
and his hazy memory ain't
gonna get you far either.
Jaden says somebody broke into his
girlfriend's apartment, took the money.
- What's our next move?
- It's my day off.
I helped you catch the killer.
Finding the money's your problem.
- Hey, Smitty.
- Haven't seen you guys in a while.
It's been nice.
- It's about to get a lot nicer.
- How'd you like to make a hundred grand?
[Scoffs]
Pass.
- Hear us out.
- The shit I've done for you guys for peanuts...
I don't even want to know
what a hundred grand looks like.
Looks a lot easier
than you think.
Lem's in jail. You're gonna put up
a hundred G's for his bail.
- You expect me to just give you a hundred "K"?
- We're gonna give it to you.
And when Lem shows up in court,
you're gonna keep it.
And the catch is?
I.A.D.'s gonna ask you about it.
Might wanna look at your books.
Your business is profitable
lately, right?
- Very.
- How'd those leads we
gave you last year work out?
Great. Could always
use a few more.
How many jobs does it take you
to clear a hundred grand?
Why are you guys always coming
to me with this shit?
'Cause you're the last
honest guy we know.
Hey. Found someone
willing to post bail.
An old friend came through.
Kavanaugh will be looking
into that old friend.
Nothing to find.
He likes Lem.
I'll see if I can wake up a clerk,
get things fast-tracked.
Thanks.
What? What is it?
I'm stuck here.
I don't wanna convince
you all to turn on Lem...
and I don't want to convince
him to turn on you...
but that's what a good lawyer would be
advising all of you to do right now.
L-I don't want to see any
of you going to prison.
That's nice to know.
Right now...
I think I'd make a better
friend than a lawyer.
Lem-
Lem needs you
right now-
And we sure can't afford
to hire someone else.
If you have to make a choice,
you go with Lem.
And advise him to hurt you?
If you can make a deal that has me
switching places with Lem, then you do it.
Just me.
None of my guys.
I wanna see you get
your second chance.
I already have.
On behalf of the entire department,
I'd like to apologize...
for the wrong done to you.
The captain learned about the photos
earlier this afternoon, came to me.
- Did you find the dickwad, or what?
- Unfortunately, no.
- The identity of the culprit's a mystery.
- Great.
- So where does that leave me?
- During the course of our conversation...
I mentioned to the captain that you
have really great instincts...
and he agreed that
you have a lot of potential.
- And potential needs to be nourished.
- I've asked permission...
to take you under my wing, show you
the detective ropes in your spare time.
Unless these photos have you too upset
to focus on career advancement?
I see.
So, I keep my mouth shut,
I climb the ladder.
Dutch is just offering
an opportunity.
- Did you get rid of the rest of them?
- Every last one.
I look forward to working
with you, Detective.
Thanks, Captain.
[Man On P.A.]
Security guards to cells "A"and "B."
Prisoner all clear for release.
Hey!
Told you we'd get you out.
Hey. Looks like
your hymen's still intact.
Gonna have to get your own pussy
tonight, though, buddy. [Groans]
- Where's Vic at, man?
- He's, uh-
He had someplace he's gotta be.
He'll meet us later.
- Come on, man. Let's go grab a beer.
- Come on. Smitty's buying.
- I am?
- Yesl
- One round.
- You're riding with me.
What are you doing here?
Kavanaugh.
He's out of control.
He's unbalanced. He's breaking the rules.
He's threatening Lem's life.
I.A.D.'s your problem,
not mine.
The look on your face walking out
of his office today says otherwise.
He's got screws
in you too, yeah?
I, uh-
I'm an element in Kavanaugh's
investigation-
Price I pay for
having been your boss-
But I'm hardly in the same
category as you and your guys.
Really?
You think if Kavanaugh's successful
I'm gonna go down quietly?
[Laughs]
I will scorch the earth covering
this whole department, starting with you.
I can tie you to every bullshit thing
Kavanaugh's accusing me of, and then some.
Your stink will smell up every
voting booth in this city.
On the other hand...
you want that little nameplate
on your desk to read "Mayor" someday?
We work together.
Make sure that you,
me, my team...
are the last men standing long
enough to go our separate ways.
What's your plan?
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Continues]
##[Ends]