Previously on The Shield.
You ever suck a dick
like a cell bitch, cop man?
I'm just gonna tell the whole courtroom
what went down with us.
ConvinceJuan
to miss his court date.
Took a 40-pound dumbbell
to the back of the head in County.
[Mackey]
So Aceveda meets with Juan, then with Antwon.
Antwon gets a deal.
Juan gets killed.
I get to officially notify you
that Internal Affairs...
is investigating
your former Strike Team.
I'm representing all four
of these detectives.
Vic gave me some cash
in a bag a little while ago.
- How much?
- 65,000.
I've got lupus.
Had it for 15 years.
Hey, you guys have a Fatima Gardner
sign in to see you this morning?
Her brother just reported her missing.
Maybe she started lookin' at you funny.
So you killed her...
- and reported her missing
so you could make yourselflook innocent.
- Nol
- Don't talk to me like that!
- I'll talk to you any way I goddamn please.
You can't arrest me, and you're not helpin' me.
I'll find her myself!
Uni says it looks like rape.
His own sister?
- [Claudette] It's not Fatima.
- You recognize the haircut?
Looks like I got
under Kleavon's skin after all.
[Man]
Two outs. Olympic Division, 6, Farmington, 5.
Come on, Lem.
One to tie, two to win it, baby!
Put a bat on that ball.
This guy's pitch is as bad as his arrest record.
- Let's go. Batter upl
- [Men Chattering]
Lay it in there, baby.
- [Cheering, Chattering]
- [Curtis] I got the next one. It's all right.
- [Mackey] Shake it off, Lem. Let's go.
- Come on. Make this one count.
- Easy.
- [Chatter Continues]
Big swing. Big swing.
- Take me home. Take me home, brother.
- Come on. Take 'em home.
[Mackey]
This is it. This is it. You go, Lem.
Eye on the ball.
Big swing. Big swing.
- [Shouting, Chattering]
- There you gol
- Go, go, gol
- [Shouting Continues]
- You go, Shane.
- Come on, Lemmy. Gol
- Let him go homel
- Let's go, Shanel
- You go, Shanel
- Hustlel Hustlel
- Down! Down! Down!
- [Grunts]
- Safe!
- [Cheering]
Hey!
There's no contact allowed.
- This is C-plus league softball, for God's sake.
- I trippedl
- That's bullshit! You gotta call him out, Billy!
- Hey, hey, now relax.
- Calm down.
- Hey, that's bullshit.
- Cheap shot.
- You know what? You know what?
You win some, you win some.
Hey, this ain't over.
Game's still tied, 6-6.
- Hey, hey, heyl
- All right, fellas. Back off!
- Jesus Christ. Put that away.
What is wrong with you?
- Hey, lose the gun, man.
That's ball game.
- Olympic Division calls,
you tell 'em to shove it up their ass!
- [Cheering]
All right.
Actually, Paul Reyes did just call
from Olympic.
- Is he still complainin'about the game?
- That is a sore loser.
Let's call him back and tell him
to shove it up his ass, times two.
- Times two.
- I think he wants your help on a case.
- Oh, sure. Tell him I'll get right on it.
- [Laughing]
You know, Reyes is headin' up that citywide
task force. Maybe you better give him a call.
- All right.
- Where's Sofer?
She called in sick,
and I can't do her job and mine.
Goddamn it.
I knew that baby was gonna screw me.
Gardocki, got a minute?
No, he doesn't.
I need him for a special assignment.
I can get him freed up for an hour.
Who should I call?
Why don't you tickle your balls
on your own time.
- I'll see him in my office.
- Not until his lawyer gets down here.
- Tell her to hurry.
- We'll do that.
I'm gonna feel him out,
then maybe spring Fatima's visit...
his missing death kit on him-
look for a crack.
- Actually I'm gonna go at him alone.
- That's not your decision.
It was his the minute he cut
Pauline Wahler's hair to look like mine.
Okay, okay. Okay, good, good.
He knows how I operate...
thinks he's got a bead on me.
Come at him from a new angle.
I'm gonna watch on the monitor,
develop a game plan. If you want me to jump in...
ask him if he wants you
to turn down the air-conditioning.
It's a code.
Between San Antonio and here...
you've killed at least eight women,
including one last night.
Your sister's missing 24 hours.
We think you killed her too. Let's start talking.
If you're lookin' for a rematch, I left my cleats
at the Barn. Left half his skin on the dirt.
Unless it's the postgame activities
you're lookin'to finish?
Nah, you cheated us fair and square.
We'll get you next year.
- Since when are you good losers?
- Since I got the news my task force was expanding.
I was thinking of offering your team the new slot.
I hear the Barn's a sinkin' ship.
We could've discussed this
over a couple beers just as easily.
I was going to after the game.
Didn't get the chance.
Figured we'd talk over a couple of bodies,
give me a chance to see you in action.
I don't know if you heard, uh,
I.A.D. 's had a wild hair up their ass about us.
I've tangled with those bastards a couple of times.
It just means you're gettin' shit done.
When this case is over,
we'll get those beers.
- Hell, I'll even buy.
- Let's go.
- How old?
- She was two, maybe three.
House belongs to Maurizio Ochoa.
Dead woman's his girlfriend, Jenny Rayball.
Shot 15 times.
Ah, we've picked up Ochoa before.
Deals meth.
- Little girl's name was Violet.
- Didn't Ochoa get popped once
for bustin' up his girlfriend?
Couple of times.
Broke her jaw six months ago.
[Shane]
That sounds like the crank talkin'.
Ah, let me guess.
He took his stash with him on the way out.
Ochoa hooked up
with a Mexican cartel guy in Chino...
convinced him he had the chops
to handle the weight.
We've been set up
on Ochoa for three months.
Had our guy in place to make the buy,
just waitin' for the word.
So even if Ochoa didn't do this, his business did.
It could be a rival slanger.
Either way, shot 15 times, it was personal,
and we gotta track down Ochoa.
Well, he sticks his head up,
we'll be there to whack it.
We think he's sittin' on
a hundred pounds of meth... to sell.
I looked into your finances.
You know what I found?
Yeah. Nothin'unusual.
How did you manage to hide
your dirty money so well, huh?
The only money that I get
is from my weekly paycheck.
You tryin'to tell me that you never took
just a little bit off the side?
Why don't you provide some proof
before you accuse him of a crime?
Ronnie, you got any idea where Mackey
came up with $65,000 in cash?
[Rebecca]
Don't answer that.
[Kavanaugh]
You said you wanted some proof.
- I think you're bullshitting.
- Vendrell- He's got money
he can't account for either.
Which means one of two things:
Either these guys,
they don't include you in their bounty-
which should piss you off-
or... you're the one guy who's bright enough
not to leave a trail.
Which one is it?
You just said you checked my records,
and you didn't find anything.
And I don't keep track of how the other guys
balance their checkbooks.
Hmm.
One lawyer for four guys?
Who's lookin' out for your interest?
'Cause from what I see...
she seems to be more concerned
with steerin' the conversation away from Mackey.
Who hired her in the first place?
- Because she's certainly not
lookin'out for your interests.
- Let's go.
My client is cooperating.
He's willing to answer any questions.
If you have another one, you let us know.
Come on. Let's go.
Ronnie.
Ronnie, you've been disciplined.
You've been careful, but not them.
They're gonna screw this up.
They're gonna bring you down for a mistake
that you were too smart to make.
That's it. Let's go.
We can pick this up later, okay?
[Vehicle Engine Stops, Doors Closing]
- How'd it go with Kavanaugh?
- Asked me if I knew where you came up
with $65,000 cash.
- 65? Exactly?
- Yeah.
He's been going through our financial records-
all of them.
- He said this in front of Becca?
- Yeah.
What'd you do with your share
of the money train cash?
I gave it to Corrine for the kids.
- She gave it up to Kavanaugh.
- What else could it be?
- You said she wasn't calling you back.
- Look, I'll get into it.
Well, tell me another way
that he could've known the exact number.
That's gonna look great.
Your ex-wife on the stand...
- talking about dirty money
we stole from the Armenian mob-
- She doesn't know how we got it...
and she's never testifying
against me in court.
Now let's go find Ochoa
before he dumps these drugs on the street.
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Ends]
##[Man Rapping In Spanish On Speaker]
- Yeah?
- We're lookin' for Maurizio Ochoa.
- What for?
- He won the lottery.
- We're here to give him a check.
- [Glass Shatters]
[Shouting, Indistinct]
[Shane]
Hey! Stop!
[Both Grunting]
Face down like your little girl.
Just sorry I can't put a bullet
in your head.
Get up. Get upl
[Claudette]
Fatima came to us, brought us that.
- Whose blood is that?
- That's not my shirt.
She also let my partner into your house.
He found a death kit:
Tape, gloves, a knife- to control your victims
before strangling, I presume.
Fatima would never have come to you.
Well, maybe you found out
she visited us.
Or maybe she got so nervous,
she showed her hand.
She's known for a while how you hunt women.
If that girl had a problem with me,
believe me, she'd let me know it.
- Where am I gonna find Fatima's body?
- Why you sure there's a body?
Detective, you wanted to know of any hits
on a Fatima Gardner?
$2,300 MasterCard purchase
at Hahn's Furniture Store on Western.
Sounds stolen, but whoever took it
may know what happened to her.
- I can't leave here. Can y-you-
- We'll run it down, get back to you.
- Thank you.
- [Claudette]
So, why did you follow Fatima to L.A.?
So she'd continue
to look out for you?
I thought it was because those Texas cops
had you pegged for those murders...
so you decided to swim
to safer waters.
Ah, they had the wrong guy, just like you.
Those boys still living Jim Crow.
They see a proud black man, they gonna come up
with a reason to put his ass in jail.
Press him.
What about me? I just gotta see
a proud black man behind bars too?
Oh, you're just like them Texas cops-
racist white folk.
Don't try to convince me that you're sittin' there...
because I'm some kinda Uncle Tom.
You're no better than a house nigger
called up to massa's room each night.
Okay. This guy's got a real need
for black women to be subservient.
Last time you got in his face, he lost it,
killed a woman.
We've got him trapped here,
so press him... hard.
Don't take his shit.
Fling it right back in his face.
He'll get angry, lose his balance.
I need some water.
Take him into Interrogation, twist him.
I'll be there in a minute.
When were you gonna tell me
about the $65,000?
I wasn't.
First you're being persecuted...
then you're a prime suspect in a cop killing,
and now you're just a cop on the take?
Sometimes things crossed our path:
Drugs, money.
Sometimes we took a little to use later-
to help with intel on the street.
Some just ended up in your pocket.
- I gave it to my ex actually.
- [Exhales]
[Chuckles]
Looks like Kavanaugh got to her.
I am trying to defend you.
Do you get that?
I let your guys answer Kavanaugh's questions
because I was told...
there was nothing to hide.
If you really want me to help you,
you better mend fences with your ex...
- and me.
- We're not gonna have to worry about her.
- We need to find out what side she's on.
- Look. I got two autistic kids.
There's special schools,
there's doctors-
No, that's bullshit. I'm not gonna use my kids
as an excuse. It's bullshit.
[Sniffles, Sighs]
It was easy, all right?
No fuss, no victims.
I was clearin' twice as many cases
as anyone here.
I worked my ass off. I knew I was makin'
a difference, so I took some for me. Me.
City got their money's worth.
Trust me.
- But that was then. I'm not the same person now.
- Why?
Because you got caught?
Because I wanna still be a cop.
Because I don't wanna be smeared
and pushed outta my job by the same people...
who patted me on the back every time I brought
some murdering, rapist asshole in here!
Because I can do better.
But if I'm gonna have
a second chance, l-
I'm gonna need your help to get it.
[Shane] You don't shoot your lady 15 times-
not unless you want the bitch extra dead.
Wasn't enough to break Jenny's jaw,
send her to the hospital last summer?
I lost it a few times and messed her up.
But I never hurt Violet.
You had 100 pounds of Mexican weight
you wanted to unload.
What's another 30 pounds
oflittle girl?
You knew we'd rip the place apart
once we found 'em, so you had a choice:
You move two bloody bodies,
or you move the drugs.
A lot easier to hide your meth stash.
A lot less messy too.
You shot your girlfriend 15 times,
you killed your daughter...
and then you pulled your product
down from the kitchen ceiling.
Wait. Are you sayin' the drugs
aren't in the crawl space?
That's what we're sayin'.
- He stole them... and killed 'em both.
- Who?
Ted "Someshit,"her ex.
He's the guy.
- "Someshit"?
- Why you so sure it was him?
He's a meth-head. And he never got over
the fact that his woman left him for me...
while he was doin' a year and a half in Folsom.
He just got out last month.
So he wasn't too happy when he found out
about the daughter that she had with you?
- She wasn't my kid.
- What?
Violet was his- "Someshit's."
He didn't even know.
That's the wayJenny wanted it.
His name's not "Someshit."
Shusett. Ted Shusett.
M.E. Called.
Nothing on last night's vic we can use.
- Not even a hair?
- He's that good. He's such a perfectionist.
He killed extemporaneously
without leaving a trace.
He's made the move from organized killer
to thrill killer without missing a beat.
But he knows it wasn't his best work.
Got impatient. He rushed it.
He's probably on edge about leaving
trace evidence behind. Hit that hard.
He screwed up.
Didn't take his time, didn't plan it.
Knows he left himself exposed by cutting the hair.
He said too much with that.
Gotta be kickin' himself for it.
Hey, don't let up.
- Have a great weekend, you guys.
- See you later.
Well, now I know why
you won't return my calls.
Shouldn't you be at some Lamaze class
or somethin'for your new baby?
- Is that what Kavanaugh told you?
- Is it true? That pregnant cop?
- She didn't tell me I was the father.
- But you're a candidate?
- Well, you must be very proud.
- So you told Kavanaugh
about the money out of spite?
- No.
- I gave you the money- for our kids.
You get angry at me for a second,
a-and you wanna send me to jail?
- [Vehicle Alarm Chirps In Distance]
- No. I didn't want that, okay?
He was looking into our accounts.
We didn't declare that money.
- You wanna put me in jail?
- He's bluffing. He wants me.
What kind of man puts the mother
of his children in this position?
- What did you want me to do?
- Nothing. I wanted you to say nothing.
Look, I'm sorry, okay?
I didn't want to hurt you. I'm sorry.
[Vehicle Door Opens]
Hey.
Ochoa's alibi checks out.
He was at a house party in Whittier.
- Got a lead on Shusett: Apartment on Rowena.
- Good.
Listen, you guys should know. I told Becca
about some of our money skimming.
- You did what?
- I had to explain the 65 grand.
So you just confessed for all of us?
- She's our attorney.
- Maybe we need to talk about that too.
It's all privileged.
She has to know how best to protect us.
Vendrell, why don't you come on up here,
spin the wheel.
- Bring Becca.
- I don't want her.
Hey, we can't take any chances.
Trust me.
[Shane]
Counselor.
[Both Moaning]
Get on the ground right now!
Get down!
- Get on the ground. Don't move!
- [Curtis] Hands up! Hands up.
Sorry to crash the party, fellas.
- [Mackey] Which one of you is Ted Shusett?
- He ain't here.
- Who are you?
- Billy Boyd. That's my brother, Jimmy.
- You know where he is?
- He comes by at night to crash lately.
- I don't know what he does in the sunlight.
- He kills people-
like his ex-girlfriend and his kid,
for example.
- [TV: Moaning Continues]
- Here. You hear from him, you call that number.
You don't, I'll have you both arrested
for conspiracy in their murders.
You must be doin' okay. You bought
a $600,000 house in Atwater six months ago.
- How do you like the area?
- We don't live there.
That's right. Contractor said you gutted it.
Everything new from the ground up.
Do you have a question, Lieutenant?
Actually, you pay as you go?
He gives your wife the bills,
and she writes the checks?
And we save every goddamn receipt,
every invoice, every cashed check.
Everything is accounted for.
You wanna see 'em?
I already have.
I've seen everything.
As I.A.D., you're only entitled
to look at department pay stubs.
You'd need a subpoena
for any other financial history.
Every penny is accounted for...
except for the normal, everyday expenses
of people living.
We scrape by.
You wanna jump in here?
Do you get any help from anybody-
your friends, your family, your relatives?
- You doin'anything to make a little extra cash?
- Don't answer that. We're done.
Next time, you submit your questions
in writing to my office.
Hey, I just wanna know where you get
the extra money from. Come on, Vendrell!
Now she's defending me
like we're guilty.
Why don't you just put it up
in big, flashing neon lights?
I'm not the one with bags of cash
floating around.
And excuse me if I step on his questions
to help keep you out of jail.
This is about more than that.
It's about keeping our jobs.
It's about walking out of here
with our pensions, our reputations-
Keeping us out of jail
is just one piece of the puzzle.
Until Kavanaugh charges somebody,
we just have to deflect-
- hope he reveals more than he should.
- Not me.
I'm sorry, darlin',
but you don't represent me anymore.
- Can you give us a moment, please?
- Yeah.
[Mackey]
All right.
- What the hell happened up there?
- He's lookin' into my records:
What me and Mara bring home,
what we're payin' for the house.
- I thought that was all covered?
- It is, to the penny.
The problem is, there's nothing left over,
and he knows it.
- This isn't good.
- No shit.
- All right, all right, all right.
- Let's just take a deep breath.
- Yeah, while we're still breathing free air?
Vic, we got a "shots fired"call
from the address you guys just left.
- All right.
- Lemansky, I need to see you for a sec.
- What happened?
- [Man] Some kinda shootout.
Dead guy inside
is this guy's brother.
- Who killed Jimmy? Was it Shusett?
- [Billy] No.
Saw him comin' up the stairs.
Knew some major stuff was gonna go down...
so I went and got my gun.
By the time I found it,
Jimmy was all shot up.
[Ronnie]
Did you see who killed him?
Some cholo dude, rolls with Ochoa.
Guess Ochoa was more broken up
than we thought about his dead lady.
- Or he wanted his drugs back.
- He killed my brother, man.
My street intel says someone's tryin'
to unload weight-Mexican meth.
Shusett didn't go to Ochoa's to kill
his ex-crank skank. He went to steal his drugs.
Those things flood the barrio, forget it.
- So let's find them first.
- Better yet, let's buy 'em.
Who do we know who could buy from Shusett
without raisin' flags?
I got a dealer.
His street name's Burnout.
- Think he got popped with Shusett once
for possession.
- [Mackey] All right.
- Gonna check in with my guys.
Let me know if you find him.
- [Mackey] Great.
[Tires Screech]
My quota's a little low this week.
- Who wants to do the bracelet dance?
- Back up, Burnout.
Look, we need you to buy some drugs
from an old friend of yours, Ted Shusett.
- You got popped together once?
- Once a fellow fiend, always a fellow fiend.
- Partying together don't make us tight.
- Call him, all right?
- Tell him you're lookin' for product. He'll listen.
- Do I look like a stupid nigger?
- Why do you think we're talkin'?
- Look, man. This is legit.
When he stole those drugs,
Shusett killed a two-year-old girl and her mother.
So?
- Tried to do it the easy way.
- [Handcuffs Clicking]
Okay. Hold up. Hold up, man.
Look, a call like that-
little girl dead, man- street's gonna know
I'm the one givin' it up.
That's pretty rough
on my reputation.
- What's the goin' rate for a reputation these days?
- [Clicking]
- Twenty-five grand.
- [Mackey] Get him outta here.
That's too much for the department to authorize
on less than 24 hours' notice.
- City council could rubber-stamp
a reward though.
- [Car Door Closes]
[Chuckles]
- See you guys inside, all right?
- See you inside.
Councilman?
Glad I could catch you.
- You got a minute?
- I have a speech to give.
- Yeah, this is really important for the investigation.
- [Man Chattering]
You ever heard of a guy-
[Quietly] named Antwon Mitchell?
You know I have.
- Talked to Lemansky-
- [Man] Hi, David.
And I don't want to push on Antwon Mitchell
until I heard what you got to say about it.
I don't know what I can tell you.
How did Mackey learn that, uh, Crowley
was workin' with Justice?
- What does this have to do with Mitchell?
- Humor me.
Well, I suspected it was Gilroy.
Maybe it was you.
You set up Crowley.
You tipped Mackey.
Right. I'm also the fifth Beatle.
Mrs. Mackey reported that he gave her
65 grand in cash.
What was your share?
Runnin'a political campaign
gets really expensive, huh?
So's my time.
And now you're wasting it.
I'm just tryin' to figure out how Antwon Mitchell
and a guy named Juan Lozano...
figure into all of this.
Lozano was the guy-wasn't that the kid
who assaulted you?
Yes!
- Yes.
- He grabbed your gun?
You killed his buddy durin' a robbery,
tracked Lozano down yourself-
I mean, that's a pretty impressive bust
for a desk jockey.
Then later you visited him in County.
Yeah, well, he was planning
to appeal his case.
Hmm. I know that, uh, Mackey and his guys-
they have some connection
with Antwon Mitchell...
and he was in the same cellblock
when Lozano was found dead.
Somethin' big goin' on here.
You, Mackey, Mitchell, Lozano-
- You wanna fill me in?
- Waste your time with these conspiracy theories...
and you'll find yourself even more lost
than you are now.
[Julien On Radio] Clerk said it was a black woman
who used the credit card.
He wasn't sure
if it was Fatima Gardner.
- Is anybody listening to me?
- We've got a motel address for-
Wh-What? Say- Say again.
- I said, Terry's the guy you're looking for.
- I'm not talkin' to you.
- Say again, Julien.
- I said, we've got...
a motel address where the woman
wanted the purchases delivered.
- We're headed there now.
- Okay, good.
- Copy.
- You gotta find Terry.
He's the one that needs to be in here.
Shut up.
That's pretty sloppy work you did last night,
killing that girl.
Not your usual work of art.
- Why'd you cut off her hair?
- Why'd you cut off yours?
Don't interrupt.
My questions, not yours.
You used to look a lot different.
How long you been sick?
You're the one who's sick, Kleavon.
Please, girl. You wobblin'more
than a squirrel fell from a tree.
Oh, you may act like
everything's all right...
but your needle's
goin'back and forth.
Yeah. I hear your bones creakin'
every time you get out that chair.
- Get in there.
- Hey, what am I doing here?
One of the victims I.D.'d the guy
you sent to kill Shusett, get your crank back.
We can lure "Someshit"out
if we make an offer to buy.
The only problem is, we need a 25-grand reward
for our conscientious dealer first.
Why is this guy so important
you have to pay him?
'Cause he can guarantee puttin' us in touch
with the guy. He knows "Someshit."
It's the fastest way we can get our hands
on this guy and the suitcase full of crank.
- All right. How fast do you need it?
- Guy stole over a hundred pounds.
He's holdin' a fire sale.
It's only a matter of hours before he finds a taker.
- Or Ochoa's guy finds him first.
- [Reyes] My boys put a lot ofhours into this.
Hate to see it slip away,
end up on the street after all that.
All right. I can authorize the reward,
but expediting it's another question.
A two-year-old girl was executed.
Two-year-old?
Hell, I'll give you some money.
Nah, it's okay, pal.
We got it.
Let's go.
You didn't tell me I.A.D.
Set up shop in the Barn.
Yeah, well this guy's
a special kind of asshole.
- [Door Closes]
- [Aceveda] Kavanaugh's case against you...
is a hell of a lot stronger
than you think.
Since when are you
lookin'out for me?
He's holding back his trump card
until he can nail all four of you.
It turns out he reports directly to ChiefJohnson.
Even the mayor's office is involved.
The city is committed
on getting its P.R. Win off you guys.
But, um, I could broker a deal-
make sure the jail time's knocked down...
- to just one year for all of you-
- No.
- Instead of the seven to 10
that you're lookin' at now.
- No way.
Look, all you need to do is give Kavanaugh
something on the others-
something that will give the city its win.
Give him Vic.
He's dragging you down.
And any of this...
"all for one, one for all" pep talk
he's feeding you is a bunch of bullshit.
[Sighs]
Fine, but you gotta let me know soon.
Look, when are you gonna get it through
your head? I don't want your helpl
It's just one yearl
Lem, one year for all of you.
Just one year for all the shit
you guys have done!
But if you're too stupid to take it...
well, then the four of you
deserve everything you get.
[Door Opens, Closes]
Let me know when you see him,
but let him get all the way in the apartment.
- All right. Copy.
- [Mackey] Stay sharp.
Man, you didn't say you was gonna be usin'
my house. Man, I would've charged you more.
Twenty-five grand was to lure him here.
I said nothin' about protecting you.
Man, shit.
- ##[Rock, In Distance]
- Hold on. Someone's comin'.
- ## [Louder, On Speaker]
- Hey, I think that's him.
- ## [Stops]
- [Whispering] Okay. Come on. Come on.
[Mackey]
Okay, we're ready.
You know, this guy's tweakin'big-time.
[Ronnie]
Where's he goin'?
[Curtis]
Shit. Vic, he's goin'to the wrong door.
- Does he have the drugs?
- No. Maybe in his car, but it's not on him now.
- [Knocking]
- What is he doin'?
I can't see past this goddamn fence.
[Curtis On Radio]
He's arguing with the woman next door.
She's telling him he's got the wrong place,
but he's not leaving.
We need him and the drugs.
- [Shusett Arguing]
- Goddamn it.
- [Speaking Spanish]
- Oh, shit. Hey, Vic, Vic,
Reyes and his guy are moving.
- [Ronnie]
We gotta go too, man. There's kids around.
- No, goddamn it. Stay put.
- [Ronnie On Radio] Shit!
- [Shusett] Listenl Goddamn you.
Speak to me in Englishl I'm supposed to meet
Burnout here right now. You understand me?
- I wanna see Burnout.
- Yo, what's happenin', man? Chill out.
- Hey, let her go. Everyone back! Back!
- [Child] Mommyl
- Let's go!
- Go!
- Go! Go! Go!
[Man]
Gol Get out ofherel Get back across the streetl
- Got a hostage.
- Yeah, and a damn good vantage point.
- SWAT's rollin', 15 minutes out.
- [Glass Shatters]
[Shusett]
Back off! You guys back off!
Shithead's on a Mexican high.
We don't have 15.
- No.
- [Gunfire]
- Heyl I want a plane or I'll kill the bitch.
- This girl's toast, man.
Let's pull back and wait for SWAT.
- Anyone got a better idea?
- [Shusett] Okay, lady. You stay over therel
Department lets you guys carry C-4?
- Yeah, just finished my weekend in the Guard.
- [Shusett Continues Shouting]
- Never hurts to bring home
some supplies from the office.
- Yeah.
Whenever you're ready.
- You're sure about this?
- It's this woman's best shot
at gettin' outta there alive.
All right. Let's do it.
[Cell Phone Rings, Beeps]
- Yeah.
- It's just him at the window now.
It's clear. Go now.
- [Mackey] Okay.
- Ready!
Do it!
[Coughing]
[Woman Crying Out In Spanish]
- [Shane] You okay? You okay?
- Don't move!
Got him? Come on.
Let's get you out ofhere. Come on.
Don't move.
Gimme your hand. Give it!
You had the drugs.
Why'd you have to kill that little girl?
Wasn't me.
Drugs were stolen from Ochoa's house
same timeJenny and the kid were killed.
I got news for you. That little girl-
the one you killed this morning-
she was your own blood.
You had a daughter, Ted.
You didn't just kill an innocent child.
You murdered your own baby girl.
Two-and-a-half years plus nine months.
That means you and the ex, what?
Christmastime, three years ago.
You do so much meth you forget
how to do a little arithmetic, Ted?
Wouldn't kill my own girl-
not if I knew.
Hey, what was her name?
What was her name?
- It was good workin'with you.
Pretty crazy stunt, blowin'that wall.
- Yeah.
I talked to my captain.
This I.A.D. Thing is really pretty entrenched...
- so-
- Means I'm gettin' shit done, right?
Yeah. I would love to work with you again...
but the boss-
he won't have you workin' for me, so-
You know what?
Saves me givin' him the bad news.
Me and my guys, we talked about it.
We're happy where we are.
[Quietly]
All right. All right.
- I'll see you on the diamond, then?
- Yeah.
[Door Buzzes]
Hey. Listen to this.
When I was talkin' to Kavanaugh,
I noticed he was wearin' a wedding ring.
But he's been divorced, like, two years.
What's that about?
Huh. Well, maybe
this gives us somethin'-
lets us put our boot
on his neck for a change.
Policel Open upl
Give me the key.
[TV: Voices Chattering]
Ms. Gardner?
Fatima, you need to open up, ma'am.
- [Fatima Screaming]
- It's all right. It's okay.
- No! No, please no.
- It's okay, ma'am. You're safe.
We're not here to hurt you.
- [Continues Whimpering]
- It's okay.
We have him in custody.
You have nothing to worry about.
And what if you can't arrest him again?
Now he knows I've talked to you.
[Dutch]
He values his relationship with you.
[Fatima]
He was always our little prince-
a sweet, sensitive boy
with just me, my mom and auntie.
We just wanted him to know
he was special.
Unfortunately, that resulted
in his narcissism.
So how do you want to play this?
[Door Closes]
We found Fatima-
strangled, dumped in an alley.
I'd say sorry,
but this is the way you wanted it, isn't it?
It's all you: Your signature.
[Exhales]
You're wrong.
You killed her
like you did those other girls.
You're telling me you have blackouts
after you kill 'em? You don't remember it?
[Clicks Tongue]
No, no. This is you.
Your fault.
You should've found her in time.
You didn't even try.
This was all you.
And now ya sit here blubbering,
expecting mercy from God's vengeance...
when you didn't even give a damn
about those brothers and sisters...
the mothers and fathers
of the girls you killed.
How many of them had to suffer
because you felt you had the right to kill?
You didn't respect them.
You didn't even see them as people.
- And now your own sister-
the one who took care of you-
- [Spits]
- Oh.
- Jesus.
[Chuckles]
- He's not gonna break.
- Oh, he's crackin'.
No, Dutch, he's not.
He's, uh- His grief over his sister's death
is fueling his rage.
Just one more push-
I can't.
[Sniffles]
- Oh, don't- don't pull out now.
- [Sighs]
Dutch...
I can't do this.
W-Well, you have to do it.
There's no evidence. You've accessed this guy
better than anyone else ever has.
That's why it has to be you, now.
You're-You're-You're so close.
[Quietly] I can't. Look at me.
[Sobs]
- [Sniffles]
- You've accused me
of letting you being sick get in the way.
Well, now you're letting it.
This guy is a killer,
and I don't give a shit...
how tired or weak or pained you are.
If he walks today, he's gonna come after
Fatima or you or some other woman.
So you get back in there,
and you close him.
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Sniffles, Sighs]
As your lawyer,
it's a mistake and a big one.
But you know I have to do it.
You can't change the past,
and it only makes the present harder.
I can't get a fresh start
unless I know she has one.
- It's dangerous.
- It makes amends.
I'll deal with the danger later.
- Haven't been here in years.
- Young and poor-
We actually thought
this was fine dining, remember?
[Corrine]
This doesn't feel too weird.
Listen, l-
You and the kids
can't get caught up with this.
- Well, feels like it's too late.
- No, it's not.
I want you to get a lawyer. Make a deal
that gets you clear with Kavanaugh.
- And make sure he gets you I.R.S. Immunity too.
- But he-
And I want you to answer all his questions.
From now on, complete cooperation-
like, the whole truth,
no matter what it makes me look like.
I don't want anything
to happen to you.
Let me worry about me.
You just worry about our three.
- What do I say about the money?
- Well, when we needed it, I came up with it.
I said I was gonna take some overtime
to cover the expenses.
As far as you know,
that's what I did.
- But that's not gonna go with anything-
- Let me worry about me.
Menu hasn't changed.
Ah, some things never do.
Maybe I should just give them some minor bullshit
that won't stick. Get us all out of it.
You gonna trust Aceveda now?
Hey.
[Sighs]
Why are we havin' this conversation without Vic?
'Cause Vic's listenin' to his lawyer
more than he's listenin' to us.
I don't like her representing
all four of us.
But I hate to say it, but we all...
have different levels of involvement.
Yeah, they'll get Lem on possession.
They'll get me and Vic on tax evasion.
You're the only one clean so far.
Hey, I'm in this with you,
and so is Vic.
But I don't like
this unified lawyer front.
Kavanaugh cannot handle
four lawyers pokin' holes in his case.
I say we all lawyer up, get them to throw
everything they can at him. Keep him off balance.
I mean, what are we waiting for?
- Vic.
- [Scoffs]
[Scoffs]
The medical examiner found
the hair of an African-American male...
on last night's victim's body.
We're gonna need to draw some blood
and take some hair samples.
- I won't agree to that.
- It's not your choice anymore.
It's the court's.
It's real stupid of you.
You got so pissed at us asking you questions
about Fatima's disappearance...
you finally got sloppy-
went out there, killed in a hurry.
All the other times
your planning was just perfect. Why?
You've sat here before.
What's different this time?
You had a fight with Fatima?
She confront you about the other girls?
Is that why you finally killed your own sister?
Or was it just me you couldn't control?
- I didn't kill her.
- You must have known what was happening-
seen her loathing,
her disappointment.
When she came to see us,
she said it was all her fault.
- She never came to you.
- Sald she should have trled to stop you.
Is that what happened?
She tried to stop you?
You're bleeding.
- [Door Opens]
- Let's get some ice.
- I'm fine.
- Come with me.
No.
Fatima hated you.
Her own brother, a killer.
- She loved me.
- And you loved her?
Bullshit.
You killed her over and over.
All those girls-
Texas, here, and God knows where else-
they were all Fatima to you.
You needed her, but you hated her.
And then you killed them until
you finally got up the courage to kill her.
- No.
- And now with that hair we found
on that woman last night...
we got you, you son of a bitch.
I've got you for her,
and the jury-
if I got one-will put all the others
on you too, including your sister.
- I didn't-
- We have the evidence this time.
- I could never-
- You killed Fatima...
and the hair proves you killed
the woman last night.
She was nothin'!
Those others were nothin'.
Fatima- Fatima was my sister.
So the others-you killed them?
[Exhales]
Pauline Wahler last night?
Mary Simpson?
Lana Gregory?
[Sighs]
They were just... things.
You could hardly call that killin'.
- The ones in Texas.
- Them too.
But not Fatima. Not her.
She was a person.
I didn't kill her.
Fatima?
You did this? You helped them
make me think you were dead?
Your soul's gonna burn, Kleavon.
And until it does, I'll visit you.
- You bitch!
- [Sobs] You're never gonna see Mom and Auntie.
They're cryin'over what you've done.
What's wrong with you?
- Why'd you tell them?
- Move!
- Someone get her out of here!
- You traitor! I'm your blood!
- What's wrong with you?
- [Claudette] Someone get her out ofherel
- [Sobs] Kleavonl
- Put him in there to cool off, huh? Claudette!
- [Dutch] Oh, my Godl
- [All Clamoring]
Claudettel
- Claudette?
- He pushed her.
- What's goin' on?
- No, no. She fainted. She was out before she fell.
- Claudette?
- She fell?
- She bleeding?
Don't-Don't move her.
Call the paramedics.
- Look, her neck is-
- [Julien] Call an ambulance.
- [Dutch] C-Claudette?
- Dispatch, we need paramedics immediately.
Who's goin'to hell now?
- She's breathing.
- Hey, hey, hey, Claudette? Claudette?
- C-Claudette?
- [Chatter Continues]
- [Siren Wailing, Approaching]
- [Dutch Whimpers]
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Continues]
##[Ends]