Previously on The Shield.
- The bosses are shipping grenades into L.A.
- Guardo's in charge.
- Get 'em up!
- [Shouting]
Grenade!
Guardo's gone.
- Vic. What the hell?
- Kavanaugh. What did you tell him?
That I saw your guy
take the heroin. That's it.
Six months
you could've warned me!
Maybe all of us are going to jail
because of you!
- Without you, I.A.D.'s case goes away.
- [Whimpering]
[Door Opens]
Jesus. It's you.
- You're trying to get Mackey running to me.
- I want trust between you two.
The enemy of my enemy
is my friend?
[Kavanaugh] They're gonna need
a friend in a high place, like you.
If Kavanaugh's successful,
I will scorch the earth...
covering this whole department,
starting with you.
Ever hear of an Armenian
money train?
It's a money-laundering operation
of the Armenian mob.
I think the Strike Team
ripped them off.
Heard you had a rough week,
so I told Jon I'd stop by.
Your ex-wife's pussy
tastes like sweet butter.
You're under arrest for possession of heroin
with intent to distribute!
[Curtis] If I plead guilty
to the heroin thing, this all seals off.
He's got nothin' on you guys.
I got Niners
in every pen in the state...
so wherever he touches down,
it will happen.
You send Lem to Lompoc,
it's you that's the real murderer.
You don't have the stomach
to serve Lem up to Antwon.
I didn't use to.
[Rebecca] They're taking him to the courthouse,
9:00 tomorrow morning.
- I gotta tell you something.
- What?
You're not going to prison. We made a deal
with Antwon to get you safe passage inside.
It went bad.
Antwon's blaming me.
What the hell
am I supposed to do?
- We're gonna hide you locally.
- Putting him on the run?
- I can't run anymore.
- Lem, this is about keeping you alive!
- [Curtis] No.
- [Mackey] It's only temporary.
I promise you that.
I promise you we're gonna make this work.
He screwed my ex-wife
with the sole purpose...
of making this investigation
seem like a personal vendetta.
You have 48 hours
to tie up loose ends.
[Knocking]
Can I talk to you for a second?
- [Corrine] Why are you here?
- First of all...
I need you to know
I always liked you...
from the first moment
that we met at the school.
I hated that I wasn't able
to tell you the truth about who I was.
Maybe- Maybe if I had,
you'd have a whole different picture of me.
I mean, you liked me, right?
Before you found out
I was a, you know...
you thought
I was like a decent guy?
[Whispers]
Yes.
Different circumstances,
different time...
our relationship
could've taken a different turn.
I'm just really,
really tired, you know?
I have- I haven't
been able to eat lately.
[Corrine]
I'm gonna go put on a robe.
- [Mackey] Why aren't you guys inside?
- Lem's not here yet.
Where is he?
He's already half an hour late.
He'll be here.
How are you this morning?
I'm okay.
- [Phone Beeps]
- He didn't leave a message.
If I was going to jail for 18 months,
I wouldn't be in a rush either.
Give him some time.
I've made you coffee,
and I've been patient.
You need to go.
Okay, stop. Stop. Stop!
- Don't touch me.
- Right. You're right.
- That's good. That's good.
- Why are you still here?
[Sighs]
Because there's nowhere else.
Don't you see how lonely
he's made both of us?
I'm not lonely. I'm moving on with my life.
You need to do the same.
Not until there's justice.
- You need to let this go. You need to let it go.
- No, I don't.
Because nobody ever
fights back against him.
Nobody ever takes his punch
and just smacks him one right back.
You need to leave.
If I take this fight to him...
and I win...
I need to know
that you're gonna be okay.
'Cause I don't want you
to hurt anymore.
What are you talking about?
Would you be all right
without him?
- No.
- Mom?
- What's going on?
- Your mom, she's...
a very good person.
She's a...
very good person.
[Bang]
Kavanaugh was here?
All morning?
Yeah. He said
he wanted to ask me...
a few questions
to wrap up his case, but-
- Did he try to touch you?
- Why would you ask that?
[Exhales]
Wh-What did he say?
He was desperate and kind of lonely,
and I felt bad for him.
Then out of nowhere he said he's coming
after you, and he wanted to make sure...
- me and the kids would be okay if-
- If something happened to me.
This is about Lem.
He didn't show up at court to turn himself in.
- Where is he?
- Nobody knows. He's a fugitive.
Kavanaugh probably figures
I had something to do with it.
No, I didn't. He's just pissed
because his case against Lem tanked.
He's making it personal.
He wants to hurt me through you.
Please, don't let him
in this house again. All right?
- [No Audible Dialogue]
- All right.
- Be careful.
- Always.
- Where's Lemansky?
- I don't know.
You screwed him once, and now you've
done it again, putting him on the run.
[Shane] Didn't they kick
your ass out of the Barn?
You aid and abet him, you communicate
with him in any way without reporting it...
you'll be put in prison
alongside ofhim.
We had nothing
to do with this.
My office will have eyes on all of you
every second of every day...
until Lemansky's caught.
Thank you for bringing me back
into your life.
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Ends]
Where are we
with those errands?
Spoke to our "federale" buddy
who took Doomsday off our hands.
He's gonna meet Lem in T.J.,
get him to a safe house in Ensenada.
- That's wall-to-wall wetbacks.
Surfer boy'll be obvious.
- He'll be on the move.
Taco cop's got a brother. Owns a goat ranch
in the mountains north of San Ignacio.
- It's a really good place to get lost.
- How much?
Two grand. And a call on our
services to be determined later.
Oh, I can't wait.
What about living expenses?
Got a line on wire transfers
through Guatemala.
- [Mackey] How secure?
- Enough to keep it off Immigration's radar.
- Used to pay coyotes, mostly.
- [Mackey] He's gonna need cash.
- It's gonna be his only leverage.
- Let me work on that.
Now all we need is a way
to get him across the border.
How are we gonna
pull that off, man?
Kavanaugh and his cronies
are watching us 24-7.
We're gonna pull it off
the way we always do-
right under their noses
with a goddamn smile.
- [Police Radio Chatter]
- [Sirens Approach]
Claudette.
We were working something else.
Not anymore. You've got history
with these grenade tossers.
- Any victims?
- Just a half dozen Crown Vics.
You've tangled with some
well-armed Salvadoreans before, right?
The guy who imports the grenades
is named Guardo.
We hit him hard
and his weapons stash, but he got away.
Looks like he didn't go far.
- Agent Gallagher, D.E.A.
- Captain Wyms.
- Farmington Division.
- This is our lot.
We've been running an op on the
El Salvadorans out of the travel agency.
Someone wants to move
up to first class.
Detective Mackey and his team
busted some of that gang a week ago.
Swept up a bunch of grenades,
MP5's, few top-level lieutenants.
And let their playmaker Guardo
slip out from under your nose.
- We're here to assist.
- Great. Start directing traffic.
Look, a grenade goes off on my turf,
you get help whether you like it or not.
Don't step on our toes.
We'll stay off yours.
What an asshole.
Well, Rawling did burn them.
But now's our chance to make it up.
Track down whatever you can find.
Run everything by me.
And, Vic, that renegade shit's not gonna fly
on my watch. But you already knew that.
Looks like a new sheriff
just limped into town.
Well, she's smart.
She keeps tabs on us from her end...
D.E.A. Keeps an eye on us
from the other.
I don't give a shit about either.
We'll follow up on this, but finding Lem
safe passage to Mexico's still priority one.
- [Child Crying]
- ##[Loud Rock]
- [Crying Continues]
- ##[Continues]
- [Child Crying]
- ##[Loud Rock]
Hey, hello.
Hey, open the door.
Open the door now!
[Announcer On Radio]
[Crying]
Hey, it's okay. It's okay. Where's your mommy?
Where's your mommy?
- [Girl] She's gone.
- She's gone.
Hey, buddy, what's your name?
- What's your name? What's his name?
- Wendell.
Wendell, you want me
to wash that out for you?
Shh. It's okay.
It's gonna be all right, buddy.
- It's gonna be okay. It's just a little cut.
- [Sniffling]
- It's all right.
- What the hell's going on in here, guys?
- It's okay. It's all right.
- Lisa.
It's okay. I'm a cop.
- Lisa, there's a gun. Call the policel
- Come here. Come here.
- Lisa, are you calling?
- Hold this tight till someone gets here, okay?
Okay, buddy.
That's the guy. I told you
something wasn't right with him.
[Woman]
He had a gun?
- [Pool Balls Clack]
- [Chattering]
[Mackey]
Yo.
Hey!
We're cops! We're cops! Get out.
- [Mackey] Right now.
- [Man] What do you want?
Some of your Salvadoran amigos went all
Superdome on a D.E.A. Parking lot.
Turned some Crown Vics
into some scrap metal.
- [Shouts]
- Start talkin' before he goes
Superdome on your head.
The D.E.A.'s been up our ass.
Busted our number two, Osario.
Bosses sent a message
to the feds.
[Cell Phone Rings]
Yeah.
That's the third Mexican that gave up
that it's payback for busting Osario.
Which means it can't
possibly be true.
Soldiers have been fed
their cover story, but what's the truth?
- Hey. I think Kavanaugh found Lem's trailer.
- What?
Sheriff's department got called
to the trailer park on a disturbance.
Cliff says Kavanaugh's
on his way there now.
- Your pal say anything about Lem?
- No, radio blackout.
- But something's poppin'.
- If Kavanaugh's poking around,
what else could it be?
We'd have heard something
if they arrested him.
Maybe. Maybe not.
Who knows with Kavanaugh?
Maybe they found him, and he was-
There's no way
he'd eat his gun. No way.
We told him not to contact us
at any cost.
We're in no-man's-land.
Best-case scenario,
he's on the run with Kavanaugh on his ass.
Look. Lem knows the score. He's gonna
meet us tonight and get supplies...
which means we gotta pull our shit together
and get his ticket outta here by then.
Truth is, this could be good-bye.
Come on.
Well, he went runnin' that way.
[Man]
This is it.
- That the man you saw?
- Yeah. That's him.
- So, what happened?
- I heard something.
Came outside. Saw him in the trailer.
Saw the kid bleeding.
Did he say anything to you?
He said he was a cop.
The whole thing
seemed pretty weird...
so I had my lady
call the real cops.
- What then?
- Oh, he was off and running.
Funny thing was,
big guy like that with a gun and all...
he still looked awful scared.
Yeah, it's funny.
[Mackey]
What's this?
Your former C.I. Says she's got information
on the demolished D.E.A. Cars.
[Mackey] Give her to the feds.
We don't want her.
- I tried. She'll only talk to you.
- Kavanaugh cut me loose, Vic.
I'm not working
for him no more.
Now that you stabbed
one of my guys with an indictment?
You need another P.D. Tit
to suck on?
It's- It's-
It's real good intel.
- It's not my dime. Your call.
- Give us a minute.
I know she's the one
Kavanaugh had testify against Lem.
- It's all bullshit.
- She as inside as she says?
See what the story is.
Make sure she sticks around the Barn
where I can see her.
Blowing up those D.E.A.
Cars wasn't retaliation.
- Nothin' we don't know.
- Guardo's play for drug protection's paid off.
Colombians have a huge shipment
coming up from Mexico.
Hired him and his crew
to guard it.
The feds feel like they were
making a dent in the Salvadoran drug game.
Meanwhile, something else
is going on underneath their noses.
Yeah. Guardo's a crazy shithead.
- Any excuse to blow something-
- When and where?
Tonight. Going through
a grocery import guy. Aldo Melchor.
The importer- he Salvadoran?
Mexican.
Need a place and a time.
That's-That's all I got.
- That's real good information, though.
- Yeah, if it's true.
Not just another chance for you
to help Kavanaugh to nail us again.
No. I never wanted
to help Kavanaugh. L-
Right. Now who's the source
of your intel?
- You never needed to know that before.
- I trusted you before.
Fine.
I wanna get paid up front then.
I need money to get out of L.A.,
take Sebastio, head up to Seattle...
be with my sister.
I'm so happy you got a little plan.
What about Lem?
He gonna head up to Seattle...
live with your sister too?
Oh, that's right, he can't.
Because he's gonna be in prison.
- I'm sorry!
- Vic took care of you!
He fed you and your kid
for months.
- And you were sticking us
the whole goddamn time!
- No!
You see this? I slept with this scumbag Ignacio
to get this info for you, okay?
Then two of his buddies
joined in, ripped me up pretty bad.
If you...
made different choices
from the beginning...
none of us would be
ripped up right now.
##[Rap]
[Chattering]
Becca.
Come on. Make it look like
we're on a date.
I can't do anything
to help you escape the police.
Make it look like
a lover's quarrel then.
The only advice I can give you legally
is to turn yourself in now.
- That's exactly what I wanna do.
- Then you're on the wrong side of town.
- Look, I need assurances.
- You're not exactly in a position to-
I need to do my time someplace where the
One-niners and Antwon Mitchell can't get to me.
- Federal prison back east.
- The feds aren't calling this.
And going fugitive
means the original deal's gone.
Then I'll plead
to new federal charges.
I'll tell them
all the shit that I did.
- You can't just serve them
your head on a platter either.
- Kavanaugh's not gonna stop...
till he's carving me up.
Tell them that I ripped off
an Armenian money-laundering operation...
stole cash that was part
of a federal sting- I'll plead to that.
- You did this by yourself?
- Yeah.
Listen to me. They're going to
insist on Vic and the others.
I got nothing to say
about them.
- Then why are you running?
- I'm not running. I'm giving myself up.
- I'm ending it.
- You want a new deal.
They'll want new information.
I'm giving them new
information on myself.
You are not hearing me.
There will be no deal
until you give them more than you.
Curtis, please. Listen to me.
You have got to think
about yourself- this one time.
It's your only option.
Vic told me you guys sometimes spread around
drug money to keep peace on the streets.
- I can spin that-
- Listen. This Armenian thing was armed robbery.
People got killed.
And they weren't the only ones.
You think it was all just-just palming off
some drug money to keep the streets quiet?
I can't tell the truth
about the others...
because they'll throw us away
for the rest of our lives.
- Open your goddamn eyes to who we are!
- People got killed?
This is all
attorney-client privilege.
- Detective Terry Crowley-
- You've heard enough.
Just get me my deal.
Do my time back east.
Then I'll turn myself in.
I'll call you in a few hours.
[Machine Hums]
Ow! Goddamn it!
[Billings] You gonna put me
at your old desk?
What are you doing, Dutch?
- Piece of shit just scalded my hand.
- Could have been user error.
If you can push through the pain,
we've got a woman assaulted on Vermont.
- Let's roll.
- Get a statement from her.
What- Um, you're not
pairing me up with him.
You're the only two singles on the floor.
Consider it permanent.
- Cross street's Seventh.
- Hey, it's no great joy for me either.
I'm gonna put some ice on this.
Six months I kept this place
runnin'smooth as silk, and for what?
No commendation.
No letter for my package.
Not even a "Hey, Steve, way to go."
It's humiliating.
Welcome back.
[Giggling]
See? No respect.
Wyms is even moving my desk...
where everybody can get a good gander
at Caesar lying in a puddle of blood.
So in this story you're Caesar?
Did I get stabbed
in the back or not?
Um, I'm driving.
I get nauseous
in the passenger seat.
Why don't you apply for a transfer,
show 'em they can't kick you around?
Nah. I got this commute
all figured out.
Besides, it's only 56 months
till I retire...
then I get outta
this shithole for good.
##[Spanish Muzak]
Aldo Melchor.
Hey! Let me see your hands!
Easy, easy.
It's a knife.
To cut my chorizo.
It's okay if I have my lunch?
As long as it's finger food.
What can I do
for you officers?
Rumor has it you import more than
just chorizo from down south.
Everything in this store is legal.
Really?
You won't mind if we stick around,
monitor your import/ export?
- I close at 7:00.
- Not tonight.
You're gonna stay open
until that shipment of coke arrives.
We're just gonna hang out,
provide a little after-hours security.
Salvadorans realize
you snitched on 'em...
they're gonna grind you
into chorizo...
sell you by the quarter-pound like the rest
of the sausage you got down there.
Is there something
I can do for you?
Tell us what time
the shipment comes.
We'll keep you out of it,
bust the Salvadorans after they leave...
keep your pipeline
up and running.
What else?
Obviously, you can import.
Your exporting skills
better be just as good.
I've stayed in business 15 years.
We got a little package
we want to overnight to Mexico.
- How big is it?
- About 6'2".
Just heard.
He's a good-looking kid.
His name's Lee...
after my dad.
Congratulations.
Yeah. Thanks.
- You good? You need anything?
- My mom's coming in tomorrow.
My two brothers this weekend.
- I got more help than I know what to do with.
- Mm-hmm. Oh.
Cash from the baby pool.
It was pretty shrewd
not revealing the baby's daddy.
- Wanna hold him?
- Sure.
[Baby Murmurs]
- [Whimpers]
- Shh.
Okay.
We didn't find a winner. Uh-
Everyone thought you could use it
more than anyone else, so-
It's almost three grand.
My evil plan worked.
Tell everyone I said thank you.
When he's old enough
and he asks...
I'll tell him.
But for now, I just-
When he's old enough.
[Squeaks]
- [Phone Rings]
- [Chattering]
[Mackey, Whispering]
Hey. Yol
[Mackey] You wanna tell me what the hell
Becca's doing up there?
Talking to Kavanaugh
and Aceveda.
You think of any scenario
where that's a good thing?
Curtis Lemansky is prepared
to turn himself in.
If you talked to him, you have
an obligation to tell us where he is.
I know my obligations.
I don't know where he is.
Curtis knows where the Barn is
ifhe wants to turn himself in.
He couldn't turn himself over to you
for reasons that involve his safety.
Any cop who's incarcerated faces those risks.
He knew that.
He made his choice
when he broke the law.
This was a calculated move
by Lieutenant Kavanaugh...
to put Curtis's life in jeopardy
to compel him to testify against his team.
[Aceveda]
You have any proof of that?
Look, the department
wants to mitigate the damage.
When Lemansky didn't
show up for processing...
the chiefhanded authority
to my police committee.
All we're asking for is protection...
at least until I have a chance to investigate
his claims against Lieutenant Kavanaugh.
- And after that?
- He'll accept the previous deal.
As long as we can reasonably
guarantee his safety.
He can't have the same deal.
He ran away from that deal.
And if the council signs off,
they're gonna want more.
My client is willing
to plead to new charges.
- But he wants his choice of federal prisons.
- What's he say about his friends?
- Nothing.
- [Kavanaugh] Not good enough.
I have to run this up
a few ladders, so, uh...
give me till
the end of the day.
Look, I'll- I'll find him first.
Then we can dictate the terms.
I need bodies though. I want two
surveillance teams on Mackey and his guys...
in case they try to help
Lemansky escape.
You've burned your bridges
with the chief.
I need my people on the street.
Becca! Becca,
what happened with Lem?
- Is he all right?
- Privileged information.
Tell me he's okay.
At least tell me
what's wrong.
- Wait!
- Don't touch me.
Haven't you done
enough damage yet?
Becca, come on.
Come on.
- Let's go somewhere and talk.
- Talk about...
armed robbery of an Armenian
money-laundering operation?
Talk about
murdering Terry Crowley?
- I told you.
- Yes, you did.
And now I know the truth.
I let you touch me.
- It makes me sick.
- Becca.
I don't know what
Lem told you-
No more explanations.
It's all bullshit.
You've lied so much...
you forgot what the truth is.
Was I lying to you last night?
I don't ever want to
think about last night.
You know,
I was worried about...
what I'd do if I had to choose between
being Curtis's lawyer or your friend.
Not anymore.
[Engine Starts]
[Billings] Did you see the guy
who attacked you?
No. He just came up from behind me
and started hitting me...
and I was trying
to cover my face.
This area can get pretty rough even in daylight.
What were you doing here?
Besides, uh, prettying up the place.
[Laughs]
Thanks. Um...
I'm a volunteer tutor
at the community center on the corner.
I was trying to help
some kids, you know.
We're gonna have you come in,
look at some pictures.
But why? I told you
I didn't see him. So-
- Maybe you saw more than you think.
- Is that really necessary?
Excuse us for a minute.
Send her home.
If she remembers anything, she can call us.
Yeah. Why don't you figure out
another way to get her phone number?
'Cause I'm bringing her in.
I was acting captain, remember?
I'm making the call.
[Laughs]
Hey. I talked to the owner of the store
across from where Tori was attacked.
- He see anything?
- She saw them arguing. She went in the back.
When she came out, the guy had Tori
on the ground and was hitting her.
- You get a description?
- I got an I.D.
Owner says the guy's
a curb jockey.
Sits in a green cab most days
waiting for fares.
Well, Miss Pretty Thing never said
anything about arguing with the guy.
No. I know she didn't.
We should take another run at Tori.
Maybe she'll ask you to give her a hug.
Let's wait.
Bring the suspect in first.
Uh, yes. Yes. I'd like to
talk to the owner...
of the vending machines
at the Farmington Police Station.
- Hey, it's Curtis.
- Hi.
- Look, I'm kinda in a hurry. What's goin' on?
- They're in a holding pattern.
They said they'd take
your offer under advisement...
but gave no indication
when or what the answer might be.
Jesus Christ.
Okay, look, uh...
I need you to get
a message to Vic.
- That would be breaking the law.
- Shit.
- All right. Forget it. Forget it.
- It's gonna be worse if they catch you.
Now that I've told them what you want,
they know there's more shit to uncover.
- Kavanaugh will show no mercy.
- I know.
There is one other
option though.
- What?
- Witness Protection.
And you tell them everything.
- The entire truth.
Imagine. You'd be free
of the lies, the running.
People pay a price
for what they did.
I can't. I can't.
Curtis, you're the one
with the heart.
Now use your head!
This isn't about
my goddamn heart!
I'm just trying
to help you here, Curtis.
No, you're trying
to get me to turn...
on my family.
Please just get me my deal.
- He held on as long as he could.
- He's still holdin'.
- He didn't want to run in the first place.
- He'd run before he'd rat.
- How do they know about the money train?
- Educated guess.
There's always been plenty of suspicion,
just never any proof.
- Unless Lem gave it to them.
- [Mackey] We know Lem.
If he had a change of heart,
he would have tipped us.
Or he wouldn't if his deal
meant us going down.
I'm not saying that it happened. I'm just saying
are we willing to bet our freedom-
I'm not gonna believe it
till I see it with my own eyes.
Lem's not contacting us to protect us.
We're gonna meet him tonight at midnight...
and he's gonna travel tonight-
that's it.
Okay.
On whose nickel, man? This spic cop
doesn't take American Express.
- I know.
- It's already taken care of.
I told Mara that Lem
was in trouble.
She felt strongly
that we needed to help him.
So we pulled a little cash out of the house.
It's not a lot, but-
Five grand oughta keep him
in burritos and beer long enough, man.
All right.
Go get this cashed.
Keep half of it for tonight.
Put the rest on the wire.
Lem must have said something
to Becca about Terry too.
All that gives Kavanaugh
is a little more suspicion.
Doesn't mean we're gonna catch a case,
let alone a needle.
Lem starts talkin'...
he puts teeth in an otherwise
empty rumor.
These people,
every time they look at us...
they're gonna see
two cop killers.
That's on me.
- Terry was a decision that we both made.
- I forced it on you.
Now you're in Kavanaugh's crosshairs.
That's on me.
Lem's gonna have to hide under a rock
for the rest of his life.
- That's on me too. I know that.
- And skewering yourself is helping Lem how?
How's it gonna help
any of us?
You made a call, and that call
was to protect the team.
That couldn't have gone down
any other way.
And it's done. It's done.
Now, is he still on our side
against Kavanaugh?
I'm gonna find out.
[Mackey]
Yol
What the hell was that
powwow upstairs about?
- Call me later.
- I'm runnin'out oflater.
Now. Are you and me still allies
against Kavanaugh?
Or do I pull out my flamethrower
and start that scorched-earth plan...
that I talked to you about?
Becca's being a good lawyer.
Lem wants to turn himself in
if he can get his original deal back.
Kavanaugh won't sign off on it.
He's gonna file new charges for him running.
- I thought Kavanaugh was outta the picture.
- He was until Lem didn't show.
And now the chief's believing
that Kavanaugh was right.
He's giving him back
all his power.
- What about Lem? Gonna
let him twist in the wind?
- Claudette's gonna call the D.A.
But she's waiting as long as she can
to give Kavanaugh a chance to find Lem.
- That's all I know.
- You gotta throw a wrench in the works.
You wanted an inside guy for intel.
You got one.
You need help aiding
and abetting a fugitive, find someone else.
- [Billings] What happened to your face?
- Nothing. What happened to yours?
Where were you
at 8:00 a.m. This morning?
- Driving. Working.
- On what, your right cross?
Witness says
you attacked Tori Burke.
Also says you two had an argument first.
What was that about?
You just think you can go around
beating women on the street?
How do you know her?
She take your cab?
You stalking her or something?
Okay, your thing is just knocking the shit
out of random total strangers.
- Works for me, Gilbos.
- So l- So I picked up a hooker.
I'm not the only guy
who's had to bust out of a slump.
Doesn't mean I deserve
to get rolled and robbed.
- Say again.
- She set me up.
Soon as I got my clothes off
and my dick hard...
these two black guys ran in,
started smashing me up.
Took everything.
The woman you attacked
is a volunteer tutor for at-risk kids.
She was on her way to a session
when you jumped her.
That whore flagged my cab, okay?
Offered me anything
in the book for a C-note.
Picked the motel,
then had her buddies steal my wallet...
and a chain
my mother gave me.
So I gave her a little payback.
Arrest her ass-not minel
So, did you find him?
We did.
Good. So I guess that means
that I can go now...
and, uh, you'll just let me know
if you need me in court or anything?
We talked to people
at the community center.
- You volunteer there
at least three days a week?
- I read to disadvantaged kids.
Are you a prostitute, Tori?
[Laughs]
Maybe in your fantasy
I'm a prostitute-
You know what? Um...
if I'm gonna be insulted on top of assaulted,
I think I'd like to leave.
Okay. Uh, we need
to ask you a few more questions.
You're a suspect in
a separate assault and robbery.
I'd like to see
my legal counsel.
[Mackey] All right.
They're moving the blow into the van.
- Still no sign of Guardo.
- They'll lead us to him.
- ##[Rock]
- [Girls Giggling]
That's the second time
that car's passed by here tonight.
What, the Mexican chicks
in the El Camino?
They don't look like Kavanaugh's boys.
I think we're all right.
[Ronnie]
Gracias. Hey.
Wire transfer went through.
Meet and greet in T.J.'s confirmed.
Now we just need to get
Lem on board.
Okay. Good. Almost home.
[Mackey]
They're on the move.
[Man Shouting Orders]
Hey. Come on.
Pairing me up with Billings?
You know a guy like this
is gonna throw me off my game.
- You'll adjust.
- L- l- I'm filing for a transfer.
- Dutch.
- No, I'm serious.
Things haven't been the same between us,
even before you got captain.
There is no reason
why we can't work this out in a new way.
Yes, there is.
The only reason I was hanging around here
was because we were partners.
That's gone.
I'd just like to move on.
Okay. I'll prepare
the paperwork.
Okay. Check this out.
Tori has an M.B.A. From UCLA.
Worked as an account manager at a brokerage
firm until she was fired six months ago.
- What for?
- Well, her work started to get sloppy...
and she stopped showing up
half the time.
- But no arrests.
- Yeah, if she's a hooker, she had me fooled.
- I can usually smell 'em.
- Excuse me, Captain.
This guy is here for Tori Burke.
I'm her legal counsel.
What are your credentials,
"Mr. Wallis, Esquire"?
What I have is a client,
and I need to see her immediately.
Now, do I get to see her now?
Or do I file for a dismissal?
- She's in 2. Show him up.
- Yes, ma'am.
I'll check him out.
I'm gettin' a whiff
of something now.
Gallagher's D.E.A. Bozos
are tied up in a sting in Compton.
They're a little short on cars.
Maybe in a few hours.
We can't wait.
We gotta meet Lem.
- What about backup from the Barn?
- [Ronnie] There's a manhunt on Curson.
A Byz Lat shot a grocery clerk,
and there's no units to spare.
We gotta go in.
There are six of them at least.
We don't know how many more inside.
Lem's gonna be waiting on us.
Who's comin'?
##[Spanish Rap]
- Get down!
- Down on the ground!
[Mackey]
Don't move! Get down on your knees!
- [Shane] I got rabbits!
- [Mackey] Let 'em runl
Get up! Let's go!
Hands on your head.
Hands on your head!
- [Mackey] You all right?
- [Shane] Yeah.
On the ground.
On the ground right now!
[Mackey]
Search itl
##[Rap Continues]
Jesus Christ!
How many grenades
do these guys got?
Claudette's so hot for these guys,
she can book 'em herself.
We gotta go get Lem.
Yes. Yes. I still wanna hold.
Tyrez Wallis is no more a lawyer
than I am a figure skater.
Really? So Dutch's
girlfriend's got a pimp?
You know, they've, uh,
been up there a while.
- Dutch, let's go.
- N-No. No, l-
l- I want the name of the owner
of these machines right now...
or you will be sitting in a holding cell
for as long as it takes me to track it down.
Dutch, let's go. Hang it up!
[Phone Closes, Beeps]
- You own those machines?
- I was just filling a need.
Isn't it illegal
for department employees...
to profit from things
like vending machines?
Especially when you use your position
as acting captain...
to create a de facto monopoly?
- I think it's more of a gray area than that.
- I don't think so.
I think it's more
black and white.
All right, so what now?
You gonna snitch me out to Wyms?
Like I haven't been
shit-hammered enough around here?
Is that what
this is gonna be?
[Laughs] I don't know
what I'm gonna do yet.
[Man And Woman Moaning]
[Claudette]
Attorney-client privilege?
It's illegal to practice law in the state of
California without a license, counselor.
What do you think?
Do I need any more practice?
[Giggles]
[Police Radio Chatter]
Bomb squad's on a crank call
at some West Side abortion clinic.
They'll pick up
the grenades later.
I told you to call in every move.
You were outnumbered 3-to-1.
They were getting ready to bolt,
split up in two vans. We had no choice.
Sorry I missed all the action.
Good work.
Just wish we were able
to nail Guardo.
He's been staying off
the front lines these days.
Probably feeling the heat
from you guys.
Two busts in as many weeks.
He's feeling your heat.
And I've seen what they do
when they get pissed.
Better watch your Crown Vics.
You should be
warning him, not me.
Thanks.
- Glad you caught the guys.
- Actually, we didn't nail Guardo.
I'll- I'll see if I can
find something out.
You find another tip,
find another buyer.
Please don't be this way. I'm sorry
I made that deal, helped Kavanaugh.
You should go.
I did it for Sebastio. You'd do
the same thing for your kids too.
Take your rat money, your retarded
rat baby kid, and get on the first bus-
- Hey, hey!
- Don't you say that about my boy!
What? You gonna let him
talk about Sebastio that way?
I showed you mercy once,
and it ruined my friend's life.
Not gonna happen again.
Get out!
The police committee
is willing to consider a deal.
- But like I thought, they
insist on adding more time.
- How much?
Maximum of 10 years with parole in four
ifhe turns himself in immediately.
- What about the safety issue?
- He'll be held in protective
custody until it's sorted out...
but there's no guarantee oflocation
unless you can prove your claims.
What about the others? No condition
about him giving us something on them?
[Aceveda] We want to
put this behind us.
If he's caught before he comes in,
all bets are off.
Excuse me.
[Door Opens]
What's going on, man?
- What-What is that?
- It wasn't my choice.
It's what the police committee
wanted.
If we don't find Lemansky before he comes in
or he gets out of the country...
we're gonna lose our last...
chance at nailing Vic...
- before this case seals off.
- What do you want me to do, Jon?
He trusts you now, right?
- When it comes to me.
- Maybe.
I want you to scare him.
I want you to make Vic
lead us to him.
- How?
- [Exhales]
We both failed at, uh,
trying to nail Mackey on old business.
They don't crack.
They don't turn on each other.
[Laughs]
Good for them.
The way to get him is
we gotta catch him in the act.
With Lemansky AWOL,
Vic knows he's got eyes and ears all over him.
He's not gonna do
anything stupid.
- Unless he thinks he's got
one last mess to clean up.
- What mess?
There's a detective I spoke to here.
He suspects that the Strike Team
robbed an Armenian money train.
- Wagenbach.
- Yeah, but he doesn't know it was Dutch.
You-You gotta
make him believe...
that Lemansky gave it up
for Witness Protection.
It'll put him in motion.
We follow. We catch him
trying to help Lemansky escape.
And nail them
for harboring a fugitive.
It won't be the amount of time they deserve,
but it'll be enough time...
to make 'em lose their badges
and get 'em off the street.
Catching 'em in the act-
that's gonna give us leverage.
Lemansky, he may have
held his tongue, but the other ones-
they might not be as strong.
Hey, it's time to put the mess
that Mackey made behind both of us.
[Siren Wailing]
- Lemansky's talking.
- That's bullshit.
Is the Armenian money train bullshit?
Because that's what he gave them.
- He's coming clean.
- There's nothin' to come clean about.
That explains where your 65,000
unaccounted-for dollars comes from.
Look, he's tired, he's scared
and he wants his freedom.
He doesn't want to die
at the hands of Antwon Mitchell.
The D.A. Says he's gotta
give him something on the team.
- I guess he's agreed.
- Lem would never agree to that.
D.A. Gave him no choice.
He has to give you guys up.
And now all this bullshit
can blow back on me.
You gotta get a message to your boy,
tell him to shut the hell up.
Can you do that? Hmm?
If you can speak to him, can you
convince him to keep his mouth shut?
Yes.
Then do it, for Christ's sake.
I don't know where he is.
You know, Kavanaugh
is out of control.
With Lemansky unaccounted for,
he's got the chief's ear...
and now the D.A.
Is smelling blood- all of ours.
I shouldn't be telling you any of this,
but you threatened me...
so now I've told you
everything I know.
Now it's time
to clean this up.
[Car Door Slams]
We'll look the other way
on solicitation...
but you gotta make
a statement...
about Spank's involvement
in the robbery and the beating...
do a little time yourself
for the stickup.
No. Spank wasn't there
when the cabbie got rolled.
If you're afraid of Spank, we'll protect you.
He will not hurt you.
You guys just see pimp and hooker.
That's not who we are.
Yeah. Says the hooker letting pimp daddy
drag her into the shit with him.
No. Actually, he dragged me out.
He dragged me out...
of the steaming shit piles
of a superficial...
empty everything.
And then he hosed me off and he held me
and he made me whole.
I had nothing.
I was nothing before I met him.
According to your sister,
you had a pretty nice condo.
You equate a roof
over your head to love?
What, exactly,
does equal love?
Do you see the wrinkles
on my face?
- Do you see them?
- Yes.
Well, Spank doesn't.
I understand you not wanting
to be away from your, uh...
boyfriend, but what do you think's
gonna happen when you go to jail?
Because we both know
that your man is just gonna set his sights...
on the next piece of Century City ass
that comes his way.
Shut your mouth!
Shut your goddamn mouth!
- Hey, hey!
- Who do you think you are? You don't know usl
- Okay.
- Get her off me, Dutch!
- Get her off me!
- No, no, no. Let's just sit down.
You don't know me!
- Sit down.
- Let go of me.
The girl just gave you up.
Says it was all your idea,
and you're the one who beat up the john.
I know that didn't happen.
Oohl She put the claws
in you, right?
You shouldn't let no woman
do you like that.
Woman like Tori, smart,
educated, good job-
how do you turn out
a girl like that?
[Chuckles]
Any punk can get
some crack ho to go down on dick.
But how do I get
a little pink toe from Westwood...
to do what I say
whenever I say?
Every chick
got a hole in her heart.
And it's connected
to the one between her legs.
I just figure out
how to fill it...
and then I feed it to her.
And I keep feedin' it
to her till it's overflowing...
until she can't live without it.
And then I take it away.
That makes me God.
Tori was easy.
Her fianc left her last year...
for some young blood bitch.
I just kept telling the old girl
she was still a prom queen...
like back in the day, and that white
faggot dude- he didn't have eyes to see.
Sooner or later,
all bitches break...
every goddamn one.
That's if you got game.
And that's why
she's your whore?
If you're born a woman,
I can make you my ho.
Which is why she's sayin'
I had nothing to do with no illegal shit.
Now that y'all got
some pimpology-
no charge- my black ass
is outta here, right?
Anyone here believe
Lem cut a deal?
Maybe he felt like
he had no choice.
[Mackey] He's out there in the wind alone.
Becca's probably pushing it.
He has no idea about
this ranch in San Ignacio...
or the money we're gonna
be funneling to him.
- Becca told you he took a deal.
- No. Aceveda.
- Aceveda?
- He's got a stake in this too.
- Not like we do.
- He could be full of shit.
Look, the truth is we can't know what's inside
Lem's head until we see him face-to-face.
We need an exit strategy.
How are we gonna get outta this?
We don't need an exit strategy.
We need to fill Lem in.
On the cash, the ranch,
lines of communication.
He's right. You know, Lem- he's been
in the dark as much as we've been.
And if Lem is talking,
it's because he believes...
that Antwon has marked him
as a dead man behind bars.
Now, once he knows
what we've pulled together for him...
he'll go along.
He will.
We go to the spot.
If he doesn't show...
- assume he made the deal.
- And then what?
[Shane]
If he does show...
then we'll take
his temperature...
make sure he's still
solidly on board.
He'll be on board.
Lem trusts us.
He trusts us.
And I still trust Lem.
I do.
[Men Chattering]
- Where's Vendrell?
- [Kyle] Shit, they're taking different cars.
- I take Mackey. You take Gardocki.
- All right.
- [Kavanaugh] Kyle, keep your distance.
- Okay.
[Phone Beeping]
Ronnie, I got a tail.
I'm trying to lose him.
- You sure?
- He's pretty far back, but he's there.
Watch your back, man.
- Looks like I got one too.
- Call Shane. Give him a heads-up.
##[Cell Phone Tune]
- Yeah.
- Vic and I both have tails.
Shit. I'm lookin'.
We gotta lose 'em without looking like
we're trying to. Take your time.
We can't lead Kavanaugh
to Lem.
- I don't see anyone on me yet.
- Vlc says whoever loses hls tall first...
gets to Lem, moves him someplace safe
till we can all regroup.
All right. I got it.
[Gears Clunk]
[Exhales]
[Vehicle Approaches]
- [Shane] Hey. Hey.
- Jesus, man. I'm glad to see you.
- [Curtis] What's up?
- Look, we gotta get outta here.
- What's goin' on?
- Kavanaugh's got a tail on Vic and Ronnie.
Could have an eye in the sky. Follow me to that,
uh, the old body shop that closed down...
- the one on Mission, okay?
- All right, man.
Captain?
Uh, I've been reviewing
Officer Hanlon's package.
Julien's T.O. Report.
You ignored a recommendation
for dismissal.
Right. You know,
with all due respect...
toJulien, you'll find, as I did,
that he's a little tightly wound.
Suffice it to say, I felt he was too tough
on Tina and she deserved a second chance.
"Two counts of excessive force,
contamination of crime scenes...
failure to identify
an undercover officer in the field."
[Claudette]
Seems more like a sixth chance.
Well, she's still learning her fieldwork.
But her instincts are good.
It's why Dutch agreed
to take her under his wing.
Uh, she's very intuitive.
I'm calling her P.B.A. Rep,
start the paperwork for dismissal.
You know, you may not
want to do that.
Tina and l- We, uh...
made an arrangement.
Someone was ripping off
the Gourmet Quick-Mealer.
I figured it was an inside job,
so I put a nanny cam in the locker room.
There are photos of Officer Hanlon
in her skivvies that got out into the world.
The important thing is is that Dutch and I
handled it quietly and efficiently.
Uh, all I did was find the pictures,
bring them to Steve's attention.
I had nothing to do
with any deal.
Please. You helped cover up this mess
for a shot in Hanlon's panties.
- Asshole!
- You wanna spend your first month on the job...
overseeing a full-time lawsuit, ruining
several careers, Wagenbach's included?
Go right ahead.
- Asshole.
- [Door Closes]
[Tires Screeching]
I never thought
it'd come to this.
Hasn't come
to anything yet.
What now?
I'll go back
and get Vic and Ronnie.
We got a way for you
to get to Mexico. [Laughs]
What, like Gilroy?
No, man. The man died alone.
- I'm not goin' that route.
- You're not a miserable drunk.
- It's gonna be different.
- No, it won't.
It won't.
Look, I'm not goin'.
- No more running.
- So you spend the rest of your life...
Iooking over your shoulder
for Antwon Mitchell?
You in Mexico's the only thing that keeps us
all safe, man, especially you.
- How the hell am I gonna live in Mexico?
- We got it all figured out.
- How?
- San Ignacio.
- What the hell is that, some shithole?
- No, man. It's a ranch.
Up in the mountains! We got a "federale"
that's gonna get you there.
It's beautiful, man.
It's gonna be peaceful.
We got money parked
in an account for you. It's all set up.
Mara and I even
kicked in five grand for you.
- I don't want that.
- It's just a start.
We'll keep skimming off the street, man.
We'll keep you hooked up.
I can't. I can't.
I can't do that.
It's all in play.
Trust me, man.
It's gonna work. It's gonna work.
There's a way for me
to take the hit solo.
No, there's not!
No, there's not, man! Kavanaugh?
Aceveda? The D.A.?
There's no other deal to make!
They're gonna make you
give us up.
Maybe not now.
Maybe a year from now. Look, man.
You got one chance
to get outta here.
Take it, man.
Take that chance right now. Take it.
I got it figured out.
Why'd you even come back here tonight
if you weren't planning on leaving?
Dude, I came to see you guys.
Don't do this, man.
Look, where's Vic?
L- I wanna talk to Vic.
He'll call
when he loses his tail.
We can't let Kavanaugh
catch us with you, man.
[Exhales]
Mara's pregnant again.
No shit.
Yeah. Yeah. Almost, uh-
Almost three months.
I wasn't supposed to say anything to anybody
until next week, but-
- Congratulations.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Hey.
- Yeah. It's another mouth to feed.
Mara's gonna be laid up
near the end...
so I'm gonna have to-
I'm gonna have to step it up, you know?
Man, I hope I get to see
the little guy.
Or girl.
Little girl, huh?
Yeah.
Yeah. Little girl.
Hey, I'm gonna be all right.
Shane.
- Yeah.
- Shane...
I'm gonna be all right.
It's all about family, right?
[Siren Wailing
In Distance]
Look, what if Vic and Ronnie
can't shake the tail?
Yeah, maybe they
doubled back to the Barn.
I'll, uh- I'll go
check it out, all right?
Move your car.
Get it out of sight.
- Did you get enough to eat today?
- No, man. I'm hungry.
- I brought you some food.
- Thanks.
[Paper Rustling]
- Hey.
- [Paper Rustling]
Thanks, man.
[Laughs]
My favorite, buddy.
[Object Thuds]
Shane? Shane-
- [Coughing]
- [Metal Clatters]
[Sobs]
I'm sorry.
[Whispers]
Shane.
[Sobbing]
I'm sorry, bud.
- I'm so sorry, buddy.
- [Groaning]
[Crying]
Lem!
Lem, I'm sorry!
But I had to, right?
But you know I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, man.
Buddy.
Oh, God!
[Sobbing]
- What are we gonna do if Lem doesn't show?
- He's gonna show.
He will.
[Vehicle Approaches]
Hey. I, uh- I had a tail.
- Took me a while to shake it.
- [Mackey] Yeah.
- Lem hasn't shown, huh?
- He's late.
But he'll be here.
Hey. It's your lucky day.
Cab driver can't I.D. You.
She won't testify against you.
Only thing to testify about
is my love for that girl right there.
I'm gettin'you outta here soon, baby.
Yeah. Just get yourself outta here.
Take him out, would you?
- [Door Buzzes]
- [Tina] Dutch.
I spoke to your ex-partner,
the new captain...
and she says
she trusts your instincts...
so she wants me to increase
the number of hours I trail you.
- I wanted to say thank you
for putting in the good word.
- Yeah. Sure.
Okay.
Hey, um...
you know why you're gonna
be such a great detective someday?
Because most people
don't realize how damn smart you are.
They just see the surface.
They can't get past your looks
to see what you're really about.
[Laughs]
I know, right?
But you're not nearly
as smart as you need to be.
The kind of help I'm offering
doesn't come along every day.
And if I'm gonna spend
my valuable time focusing it on you...
well...
you'd better make it
worth my while.
Sure. Definitely.
Of course.
[Chattering]
[Tina]
What's going on?
- I don't know.
- [Man] Officer down.
- [Ronnie] He did it.
- No!
He's not coming.
Look, maybe he had
some heat on him. He had to hide.
He's coming, or he's gonna get
a message to us.
We're gonna wait for him.
We're gonna give him more time.
Kavanaugh could be
at our houses right now, man.
We have got to
get outta here!
Vic.
Go home.
Check around.
Look for anything incriminating.
Don't take any chances.
No. We're gonna wait.
[Cell Phone Rings]
Yeah.
[Police Radio Chatter]
[Sirens Approach]
Your transfer's denied.
I need my best detective on this.
- [Siren Stops]
- [Police Radio Chatter]
Grenades.
The thing this morning.
The El Salvadorans.
The leader's missing.
His name is Guardo.
Start there.
[Gasps] Oh, my God!
[Sobbing]
Why?
[Tina Sobbing]
Oh, my Godl
[Sobbing]
Why? Why?
Oh, my God!
[Dutch]
Vic, Vic. You can't touch anything.
[Police Radio Chatter Continues]
[Kavanaugh]
You happy?
Are you happy now...
Detective Mackey?
[Kavanaugh Shouts]
[Tina]
Stop itl Stop itl
- Break them up.
- [Man] Come on.
All right, guys. Come on.
That's enough. Come on.
- [Mackey, Kavanaugh Grunting]
- Hey, hey. Come on. Come on.
Break it up. Come on.
[Grunting]
[Shane]
Get off ofhim. Move.
Get off. I got it.
It's all right.
[Kavanaugh Grunting]
- There you go. There you go.
- Calm down. Calm down.
We're gonna find out
who did this...
and we're gonna kill him.
[Police Radio Chatter]
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Continues]
##[Ends]