Previously on The Shield.
Detective Terry Crowley.
Remember him?
Two and a half years ago,
he was on your Strike Team.
He was undercover.
Part of a federal investigation.
He was your teammate.
He was a threat.
So he had to die.
We killed a cop.
Get over it
and don't bring it up again.
You didn't know, did you?
Vic never told you.
- Vic did not kill Terry.
- So prove it. Wear a wire.
- Hey.
- Hey, man. We need to talk.
Don't you lie to me.
Don't lie to me.
- What are you doin'? Stop!
- [Radio Static]
- I need sound.
- I.A.D. Has me wired, all right?
- What?
- I just disconnected it.
They're watching us right now.
They busted me with some heroin,
and they're talking prison if I don't do this.
- Why is it even a question?
- Because I think you're lying to me.
You look me in the eye
and tell me the truth about Terry.
- Don't buy into their bullshit.
- Then you look me in the eye,
you tell me the truth.
Oh, my God.
[Kavanaugh]
What happened to your mike last night?
It got disconnected
in the fight.
- How much you get?
- Nothing-after you two started to mix it up.
You want to fill me in?
Yeah. Well, I asked him about Terry, and he
still says it was the drug dealer who shot him.
How'd it get physical
with Vic?
Guys like him, they just don't come out
and tell you shit.
I had to make it personal
to get the truth.
I can't believe I was stupid enough
to let you in my head.
Make me think Vic had something to do
with Terry dying.
- Lift up your shirt.
- Nah. You know what?
- I'm done with that.
- Done?
Let's just put a pin
in Terry for a minute, okay?
I still need to get a sense
of what your team's into.
And I got a 15-year sentence
hanging over your head.
So, please.
Lift up your shirt.
And let's avoid any technical
malfunctions this time. All right?
Yeah.
- All right? Okay.
- Got you.
Hold on, buddy. Yeah?
Hey, what is it?
- When we're alone, man.
- Baby?
- Yeah?
- Can you take him?
- Hey, guys.
- There she is. Here's Mama.
- Come here, cutie.
- Gonna be just a second.
- Okay.
- I love you.
Yeah? What's up?
Lem got picked up
by I.A.D.
- For what?
- They nabbed him for heroin.
Heroin?
We haven't busted any heroin in a while.
What's Lem doing with horse? He's not using.
He's running something on the side?
He wouldn't do anything
without telling us.
What, like burn
the money train cash?
I.A.D.'s got him
wearing a wire.
So they're
coming after us.
We planted a gun on Doomsday
and dropped him off in Mexico yesterday.
Lem wasn't even there. He was covering us
the whole time, we didn't have a clue.
- What do you think they're looking at us for?
- How long has this been going on?
I don't know. But right now we gotta
stay focused on Lem.
Figure out exactly what they've got on him
and how to get him out of it.
How we gonna do that
if he's wired?
Grab your laptop, sweep the clubhouse
for bugs and meet us there in a few.
Hey. Let's keep
our regular routine.
I.A.D. Gets a whiff that Lem
tipped us, it's over for him.
Lem asked me about
Terry last night.
- On tape?
- He pulled the mike out first.
- Well, what did you tell him?
- Nothing.
But he knows.
So what are
we gonna do?
Lem needs help right now.
We just got to back him up.
We'll explain everything to him
once he's out of trouble.
First downtown ask us for our records on Terry,
now Lem. You think he told 'em somethin'?
- He's got nothing to tell.
- But that's what I.A.D.'s coming after us for.
You and I were the only two people in that
room. Nothing that Lem or I.A.D. Can do...
can ever change that simple fact.
Just gotta stick together.
First one in.
Came to put the java on, when I found 'em.
- What time was that?
- Let the detectives handle the interviews.
We just need to preserve
the crime scene.
What do you think? Heart attack,
then she got crushed underneath him?
Talk about
coitus interruptus.
What?
- [Whimpers]
- [Tina Gasps]
- She's alive.
- [Tina] Jesus.
Give me a hand.
[Grunts]
- Jesus.
- She looked dead.
[Whimpers]
[Door Opens]
[Mouthing Words]
- You got no sense ofhumor, asshole.
- It's just not that funny.
- It's not that funny.
- Tell me this isn't, uh-
- Oh, for God's sake.
- Isn't hysterical.
- Don't tell it again.
- What?
You got three explorers
in the Congo, right?
They get captured by natives.
Natives tie up the three whiteys.
They bind and gag 'em, right?
Chief walks up to the first explorer
and he says, uh...
"You have two choices.
You can choose death or chi-chi. "
- [Curtis] Okay.
- First explorer didn't want to die, right?
He says, "I'll take chi-chi." Twelve men
grab him, rape him, sodomize him for hours.
Cut offhis dick and his balls,
shove it into his mouth...
send him into the woods
bleeding from every hole.
The, uh-The chief walks up to
the second explorer, and he says, uh, uh...
"You have two choices.
You can choose death or chi-chi."
The second explorer
debates in his head.
He doesn't want to die.
He says, "I'll take chi-chi."
Eighteen tribesmen grab him,
rape, sodomize him for hours...
cut off his dick and his balls,
shove it into his mouth...
send him into the woods
bleeding from every hole.
The chief goes up
to the last explorer, right?
And he says, uh,
"You have two choices.
You must choose death
or chi-chi. "
- [Mackey] Yeah?
- Um, third explorer...
big macho guy, mustache,
looks at him and says, uh...
"I'll choose death."
The chief turns to his entire
tribe of 100 natives and says...
"Very well then. Death by chi-chi."
- [Laughter]
- Geez.
- See, I told you it was funny.
- [Ronnie] It's not funny.
- It's disgusting.
- [Knocking]
- [Door HandleJiggling]
[Danny]
Hey, guys, it's locked.
[Shane]
Hold on.
Sorry about that.
We didn't know it was locked.
You got a dead body.
Possible sex crime.
Can you give that to somebody
whose time isn't as valuable?
We've got a million balls
in the air right now.
Yeah, well,
welcome to my world, hon.
Hey, boys. What do you say
we clean up a D.B. By lunchtime?
- All right, man.
- You okay?
Uh, yeah,
he just kicked.
He? It's a boy.
Congrats.
- Thanks. Yeah, I just found out.
- Congratulations.
I'll get the car.
Find out everything we can about
this Kavanaugh guy sweatin' Lem.
Yeah, what about the heroin
they got him on?
Could be chum
to set us in motion.
No, let's get a bead on this guy
before we take his bait.
Okay.
[Julien] We found him on top
of an unknown female.
Arms were bound.
We found keys on the table.
Guy's got a truck outside.
He let himself in.
Poppers.
Intensifies the orgasm.
Guess he popped more
than he bargained for.
Run it.
The shop owner called it in.
- [Mackey] You know this guy?
- Never seen him before.
Really? Then why does he have keys
to your place?
It's a teamster shop.
Hey, Shane, call the local 629.
Tell 'em Rick here is taking
hard-earned cash out of their pockets...
and feeding it
to the nonunion wetbacks.
Rodrigo's a part-time driver.
He never made trouble before.
The union wages
are killing my bottom line.
I see the scabs
are working out nicely for you.
- Where's his rig parked?
- Over there.
You know what?
Check the cab for a purse. We need an I.D.
Check 'em.
- Dude, no drugs, no candy.
- Nothin' in the cab.
Goddamn itl
Hey, guys?
- Let me see that crowbar.
- Here, man.
Here we go.
Watch out, watch out,
watch out, watch out.
[Grunts]
- [Curtis] Shit.
- Aw, Geez.
- Get this off!
- Watch out!
[Mackey]
Come on. Let's go.
They gone?
Yeah.
All three of them.
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Ends]
The guy covered up the air vents
with electric tape to keep 'em quiet.
Shithead
suffocated them all.
No I.D.'s on any of'em.
Rodrigo did a nickel in Chino
for assault and rape a few years back.
And you saw
the Los Perdidos ink.
They must have expanded
from drugs to skin trafficking.
Address on the license is old,
but his P.O. Gave me a new one.
Why don't we file for a warrant?
Gotta check out his crib, see what's there.
Lem and I will hit Mission Cross,
see what we can get from the victim.
- How she doing?
- She's sedated and severely
dehydrated, but she'll live.
- Any signs of sexual assault?
- There's multiple tears. It's pretty bad.
Tox report shows
Rohypnol in her blood.
- She give you a name?
- Magdalena.
Says that a "federale" in Mexico sold her and
her little brother to Mexican gangbangers.
She's not too big on cops.
I told her you were two
of the good guys.
[Mackey] We found three girls
in the truck. We didn't find your brother.
It's okay to talk to them.
They drop him off
just before we stop.
I heard a man take him.
About 10 minutes later,
we stopped again.
That's when the driver
took me inside.
Forced me.
Then he just died.
Is there anything you can tell us
about the men who sold you?
Or who you were
supposed to go to?
They tell us nothing.
[Sighs]
My brother, Pablo.
Please find him.
We're gonna do
everything we can.
[Danny] Excuse me, Detectives.
I have an attorney here for you.
I'm Becca Doyle.
You arrested my client, Evan Dayne...
for the cafeteria shooting
during the school riot.
- Evan? Calls himself Every-Day?
- How'd that come to your attention, counselor?
I represented him two years ago
when he was guilty.
This time he's innocent, so I
offered my services pro bono.
What makes you think
this guy's innocent?
Is there someplace
we can talk?
Several eyewitnesses
I.D.'d your boy.
I reinterviewed your witnesses.
Sorry to say,
pretty shoddy work.
[Scoffs] Mariano gave us Evan,
four others confirmed it.
There all Mariano's close friends.
Did you know that?
We're not gonna reopen this case
based on who's in what clique.
Mariano gave you a patsy,
and his buddies backed him up.
You didn't look into your original witness
very hard, did you?
Evan has a history
of weapons and assault.
And he's cleaned
himself up since.
He's stayed away
from guns and gangs.
I've checked in with him
every few months for the past two years.
We do our
own investigations.
Look. We all have tough jobs,
and we all make mistakes.
Mine's having a little too much faith
in my clients sometimes.
But this time
my faith is justified.
We'll look into it.
Thank you.
I'll wait.
Yeah, all right.
We'll hit you up, bud. Yep.
Coroner says Rodrigo died
of a heart attack.
Mixed too much party fuel.
Shane and Ronnie got the warrant.
Call 'em back. Tell 'em we'll meet 'em there.
I'll see you at the car.
Has anyone from the department come around
asking any questions?
What are you talking about?
Ah, there's a rumor flying around
that someone might be trying...
to make political hay
by coming after my team.
Could be I.A.D.
- And this is just a rumor?
- No, we're clean.
But they might come
poking around asking questions.
Look, the fact is that you
and I were married...
so spousal privilege
applies to that entire time.
- So you don't have to tell anyone anything.
- What do I say if they ask?
Just tell 'em nothing.
Call me.
- What?
- Is there something that
I need to hide from them?
Of course not.
Listen, thanks
for the help with Magdalena.
- Rodrigo's place.
- Something wrong?
- No, I'm fine.
- Come on, ladies. It's playtime.
- Police!
- ##[Speakers: Spanish Rap]
All right.
He's gone.
- [Curtis] Clear.
- Tear it up.
Yep.
- ## [Stops]
- Rodrigo's gonna be pushing the snooze button...
in hell from now on.
Nothin'.
Shitl
No, it can't be that easy.
He's an ex-con from Mexico.
It damn well could be.
Ho.
Rip that open.
Jackpot.
Let me see that.
[Shane]
Picture of girls, a few boys.
Hey, it's Magdalena.
The other three girls
in the truck.
That accounts for four of them.
What about the rest of these kids?
- Where are they?
- Hey, Magdalena's brother.
- [Ronnie] Names, prices-
- And a passenger manifest.
- [Mackey] It's a goddamn kiddie catalog.
- Hey.
What's granny
doing in here?
Either someone's into dry pussy
or she's helping traffic these kids.
Fifth and Alvarado.
Let's go.
I just checked
with my witnesses.
Those kids are contradicting
everything they told you.
They still say Mariano's innocent
and Every-Day did do the shooting.
Maybe it's time
to reexamine your faith.
Mariano must have scared his friends
to keep their mouth shut.
We're trying to get
at the bottom of this.
You don't know anybody who would be
willing to give up Mariano?
If he did, I would have
given it to you already.
Look, Mariano's a bad dude.
Besides, it was a riot.
We were all runnin'- Maybe I was
the only one that seen him pull the gun?
So, right now, it's still his word
against five others, right?
No one said
this would be easy...
but someone will
tell the truth eventually.
Or maybe it's just
a play on your part?
You get us to reopen the case, that creates
the reasonable doubt you need to go to trial.
He's facing 12 to 25.
All I'm asking is we be sure.
Why are you still
playing along with her?
You know witness statements.
They go down quick. Maybe we got taken.
- No, this is about something else.
- No, it isn't.
You're pissed I called you out
about dragging your feet.
Now you're undermining a case
I pushed for.
Excuse me, Detectives.
I'm really shorthanded.
- Is one of you free?
- Dutch is.
Dutch, this is, uh, Parole Officer
Marshall Traynor. He's got a case.
I think it's pretty much
right up your alley.
Loel missed his court date the other day,
violated his parole.
Means he goes back
for another two years.
My friend Ned just did a stretch
for armed robbery.
Some dude was taking care of his dog,
and Ned asked me to drive him to pick it up.
The dude wouldn't give it back,
so we go to this guy's place.
- [Traynor] A trailer.
- Where?
Somewhere around here.
He doesn't remember.
So I'm sitting in the truck, and all of a sudden,
Ned comes out all bloody and shit.
Tells me the guy
wouldn't give him back the dog.
They fought, and Ned did him
in the head with a shotgun.
So you, uh, just decided to hang
around and violate your parole?
Ned had the gun! He made me
grab the dead body, hack the head off...
buried it in a field
and then chopped up the body.
What did you do
with the body parts?
There's this junkyard with,
like, a half a dozen guard dogs.
I was an unwilling
participant, okay?
- Do you buy his story?
- I believe he's telling the truth.
Because you've dealt
with him a lot?
'Cause his brows were raised,
his lips parted and stretched.
I've studied up
on reading faces.
Gotten pretty good at it.
I've read up on micro-expression
facial action units.
'Cause it's fascinating stuff.
The results are disputed.
Proof's in the pudding.
So can you spare some time
and help me find...
this headless pile
of dog food?
Yeah. Um, first though-
What do you think
of this kid?
[Claudette On TV]
You sure you're not wasting our time?
[Every-Day] Lady, I don't have a lot
of friends at that school.
But I ain't never
shot no one.
My initial hit
is he's being truthful.
[Claudette On TV]
So, you're sticking with your story?
- ##[Calliope]
- [Chattering]
Take a look.
Got it?
##[Ranchera]
##[Continues]
There's our granny.
Who's she with?
Abuela.
Heyl Heyl You get the tortoise.
We got the hare.
- Clear the way!
- Stopl Stopl
Drop the knife.
Drop it!
- You got him?
- Yeah!
Give me your hand.
Give me your other one.
- I want my lawyer.
- Yeah, in a minute you're gonna want a doctor!
- Hey, hey, hey!
- [Curtis] Easy.
Hey.
If he wants his lawyer,
he gets his lawyer.
[Groans]
[Shane On Tape Recorder] Big macho guy,
mustache, looks at him and says, uh...
- [Door Opens]
- "I'll choose death."
The chief turns to his entire tribe
of 100 natives and says...
"Very well then.
Death by chi-chi."
I always get a kick out of that one.
They just got it wrong, right?
It's "kee-kee,"
not chi-chi.
I don't know, must be
some kind of white thing or something.
I got your message about Lemansky's
wire mishap last night.
Do you think your
operation's compromised?
I sweated him pretty good.
I'm hoping we're still okay.
You're still making the same mistakes
everyone else makes.
And what is that?
I used to think that Mackey was the luckiest
son of a bitch alive-
how things just fell
into place for him.
And then I realized he was
creating his own luck.
So what you see as a simple
microphone malfunction...
I see as calculated.
The worst animal
in the joint...
98% of the time...
he's just like anybody else.
Anybody.
It's the other two percent
that lands him where he is.
And I'm going
to know everything...
everything,
about Vic Mackey.
And when he goes into
the two percent zone...
I got him.
You still don't know
who you're dealing with.
Or maybe you're still too convinced
that he's evil 100% of the time.
And that's why you keep
grabbing for air...
and he keeps slippin' away.
You've never looked Mackey in the eye,
had him lie straight to your face...
and made you doubt yourself even though
you know he was full of shit.
So until you do...
this is all just
a waste of time.
I am so surprised
that you're here.
Yeah, you knew
I couldn't let go.
Well, Terry was your guy,
so I understand.
Stop playing me
and start worrying about Mackey.
This could be our
last shot at him...
and I'm gonna be right here
to make sure you don't blow it.
Here, here, here, here.
Now where are these kids, lady?
[Tina Speaking Spanish]
- Ah!
- [Mackey] You're not exactly his type.
And Nixon was in office the last time
you could pull off wearing a skirt.
- [Speaking Spanish]
- Rodrigo likes the youngbloods.
[Spanish]
Listen to me,
you piece of shit.
[Spanish]
I don't know these girls,
and I've never seen them before.
[Spanish]
[Tina] And I don't have to
talk to no goddamn cops.
This is just
more gringo bullshit.
Threatening me because
I'm some poor, old, sick Mexican.
I hope your
syphilis-infected dick...
- gets ripped offby a rabid dog-
- Hey. Come on.
- Simmer down.
- Then gets fed to your whore mother.
May she rot in hell.
- That's enough of that.
- Whoa.
I want to talk
to an attorney.
Did you get that?
- That is one cold slice.
- That's a skill she picked up
doing a dime and a half...
in Chowchilla for murder
30 years ago.
- How's this going?
- It's not. She lawyered up.
Man, there goes eight hours before we can
push her P.D. About these missing kids.
Jesus. Call the
public defenders' office.
- See if they can get a lawyer here sooner.
- Right, man.
Got a minute?
It's Doyle, right?
- I'm working a case now.
- That's funny, so am I.
I got a little old lady right in the middle
of a sex-trafficking ring.
Uh, she needs a lawyer.
I'm sure the public defenders' office
will send a capable candidate right over.
I can't wait. I still got almost 50
Mexican sex slaves in play.
And once word hits the street that
Grandma and Jethro got busted...
whole operation
goes underground.
They cover their tracks.
How'd you like to do a good deed for today?
Already have.
And I seem to remember you have a talent for
shading things on the witness stand, Detective.
I think you'll be fine.
You're still upset
about the Crawford case?
The jury felt
that that guy was guilty.
- You can't hold that against me.
- The case rested solely on your testimony.
Which was completely
on the level.
Sorry, I have my hands full.
So you'd rather hold a grudge than help make
a case that could save lives.
Actually, it's about picking
and choosing my clients.
As appealing as your offer sounds, I'd rather
not devote the next month of my life...
to protecting a sex slave-master
grandmother.
All I'm asking is an hour.
[Speaking Spanish]
[Spanish]
They bring other girls to the fruit stand
a few at a time.
Her job is to take 'em
to the drop-off point.
- ¿Dónde?
- [Spanish]
Different places.
A place where there's a lot of kids around.
A bunch of teenage kids with a little old lady
like yourself doesn't raise eyebrows.
- Who's the contact?
- [Tina Speaking Spanish]
[Spanish]
It always changes.
He finds her after she makes the call.
- We gotta set up a meet.
- [Rebecca] That's not part of the deal.
I have to send one
of my people to the meet.
Then we follow the contact
and bust up the whole operation.
If you want her
doing fieldwork...
which wasn't in the deal,
then I need probation.
- Dream on.
- If everything hinges on her...
I'd be a fool
to give up that hammer.
Just like you were foolish
for letting me know...
how important she is
to making your case.
Come here.
You'd set her free?
No. You will.
And maybe next time,
you won't make that mistake.
Right now,
it's the only deal to be made.
We're gonna be
able to hear every word you say.
You're gonna be in our
sight lines at all time.
- Questions?
- No, I'm good.
Officer Lowe has some misgivings
about putting his trainee under.
- She's still on probation.
- [Mackey] A decoy is supposed to look young.
Wide-eyed and new to the game works
for us. The only thing I don't want...
is the bad guys getting
even one whiff of cop off ofher.
- Could jeopardize the whole takedown.
- What about you, honey?
- You think you can handle this?
- They got me covered. I don't see a problem.
Then let's do this thing.
Julien, you're in charge of uni backup.
- Appreciate the support.
- You heard my reasons.
My only concern now is
gettin' you home safely.
- Hey, Vic?
- Yeah?
That, uh, report
you asked for.
[Ronnie] Everything we could find on
Kavanaugh on such short notice.
Word is he gave up his own partner
to I.A.D. Back in the day.
Flies solo. Only investigator that works
without a partner.
Means it's four on one.
That's good. Anything else?
[Shane] Grew up in Inglewood.
Uh, put himself through school.
Degrees in psychology,
criminology.
- Poor kid done good.
- Bookworm.
Golden Gloves champ
at the academy. Five in Vice.
- Stint in Robbery-Homicide.
- Family?
Divorced, no kids.
We gotta figure out
what this guy has to lose.
Look, Everybody's All-American
can't be that clean. Keep diggin'.
- [Chattering]
- ##[Spanish]
[Mackey]
She's droppin'her off.
What's this guy doin'?
- Teresa?
- Sí.
Vámonos.
- [Mackey] Looks like our trafficker.
- [Ronnie] Gettin'in the van.
- You speak English?
- Sure.
- [Man On Radio] That's good.
- Julien, suspect's drivin'...
a brown, two-tone, shitbox van.
- Keep your team in position.
- [Man] The gringos...
- like it when you come in English.
- Whatever you want.
- Hey, move it, shithead!
- Hey!
- Yol
- Hey, move your carl
- What the hell, dude? Come on, man.
- [Mackey] Movel
- Move your carl
- I'll move my car. Relax, huh?
- Shit, shit, shit!
- Whoa, whoa, whoal
- [Ronnie] Turnin'left on Wilshire.
- I got it.
[Shane] Come on, man.
We're losin' 'em.
[Tires Squealing]
[Man] When you get to the house,
senorita gets you started.
- Gives you clothing, makeup, morning-after pills-
- [Mackey] He's turnin' again.
- Vic, where are you?
- [Mackey On Radio] Minor detour, Julien.
- Just hold your positions.
- [Tina] When can I see my brother Pablo?
[Man] Turn enough tricks,
then you get the privileges.
- Till then do as we say.
- Is he safe?
[Man] Yeah. As long as you behave,
he'll stay that way.
- [Man] Got it?
- He's heading into the alley?
[Tina]
Sí. What is going on?
- Gotta break you in first.
- [Ronnie] He's stopping in front of the gate.
[Man]
Get down on your knees.
Fiesta time, amigos.
Yes, fiesta time.
- It's a gangbang.
- Screw it. Let's go, man.
- No, hold on, hold on.
- [Tina] You boys got a condom?
[Chuckles] We're gonna do your mouth,
not your clam, bitch.
Come on. Open up.
Es que... I got gonorrhea
in my throat.
- What?
- Look, I'll suck you boys off.
[Tina On Radio]
But don't hate me later if it burns.
[Man] Forget about it.
Never mind.
When we get to the house, we're
gonna run a train on your ass.
- And don't be telling any customers
that you're sick. Got it?
- Good girl.
Yeah, shorty's got game.
They're moving.
- [Dogs Barking]
- You, uh- You sure they're chained up tight?
Long as you don't piss me off,
we're good.
[Chuckles] I always thought, uh,
face reading should be...
one of the first things
they teach at the academy.
I taught myself. Be happy to loan you
some books and DVD's.
If you want to grab a bite later,
I'll give you a quick rundown.
- Yeah, sounds good.
- You'd be surprised how
transparent people become.
Your partner, for instance.
- Claudette?
- Trying to hide something from you.
Pretty obvious.
Something's in the closet.
The whole pack was over here
the entire day.
That's when I found it.
Well, thanks for the hand.
[Chattering]
[Curtis] This is his place
or they run girls from here?
[Mackey]
Hold on.
We jump too early,
we'll get nothin'.
[Spanish]
[Mackey]
Okay. Looks like the madam to me.
That's it. Everybody move in.
Let's bust it. Now!
[Tires Screeching]
- [Women Scream]
- Down! Down!
- [Mackey] Hope you take walk-ins.
- [Screaming Continues]
[Shouting]
[Julien] Hey, on your knees.
Get downl
- Hands over your headl
- Get down right now on the ground. Fast!
- Turn around!
- [Julien] Downl Downl
- [Tina] Vicl
- Hey, find Tina!
- We're clear!
- [Julien] Clear. Downl
- Tina?
- Vicl
- [Man Groans]
- Don't you move!
- [Julien] You okay?
I didn't have my baton,
but every guy's got their weak spot.
How right you are.
Good girl. Nice work.
- Where's the kid?
- This idiot's acting like he doesn't understand.
Found 10 girls off this sheet,
the rest are still missing.
You don't know
about Pablo?
What about the rest
of the girls? And the boys?
I want my lawyer.
Is that the first thing they teach you pricks
once you cross the border?
Put him in the van.
Hey, we take this shithead
to the Barn, he's gonna clam up.
Word gets out about this bust,
we're never gonna find the rest of them.
Well, maybe he's not
as stupid as he looks.
- Come on.
- Let's go, asshole.
This is a shitty day.
We only got about half those kids.
At least we get to stick the needle
in someone for it.
What are you talking about?
Guttierez is gonna get five to seven max.
- Hey, we got three dead girls.
- This asshole wasn't anywhere near that.
We got conspiracy charges, so
he's up for the murders too.
[Mackey]
That's right.
Well, that-
that is good news.
Doesn't mean he's gonna
get the death penalty, though.
- [Mackey] Well, Calhoun is prosecuting.
- Wow. Good.
So I guess
that means he will.
- Who's Calhoun?
- [Mackey] Hey, shut up, you prickl
You wanted a lawyer,
now we can't talk to you.
But I ain't gettin' no death penalty
for some girls I didn't even kill-
- I didn't even see.
- Save it for your last words lying on the gurney.
I wouldn't expect any clemency
with the Terminator as governor.
[All Chuckling]
Carlos Odonez.
He's the boss.
Whoa. You waivin'
your right to an attorney?
Of your own
free will?
Yeah.
- But you'll help me, right?
- [Mackey] Where are the rest of the girls?
There's a house on Colquitt,
another one on Adams.
All right, and the boy,
Pablo, where's he at?
Bangkok. They flew him, the rest
of the boys out this afternoon.
- Bangkok?
- Jesus!
- Hey.
- Jon, hi.
Hey, help your sister
in the car, okay? Thanks.
How you holdin' up?
Good. Andy's a handful, but,
you know, it's worth it.
Yeah, listen. Here is my address
and phone number.
- Are we still on for that Friday playdate or?
- Yeah.
If there's a problem, I'll call you,
but I'm looking forward to this, really.
Okay.
Where is Andy?
Sometimes I wonder if this extra program
is just an excuse to bilk me out of extra money.
From the school, yes.
The teachers, no.
- You likin' the teacher, or-
- I'm blankin' on her name right now.
Um, remind me. What's-
It's the woman with the, uh-
Um, I thought Mr. Dunhill
taught the after-school program.
- He does, but I'm talking
about her aide. I mean his aide.
- Oh.
Anyway, look,
I'll see you on Friday, if not sooner.
Yeah, good. You know what? I gotta
get my kids home, but I'll see you then, okay?
See ya.
I just got this case
an hour ago.
Why is my client arrested
for second-degree murder...
when another boy
was already arrested?
I'm sure you've heard Every-Day's attorney
is making my life hell.
She's taken depositions
from half the high school.
- Depositions listing you as the shooter.
- Bullshit.
My friends were there.
They saw Every-Day pull that gun.
- What are you writing?
- Every-Day's release.
The D.A. Has decided to drop the case,
charging your client.
Based solely
on witness statements?
Well, they also just found
gun residue in his locker.
[Chuckles]
- What else do you have?
- D.A. Doesn't want me revealing it...
until we're closer to trial.
This does not need
to go to trial.
What do I have to do
to make a deal?
Convince your client to drop
the high school clique crap.
School him on what it's
like to have this evidence...
a high-priced lawyer and a very pissed-off cop
working against him.
Gun residue in a locker?
I'd never let you get away with that.
Cops are allowed to twist the facts to suspects.
I directed my comments to him.
- Evan's being released tonight.
- I know.
Thanks for your help.
I owe you one. I mean that.
Call in a favor whenever you need it.
I will.
I, uh-I heard.
- Nice work.
- Thanks.
- How's yours going?
- Uh, turns out the parolee was coerced.
So he won't go down for the murder
or hacking up the body.
The other guy's
going away for a long time.
And I'm, uh-
I'm sure about him.
Good. Well, where you
running off to?
Uh, dinner with Marshall.
I can't have
other colleagues as friends?
Marshall has quite a reputation
as a man's man...
- if you know what I mean.
- He- He's gay?
While you were reading faces,
he was reading your package.
Have fun though.
The cage would look a whole lot prettier
with Abuela's ugly mug in it.
Sure you don't want to find
the loophole in our deal?
I couldn't let you run roughshod
over a little old lady, much as she deserved it.
You lookin'
for more business?
I appreciate the offer, but I'm okay watching
from the sidelines while they get theirs.
Right now, I'd like to go home
and wash this place off me.
You talkin' about the cops
or the criminals?
See you in court
someday, Detective.
- [Door Buzzes]
- Vic?
I got something important.
Someone has been
asking questions.
- Who?
- This man. He's approached me a few times.
- Where at?
- Glenridge.
He, uh- He said he was
the parent of an autistic child.
But I've been around cops
long enough to know what they sound like.
Besides, I've never even
seen his kid, so-
That him?
Yeah. Why's he coming
to our school?
- What did he ask you?
- I'm trying to remember.
Something about paying the tuition
and, uh, how do we do it...
how involved you are.
- What did you tell him?
- I told him you gave us money
for whatever we needed.
I was trying to sell you
as a good dad.
I didn't tell him
about the cash in the bag.
Good. Don't tell him shit.
Asshole has no business talking to you
about this. It's my problem.
I'll take care of it.
All right?
[Moaning]
Oh, I'm gonna come.
Ahhh.
Mmm.
- Is everything okay?
- [Exhales]
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
That was great.
But, uh,
you were somewhere else.
Is it about
that meeting this morning?
Yeah.
Lem's in
some hot water.
Yeah.
- How hot?
- We don't know yet.
I thought you said that you
were done with all that-
that you were
gonna keep clean.
- I have been.
- Yeah?
I swear.
Then why you
so worried?
- Hmm?
- Don't you worry.
Okay?
We'll figure it out.
"We" meaning you and Vic?
- Together as a team, standing behind Lem?
- No. Listen.
Listen to me.
The team's one thing,
but family's another.
All that stuff that happened
with Antwon. You know.
- Yeah.
- I was looking at prison in the eye.
- I know. I know.
- Hey.
I'm not gonna let
anything happen to us.
Jackson needs his father.
Well, I need
the both of you.
Hear me?
[Door Opens]
Buddy in Immigration called.
He's putting the word out on Pablo.
Spoke to an American diplomat
in Bangkok.
- I meant what I said about not giving up on him.
- Okay. Good.
I feel like there's some unfinished
business between us.
What's that?
It's this Terry thing.
You thought I was hiding something
from you.
Here's the truth.
I swept through that house.
I cleared that bathroom.
At least I thought I did.
Somehow Two-Time
got past me.
I left Terry exposed.
I made a mistake.
I never told anybody.
I thought it was my fault.
That's something I've been
living with for a long time now.
Finally, I decided to move on.
Something you're gonna have
to push past too.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- [Knocking]
- Hey, Vic-
Her Majesty, Billings,
needs to see you.
- Tell him I'll be right there.
- Got it.
- What's up?
- Somebody here to see you.
Jon Kavanaugh.
Internal Affairs.
- Vic Mackey.
- Yeah.
Mind if I have
a moment alone, Captain?
- Nah, not at all.
- Thank you.
What can
I do for you, Detective?
- It's lieutenant.
- Right.
We're just cops,
just like you.
I guess the, uh, good looks,
it just throws everybody off.
[Chuckles]
Anyhow.
We're making
a tour of the division.
With the budget cuts, the, uh, bosses,
they're afraid that there might be...
uh, a lot of temptation
to take shortcuts.
And I'm just here to remind everyone
that I'm still on the case...
and there is a right way
to do things.
I've been a cop for 14 years.
You guys never toured before.
New management.
Putting a friendlier face
on the old "rat squad."
[Chuckles]
Anyhow.
There is no reason why you and I should not
be on the same page.
Why you talkin' to me?
You run a Special Team.
Those get most
of the abuse allegations.
And from what I hear,
those people out there...
they all follow your lead.
Well, can't blame 'em
for having good judgment.
Is there anything brewing I should
know about? Anything at all suspicious?
Not that I can think of.
You sure?
It is good to meet you.
You too.
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Continues]
##[Ends]