Previously on The Shield.
Yesterday, Measure 16 on
the city ballot failed...
which means we'll have to make do with the lack
of manpower here in the Barn and the street.
Hold this out long enough, some people
feel compelled to take the gum.
It's a sign they'll crack under pressure.
- Gum?
- Uh, no, thanks.
- Here you go.
- Sure. Thanks.
You know I.A.D. Has been
looking into Detective Mackey...
and the Strike Team he ran
while under your command?
We've got Lemansky. He lifted
a brick of tar off the El Salvadorans.
We've been waiting for it
to spin into something more.
- Got nothing on Mackey.
- We got a C.I. Next to him. When he jumps dirty-
Vic and his guys are tight,
and Lemansky-he's a soldier.
So you're gonna need something to drive
a wedge between him and Mackey.
Terry was working forJustice,
and I think Vic had him killed.
We killed a cop.
Get over it
and don't bring it up again.
Curtis Lemansky,
I need you to come with us.
Why is it that the guy with the conscience
always has to get caught holding the bag?
- What do you want?
- We want the guy that put it into motion.
Who do you think I want, Curtis?
- [Mackey] Still no Lem?
- [Shane] Left a second message.
He's probably knee-deep
in a booty call.
- Hope he's gettin'a discount.
- I hear yours charges by the minute.
I get mine for free.
[Mackey]
Must be seein'a charity worker.
I was about to call you again.
It's nice of you to finally show up.
Better be a damn good reason
for you blowin'up my cell phone.
Who dimed you that crack mule last year?
It's payback time, man. Come look at this.
- [Mackey] Geezl
- Man, look at my windshieldsl
We don't monitor lemon laws.
[Shane]
Good thing they're sold "as is."
Look, don't waste my time again. Next time
you call me, it better be something real.
Shitl The name Vic Mackey
used to have some juice around here.
Up to no good?
Lookin'to run and hide from Vic Mackey?
Oh, no.
He'd find you, and you'd get yours.
Now assholes like him
lean on honest people...
'cause they know cops like you
can't do dick anymore.
- Who's leanin'?
- Wetback.
Street name: Doomsday. Squeezin'
every shop on the block for insurance.
- Is that real enough for you?
- How long's it been goin' on?
Couple of months.
Man, I come in today-
Man, I missed one payment,
one payment...
and look at my windshields now!
Man, my son's right. He's right.
It's every man for himself from now on.
Shit! I should've paid that prick off!
You're scared.
It's understandable.
You made a serious mistake,
and you don't see a way out of this.
I didn't commit any crime.
I'm a goddamn cop.
Gotta start with denial
till you get your head around all this.
It's cool. I understand.
Really, we got time here.
- I've never seen those drugs before.
- Come on, man.
It was taken from your vehicle with a search
warrant. I got the seizure on videotape.
You know, I can walk
out ofhere right now.
Well, if you do,
I'm gonna have to arrest you...
take you downtown,
make it official.
I'm trying to save you
the embarrassment here.
I got nothin'
to be embarrassed about.
We've both been through
enough of these.
So I can be straight with you, yeah?
Sure.
Every guilty suspect
that you've ever interviewed...
started with denial, right?
So did the innocent ones.
[Knocking]
Ah. You must be Doomsday.
- Who are you?
- I'm Armageddon.
Say hello to the hounds of hell.
- Ruff.
- You've been squeezin' some
of the local business owners.
Consider us the Better Business Bureau.
We're shuttin'your ass down.
- I didn't invite you in.
You got some paper or somethin'?
- It's an unofficial visit.
Letting you know the cops
are still on the job in Farmington.
We're puttin' the word out
one asshole at a time.
Get your toy cop ass out of here.
- Are you gettin' my message,
or you need your ears cleaned?
- [Chuckles]
What are you laughin'at?
The only words I wanna hear
out of your mouth are "Sí, señor."
Suck my dick, señor.
[Groans]
Hey!
No warrant.
It's your call.
Hey, over here.
Come on.
Get up!
- Get up here. Come on.
- Hands up.
[Grunting]
That'll give you plenty of time
to think about your new career direction.
We'll return this
to its rightful owners.
If you gotta take a piss,
be sure and give us a call.
[Grunting]
I need to get back to my team.
Eat something.
We're gonna be here for a while.
The only thing outside
that door for you is a prison cell.
And I haven't been able to tell you
how I'm gonna keep you out of it yet.
You know, I read your package,
and I met with one of your old partners.
And he said that-
He said you made a lot of great arrests.
You started off an upright guy.
What happened to you?
How'd you go from
riding with cops to hunting 'em?
[Sighs]
Tio Osmond.
Diagur Leyva.
Connie Reisler.
They were all Strike Team C.I.s.
So what?
Any of the people
you work with make it out alive?
Look, they chose the life.
They chose to cooperate with the police,
and now they're dead.
Better them than us.
Or did you forget that from the academy?
Angie Stubbs.
She was 15 when she helped you...
before she was murdered.
She choose the life too?
No.
She was a good kid.
Bet she was.
What do you think
should happen to, uh-
to someone who kills a kid like that?
To someone who kills a cop...
or a grandma?
Life in prison?
Death penalty?
Needle's too good
for someone like that.
Finally... we agree
on something here.
Detective Terry Crowley.
Remember him? Two and a half years ago,
he was on your Strike Team.
He was undercover
when he was killed.
Part of a federal investigation
into your team.
You know what?
I've seen a lot of things...
that make me think
that you're a good guy.
I just cannot figure out...
how you could be involved
with this murder.
What are you talkin' about?
Terry was killed by a drug dealer.
- I was there.
- I know you were there.
But we both know that
is not the way it went down.
Could you be
more full of shit right now?
Terry was killed in the line of duty.
The one thing I know for sure
is that by the end of the day...
you are either gonna be
helping me with the truth...
or you are going to be...
behind bars.
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Ends]
What's up, big mama?
You ready to announce Papa yet?
No, but you'll be the last to know.
Listen, guys, Lem's running late.
- He call in?
- No, a friend did. Said his car broke down.
- He'll be in as soon as he can.
- Okay, thanks.
Guess honey wasn't nothin'
to write home about.
Got multiple homicides on Dozier.
Billings gave this to you.
- Is it gang?
- You tell us. Two black males, a black female.
- You're no one till somebody kills you.
- Not in this corner of paradise.
These kids aren't flying colors.
- Any forced entry?
- Back door's busted in.
Victims had cash and credit cards.
Whoever it was didn't get much.
Whoever it was got exactly
what they came for.
- [Sobbing]
- [Ronnie] She called it in.
Came over to study with her friends,
saw the bodies through the window.
This street's gang-neutral.
Plus, this was a beating, not a shooting.
Strictly personal.
- Any crack houses in this neighborhood?
- None that register.
All right, let's find out who
these kids were, what they were into.
Bodies are still warm.
Let's crack it before they cool.
The shop owner found him on
the pavement. He didn't recognize him.
There's a strong odor of alcohol.
Any bars nearby?
Nah. Couple of auto body shops.
A church up the street.
- I checked the wallet. Lives 10 blocks from here.
- Good.
You're starting to get an instinct
for the right things to look for.
He didn't walk here on his own,
not in that condition.
Check the houses on this side of
the alley, and look around for some teeth.
Guillermo Solis.
Alcohol-induced coma.
- E.M.T. Says it's 50-50. Where have you been?
- I'm here now.
Since when does a misdemeanor
drunk-in-public need two detectives?
I don't think this guy
got plastered and fell over.
He had broken teeth, facial cuts.
I'm calling it an assault.
- Any sign of robbery?
- Didn't take his money.
- I'm thinking he was dumped here.
- So he got drunk, he passed out.
They drug him here and let
somebody else deal with it.
It's not the most neighborly thing,
but we've seen worse...
and we didn't call it assault.
Well, maybe.
Hang on a second.
[Dogs Barking]
I saw you look out.
Now open up, now!
- Always look out your window?
- There's cops. I was curious.
Curious enough to see something
that happened earlier across the street?
We're gonna keep talking.
It's only gonna take your neighbors...
about 30 seconds
to figure you do know something.
So you might as well tell me
so I can get off your porch.
- [Barking Continues]
- Quiet!
I came home to let my dogs out...
and I saw somebody
leaving that house.
- What did he look like?
- Got something?
- I'm not leavin' till I find out.
- Okay.
The guy was scary.
He looked right at me,
and I went cold.
He looked like evil.
Okay? Go now.
I'm gonna take you in and
put you with a sketch artist.
- You said you'd leave me alone.
- A lot of people wanna know what evil looks like.
Councilman?
Hey, hey, heyl Hey.
I picked up Lemansky last night.
- Where is he?
- Back at the motel.
- Feel him out before I make a move, you know.
- What about the rest of the team?
You were right about Lemansky.
And-And this Terry murder-
It is the soft spot.
But with me, it's still theoretical.
I'm trying to get inside it,
and I will get inside it...
but I need you to add
that personal element to it.
The department brought you in to close this,
and you come running back to me?
I can just see where this is goin',
and I'm not above askin' for help.
Besides, I thought Crowley
was your friend.
He was.
You suspected Mackey all along,
and you just let him go.
I pursued it as far as I could.
- Well, here's another chance.
- Mackey's out the door in four months.
- Forced retirement.
- Out the door? Fifteen-year pension.
That ain't a bad reward
for killing a cop, is it?
Sorry. Please. Sorry.
- We could never prove it.
- But you know it.
And now, we got
someone that can prove it.
Hold on a second.
- Witness give you somethin'?
- You gotta see this.
Sure looks a lot like
the Salvadoran we leaned on today.
- Doomsday?
- Could be.
It's hard to tell.
Besides, he's tied up.
- Is that Doomsday?
- We put this out yet?
Yeah. Went out on the wire
a few minutes ago. Gets worse.
I.D.'s came back on
the victims at the house.
Community college geeks.
No history of trouble.
One of the males
last names was Hughes.
- As in Hughes Used Cars?
- It was his kid.
Big "D" said he didn't
pay last week, remember?
- So Doomsday sent a message.
- We don't know that yet.
A couple of busted windshields.
Why did we push so hard?
Because there's still some
goddamn laws in Farmington...
no matter what the voters reject.
Plus, he came at me.
He was in my face.
- That the suspect in the triple murder?
- Yeah.
- Do we know him?
- Could be a Salvadoran lowlife,
lives in the neighborhood.
We're trying to get
a 20 on him now.
You think this is
another racial incident?
- I'll let you know.
- Great.
Grab some extra unis
if you need 'em.
If we can find one.
So we cause a triple murder before
breakfast, start a race war before dinner.
That's a pretty good day.
Get the word out to the Aztecs and Zulus
that this wasn't retribution.
It's a beef about business.
That's all.
- You with me?
- Yeah.
- He chew through that goddamn thing?
- Holy shit.
We gotta find this guy.
- You got a minute?
- Sure. Come in.
I need a line on a Salvadoran,
calls himself Doomsday.
- You heard of him?
- No. Know where he lives?
Temple/Colter area.
You got friends down there?
I'll have to spread a little love around.
Ah. All right.
I need to pull this guy
off the street now.
Now, this is one of those times
you can earn yourself some real money.
That's too much, Vic. All I need
is a couple of dubs for my girls.
Keep what you save. Ten times
that amount if we can get him in custody.
Everything copacetic?
- Yeah.
- That's what I like to hear.
All the emperor needs is a toga
and a violin while Farmington burns.
They offered you that job first,
you turned it down.
It would've been yours,
but you screwed it up. Mrs. Solis?
Thanks for comin' in.
How's your husband?
At the hospital. They said
the machines are keeping him alive.
- But his brain-
- Sorry.
We, uh-We just need
your signature here.
And you can take
his personal effects.
Did you see
your husband last night?
- I took him to church for his meeting.
- Is it a 12-step program?
A.A. Didn't work for Guillermo.
He just kept on drinking.
What sort of meeting was this?
Senor Romero has them drink
until the alcohol cures the sickness.
- Aversion therapy?
- You weren't concerned when
he didn't come home?
Senor Romero lets them
sleep at the church...
if they're in, you know, bad shape.
- Who's Senor Romero again?
- Our minister.
- Senor Romero?
- Yes.
- We need to talk to you about Guillermo Solis.
- Is there a problem?
He's in a coma, may not live.
Too much drink.
Lord, bless his soul.
We understand you were treating him for
substance abuse at the church last night?
I don't treat people.
I don't have a license for that.
- He attends our prayer group.
- Where you, uh, feed booze to alcoholics.
That's-That's fascinating.
Everything they drink,
they drink of their own free will.
We fight the sickness with sickness.
This aversion therapy,
it really works for some people?
It's how I conquered
my issues with alcohol. Otherwise...
I wouldn't have
my business and my church.
My ex-wife was a drunk.
You think if I'd hauled her off...
to happy hour every night,
I could've saved the marriage?
- I wouldn't wanna speculate.
- [Claudette] Who else was there last night?
Hector Santiago. He works with the church,
and he's going through the therapy.
- Just the three of you?
- Well, the group gets smaller
as more of us are healed.
- Well, uh, keep up the good work.
- Sure.
- I told you I had a feeling.
- Preachers need to stick to preachin'.
Want me to ask Romero if
he's got that in your size?
Your witness was worried about her dogs.
She made me promise to come check on 'em.
Living room.
Guess Doomsday
isn't a member of PETA.
- What do we know about Doomsday?
- He's from North Carolina.
Did a stint for agg assault in Atascadero.
Got out six months ago.
Took a guy's eye out with a fork
for stealing his food in junior high.
Keep pressing the local sets.
Guys like this make friends all over.
[Shane]
It's a good thing you pulled Irma in.
- Where are the heads?
- Nowhere.
Checked the whole place.
He took the goddamn dogs' heads?
What's he gonna do,
put 'em on a pike?
We gotta find this freak.
[Knocking]
Councilman.
- You two know each other already.
- Curtis.
- What are you doing here?
- You got a big decision to make,
not a lot of time.
So I thought you should get
as much information as possible.
It's time for you to step
into the sunlight, Lem.
I didn't do anything wrong.
You're not my captain anymore.
You took some heroin.
You got caught.
Now, we're not just talking
about your career here, Lem.
The city referendum showed all of us
what the public thinks of cops.
The department's fighting to change that
perception, so somebody has to pay a price.
And right now, that's you.
Well, you know what? I'll take
my chances with the truth in court.
Everything that Lieutenant Kavanaugh
told you about Terry was true.
You know, Terry didn't have
a grudge against Vic going in.
But it only took him two weeks
to find out that Vic was a dirty cop.
I have his original notes
detailing his suspicions.
He was your teammate.
He was a threat, so he had to die.
No. Never!
You didn't know, did you?
Vic never told you.
All this time, I thought
the four of you were in it together.
But you really didn't know.
This changes everything.
You're saying you didn't
know about it until right now?
- It was the other guys?
- I didn't say that.
- But you didn't know.
I mean,
I respect a guy being loyal...
but now you're protecting a guy for
something that you don't have any stake in...
something that you told me
the death penalty was too good for.
This is a damn
witch hunt right now.
You cannot be a cop and be
a part of it with him. You gotta choose.
Vic did not kill Terry!
So prove it.
Wear a wire.
Ask him as a friend.
Let's see what he's got to say.
You wanna railroad an innocent guy,
go ahead and do it.
Do it.
But I do not have to help.
So you'd rather take on prison...
than someone who took out
one of your own?
That-That is a tough choice.
But I understand.
[Mrs. Solis] Guillermo was a jealous man.
The drinking only made it worse.
Did you give him reason
to be jealous?
Why are you asking me
those questions?
Those are nice shoes. You get those
from Romero? Saw a pair like 'em.
They were a gift from el señor.
How long have you been
sleeping with Romero?
I have never done that.
But he's made advances, hasn't he?
I'm a married woman.
He made me feel good.
But I told el señor
I would not betray my vows.
You mean, uh,
"till death do us part"?
You know what? You know what?
I need a decision.
- I need a decision.
- What happened to having some time?
- Can't believe you need any.
- Look, Vic is your friend, and you're loyal.
But you also gotta be loyal
to your badge.
Gotta be loyal to yourself...
to an innocent brother cop.
It's decision time.
You tell me.
Do I parade you into Police 1...
or do I call a technician
and wire you up?
You know, Lem,
if Vic is innocent like you say...
you'd be helping him out.
If I do...
what do I get out of it?
- [Shane] Doomsday's here?
- According to Emolia's friend.
[Shane]
That's not exactly laying low.
All right, let's go.
- On the ground now!
- Let's go right now! Let's go right now!
- On the ground!
- Get down on the ground!
You son of a bitch.
You do need your ears cleaned.
- Where'd you put the dogs' heads?
- What are you talkin' about?
Right.
- Where does Mackey like to put these?
- On the chest.
Make a case on Mackey,
the others, you walk away free.
Here you go.
There's one more thing.
If you lie to me
or you try to screw me...
or you just don't live up
to the deal...
I will push for maximum
for distribution of heroin.
Just know that's the truth.
- Did you get all that?
- Perfect. Mike's working great.
Let's go.
Hey. Hey.
Where you going?
I've gotta run an errand. Sorry.
I'll be back in about an hour.
- Can't it wait? I'm trying to close this out.
- Sorry.
- Is everything okay?
- Yeah. I'll hurry back.
Well, I'll start.
Jump in when you get back.
Tox report came back.
He was practically embalmed.
No way he had enough motor function
to swallow, much less hold the bottle.
It even amazes me sometimes...
how much these chronic
alcoholics can put away.
You, uh, screwing any other sheep
in your flock, Reverend...
or you just like giving shoes
to all the pretty wives?
I don't know what
you're talkin' about.
And in my faith,
I am called Apostle, not Reverend.
How did Guillermo's
front teeth get broken?
- He must have fallen down.
- You shoved a bottle in his mouth.
Celia Solis said she wouldn't sleep
with you while her husband was alive.
So you tried to kill him,
but only his brain died.
The devil did that to him.
Alcohol was his demon.
Santiago said Guillermo had the shakes.
You notice anything like that?
I left them both asleep
in the sanctuary.
I went to my office.
I wrote this week's sermon.
When I returned,
Guillermo wasn't in the church.
I figured he had sobered up
enough to walk home.
And Santiago was too out of it
to say otherwise.
- You've got all your bases covered.
- I'll put my hand on the Bible.
Not as much fun as putting
your hand on another man's wife.
- [Door Buzzing]
- Get in there, you sick prick.
[Mackey]
Glad you could join us.
Hey.
Smells ripe, buddy.
Hope you put a little boom in her womb.
I had to stop by my friend's
on the way back from Chino.
The car broke down,
so I waited a half day for a mechanic.
Good thing you didn't call back, 'cause I ain't
about to haul my ass out there to pick you up.
[Danny]
Hey, Vic. Downtown called.
They wanna see any records
that you have on Terry Crowley.
- [Mackey] They say why?
- No. Just want anything you got.
- Probably just wanna close out the file.
- Yeah.
All right. I gotta pull a couple
of old boxes, but I'll see what I can do.
You missed the first half,
but we're still in the game.
- We just picked up a suspect in a triple murder.
- Put me in, Coach.
It's not him.
[Mackey]
Oh, for Christ sakes. Don't do this.
- I said it's not him.
- This man killed three innocent people today.
- That's not my fault.
- What about the next person he kills?
That will be.
He already killed my dogs.
You think just 'cause you're not I.D. 'ing him,
he's not gonna try to kill you too?
You're protecting a killer.
Makes you no better than he is.
[Irma]
I'm sorry.
For the record,
I saw someone, but not him.
What happened to your hands? Looks like
you got into one hell of a dogfight.
Scratched 'em up someplace.
Senior Hughes refuses to pay
you protection, Junior winds up dead.
Niggers die every day.
Save that grin for the lineup
before I smack it off your face!
Need a witness for a lineup.
Ruff-ruff.
I'm holding you on suspicion of vandalism
for cruelty to animals.
That means we're about eight minutes
into a 12-hour conversation.
Wanna see how cruel I can be to animals
like you? A lot can happen in 12 hours.
Problem for you is, we don't scare like girls,
and our bite's as good as our bark, asshole.
- We gain entry and do what?
- Separate the parties.
Look for visual signs of injury.
- You taking the son?
- Yeah. You get the father.
Control the scene.
Use force if necessary.
- [Shouting, Indistinct]
- ##[Rock On Radio]
Over there.
Hey! Come here! Come here!
- Calm down! Calm down!
- [Shouting]
He's on the drugs again.
- She steals all my shit!
You let her get away with it!
- I need you to step outside.
- He just gets all cranked up-
- [Shouting Continues]
- Sir, I just need you-
- [Shouting, Indistinct]
- Shit!
- Control!
[Julien]
Heyl That's enoughl
Tina! That's enough!
Thanks.
- He wouldn't listen.
- It's your job to make him listen.
- I was trying to.
- Trying gets you killed.
You failed to get the father out of
the room. Then you used excessive force.
- You said to use force if necessary.
- Controlled hits.
- Behind his knees-
- That's exactly what I was doing!
No force would have been necessary-none-
if you had followed proper procedure.
That's gonna need stitches.
Corrine. Hi.
Hi, Jon.
You picking up your son?
Yeah. My ex was supposed to.
She bailed out at the last second, so-
- Oh.
- I skipped out of work and came here.
- I'm sorry.
- It's par for the course. Hey, guys.
You know what? Why don't you guys go play
over by the swings for a little bit.
Watch your sister for me, okay?
- So was it a bad divorce, or-
- Yeah.
Uh, she's with this other guy now.
I got primary custody. She's supposed
to be paying child support.
She's this big-time money manager.
- I haven't seen a cent though
in, like, three months.
- You're kidding?
She doesn't even help out at all?
I'm just running a little late
on the tuition here.
And you're paying
for your children all by yourself?
Oh, no.
Uh, Vic helps out.
- But the occupational therapists
and the evaluations and-
- Yeah.
You know, Vic always comes up with
whatever extra cash I need for the kids.
- So-
- Sounds like a great guy.
- Well, let's not make him a saint quite yet.
- Yeah?
What's his bad side?
I'm just trying to compare him
to my ex's bad side, because-
Okay, well, he's hardheaded...
uh, he likes to get his way,
and job comes first.
Same here.
But he loves his kids.
- What's your boy's name again?
- Andrew. Andy.
- Is he-
- No. He's, uh-
He's doing some extra work
with one of his teachers right now.
Maybe you can bring Andy around
for a playdate sometime?
That would be a huge, huge help.
- Billings keeps asking what we got.
- We got nothin'.
- We got no prints, we got no weapons.
- No goddamn witness.
Why don't we just cut this guy loose and
continue this conversation on the street?
- What kind of conversation?
- Well, Irma's the only thing that we had.
She ain't stickin'
her neck out ever.
We could turn him on to Special Cases,
let them run with it.
Pass the buck?
And have the streets still think...
we're stuck behind desks
with our tail between our legs?
- They got resources, manpower-
- Every minute he walks free, we're a bigger joke.
We're gonna handle this guy
so people know that we got him.
Hey, what about the- the guy
that we met on the Mexi sting last year?
Hold on. Look, I gotta-
I gotta take off, man.
- Where you goin'?
- My stomach's been bugging me all day.
- Do you mind if I pick it back up tomorrow?
- Sure. You gonna be all right?
Yeah. It's my medicine.
I'm back on it. I left it at home.
All right.
I'll see you tomorrow.
[Door Closes]
- He gonna get paid for today?
- Keep goin'.
It's a great country,
respecting the human rights...
of a bloodthirsty
piece of shit like yourself.
I just might have to sue your ass.
I got a feeling your life
just took a turn for the worse.
Or it could just be wishful thinking.
- [Door Buzzes]
- You go back to filling out your paperwork.
Stay the hell off my street.
[Danny]
Well, I told you to lose the earrings.
I figured it was no big deal,
but I should've listened to you.
- Protocol's there for a reason.
- It won't happen again.
You know what?
Do yourself a favor.
Don't turn being a cop
and a girl into a juggling act.
All right.
See you later.
You wereJulien's
training officer, right?
He's a good guy and all,
reads the Bible.
But maybe he has a problem
working with women.
We may have the same plumbing, but that doesn't
mean I'm gonna dish with you about your T.O.
I didn't mean it like that.
You wanna succeed around here?
Do yourself a favor.
Just listen up
and do like you're told.
What did I miss?
Uh, everything.
I lasered the power points
on the Romero thing for the D.A.
- They weren't biting.
- You called the D.A.?
- I just said I lasered them.
- What'd you tell him?
What Claudette told me.
On my way out, he asked me
where we were. I filled him in.
Well, we're still investigating.
The guy's guilty.
Look, your hunches notwithstanding,
my strong sense is...
they're not gonna find the arena
sexy enough to file on.
Sexy enough?
I'm just passing along what your partner
told me and what I found out.
You got a beef with her, figure it out instead
of walking on me with your anger shoes.
Anger shoes?
That's him.
Hello, asshole.
Against the wall.
Come on.
- Somebody called for a police escort.
- Must've been you.
Always happy to help out
a citizen in need. Let's go.
- You sure you want in?
- Yeah.
- We can do this without you.
- Where's the fun in that?
We're a team.
Okay.
[Doomsday]
What are you guys talking about?
Want in on what?
Now, take everything that's
a name brand trademark violation.
- [Man] You got it.
- Take him into custody.
Is it worth taking
another run at the D.A.?
Romero skates
on attempted murder...
at least he won't be selling
knockoff shoes anymore.
You get lemons,
you make lemonade.
Where is this "Hey, man, it's all good,"
"whatever" bullshit coming from?
- Excuse me?
- Catch the mediocrity flu
Billings has been passing?
This guy tried
to kill somebody.
He's getting off on a class "B" felony
while you took a half day of personal time.
I was out of the Barn
for an hour and a half today max.
Come on.
You're coming in late.
When you're here,
your head's not in the game.
I'm sorry the case didn't make.
It was never a slam dunk.
Hey, Julien?
"Officer Hanlon used unnecessary
and excessive force...
in subduing the second suspect."
- You really want that on her record?
- That's what happened.
Look, Billings hasn't seen this yet.
Why don't you sleep on it?
You know, especially since she was
coming to the aid of a fellow officer.
The department is still liable for
her actions against an unarmed citizen.
She's 5'4". Excessive for you, excessive
for her are probably two different things.
It's my call.
Good night.
Hey, have you requested
extra baton training for her?
No.
Well, maybe you should think about
your responsibilities as a training officer.
I also have a responsibility
to wash her out if she can't handle it.
I could've washed you out
a couple of times.
I'd like to think that
I made the right decision.
Where are the dogs' heads?
They're in the freezer.
I was gonna make them into soup...
make that bitch who saw me drink it.
Where are we going?
Over there.
[Shane Grunting]
Come here. Come here.
[Shane]
Let's go. Let's go. Get in the car.
Amigo.
[Speaking Spanish]
[Spanish]
Guy spends a weekend a month at
a whorehouse in T.J. Likes his Mexican pussy.
Just keep him away
from the Chihuahuas.
[Ronnie]
But he should've left this at home.
[Spanish]
Possession of a weapon in my country
is a very serious crime.
You can't do this shit!
You can't do this shit! I'm a citizen!
Yeah? Phones work
in those Mexi jails.
Maybe they'll let you call
the State Department.
Government types
aren't too helpful...
gettin' murder suspects
out of foreign prisons.
Mexico makes our gun laws
look like parking violations. Good luck.
See you in 20 years, asshole.
I know you hate passin' the buck.
What are you gonna do?
[Sighs]
[Horn Beeps]
- Hey.
- Hey, man.
Something's bothering me.
We need to talk.
[Mackey On Speaker]
Sure. What's going on?
[Curtis] I was reading through
those Terry files Danny asked for.
Why? It's ancient history.
He died on our watch.
Somethin' always seemed weird, and now
people are asking for these files.
Where's this comin' from?
[Curtis On Speaker]
What happened that night?
[Mackey]
You were there. You know what happened.
- Two-Time shot-
- You're not telling me everything.
- Of course I am.
- No. No, you're not.
- He was my friend.
- I'm your friend.
- You tell me.
- What the hell do you think you're doin'?
- Don't you lie to me. Don't lie to me!
- What are you doin'? Stop-
- [Static Over Speaker]
- Where's the sound?
- I don't know.
- I need sound.
I'm working, I'm working.
- I.A.D. Has me wired, all right?
- What?
I just disconnected it. I.A.D. Has me wired.
They're watching us right now.
They busted me with some heroin,
and they're talkin' prison if I don't do this.
What else?
I've been protecting you all day.
They're gunning for all of us.
Some I.A.D. Player and Aceveda.
Okay, I gotta make a decision,
and I gotta make it quick.
Why is it even a question?
- Because I think you're lying to me.
- I'm not.
Then you look me in the eye,
and you tell me the truth about Terry.
Okay, if I don't believe you,
I'm gonna start lookin' out for myself.
- Don't listen to them.
Don't buy into their bullshit.
- Tell me the truth.
- We're a team.
- Yeah, that Terry was a part of once.
- [Static Continues]
- Come on. Come on.
Now tell me.
How you can even ask me that-
They told me Terry was working
with the feds to bring us down.
Now answer me. Okay, you look me
in the eye, you tell me the truth.
If we're really a team,
tell me the truth already.
- Oh, my God.
- Lem, we're in on this together, right?
- I need to go.
- Everything's fine, right?
We're- Everything's fine.
- Where you goin'? We gotta talk.
- I need to go.
- Don't.
- Where is the sound?
It's gotta be his mike.
Lem!
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chattering]
##[Continues]
##[Ends]