Prevlously on The Shield.
- You're sick.
- Dutch, I was here yesterday.
I'm here today.
I'll be here tomorrow.
About six months ago,
we found this kilo of pure heroin...
In the glove compartment of your car.
- But you never logged It Into Evldence.
- Lem got picked up by I.A.D.
Got hlm wearlng a wlre.
Councllman, a moment of your tlme.
- He came by the office.
- You didn't have regular
sit-down meetings with him?
- Just trying to figure out
which uniform you're wearing.
- It sure as hell isn't Mackey's.
- We think Kavanaugh's
gonna try to get Emolia to give you up.
- You're not safe here anymore.
- We gotta go. Gotta move you.
- Why? What happened?
- A couple of possible leaks.
- You said Vic wouldn't find out.
- Vic, what the hell?
- You didn't return any of my calls.
- Kavanaugh, what'd you tell him?
- That I saw your guy take the heroin. That's it.
Six months
you could've warned me!
One of my men, maybe all of us,
are going to jail because of you.
- [Gasps]
- I found you once. I can do it again.
- [Door Opens]
- Poll-
- Oh, Jesus. It's you.
- What are you doing here?
I had no Idea...
Vic knew about you
giving up one of his guys.
That's my fault.
I made a mistake. I'm sorry.
But now I can make sure that
you and Sebastlo are safe.
Nobody's gonna hurt you.
- L- I gotta get him to school now.
- You-You need anything?
- You want anythlng?
- No. I'm good. Thanks.
Can your guy take me back now?
Sure he can. Sure.
You know that you may have to testlfy
agalnst Vlc and hls guys In court.
That's part of the deal you slgned.
You know that, rlght?
No. Not- Not with him there.
Yeah. I'm sorry.
It's, uh...
part of the conditions.
No. You never sald that.
Just get hlm to admlt stuff. That's all.
But you haven't gotten hlm
to admlt anythlng, Emolla.
[Speaking Spanish]
Por favor, Emolla.
Por favor.
I don't wanna do this no more.
[Sniffles]
He's been good to me.
I don't want your money.
Please take it.
Scott.
- Scott.
- [Scott] Yeah.
Double security.
Take her home.
Other than the kid
going to school...
no one comes, no one goes,
no one calls, all right?
[Door Closes]
Christ.
- See you next time, Dad.
- I can't wait, sweetie.
- Jump in. Buckle up.
- [Woman Sobblng, Speaklng Spanlsh]
- [Car Engine Starts]
- Love you.
[Speaklng Spanlsh]
- I can't believe
how much homework these kids get.
- Yeah, I know.
- [Screams]
- Sixth grade. Jesus Christ!
- [Screaming]
- Watch her!
[Man]
Crazy bltch, get offhlm.! Stop.!
- Help the drlver.! Help the drlver.!
- Get off!
- [Screaming]
- Help me, God!
- Shit. Jesus.
- [Man Shoutlng]
- No, you're okay. No, don't move.
- [Screaming]
It's okay. Just calm down, sir.
Calm down.
- Get a doctor.! Aaah.!
- We're gonna get some help.
We're gonna help you out.
- [Groanlng]
- Just calm down.
Nice work, man.
- Where's Cass?
- Nurses'lounge.
She thought it was cool.
Been hanging around you too much.
Hey, this was your world
this time, not mine.
Speaking of your world,
is there anything, um...
else I need to know about
that special work thing?
- No. Everything's okay with that now.
- Corrlne, good.
Ah, thls Is Dr. Lesser, runs our E.R.
Wanted to talk to you.
- Vic Mackey. What about?
- The girl who just died.
Yeah, our officer said they found her
strolling down the 110 Freeway.
Nothing new.
She's a total nut job.
Schizophrenic.
But I found these meds on her.
Brother says she's been taking them
for the last month.
French label.
No doctor. Bad scrips?
What's on the label,
what's inside-
two very different things.
This shit's killed
five people in three months.
- Thought you guys
would've made a dent In thls by now.
- We've been on thls?
Yeah. Filled out a complaint
with your captain last month.
Who do I need to bitch to?
Let me do the bltchlng for ya.
Where'd your slster get her meds?
The drugs were supposed to stop
the psychotic breaks.
- Where'd you get them?
- Just, you know, the drugstore.
What klnd of drugstore fills a bottle
wlthout a doctor's name?
- Could you give us a minute.
- Be gentle. His sister just died.
I'm oozing gentle.
Sis was screaming
about devils before she died.
I hope she wasn't talking about you
feeding her bad meds.
- I didn't know they were bad.
- Tell me where you got them.
And don't tell me Rite-Aid.
Clínlca Esqulna.
The guy who runs It helps locals
wlth affordable prescrlptlons.
- Black market Blue Cross.
- Better than nothing at all.
Kavanaugh's gotta know
we're onto Lem's wire.
- Us tracking down Emolia?
- Why hasn't he arrested Lem yet?
Thls guy doesn't follow a scrlpt.
We can't assume anythlng.
- You think you convinced Emolia?
- At the time.
But I'm sure Kavanaugh's crawling inside
her head. Who knows where she's at now?
- So the next move is?
- Get a note to Lem. Keep hlm up to date.
Everything else, business as usual.
- Hey, guys, easy wlth that, huh?
- Hey, Billings.
You remember a doc over at Mlsslon Cross
fillng a bad scrlp complalnt?
- Yeah, sort of.
- Well, the body count's sort of piling up.
The hospltal board's about to brlng In
the feds. Thls Is gonna make some nolse.
Shit. I just thought
it was some bogus Viagra.
Stone was gonna get around
to it, time permitting.
Five dead citizens.
Phillips is gonna be crawling up your ass.
All right, look. It's drugs.
That's you guys.
Run wlth It.
Just keep me plugged In.
So Vic got to your C.I., huh?
He's resourceful.
It won't happen again.
Well, I can tap
someJustlce contacts.
- We can get her into witness protection.
- She's protected.
- Thanks, though.
- Yeah. Well, they're onto you.
So when are you gonna
arrest Lemansky?
You ever get one of those,
like, really bad feelings?
You can't explaln It-
can't explaln It at all-
but can't shake It off elther.
I got one of those...
about you and Mackey.
And I think this investigation
is going off point...
because you're too distracted
about those bad feelings.
I've got Emolia ready to testify...
and one of his own men
on the edge of turning.
So, if you are,
for whatever reason...
maybe...
working on both sides
of the street here-
Well, I appreciate
the, uh, friendly heads-up.
But I know what side
of the street I'm on.
Yeah?
Yeah.
- Check this out.
- What's this?
This would be
one of my good feelings.
[Curtis's Voice] The brother told us about
that clinic selling the counterfeit scrips.
Most of the prescriptions came from a French
drug company, went bankrupt two years ago.
Doc was right, pharmacology is hit
and miss. Pretty much a loaded gun.
Tell Billings we need a warrant
for this Esquina clinic.
- Might be one of the places-
- So what? They probably already
know you've got Lem wired.
It's not just scumbags dying,
it's families.
[Chuckles]
They're sending him on another one
of those bullshit errands.
That way he's out of earshot.
The threat out of slght...
- they now feel comfortable to share.
- [Mackey] How's Lem feeling?
[Shane] He won't go to the doctor.
Think he's puking blood again.
[Mackey]
Shlt. Keep looklng In on hlm.
- [Aceveda] You bugged the clubhouse too.
- Yeah.
O.I.G. Slgned off on It.
I planted it last night
in the base of the softball trophy.
Did you know that they were
Police League champs?
- Make sure all our heads are straight.
- Yeah, okay.
Don't worry.
I got this whole thing sealed off.
[Door Opens]
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chatterlng]
##[Ends]
Hey! That's
sophisticated machinery.
Dude, it's a vending machine.
Put money in, shit comes out.
It's a Gourmet
Quick-Mealer, asshole.
Ain't nothing without power.
Where are the goddamn outlets?
- [Ringing]
- [Sighs]
[Ringing Continues]
Hey, thls Is Danny.
Leave a message.
- I'll get back to you as soon as I can. Thanks.
- [Beeps]
[Bllllngs]
Sofer, what happened...
- to the goddamn outlets
for the vendlng machlnes?
- Oh, shit.
You were supposed
to call the electrlclan.
I'll chalk it up to hormones,
but you better get down here and fix this.
- [Beeps]
- [Sighs]
So how'd we do?
Some of it looks legit.
F.D.A. Seals, valid expiration.
But there's over a dozen boxes
that don't have seals.
No record of these being logged in. We'll run 'em
against bad scrips at Mission Cross.
City Council in the house.
- How'd Aceveda get here so quick?
- You think this is the source of the bad drugs?
- We'll see where It leads.
- What the hell is Aceveda doing there?
I should get back.
Keep me posted and so forth.
- Bring out Dr. Feelgood.
- Okay.
My office got a call.
I want to make sure everyone's
getting the care they need.
Looks like half their stock are bootleg meds.
I'm shutting it down.
Mission Cross has been overflowing
with bad scrip deaths.
We hear your clinic is ground zero.
- Our drugs aren't bad.
- They're illegal.
Yeah, but they're not bad.
Look. I make a few deals, cut some corners.
But it's not about the profit.
It's about helping these people cope.
These are different than the ones
we got from the E.R.
Real labels. American.
Where'd you get these?
Gruhani brothers.
Persian dudes.
Run a small trucking company.
Got a contract wlth Pyren Meryl
Pharmaceutlcals, dlstrlbute to East L.A.
- Gruhani skims off their shipments.
- I buy at a third the price.
- Take him.
- Come on.
You know, a lot of people
can't afford these drugs any other way.
Not looking to hurt this place. But I got
black market scrips poisoning the Farm.
- I gotta come down on everyone
till we figure it out.
- Yeah, I know.
But the sooner we can get this place
up and running again-
I'm working on it.
Someone I want you to meet.
Who?
- [Shane] She's that lawyer chlck, rlght?
- Yeah.
You hitting that?
No. I hired that.
You hired a lawyer?
Why?
Not me. Us. She's walking us
through this thing with Lem.
Collecting intel on the whole
suit-and-tie side of things.
- You think we're gonna need lawyers?
- I just wanna be prepared.
It's a whole new playing field
we're on right now.
Holy shlt.
A lawyer.
- Should I get my own?
- Shane. Relax.
She's just advising- all of us.
- Detectlve.
- Counselor.
This is Detective Shane Vendrell.
- Hello.
- Welcome aboard.
Someplace private we can talk?
Sure. Let's go Inslde.
Hey, Ricky, park that for me?
- [Rlcky] Yeah, no problem.
- This make sense?
I think it does.
Right over here.
I was just getting Shane up to speed
on our arrangement.
- The others too?
- Lem's still wired...
- so we have to keep him in the dark for now.
- Huh.
[Rebecca]
How'd you find out about the wire?
[Mackey] We were hooplng
In the back, and I felt It on hlm.
We got hlm In here. Scrlbbled a few notes.
We found out It was I.A.D.
So, uh, you have any luck?
I went dlgglng.
The rabblt hole's deep.
The I.A.D. Investlgatlon
was Inltlated by Captaln Rawllng...
- Ilttle over slx months ago.
- Rawllng set us up?
I don't think it was
a search and destroy.
It was to prove
we weren't crooked.
Cover her ass. Shit.
She was trylng to warn me.
I dldn't Ilsten.
When the chlef's staff
saw It In play...
they took it in
another direction.
- And what direction is that?
- The way of polltlcs.
This new chief wants to move past
the stain of the last five years.
The riots, lawsuits.
He sees the Strlke Teams
as a fallure of the old reglme.
You're a hlgh-profile team leader.
Hanglng you and your guys
puts a face on that fallure.
The brass puts some dlstance
between then and now...
buys them their public
cleansing ritual.
- Yeah, and we get screwed by a history lesson.
- What about Kavanaugh?
Closed book. All I found out
was he's way inside.
Looks Ilke he reports
dlrectly to the chlef.
[Shane]
Goddamn It.
You need to shift perception.
Start piling up some wins in bigger cases.
Make Internal Affairs look like
they're hurting good guys.
[Mackey]
Okay.
- Yeah.
- Got It.
That's a huge help. Thanks.
- Looks like I'm on board.
You know what that means?
- You'll need a retalner.
- How much?
- I'm a one-gal shop.
I'll need at least 10 grand
to get started.
- [Sighs]
- If I strlke early...
I mlght be able
to make a deal for Lem.
- [Mackey] Deals are for the guilty.
- Shit.
You need to know the financial
realities of this.
We're talklng about
legal counsel for four.
That's a shltload of man-hours.
On cop salarles.
You guys both have famllles.
We'll worry about that later.
No compromlses.
We all get cleared.
We all keep our badges. Nothing less.
Okay. Look that over, and, uh...
call if you have any questions.
I'll be in touch.
[Shane]
Thank you.
Thanks.
What's the matter?
Attorney-client privilege.
It's all inadmissible.
This quasi-pharmaceutical shit...
caused an aneurysm in your sister.
It stroked her out.
We find out you knew
these drugs were illegal...
we're gonna arrest you
for manslaughter.
- You get these from the clinic?
- Clinic charged 45 bucks for her prescriptions.
That wasn't cheap enough
for you?
L-I knew they were Russian mob.
Had the same kind of drug.
Ten bucks a bottle.
I was afrald to tell you.
Where can we find these guys?
Operate out of
a strip joint on Hensley.
That's Popovich's place.
Popovich stepped in for Tretiak.
He's running the red clan now.
- Sounds like a guy we should get to know.
- Yeah.
Somebody trashed the Gruhani
brothers' trucking office.
Checked the brothers' homes. Looks like they
left in a hurry. Both Zal and Babak are M.I.A.
- Zal and Babak?
- Yo, Vlc.
[Mackey]
Hey.
- Found these up your ass.
- [Men Laughlng]
- [Man] Hey, close the door.
- Oh!
- ##[Soft Rock]
- Is that pussy smiling at me?
- Hey!
- Oh, Shit.
Come on, girls. You know this is
a patch-the-snatch zone.
Here's your pink slip, ladies.
Mikula Popovich. [Chuckles]
I hear you're the czar to know.
You have warrant to be here?
Violation of pornography laws,
assaulting a police officer.
Probable cause.
Search and seizure, boys.
- About a half dozen of these in the supply room.
- Not much of a supply.
It's French label.
It's the same shit we got from the E.R.
You selling hangover cures,
Popovich?
No. I just like pussy.
Dancing pussy.
[Curtls]
Turn around.
Last time I saw you, you said
you were headed back to Saratov.
Mikula lets me strip.
Better money.
Safer than being whore.
Congratulations on your promotion.
Your boss is selling
bad prescriptions out of this club.
Killing a lot of innocent people.
I need to know where
he keeps his supply.
I just dance. I know nothing about drugs
or gambling or anything.
How about I share with Popovich
how you ratted out Tretiak.
Kaboom.
I know they have a garage
on Savannah. Blackburn Auto.
That's a start.
Tough shit, white cop.
I tell you nothing.
You go shit yourself.
Nice touch.
- You wanna wait up there?
- Paramedics are here if I don't make it.
Fear of gates?
Border flashback?
Maybe hejust Ilkes a challenge.
He told us he got hit by a car. Knocked him
down the hill. Witnesses saw it different.
[Speaking Spanish]
A nelghbor saw hlm jump
out of a movlng car. Red Infinltl.
- Gang retaliation?
- Lots of scratches, no ink.
- No, no. Estoy blen.
- [Tlna Speaklng Spanlsh]
[Grunts] Estoy blen.
[Speaking Spanish]
- He says he doesn't wanna go to the hospital.
- Forearm's gotta have a fracture.
No I.N.S.
No mlgra. Está blen.
- [Speaklng Spanlsh]
- We can't force him.
We can. Trespasslng.
Destructlon of prlvate property.
You're under arrest.
Take him.
Make sure he gets medlcal attentlon.
- Flll hlm In, huh?
- Okay.
Sir, people are gonna break
their necks on those wires.
Then tape 'em down.
People gotta eat. Aw, shit.
Men's tollet's clogged.
Take care of that next.
Detective Wyms, Tina talked
to Hidalgo down at Mission Cross.
- He wants to tell the truth.
- Said he jumped out of the car
because he was scared.
Gave us a descrlptlon of the woman drlvlng.
Black, 40s, heavyset.
Plcked hlm up for daywork
at the Home Depot on Thlrd.
Drove him out to the Angeles Crest.
Made him dig a hole.
[Speaklng Spanlsh]
What?
- She wanted him to bury a body.
- She must've seen him getting skittish.
He said she threatened to report him
to the I.N.S. If he didn't finish the job.
[Tlna]
That's when he freaked andjumped out of the car.
That's, uh, really good work.
Both of them.
- Absolutely.
- Right.
- [Speaking Spanish]
- [Dutch] Wow.
- How tall are you?
- 6'4".
She asked him to make it this big?
- [Speaking Spanish]
- Sí, sí. [Speaking Spanish]
Yeah. She told hlm
to make It longer.
- Hey! You guys done?
- Yeah, you done?
Uh, yeah. Sorry. Good job.
Clear!
Got nothing, man.
There's nothing.
- Think the whore lied?
- You mean the stripper.
- [Muffled Shout]
- What the hell's that?
[Muffled Shouts Contlnue]
Hey. Jesus, In here.
Holy shit.
Got him?
- Who did this to you?
- Hey, Vic.
- Blngo, man.
- [Man Coughlng]
Zal Gruhani. One of the brothers
who owns the trucking company.
Jesus Christ. This is chemo medicine.
Do you have cancer?
[Straining]
No. Why?
Popovich knew this French shit
was killing people.
So he wanted our supply.
Take over our shipments.
I said no.
Then throws me in that hole
for two weeks...
and pumps thls polson In me.
- Until you change your mind.
- Yeah.
Can't say you're not committed.
- Where's your brother?
- Babak runs our West Side office.
[Breathes Deeply]
But Russians don't know him.
He's hiding at our mom's.
We hlde the drugs In her garage.
Lock it on that side.
Pick up the scrips at the mother's?
- Charge Popovich with attempted 187?
- Yeah.
Hang on.
- Have a seat, Ivan.
- Mikula.
[Shane]
Yeah, whatever.
They're back.
- What is this room?
- Thls Is the room of endless posslbllltles.
Away from the department's cameras.
We have a business opportunity
we'd like to share with you.
Turn It down, It's a short walk
back to the cage.
[Mackey] We know about
the garage and your cancer research.
Don't know garage.
Just manage club.
We know.
Dancing camel toe.
I can arrest you and your guys. Squeeze one
of'em till we find out where the drugs are.
But I'm all about diplomacy,
raising the iron curtain.
So, you're talklng
maybe relatlonshlp?
[Shane]Just Ilke the way
you guys Ilke to do thlngs back In Moscow.
You Ilke to help out folks who can't afford
the, uh, hlgh cost of medlclne.
We appreciate that. We just wanna make
sure your product doesn't kill anyone.
- That's just bad business.
- We'll trade you that French shit
you've been dealing...
for all-American, F.D.A. -approved shit.
We'll give you access to
the Gruhani brothers' supply.
You give them 20% .
Why would Gruhani agree to this?
[Mackey]
If he doesn't, we'll arrest him and his brother.
- They'll lose everythlng.
- [Popovlch] What's In It for you?
We get bad drugs off the street.
[Mackey Chuckles]
We also get 10% off the top
for putting you on the right track.
[Shane] That's 70% In your pocket.
Easy half mll a year.
You say yes,
you walk out ofhere, free and clear.
You say no, or try to burn us...
perestroika dies.
I can say yes
to this relationship.
Good.
You bring the bad
French scrips to the garage.
I'll get Gruhani's brother,
Babak, to bring what he's got in storage.
We're gonna need a piece
of our fee up front...
good faith gesture-
$10,000.
- [Popovlch Chuckles]
- [Mackey] You get a better product.
We track down the bad drugs.
Everybody gets a win.
- Huh?
- Who says there is never police
around when we need them, hmm?
- [Laughing]
- Who says that?
Yeah, who says?
[Kavanaugh]
Faster than that, Leo. Tell 'em It's for me.
- What's going on?
- I got Mackey making a deal with the Russians.
Hot prescription drugs.
You know anythlng about that?
They closed a city-funded clinic today
for doling out illegal prescriptions.
- People were dying.
- He didn't call you about it?
Talk to you about it in one of his,
uh, private conversations?
- No.
- Dld you know our boy...
has hlred a lawyer
for hlm and hls team?
Checked around.
Sounds like her.
- Rebecca Doyle.
- Yeah. You know her?
Met her a few times.
Well, it makes sense.
She knows how to
protect career criminals.
There's another brother
of a dune-coon mother.
Fill our Persian drug boy in on the plan.
I'll wrangle the big man.
- Yeah.
- What the hell's golng on?
- Come on, man.
- Sofer told me you released Popovlch.
- I thought he was the one
pushing these bad meds?
- He is.
We just don't know where
he keeps his supply.
We couldn't hold hlm
on the shlt we found.
Phillips just drilled me a new ass channel
for my lack of community awareness.
This bullshit's
gonna totally ding me.
I'm working on something that might
cool your anal burning. I'll let you know.
There was two missing persons
over 6 foot 4, guess who reported one.
Peaches Pyman.
Reported a red Infiniti stolen this morning.
Puts Alex Gardllng
mlsslng May, 2004.
Six foot 5.
A perfect peg
for a very large hole.
- You found my car?
- Yes, we did.
There something I gotta sign?
Just need to ask you
a few questlons.
- Anyone else have the keys, Peaches?
- Not to the car.
My Realtor has the house keys.
Just sold my house.
- Moving out of state?
- Nope. Just outta the hood.
- Where were you this morning
when the car was taken?
- Sleeping in.
I run a sports bar.
- Didn't get to bed till after 3:00.
- While we have you here...
we also need to ask about that
missing person's report you filed.
On Alex?
That was over a year ago.
You're just following up on that now?
- Alex your boyfrlend?
- He was.
He sent me an e-mall
a few months later.
- I should have reported that, I guess.
- So he's alive?
No, I don't think so.
He was termlnal.
Some klnd ofblood dlsorder.
He didn't wanna put me
through that.
He moved to Panama.
Wanted to die
in his boyhood home.
So he e-mailed me to apologize
and say good-bye.
Had the techs plant cameras
and mikes in the garage.
Gives us a 360-degree view
of the whole space.
Front row seats to Mackey's drug swap
and cash infusion.
- Hey, he's on.
- [Mackey] How's our cancer victim?
He's doing okay.
He's real worried about his brother.
He should be.
How's your gut?
[Curtis]
Same, I guess.
You should stay home tonight.
Take it easy.
- We can take care of things.
- Okay.
- You hear anything else about that other thing?
- No.
Gonna give our guy a call.
See if there's any movement.
- All right, man. Thanks.
- [Man] I need- I need two. Two more unls.
- [Cell Phone Rlnglng]
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Baslcally we're In a holdlng pattern rlght now.
- Yeah?
Hey. Our C.I.'s given us
the 20 on those bad scrips.
Thought you might wanna be there,
spin it that Aceveda way.
I'll give a call.
You bring the cameras.
Yeah, I understand.
Right.
It was Mackey.
He wants to turn picking up the bad drugs
into a media event.
After he makes the trade
and takes the payoff In prlvate.
Steals his cake and eats it too.
Look, I got a district to take care of.
You don't mind sticking around.
- Do you, Councllman?
- Why?
Help me get rid of that
bad feeling I got.
You know, prednisone's
pretty toxic stuff.
How'd you-
You looked in my desk?
Your drawer was open.
I glanced over.
- Unbelievable.
- Why don't you talk to me about this?
- I just want to help.
- It's not about what you want.
- What's golng on here?
- Who are you?
I live here.
Shonda Cromwell.
Well, we got a warrant
to search the house.
Oh, my God.
What did Peaches do?
- Detectlves.
- [Claudette] What Is It?
You're not gonna believe this.
[Dutch]
Is that a- Is that a body?
Damn. He must've
plssed somebody off.
Yeah. Or maybe he was caught
rlfllng through thelr drawers.
Or maybe his dying wish
was dry-clean only.
You, uh,
recognize this guy?
- Breaking up is hard to do.
- We found him that way.
- In your garage.
- Oh, my Lord!
[Sobbing]
No, no, no.
No. Alex, baby.
Oh, no.
[Sobbing Continues]
No.!
No, no.
Oh. No, no.
That's not the response...
- of a woman who just tried
to bury a guy in the woods.
- No, it isn't.
Slt down. Someone'll get
your statement In a mlnute.
- [Phone Rlnglng]
- [People Chatterlng]
- What's that about?
- When you gotta go, you gotta go?
Hey, I checked out that e-mail that
Peaches said came from Panama.
Turns out our I.T. Guy says it came
from an Internet café in Burbank.
- Long way from the Canal.
- Thanks.
- Nice catch on that Infiniti by the way.
- Oh, sure thlng.
- [Thuds]
- Oh, God!
- [Man] What happened?
- Danny. Danny, you all right?
- Oh, shlt.
- You okay?
- You want a doctor?
- No, really, it's just stupid.
- She ran into the pole.
- Just help me up, okay?
- I'm- I'm sorry.
Are you sure you're okay?
[Crying]
No, I'm fine.
Just-
[Chuckles]
Who put the goddamn pole there?
I got it.
[Dutch]
I was- I was walklng thls way-
[Tollet Flushes]
How's the head?
I just gave Tina a whole lecture...
on "never let 'em see you cry."
Then I go and give 'em a ticket
to my emotional breakdown.
Christ.
When I was pregnant with my first...
I trashed the aisle at the Ralphs...
'cause I couldn't decide
which disposable diaper to buy.
I just don't- I don't- I don't know
what I'm doing here.
None of us do, sweetheart.
They all need to mlnd
thelr own damn buslness.
You just worry
about what's in here.
Let the rest of us
wade through the sewer.
## [Laptop: Rock]
##[Contlnues]
How you gonna handle it
if he makes the deal with the Russian?
You gonna just go in,
or wait till you have more?
Gonna use the shock and awe
to our advantage.
Take 'em into custody.
Separate 'em.
Full court press.
One of them will turn on the others.
##[Contlnues]
See ya later.
Good luck tonight.
##[Contlnues Over Laptop]
Hldalgo was afrald ofbelng deported.
- I told him we weren't gonna do that.
- [Claudette] What else?
Said sometimes people who cooperate
with the police get their green cards.
No wonder he was so happy to help.
- It's true.
- Well, yeah. If you, like, help bring down a cartel.
But It worked.
He's been cooperatlng, rlght?
He I.D. 'd the first black woman
you put In front ofhlm.
Now the wltness Is an Illegal...
coerced into a statement by
a false promise of citizenship.
Shit.
- It seemed like the right thing to do.
- It wasn't.
It'll be okay.
Dutchman's got a plan.
- Oh. Sorry to keep you waiting.
- Oh. It's okay.
Is that pregnant cop all right?
She'll be fine.
It's a crazy day, huh?
[Chuckling]
No kidding.
Geez, and Peaches
killing Alex like that.
- I just can't believe it.
- Well, no one can.
- What do you mean?
- We mean...
Peaches didn't kill Alex.
She loved him.
- You kllled Alex.
- And you a crazy bitch. I ain't killed no one.
Then why'd you send this man to dig a grave
in the Angeles Crest this morning?
[Dutch]
What's the golng rate for dayworkers?
You also work two blocks
from the café...
you e-mailed his
"Dead John" letter from.
So Peaches would stop looklng.
Your shrlnk-wrapplng skllls preserved Alex
so well, we've got your D.N.A. All over hlm.
You were trylng to move the body
before Peaches sold the house.
Oh, shit.
Flrst rule ofhole-dlgglng: :
If you're standlng In the hole, stop dlgglng.
So tell us the truth.
One crazy bitch to another.
All rlght.
Look.
He was with Peaches.
- But then he came on to me.
- It's understandable.
We started having some fun.
But then he falls
all In love wlth me and shlt.
Wants to tell her everything.
Peaches owned the house.
She would've kicked my ass out.
He wasn't worth all that.
- [Dutch] What happened?
- We had sex.
Started fighting about Peaches.
I keep a bat, side my bed.
Shit just happened.
Up against the truck.
- Don't you trust us?
- Sure.
What makes you think I don't?
Oh. Tsh-tsh-tsh-tsh.
When we see the drugs.
Don't ya trust us?
Hey, Vlc.
Old French Zocor.
I think I arrested him once.
[Popovlch]
That's all of It. Everythlng we have.
Good.
[Mackey]
Open It up. Let's get the real meds In here.
We're ready.
Go on my call.
[Truck Beeplng]
[Gate Closlng]
Babak,
meet your new boss.
I want to see merchandise.
Gotjust what the doctor ordered.
Show hlm.
Yes.
You got that tingling
feeling like I do?
[Men Chattering]
Yeah, right here.
Here's our good faith.
The 10,000.
Come on. You deserve it.
Just take it.
Yes.
That's bullshit!
He almost kill my brother.
He poison him and then
he take our business!
[Aceveda] What's he dolng?
Where'd the gun come from?
[Grunting]
Let it go.
Hey. Hey!
- Son of a bitch.
- Kill me. Go ahead. I don't give a shit.
Can't let hlm walk out ofhere.
He'll glve us all away.
What the hell?
- You take care of it.
- No.
He's your problem.
- He's our problem.
- Man, come on.
- There's gotta be another way.
- [Popovlch] No other way.
You want relationship, huh?
Just not in the face.
- [Kavanaugh] Go In. Go In.
- [Man] We're a go.
Vic. Vic!
- Freeze!
- On the ground.
- Get down! Get down!
- Hit the ground.
- Let me see 'em!
- [Grunts]
- Face down.
- Let's go.
- Aaah.
- Don't move.
- Secure.
- All clear here.
- [Gruntlng]
Slr, all suspects
are accounted for.
Vic, what the hell is going on?
I.A.D. Just shlt all over our stlng.
What's this?
Detective Baham.
- There were blanks In the guns.
- [Aceveda] What are you runnlng?
We're trying to establish
a relationship with the Russians.
Knew Popovlch wouldn't let
the Perslan threat get out allve.
Kllllng the competltlon would've
been the blood tle that blnds.
Prescription drugs is
just the tip of the iceberg.
This shit-bag's got ties
going back to the Kremlin.
Would've been a huge wln for us.
You thlnk I was maklng a deal wlth
the Russlans? That I'd actually klll someone?
- [Chuckles Nervously]
- I don't know where
you got your Intel, but It's wrong.
He ran the whole operation
by me this afternoon.
I guess I.A.D. Wlll spln any klnd of fictlon
to staln good cops bad.
Uncuff my men. You idiots did
enough damage for one night.
Book him for attempted murder
and illegal dancing pussy.
Won't topple R.O.C., but at least
it'll make a dent in the local machine.
[Chuckles]
Councilman.
Gannon come out
of retirement?
Hey, if it ain't broke,
it ain't the Barn.
Heard about I.A.D.
That's bullshit.
Yeah. Typical.
How you feeling?
Oh. A little better.
- Thanks.
- Uh, can I get you something to eat?
Sort of lost my appetite.
Right.
Should we talk?
About what?
Well, maybe I can help.
Looks like the dad's
not in the picture.
Yeah. Well,
the dad doesn't know.
I think it's better that way.
I just-
I don't think that he could
handle it right now.
I'm gonna do this on my own.
If you change your mind,
offer still stands.
All right.
Thanks.
[Phone Rlnglng]
[Chatterlng]
I've got lupus.
I've had it for 15 years.
It's just been flaring up lately.
Fifteen years?
Got my girls, James.
I've got family.
I just need you to be you.
[Phone Rlnglng]
- ##[Rock]
- [Men Laughlng]
- Ah.
- Little Southern'll comfort that belly.
- [Curtls] I thlnk I'll stlck wlth the plnk.
- [Mackey] I Ilke the plnk.
Bllllngs wants us to clean up In here,
make sure there's no code vlolatlons.
Seems someone ratted him
out to the fire marshal.
[Mackey]
Who would do something like that?
Know what we should do? We should get
rid of some of this shit on the locker.
It's a little too close
to this light.
[Shane] No, not the trophy, man.
I went 3 for 4 to wln that.
You were 0 for 5,
but who's countlng?
Know what, screw It.
It's a cheap plece of shlt.
You know what?
We'll just beat I.A.D. Again next year.
[Muffled Statlc]
##[Contlnues]
- [Door Closes]
- [Sighs]
Hey.
Hey, Dutch.
I just wanted to thank you.
You keep going out
of your way to help me...
and, well, I just
really appreciate it.
Oh, sure thing.
Uh, any time.
- Well, I'll see you tomorrow?
- Night.
Night.
Word is I.A.D. Stepped on a big sting
you guys were setting up on the Russians.
They just keep
hurting the good guys.
Could've picked it up
on Lemansky's wire maybe.
Thought you guys were
making some kind of deal?
Possibility.
There's egg
all over I.A.D. 's face.
If this tipped Kavanaugh off
that you're onto the wire...
he's gonna be plssed.
I have Ronnie sweep
for bugs every day.
He found one
in the clubhouse.
We knew It had to be Kavanaugh,
so we spun It our way.
- Just like you said.
- Jesus Christ.
You knew the place was bugged
when you talked to me?
- That conversatlon-
- You used me too?
- Any part of that conversation is privileged.
- No.
- You withheld information. You lied to me.
- They can't use It.
No. It-
It happened fast.
L- l- Look.
I'm winging it here.
I'm sorry.
Any move he makes against us now...
just seems like part of an ongoing,
misguided vendetta.
I better prepare our next move.
Because Kavanaugh is going
to arrest Lemansky.
And he's gonna try to
hurt you by hurtlng hlm.
We'll be ready for that too.
- ##[Laptop: : Rock]
- [Mackey] You know what?
We'll just beat I.A.D.
Again next year.
- [Beeps]
- [Voices Rewinding]
- [Men Laughing]
You want me to go
back to the Barn?
- Plant another one someplace else?
- [Mackey] I like the pink.
- Billings wants us to clean up in here-
- Don't bother.
Someone ratted hlm out
to the fire marshal.
You know, Farmlngton dld beat us
In the semlfinals.
Could've been talklng about that.
- Thanks, Buzz.
...get rld of thls shlt on the locker.
- You should get going.
- [Shane] No, not the trophy, man.
- I went 3 for 4 to wln that.
- You were 0 for 5, but who's countlng?
Know what? Screw It.
It's a cheap plece of shlt.
- [Door Closes]
- [Mackey] You know what?
We'll just beat I.A.D.
Agaln next year.
[Screaming]
[Panting]
[Breathing Heavily]
##[Rock]
[Men, Women Chatterlng]
##[Contlnues]
##[Ends]