Read the prepared statement
and then ask for questions.
And expect Hanratty to ask
about the Wilkey Gardens bust.
Reflect, but don't deny.
Right. You got your notes?
Don't need 'em.
Thanks for making the trip.
And now here's Captain David Aceveda.
Thank you, Wanda.
The Farmington district of Los Angeles...
...which I've been commanding
for the last four months...
...has traditionally been one of the most
dangerous, crime-ridden areas of the city.
Some reporters have gone
so far as to label Farmington a war zone.
Yeah, it's over at the corner!
I'm proud to announce
that murders, rapes, armed robberies...
...and many other violent crimes
have decreased dramatically here...
...in the last six months.
Under my direction,
law enforcement officers...
...now participate
in neighborhood outreach programs.
Already, the effect
is being felt by local families.
Mothers feel safer
as they shop for groceries.
Too late, G-man.
With the continued support of community
leaders and ordinary citizens...
...we can make the Farmington district
a safer home...
...for all of us.
Mother...
That's for running, asshole.
Get up.
What the hell, man?
Look at that, Booty.
Looks like you got
some kind of third nad going down there.
Let me get that for ya.
No, wait!
Shit!
I got an evidence bag
somewhere.
No, that's okay. I got it.
All right.
Come on.
Buenos dias.
Any questions?
Christ!
You do not see a pair like that every day.
It's called rigor.
Rigor or no rigor, that's a serious rack.
You wanna give 'em a squeeze?
How much time we got
before the M.E. shows up?
Victim's sister is outside.
Wants to know what happened.
Dutch is in charge
of all potential criers.
Thanks.
Are you the first one here?
Yeah. Me and Julien got the call.
Last few weeks,
dead bodies seem to follow you around.
Yeah, I'm a real fun-time gal.
Any notions on this one?
Nature of the wounds, we're looking at...
...an inexperienced under-achiever type.
Covered genitals,
feels shame for what he did.
Family member, boyfriend.
This one will break easy.
Don't! Let me go!
Goddamn it! Get outta my way!
Miss, I need you to calm down.
- Who are you?
- Detective Wagenbach.
Is she dead?
There's a young woman inside.
We haven't identified her yet.
This is my sister's place.
Like I said, we don't know who she is yet.
Long blonde hair, pretty.
That sounds like her. I'm sorry.
Ma'am.
Where's Jenny?
Jenny?
Nancy's little girl. Where is she?
Come with me.
Guess what's missing?
Shit, son.
I know.
It just got interesting.
Hey, Sarge.
Thanks.
I gotta hit the head.
I'll see you in the clubhouse.
Hey, doll.
Just in time.
I've got some reporters here.
You feel like talking?
Nah.
You sure? Gilroy and the chief
will push this story hard.
Your team deserves a lot of credit.
Let the poster boy do his thing.
Talk to you.
Peterson, the john's still not working?
Plumber must have gotten lost.
If this city wants to thank us...
...for a job well done,
how's about making sure...
...we don't all have to all cram
into the same goddamn stall?
Vic, can I see you?
Give me a sec.
I need you now.
I'm taking a piss.
Provided a spot
in the ladies' room opens up.
I got my fingers crossed.
Now.
Aye, aye, Captain.
Great.
Have fun in here, bro.
You remember Miguel Esteana.
Sure.
Miguel's a piece-of-shit drug dealer
with the 25th Street Coronas.
This is the kind of attitude you foster
under your command?
- Mr. Esteana's attorney, José Garcia...
- I know José.
He represents a bunch
of piece-of-shit drug dealers.
What I do is ensure my clients' rights
aren't violated...
...by thugs like you.
Mr. Esteana claims
you used excessive force during his arrest.
Really?
Is that what you claim, Miguel?
Yeah, that's some hickey.
Boyfriend give you that?
No, you did it with some pliers.
I don't recall any pliers.
I remember the eight dime bags
of pure H we nabbed you with.
The search, we'll be contesting
with Judge McAllister.
I'm sorry. I'm drawing a blank
on this whole pliers thing.
Feel free to ask my guys, but I doubt
they remember it that way either.
You're a disgrace.
That's funny.
I don't recall signing up for ethics class
from a scumbag drug lawyer.
Is that all...
...or can I go take that piss?
So Miguel is lying?
Anything to stay out of jail.
Fourth complaint since I came here.
Lucky for me you don't believe 'em.
Keep smiling for the cameras.
See what you can do
about getting the men's john fixed.
I stopped listening to you five minutes ago.
I'm just saying our un-sub's disorganized...
...probably a record and no violent history.
- "Un-sub"?
- Unidentified subject.
You mean the killer.
Yeah.
Then just say that! Christ!
You think Danny would go out with me?
Danny?
A study says over 40 percent of female
police meet their spouses on the job.
You wanna date again, fine.
But why chase after a uni-cop
in our own station?
That's just lazy, son.
Get her out of uniform,
I'll bet she's a knockout.
Sign up for dance classes.
Take out an ad. Join a book club.
For God's sake, show some imagination.
No wonder your wife left you.
- Lucy had intimacy issues unrelated to me.
- Right, unrelated to you.
Buzzer, Sarge!
Yeah!
You're such an expert,
how come both your husbands left you?
It sure as hell
wasn't for a lack of imagination.
You got a missing kid?
Jenny Reeborg, 8 years old.
We found her mother stabbed to death.
Any leads?
We're following some things up.
What have you got so far?
Her father's a crackhead.
Personal nature of the crime, his daughter
missing, he's gonna be our guy.
Also, a neighbor saw Ponyboy Harris
banging on the dead lady's door yesterday.
Who's Ponyboy Harris?
He's a local fence. Bit of a fancy.
Collared him three or four times personally.
You guys need anything run down, just ask.
I wanna help.
Thanks, Captain.
Since when does he get his hands dirty?
Can't blame a guy for trying.
Danny, hey!
How's the coffee?
Usual police issue?
Pretty much.
There's a shock.
Listen, I don't...
I don't know what your plans are...
Lookie here, Shane, it's the ladykiller!
Dutch boy, what's this I hear...
...about some dead girl's sister
blowing you at the crime scene?
Dutch man! Going to town!
You guys are sick.
Us?
You're the one getting your pipe smoked
by a grieving relative right by the body.
She was upset. I was comforting her.
You don't have to tell me
about the different stages of grief.
There's denial, anger, sucking you off.
If you can think of anything else,
you just call 911 and ask for Det. Blow Me.
Excuse me.
"Detective Blow Me."
Dutch, what?
Come on, don't be so sensitive.
That was real classy.
Come on. Dutch thinks he's
a notch above the rest of us.
I'm bringing him back down to earth.
That's big of you.
I gotta go run an errand,
but I was thinking...
...you and I should get a drink tonight.
Is your wife coming?
Damn, she can't make it.
Damn, neither can I.
Since when did you get morals?
Always had them.
Sometimes I just lose track.
Really?
How's about you
lose track of them tonight?
Yeah, I don't think so.
You want me to back off?
All you gotta do is tell me it wasn't great.
You ready?
Yeah.
- Back to the barn.
- Who was that?
Guy I know.
I went through the books.
The guy I saw Mackey talking to
is a drug dealer named...
Named Rondell Robinson.
Right.
You suggesting
Mackey's working for a dealer?
I'm suggesting
he's working for Mackey.
What?
Robinson's main competition...
...is a guy named Two-Time.
Mackey's been taking out all his dealers...
...giving Robinson a monopoly.
A monopoly means
profits go up for Robinson...
...street violence goes down for Mackey.
And I want you to help me prove it.
Okay.
- Who's he?
- Moses Hernandez.
We went to SC together.
He's in Justice.
Moses, this is Terry.
It's good to meet you.
I didn't agree to be a witness
in a federal case.
The friends Mackey has,
federal's the only way we'll nail him.
I go outside the department and rat out
another cop, my life's not worth crap in LA.
He's right.
It's too dangerous.
He can't pull it off.
I didn't say I that.
I know.
I just meant you need assurances
of an upside to all this.
Such as?
Such as...
...a guarantee of a job in Justice
when it's all over.
You think I want to be an errand boy
in some Alaskan outpost?
You pick the city then.
Okay. Try the home office in DC.
I'm gonna need moving expenses.
Sure.
Plus a car and a nice big fruit basket.
I'm giving up my life,
you gotta give me something back.
I can make it happen.
Okay, no offense, I'd like it in writing today.
Let's be clear here, Terry.
We're talking about making a case...
...that puts Mackey
behind bars for a long time.
Because if we only wound him...
...his friends upstairs will crush both of us.
Yeah, I know what I have to do.
Good.
I know what I'm getting out of this.
What are you getting out of this?
I just want a dirty cop off the street.
You wanna be mayor someday, better learn
how to lie a hell of a lot better than that.
Ponyboy!
Goddamn!
Claudette! Look what you made me do.
What is all this stuff?
That? That's just a big bunch of VCRs
I stole from Circuit City.
I don't know anything about that girl.
All right? Be real.
You know me. Come on.
Why were you
at Nancy Reeborg's house yesterday?
I was looking for her old man, Lonnie.
Lonnie's not living there anymore.
- I know that.
- You ever find Lonnie?
You know Bunny Jenkins?
Said he was using at this crack house
run by a guy named Monty.
I was gonna go there after I unloaded
the VCRs, which is when you showed up.
Okay. Good.
Good?
Now let's work out
this Circuit City misunderstanding.
Claudette?
Vic?
Yeah, what?
You know a crack house run
by some guy named Monty?
Yeah, sure. It's on Crescent,
just west of 7th. Why?
I gotta pick up a smokehound there.
No, no can do.
Monty gives me dirt,
I give him safe passage.
This guy might have
something to do with the missing girl.
All right, I'll go get him myself.
The cards suck anyways.
Come on, Vic.
No, I'm gonna go.
Shut up!
Vic.
Open.
Shut up!
Lonnie Reeborg. He here?
- In there. Is there a problem?
- Show me.
Okay, Lonnie. Let's go.
Come on. Rise and shine.
You stop that.
Let's go!
What'd he do?
You got kids here.
It's Teacher Institute Day.
Where's their mom?
Buying supplies.
Jesus Christ, Monty.
You can't have kids around this place.
What am I supposed to do?
Stick them in a back room.
- Rent The Lion King.
- Someone stole the TV.
Then buy them some crayons
for Christ's sake!
Just keep them away from this shit.
Think back, Lonnie.
You killed your wife last night.
Why do you keep saying that?
'Cause that's the God's truth, son.
- You can't lie to God.
- Or the crime lab.
Her blood's all over your shirt.
I don't even got a shirt.
It's evidence now.
Where's Jenny?
Jenny?
Where is your daughter?
I went there to pick her up.
Where is she?
I needed her.
You remember killing Nancy?
You remember the knife?
I just went there for Jenny.
Think, Lonnie.
You went over there...
I said that.
to get Jenny.
She's half mine.
Nancy made you angry.
She wouldn't let me take Jenny.
You didn't mean to kill her,
she made you do it.
I didn't kill no one.
Think, Lonnie. What did you do to Nancy?
I don't feel good.
Concentrate!
What happened to Nancy?
I don't...
You gotta keep trying.
I'm trying.
I went there to get Jenny.
Yeah.
Nancy tried to stop me.
Keep going, Lonnie.
She had a knife.
What then?
I took it away from her.
What is it?
What is it, Lonnie?
I killed her.
I killed my sweet Nancy!
And where's Jenny?
What did I do that for?
'Cause you like crack?
My daughter!
I told you from the start this guy did it.
Now where is she?
I sold her.
Sold her? You sold her to who?
He gave me $200.
Who did?
This guy.
He likes girls.
How come nobody stopped me?
I don't know.
Search warrant!
George Sawyer.
Where's Jenny Reeborg?
"Sexy Schoolgirls.
"Jane at 15."
This is quite the reading list.
Where's my mother?
- It's time for her medication.
- I'll make a call.
Make sure she gets her meds.
If you wanna hold this pervert's hand,
be my guest.
Can I get you a cup of coffee?
Okay.
Who took my Ding Dongs?
Problem, Dutch Boy?
I had some Ding Dongs. They're gone now.
Ding Dongs?
What are you, in kindergarten?
Look.
I've got a suspect whose profile screams:
"Organized, humiliation-driven offender."
Which means he won't crack easy.
Which means an interrogation
that will go on all night.
Which means I need my Ding Dongs...
...and you took them. Didn't you?
Right.
'Cause I can't make it through the night
without one of your precious Ding Dongs.
Stay away from me,
and stay away from my desk.
We got an interview.
What are you all riled up about?
He took my Ding Dongs.
Come on, son. Fork over his Ding Dongs.
At my old squad,
people had respect for other people's...
Forget it!
How come everyone loves
this asshole so much?
Let's go, we've got an interview.
I think I saw some Twinkies
up in the break room.
It's not the same thing.
Here's your coffee.
When you gonna call about
my mom's pills?
In a minute.
I got nothing to hide.
I know.
Tell me something.
Think there's something wrong
with gay people?
Something wrong?
In the head, you know.
With queers, I mean,
you think they got a screw loose?
I don't know.
Not so long ago...
...medical community
classified homosexuality...
...as a disorder.
Called it an illness.
Yeah?
Now scientists think maybe it's some gene
that makes people gay.
So?
For booking.
So if God made 'em that way...
...who are we to say they're wrong
for doing the things they do?
It got me thinking.
What if scientists discovered...
...there's a gene
that predisposes some people...
...to be attracted to young girls?
You think there is? In some people?
Why not?
And if scientists discover that gene, then...
Then maybe people won't think...
...it's so wrong
to have sex with underage girls.
Maybe not.
Forgot to call about your mom's pills.
How's the car running, Miguel?
It's leaking oil.
Yeah, these old cars
always need a lot of work.
Must be a handy guy
with these tools laying around though.
No pliers though.
Miguel's not too fond of pliers.
I can't say I blame him.
Where's your lawyer, Miguel?
I don't know.
Miguel Esteana's dropping his complaint
against you.
Told you it was bogus.
I'd like your incident report
first thing tomorrow morning.
Sure. It'll be a couple of days.
I got something on the back burner.
It's not a request.
Tomorrow morning.
You'll get my report in a couple of days.
Maybe a week.
You don't like the timetable,
you take it up with Gilroy.
I don't have to.
In this building, I'm in charge.
Maybe in your own mind, amigo.
But in the real world, I don't answer to you.
Not today, not tomorrow,
not even on Cinco de Mayo.
You call for the police?
Yeah, about two and a half hours ago.
What's the problem?
What you think the problem is?
Look at my goddamn tires!
Someone slashed your tires?
Was the real police busy today?
- Any idea who might have done this?
- Lamar. He's my ex.
I see he wasn't handling
his responsibilities as a man.
I see that, I got no choice but to step in.
Did you witness
this Lamar slash your tires?
Yeah, bro. I got the whole thing on tape.
Come on, man.
The brother dumb, but he ain't stupid.
Are you gonna go arrest him?
We'll talk to him.
In the meantime, can you think of anyone
else who might have slashed your tires?
Like who?
Maybe a business associate?
Business associate?
What, you tryin' to imply something?
Nah. I'm just wondering...
...why you got a $30,000 car
with $500 tires...
...parked outside of a
$400-a-month apartment.
Give me the goddamn money for this...
You, go to work.
Dmitri. Heard you got paroled.
I see you got your old job back.
I'm just temping
for somebody who got the flu.
Hand it over.
Bankroll, too.
Come on, Mackey, man.
That's just my playing-around coin.
DMITRl: This ain't right.
Get lost.
Yes, sir.
What did I tell you last week?
No more free passes, right?
- I know.
- Let's go. Come on.
Any news on Two-Time's party?
It's definitely on
for Saturday night.
Sure?
'Cause I gotta be sure.
He called up Ringo...
...and asked for his four best girls
for Saturday night.
Guess I got left off the list.
Look like you lost some weight.
You been eating?
Sure, after business hours.
I'll give you some money. Skip a couple of
tricks, get yourself some soup.
I don't need your money, Vic.
Here. You look thin. Get some soup.
Don't worry about me, Vic.
I get by.
Where's your boy?
With my mom.
Yeah. Get him some soup, too.
- You're sweet, Vic.
- Go see your son.
I got a daughter. 14 next month.
She's got a few friends, like to come over...
...hang out, do homework,
that kind of thing.
I don't know anything
about that missing girl.
You know who Britney Spears is?
I've seen videos.
My daughter's got these friends...
...who like to dress up like Britney Spears.
Tight jeans, cutoff T-shirts.
13 years old.
She's got this one friend.
Natalie.
I'm telling you...
I know I shouldn't be thinking
what I'm thinking...
...but the way this goddamn girl looks,
I mean...
She may not be a woman yet,
but you can't call her a girl either.
You know what I'm saying?
Thirteen's a good age.
Yeah, I bet it is.
Can I get you some more coffee?
I didn't know he had a daughter.
He doesn't.
What's your take on Vic Mackey?
How do you mean?
You know what I mean.
I hear things.
But as long as he's producing on the street,
he's got friends.
Gilroy, even the chief.
So he's bulletproof?
From you, yeah.
I know what everybody here thinks.
I'm a test taker.
I didn't earn it on the street.
Came time to name a new captain,
I was the right color at the right time.
You think taking on Mackey's
gonna change people's minds?
I'm just talking.
Right now, Vic Mackey must look like
a mighty big catch to you.
Do the smart thing though, son.
Cut bait.
It doesn't bother you, the things he does?
- I don't judge other cops.
- Mackey's not a cop.
He's Al Capone with a badge.
Al Capone made money
by giving people what they wanted.
What people want these days...
...is to make it to their class
without getting mugged.
Come home from work,
see their stereo still there.
Hear about some murder in the barrio...
...find out the next day
the police caught the guy.
If having all that means some cop...
...roughs up some nigger or spic
in the ghetto...
...as far as most people are concerned...
...it's don't ask, don't tell.
How you figure on changing that?
Lamar Tilton?
Yeah?
We're investigating vandalism to a car
owned by your ex-girlfriend.
You mean the tires I slashed?
Yeah.
You admit to vandalizing the car?
Sure. Why not?
How about 'cause the car isn't yours?
I gave that skank $1,500
on her down payment.
Day after she makes the delivery,
she kicks me out...
...then gives the car to this scrawny bitch
she's been balling on the side.
- Your point being?
- My point being $1,500!
Shit.
The way I figure it,
that at least make the tires mine.
Look, you tell that bitch
if she got a problem with that...
...she know where I am.
Now this is all wrong, man.
Jewelry.
You see that new guy she's with?
Yeah, I saw him.
Then you know what kind of prick
I'm dealing with here.
So where's the love?
Bible. Galatians, chapter 7, verse 6.
"For whatsoever a man soweth,
that shall he also reap."
You can stop with the sermon, Grandma.
When I'm gettin' outta here?
As soon as you arraign and you post bail.
You got anything else?
How much bail gonna be?
$200, $300.
$200? I don't got that kind of cash.
How were you able
to afford this jewelry then?
I don't gotta explain myself to you.
Lonnie knew I liked them young.
He needed money.
Said I could do whatever I wanted...
...to his girl for $200.
When he brought her by...
...it was obvious
she was like seven, eight years old.
Was that a problem?
I told Lonnie I like 'em 12 or 13.
Like you were talking about,
developed a little.
You must have been disappointed.
Yeah, but Lonnie'd
already spent the money, so...
Even though I didn't want her,
the girl was...
...you know, she was still mine.
So you got rid of her?
I don't hurt 'em.
I like 'em to like me. Romantic-like.
Things just didn't work out this time.
What'd you do with her?
I traded her.
You traded her?
To a doctor I met on the Internet.
He likes them 7 or 8.
He came right over and picked her up.
You traded her?
I was out $200.
What'd this doctor trade you?
A girl to be named later.
You know,
like the kind of trades ball teams make.
Right.
That's a nice boat.
Thanks.
I take the kids
up to Lake Powell every year.
You know, fishing and swimming.
- Sounds great.
- Two weeks' vacation doesn't make up...
...for a year of double shifts...
...but the kids really look forward to it.
How's the meat?
Five more minutes,
you can bring out the buns.
Great.
Did you tell Matthew
he could keep a spider in his room?
That's for a school project.
If that thing gets loose...
It won't.
Yeah, it better not.
Better not.
What did I tell you about jumping in the...
They grow up too quick.
Especially with the job we got.
Yeah, what you're doing though,
has to be done.
You think?
Absolutely.
My dad was a cop.
He admired guys like you.
Those were some
honest-to-goodness men back then.
Guys like Captain Aceveda,
they never understand.
What do you expect
from a damn quota baby?
I think I could be a lot more useful to you.
You know, do more than just drive.
Yeah?
Yeah. I know why you've been reluctant
to include me.
You got a team. You watch out for
each other, know how the others will move.
You'd kill to protect each other.
It's all about trust,
otherwise, you end up dead.
Yeah.
Listen.
Up till now,
Two-Time's has been impossible to nail.
Never keeps drugs at his place
until tonight.
Yeah, what's so special about tonight?
He's gearing up for a big bash
tomorrow night.
He's got a bunch of coke
he's handing out as party favors.
Our one chance to nail him with the goods.
- Lock and load, baby.
- Yeah!
This is not gonna be
any beauty pageant, ladies.
He's got steel-enforced doors...
...so we go through a window
and be fast before he starts flushing.
Knock, knock, who's there?
Strike Team, Mr. Drug Dealer.
And on top of that,
Terry here is losing his cherry tonight.
He's coming with us.
Terry is losing his cherry.
Welcome aboard. Congratulations.
Remember, the team comes first.
We take care of each other, all right?
- Cheers.
We just have a few more questions.
- Dr. Grady.
- Right, Dr. Grady.
And I have a practice to attend to...
...patients to see, so charge me
with something or release me.
Do you know who Jenny Reeborg is?
DR. No.
George Sawyer says...
...he gave Jenny to you
for the purpose of sexual intercourse.
I don't even know the man.
You tell us where Jenny is...
...we'll get the DA to make a favorable offer.
Charge me or release me.
We'll see what we can do.
Tell me something.
As a man of science, I'd like your opinion.
Is homosexuality genetic or environment?
The latest studies suggest it's genetic.
Really? Just the way they are?
Can't help themselves, huh?
I see where you're going with this.
Don't waste my time.
Or yours.
I've got plenty of time.
I'm bored.
Charge me or release me.
This guy is definitely
a domination-control pedophile.
Is he capable of killing her?
Fits the profile.
- Let him sit for a couple hours, try again.
- Couple hours?
Girl's missing since yesterday morning.
Has she got food or water?
- I can break him by the end of the day.
- Take all week.
There's no way this pecker's gonna talk.
I know what buttons to push
with this guy.
I'm smarter than he is.
This is not a quiz show, Dutch.
Lose the ego.
Think about Jenny Reeborg.
I am. You got a better plan?
Yes.
Let him go.
- Let him go?
- We tail him.
If we lose him, first thing he'll do is
kill her, dump the body.
Look, I can break this guy.
Your way will get her killed.
So will yours!
Anywhere in here.
What about attack dogs? I hate dogs.
I need you.
And who are you?
DR. Who is he?
You know what you're doing, son?
What's in the bag?
DR. What's that stuff for?
That's what I'm gonna use to get you
to tell me where Jenny Reeborg is.
Your turn to play bad cop?
No. Good cop and bad cop left for the day.
I'm a different kind of cop.
I'm ready to see my lawyer now.
Later.
Right now it's just you and me.
People are watching us.
I got a little girl back at home.
8-year-old daughter. Her name is Cassidy.
What do you say I bring her down here?
Let you stick your dick in her.
How'd you like that?
- What?
- You know.
Suck her tits a little bit maybe?
Not interested.
So you want to have some other guy's
little girl, but not my Cassidy?
What's up with that, man?
I'd like to take a look
at this Jenny for myself.
See what she's got
that my Cassidy doesn't.
I'm sure you could arrange that.
I don't know where the girl is.
Her name is Jenny Reeborg.
I'm giving you one chance
to let me know where you're hiding her.
I'm sorry. I wish I could...
DR. You're the police!
He's got a basement apartment
under a fake name.
Jenny's there alone.
Last he knew, she was still alive.
You got something to say, Dutch boy?
Like, "Thanks for solving my case"?
Just glad I could help!
Jenny?
Watch out.
Come on, goddamn it. Come on!
It's okay, baby.
Jenny.
Jenny, you're safe now, sweetie.
You're safe now.
No way, man. I ain't got to listen to you.
Dutch.
Heard you found your missing girl.
Yeah, guy turned out to be
a domination-control sociopath.
Had her locked in this cage thing.
Good thing you took him out.
Yeah.
So what are you doing here?
Your shift was over this morning.
As I... Right?
Wickman and Greenwalt called in sick
and me and Julien worked a double.
I hate doubles.
I'm on my way home now.
Listen, I was gonna grab a beer...
...with some of my old buddies
from Sunset in case...
...you wanna tag along?
- That'd be great.
- Great.
- But I'm not free...
...tonight.
I mean, my friend Betsy set me up
on this blind date.
It's probably gonna be a nightmare and...
No, it sounds like fun.
So some other time, okay?
I'd love to go out
with you and the guys and stuff...
...and hear some of the old stories.
- What's that smell?
- What?
You don't smell that?
Oh, man. Yeah.
What is that?
It's dog shit. Jesus Christ.
All right. Whoever did this
better clean it up right now.
It's you, isn't it? You clean this up,
or I'm gonna shove it down your throat.
You got the wrong guy.
I promise you, I am not gonna rest...
...until the culprit is brought to justice.
Attention, everyone.
I'm declaring this an official crime scene.
Nobody leaves here
without providing a stool sample.
Who gets to bag the evidence?
Some prank.
Yeah.
You know,
I once heard about this old cop tradition.
Anytime someone in the squad
started getting a big head...
...some other cop
would put dog crap in his locker.
Or desk.
Remind him he's just one guy.
Part of the team.
You heard about that?
TWO-Give me that.
Get up.