Come on, homes!
Shut up!
Get up!
Want me to fuck you?
I said stay down!
I said shut up!
Stop!
Shut up!
Please.
Don't look so bad to me?
You gonna follow us?
No!
Gonna follow us? Didn't think so!
Too late.
I see you're losin' air, homes.
Have a pack on me.
So, how many were there?
Three.
Yeah, they wore bandannas and masks.
I could tell they were beaners.
How?
By the way they talked. Spanish tattoos.
Describe one.
I saw a serpent with wings.
The other one was just "L.M."
It's Los Mags. We'd better call Vic.
Matthew, what's this?
A girl.
How does she feel?
Can't you tell?
Hungry?
Maybe Daddy can help.
Daddy's hungry, too.
Maybe she's hungry. What else is she?
Happy?
Yes.
She's happy.
And this girl?
How does she feel?
Happy.
It's work.
Today's your day off.
Yeah.
All right, I'll come in.
Been another truck-jacking.
I need a break. I'm sick.
I haven't slept more than two hours...
...all week long.
I know.
Shane gets three days off
to go play in Vegas.
Shane's not in charge. I am.
The new baby-sitter starts tomorrow.
Things'll get a lot easier for you then.
When will you be home?
As soon as I can.
Cesar, tear yourself away, will ya?
One sec.
Yeah.
Newlyweds.
Giving each other matching genital rings
as wedding gifts.
-lt's a beautiful thing.
-I'll take your word for it.
Check this out.
Any idea who that tattoo belongs to?
Not my work. Lacks the detail.
Belongs to a Los Mag. Gotta be a local.
I'll make a couple of calls.
See what I can dig up for ya.
Cholo rising.
Latino. 20s.
And there's the girlfriend.
Thank you, Cesar.
Hector Estanza.
-Let's rock.
-Let's do it.
Why you gotta be so stupid?
Leave me alone.
Remember, this guy likes
to hurt people, so be ready.
Go! Freeze! Police!
What are you doing?
On the floor!
On the floor, now!
Stop!
Freeze!
Okay!
Gun!
Lem!
He's got a gun!
My God.
Shit! I thought it was a gun.
Check and see if he's got one.
Vic?
We got him!
Stay inside the house!
I don't see nothing!
Damn.
What do we do?
We just got clear.
I shot an unarmed guy.
All right. He's the jacker.
We're gonna figure out what to say.
What, he threatened us
with cigarettes, so I shot him?
Just let me think!
6-Paul-11. Shots fired.
2728 Verbano Avenue.
Suspect is down.
Requesting backup and an ambulance.
Man, Vic.
I know.
I don't like it any more than you do...
...but we can't afford
to take another hit right now.
You saw what he did to that truck driver.
Yeah. I know.
All right. Come on.
Vic?
Want to tell me what happened?
We got a sketch off the jacking victim.
It was a Los Mag banger.
My CI turned me on to Hector Estanza.
We sit on the girl he lives with--
He shows up, we go in, he runs.
The guy turns on me. He had me
dead to rights. Lem saved my ass.
As righteous as a shoot gets.
Chaco?
What did you do?
Don't worry.
Your boyfriend's gonna make it.
Boyfriend? That's my brother Chaco.
You shot the wrong guy?
We shot Hector's girlfriend's brother.
He had a carton
of stolen cancer sticks on him...
...and a gun pointed right at me.
-He's still the right guy.
-He and Hector are both Los Mags.
Probably part of the same crew.
We'll get Hector next.
-Is the girl involved?
-Not that I know of.
Lem's at the hospital getting her statement.
Boyfriend beat her up bad.
-Maybe she'll roll on him.
-Here's hoping.
Officer Lowe.
Taking back your IAD statement hurt me.
It hurt me bad.
It let Mackey off the hook.
There's clearly misconduct here.
Give me one good reason
why I should let you off the hook.
All my life, I wanted to be a cop.
I grew up in this neighborhood.
I want to make a difference here.
You could've made that difference
by taking down Vic.
I knew I got in over my head
when I first made those charges.
I'm worried you've made a pact
with Mackey.
No, sir.
I've got nothing to do with him.
I just want a fresh start, to be a good cop.
I'll prove it to you.
You'll receive an official reprimand.
I'm docking a week's pay
and putting you on probation.
I'll decide in a month
whether or not to keep you on.
Thank you.
Captain....
A new training officer might help me
with that fresh start.
You don't get to choose
who you partner with.
Neither does Officer Sofer.
Ms. Orozco?
Tigre.
-I'm Curtis.
-What do you want?
Can we talk about the Los Mags
and your brother?
My brother jumped Los Mags
three years ago. He's out.
He didn't look "out" last night.
He was protecting me from the same guy
Hector.
So Hector beat you up.
He didn't like me breaking up with him.
You ever think about pressing charges?
Yeah, like you guys can protect me.
Chaco was taking care of me until your guy
shot him and he don't even bang no more.
-You're sure about that?
-You don't want to believe me?
Ask around.
We decided
we'd better cut him loose.
Coyotes?
This time of year,
the rabbits have gone underground.
Coyotes get hungry, can't find food,
they come down to forage.
Thank you, Ranger Rick.
My grandpa had a farm.
Over here.
It's about time.
I'm moving as fast as I can.
His name is Maynard Hawkins.
Maynard....
I'm Detective Wyms.
This is Detective Wagenbach.
-Were you chained up outside all night?
-I don't want to be no trouble.
You're not the one
who's in trouble.
He's got some pretty serious bites.
Where are the paramedics?
I'll go call 'em this time.
For God's sakes,
cut him loose.
Leave me alone. I'm fine.
He's blind.
-What's goin' on?
-Who are you?
I'm Lloyd. That's my dad.
Lloyd, your father's been attacked
by coyotes.
No.
I'm sorry, Pop.
I can explain.
Save it for the station.
Daddy.
What are you doing here?
Came to see you.
What's wrong?
I just needed a good place to read.
I can't talk right now.
I've got a case and....
Dutch, my father, Bryce.
Professor Wyms, glad to finally meet you.
It's my pleasure.
Go ahead. I'll wait.
-lt could be hours.
-I'm only on page 23...
...and I imagine this is a fascinating place.
-lt is.
-Actually, it's not.
-Why don't you be the judge?
-All right.
I don't understand why I'm here.
You're in trouble.
Shouldn't you be in there
for point-counterpoint?
There is no counterpoint.
He's guilty. It's down to a matter of degree.
Elderly abuse. That's a felony.
So it's the subtle fractions of culpability
that conspire to determine that man's fate?
I like the way you talk.
You had your father tied up
outside like an animal without shelter.
-I can explain that.
-I'm listening.
I'm divorced.
Surprise me some more.
I pay alimony and child support,
and I fell behind.
State garnishes my wages, and....
I miss some payments to the nursing home
and they kicked my pop out.
Did you try to place him in another home?
It costs too much.
I'm barely scraping by as it is.
What about his benefits?
After food and $50 a month
to keep him in Depends...
...there ain't nothin' left.
So you leave him outside, chained up.
-He's blind. He wanders.
-Where's your mother?
Ran off,
left me to care for him.
I'm telling you,
it is the system that is screwing him over...
...not me.
That's so you don't wander.
Brian, thanks for the drop-by.
Travis, what a shock
to see you back here again.
It's like going to a family reunion.
I want to ask
about one of your parolees.
-Which one? I've only got about 300.
-He's a Los Mag.
That narrows it down to about 30.
His name's Chaco Orozco.
Yeah, Chaco.
That was quick.
That's because
I remember the good ones by name.
-So he's a good guy?
-I wish they were all like him.
He's not in any kind of trouble, is he?
I think we made a mistake.
Why?
I just talked to his parole officer
and his Clean Slate counselor.
"Clean Slate"?
Program for bangers who want out.
What did his counselor say?
He's been in three years,
never missed a meeting.
He counsels bangers
on how to get out of the life.
That doesn't mean he didn't
get back in. Let's not forget, he ran.
He didn't want to get caught
with Hector's stolen smokes.
So if his sister says he's clean....
What about his gang tatts?
-Tigre says he's getting them lasered off.
-Wait a minute. His sister has a name now?
Can we just talk to Chaco,
hear his side of things?
I hope to hell you're wrong, man.
You want me to pass it on to the DA?
Not yet. I'm going
to get more answers from the father.
Come on. I'll walk you out.
-Rebecca wants you to meet Warner.
-I don't want to meet Warner.
-He's her fiancé.
-She has a husband.
They come 3,000 miles from Boston,
and you won't see your own daughter?
I'm dying to see her, but it's not fair
I have to meet this new boyfriend...
...when we should be trying
to save her marriage.
She's not going to leave Warner
alone in a hotel room.
-There you go.
-Don't be so hard, Peaches.
I'm not.
Rebecca's been married to Gordon
11 months and she's giving up?
-Do you think she really tried?
-She's a big girl now.
Where'd you park?
Rebecca and Warner dropped me off
on their way to the Getty.
-I'll give you a ride back.
-Actually, I'm staying awhile.
Dutch has offered to show me around.
I'm only guilty
for trying to protect Tigre.
-Why'd you run?
-Stolen cigs.
Los Mag tatts.
I knew you wouldn't believe me.
You were right.
Not to mention the setup,
planting that gun.
That's my third strike.
They planted the gun on you?
No way.
Next time, check your
pockets before leaving the house.
-Why don't we get to what matters here?
-What's that?
What are you gonna do to protect her?
Hector finds out the cops got
his cigarettes, he'll think she called it in.
Hector's gonna want to do a lot worse
than beat her.
Where does Hector keep
his stolen merch? Who's in your crew?
I don't live that life anymore.
She needs protection.
She'll get it.
That must have hurt like a mother...
...getting that thing lasered off.
Yeah.
Worse than getting shot.
This isn't good. I believe him.
Me, too.
Christ, man, I knew it.
Third strike,
and all he cares about is his sister.
We set up the wrong guy.
-What if I'd killed him?
-You didn't.
-Yeah, but I could've.
-Man.
What did I do?
Okay, what do we do now?
I don't know.
We gotta clear this guy.
Nobody's arguing.
How do we lift the gun charge?
We'll make the gun disappear...
...sneak into the evidence room.
That place
is like Grand Central Station.
During the day.
We'll hit it tonight.
But now we put the right guy behind bars.
We'll find Hector, sit on him,
be there when he moves on his next job.
What if his next job's Tigre?
Lem, you baby-sit Tigre.
Ronnie, you're on Hector patrol with me.
We made this mess,
we're gonna clean it up.
Hang on a second.
Hello?
Where are you?
You've been gone since yesterday.
Yeah, I'm still working on this.
Matthew has been calling for you
since this morning.
-He needs you here.
-I know.
-I thought you made an arrest.
-There's more.
I need a prescription from Rite Aid.
Is the baby-sitter there?
Yes.
Well, go.
I'd have to leave her with the kids.
We hired a baby-sitter
you don't trust with the kids?
When are you coming home?
Daddy!
How will the Dodgers do this year?
I don't follow baseball.
Would it be profiling if I said,
"I bet you follow basketball"?
Actually, I heard you were a Clippers fan.
Yeah.
Two tickets.
Floor seats. I can't make it.
We gotta roll.
I'm putting together a softball team...
...to take on those beach cops
over in Venice.
I'm penciling you in.
Center fielder.
Talk to you later.
-You're here.
-As promised.
Nice bike.
Thanks.
Hope you chained it.
-You ride?
-'Cause I'm a gang chick?
I just wanted to know if you rode.
-So how does this work?
-I keep you safe until we arrest Hector.
What do you think you're doing?
I think I got it covered.
You think?
Yeah.
Ain't nobody gettin' past me.
They've got you
in the Ambassador Suite.
Who's that?
Detective Wyms.
Social Services already told me
they're taking me away.
I just wanted to know
what happened to your wife.
Mona...
...ran away.
How long ago?
Five....
Six years, maybe.
No note? No message? No good-bye?
No.
How do you know she ran away?
Lloyd told me.
What else did Lloyd tell you?
-So what kind of work do you do?
-I'm a stylist.
Hair?
Yeah.
-So you could do my hair?
-Yeah.
Cut it off and start over.
It's not that bad, is it?
Could do some things.
Maybe after we get Hector.
Maybe.
You know, you could help.
Tell me where Hector's next job's gonna be.
I don't know.
I believe your brother.
-You, I'm not so sure.
-Why?
He's not afraid of Hector, you are.
Hector's scary.
I deal with shit like Hector every day.
Trust me, he's not as scary as you think.
He says I'm his.
Man, this is fresh.
When did he do that?
Last night.
When I didn't want to let him in
with his stolen smokes.
Looks like they're scoping out
their next job.
You know, Lem's feeling pretty down.
Better than lettin' some asshole shoot me.
What the hell is this?
Lem!
-Yo. You Hector?
-Who are you?
Check out this vato here!
Why don't you shut up?
Come on!
You like that?
Police!
Give me some pavement!
That's for Tigre, asshole!
Now you stay away from her!
-Lem!
-No, man, he branded her!
You mess with me and Tigre,
and you're dead, too!
You think I'm scared of you, pussy?
Goddamn it! Back off!
That's right, bitch ass!
Goddamn it, man!
Bitch!
You should've seen what he did to her.
He needed a lesson.
They were getting ready for a job.
15 to 20 would've been a great lesson.
Sure was a nice ass-whoopin'.
That's not the point.
Our mission was
to catch Hector red-handed...
...bring him in, break him,
lock him up, and stop the jackings.
What about getting Chaco off?.
When are we gettin' that gun?
I said tonight.
Now are you protecting the sister
or just getting in my way?
You're back.
I learned some interesting things.
So did I.
You were a classical dancer
when you were a teenager?
Okay. My father is now off-limits to you.
Where is he?
-How could you not share that?
-I studied nine months.
-In Paris.
-Do your thing and stop stalking me.
It's only stalking if you work at it.
Your father just opened right up.
-What exactly is my thing?
-Dig.
On the elderly abuse case?
Elderly murder?
The son's cashing
the mother's Social Security checks.
Guess what? She's nowhere to be found.
If he's treating his father like this,
who knows what he did to the mother.
Interesting.
He's got five other kids.
I'm gonna make some calls.
One must know something
about the mother.
I'll search the databases,
see if I can sniff a trail.
And your daughter and her fiancé
will be here in a half an hour.
What?
Come in.
You wanted to see me?
Yes.
-Julien talked to you about reassignment?
-I want to talk about a different matter.
What's that?
I have a friend in administration.
I asked to see
the early results of the sergeant's exam.
Yeah?
You missed the cutoff, Danny,
by three points.
-You mean, I failed?
-Three points is nothing.
God.
Damn it, I worked hard. I studied
with Dutch. I even got a good night's sleep.
-If I didn't pass this time--
-You'll pass next time.
You expect me to take it again?
Yeah...
...and I expect you to pass it.
Goddamn it.
I used to heal Chaco
when he was still bangin'.
It feels good.
-Does it?
-Yeah.
Wish I could've been there.
Wish I could've done more.
You know, Hector needs
to be locked up, not Chaco.
And what are you doing about that?
You gotta have faith in me.
We'll see.
Tigre.
There's something that I have to tell you.
Yeah, what's that?
What?
I shot your brother.
Not the other guy?
I thought he would kill my boss.
Did you plant the gun on him?
Nobody planted a gun.
-I don't want you here!
-You need someone. Hector'll kill you.
I don't want to see your face!
You shot Chaco.
What's to stop me from shootin' you?
Nothing.
You shoot my brother,
then you try to get in my pants?
That's not.... Look, I made a mistake.
We're gonna get Chaco off. I promise you.
Come on!
I'm right here, assholes!
Punk-ass!
Cacuzza. I was lookin' for you.
I need some help.
What's up?
You live in the Valley?
You thinkin' of moving?
Yeah.
You want to be nearer to me?
Who wouldn't?
Any suggestions?
Yeah....
West Hills, where I live, is nice.
There's a West Hills
for rent on the bulletin board.
Can you take a look?
Yeah.
Thanks.
I'll lock up quick.
-Hey, Cacuzza. Sleepin' on the job again?
-I'm right here.
I know Ronnie was lookin' for you.
I see you found him.
Are you pulling a prank on me?
No. I really want to move.
Right, and a man's just as good
as a vibrator.
What are you guys up to?
Nothin'.
Okay. But I'm watching you two.
Excuse me.
This is your father we're talking about.
Thank you very much for your time then.
Every one of Maynard's kids
hopes he rots in hell.
Have no clue where the mother is.
I ran the wife's maiden name...
...got some hits in Virginia.
It's East Coast time. Call in the morning.
-Mom?
-Sweetheart.
Hello.
Mom, this is Warner.
How do you do, Warner?
I've waited a long time
to meet you, Claudette.
-Couldn't have been that long.
-I'm starving. Can we dine?
There's a diner on the corner.
Claudette loves it there.
Come on.
Warner,
how do you like Los Angeles?
It's big.
How did you meet Rebecca?
Parent-teacher conference.
She taught my nine-year-old.
She's a great teacher.
Both my boys love her.
I see.
You see what?
-Peaches.
-Don't call me that.
I'm just trying to figure out
whether he wants a wife or a baby-sitter.
I should go back to the hotel.
No, baby, I'm sorry. Just....
How can you say that?
Don't throw away your future.
-Gordon loved you.
-We had problems.
-You never gave him a chance.
-You're not giving Warner one.
You knew how I felt.
You think forcing him on me
would make a difference?
Maybe I was crazy to think you'd
want to get to know him.
I thought
you'd try to save your marriage.
At least everyone is finally talking.
Come on. Let's go to dinner.
Did you get it?
No.
Goddamn it.
Where is his sister?
Roadside Inn. It's safe.
I had to chase off two of Hector's boys.
What are we gonna do about the gun?
I doubt she'll give us
another chance.
Once it hits central storage,
that place is like Fort Knox.
How bad do you want
to make this right?
Why?
You ever wonder how
evidence gets from here to central storage?
You're gonna think I'm helpless.
No.
I was planning on making you
a surprise dinner.
I had the blender, the microwave,
the TV going...
...and the lights went black.
You overloaded the circuit.
-How do I unload it?
-Easy. There's a switch in the breaker box.
You have no idea
how to do any of this, do you?
Maybe you trip my switch?
Who's that?
Danny, hi.
-You seeing her?
-Kim? Yeah.
It's new,
but it seems to be going fairly well.
-That's great.
-Yeah, so far.
Dutch?
Excuse me.
Good for you.
What've you got?
You must feel
good right about now.
I don't know why.
Hasn't it been a little dry lately?
Only in a Death Valley kind of way.
It's good you're dating someone.
Even better, she doesn't work here.
So, there you are.
What are you doing here?
He wanted to see
how we matched fingerprints.
Shouldn't you be
trying to track down our missing mom?
I found someone
with her maiden name in Virginia Beach.
All I have to do
is check the Social Security number.
-And I'll do that now.
-Thank you.
Rebecca's leaving
tomorrow morning.
Have dinner with us tonight.
-And repeat last night's scene?
-I'll referee this time.
There's no fight if I'm not there.
I remember a brilliant scholar who chose to
go into police work against my advice.
I wasn't brilliant.
Yes, you were.
I was mortified.
You still are.
No.
I've come to understand your decision.
When I'm your age,
maybe I'll come to understand hers.
Peaches...
-...I'm 30 years older and smarter than you.
-You're not that much smarter.
Maybe a year or two.
Lowe.
Yeah.
Johnson's having
a little retirement bash next week.
He's keeping it small, but there's room
for one more. Want to go?
-No, thanks.
-You'll meet some of the top brass.
-I'm sorry.
-All right, fine.
But if something else comes up,
I'm gonna keep you in the loop.
What do you want?
You looked out for me.
I'm just trying to return the favor.
I've seen the kind of favors you do.
Let's start out on a new page.
You're not my friend...
...so stop pretending.
Hello?
Is this Mona Gaines?
Yeah.
This is Det. Claudette Wyms.
I'm a detective in Los Angeles.
What's this about?
Were you formerly Mona Hawkins?
What do you want?
Are you aware that your son is receiving
and cashing your Social Security checks?
I don't care one bit about that,
so long as they don't contact me.
Lloyd's guilty of abusing
Maynard and defrauding the government.
That's not my problem.
Don't call me back.
Guess she wasn't murdered.
One hell of a family.
What do you want, puerco?
Tell Hector Tigre's mine now.
He's got a problem with that, he can
meet me at 11:00, L.A. River at Whipple.
I'll kick all three of your asses, all right?
No cops, just us.
-Andale, it's on then, homes.
-All right, bitch.
-Don't tell me you're puttin' one there.
-I am. What do you need?
Temporary body art,
just like the one I showed you.
You're all done.
Let's do it.
Wash your hands first.
Shit!
God, please don't hurt me!
I said the green car.
You said the blue.
Now I'm saying run the tape
to the green car.
Fine.
What the hell happened here?
The police evidence van
was robbed.
Robbed?
You gotta be kiddin' me.
What'd they take?
A gun.
That's it?
Yeah, that's it.
"L.M." stands for "Los Magnificos."
Guess what? It was Chaco's gun.
Goddamn it.
He just bailed out his senorita's brother.
What are you talkin' about?
Hector Estanza, Los Mags.
The guy Lem shot, Chaco,
who's in the hospital on a weapons charge.
Without the gun, he's gonna walk.
-Did you get a good look at them?
-Just a weird tattoo on the ringleader.
What'd it look like?
A snake with wings on it.
That's Hector.
You give us the word, we'll go pick him up.
Go get him.
Hi.
Grandpa said you couldn't have dinner
with us and I wanted to say 'bye.
Still love you.
Let's just agree to disagree.
Fine.
-Where's the ladies' room?
-lt's right over there.
I'll show you.
This is not your typical police station.
Bryce was telling me
a little bit about its history.
Care for a tour?
And this
is an interrogation room.
Man.
So....
This is where you break 'em.
Suspected rapists,
murderers, child molesters.
We sit 'em all down right there.
Want to see how it feels?
Okay.
-Where's Mom and Warner?
-I don't know.
Are you aware of just how smart
my daughter is?
-Yeah. She's smart as a whip.
-She's smarter than a whip.
That's just an expression.
-I do love her, you know.
-So, it's not just your kids who love her?
If my kids hated her,
I'd have trouble deciding who to keep.
Don't make jokes
about giving up your kids.
No, ma'am, I didn't mean it like that.
She's a public schoolteacher now...
...but she's got the potential
to go much further.
She plans on getting her doctorate.
She talked about writing a book.
I want Rebecca to achieve
everything she wants.
You've got all the right answers today.
But marriage is about having
the right answers every day.
-I'm watching you, Warner.
-Like a hawk....
Ma'am.
What's up?
Go ahead!
Get on the ground, scumbag! Freeze!
Hands up! Turn around!
Get on your knees!
I gotta say, I'm a little disappointed.
He doesn't put up a fight
unless you wear a dress.
You're the vatos
that are gonna be disappointed.
Yeah? How so?
They'll let me go for no evidence.
Haven't you heard?
Heard what, esé?
You robbed a police vehicle today.
Chalé, keep dreaming.
I was at the L.A. River
waiting for that punk-ass.
Man, you must be high.
Look what we got here.
Recently fired.
Better hope it doesn't match the bullets
found in the police van that got robbed.
Yo, it's not mine, homes.
The van had your gang's tag on it.
The cop identified your tattoo.
Ballistics is gonna come back a match.
You vatos set me up!
Like a jury's never heard that one before.
On your knees.
Get down.
Have a seat.
I saw you two bickering
over police tape this afternoon.
Anything to say?
He didn't follow orders.
I'm not a mind reader.
If she'd said it, I'd have done it.
If I separate you, you'll just carry
your baggage somewhere else.
I believe in solving problems, not shuffling
them around, so let's identify the problem.
Julien?
Communication.
Trust.
Trust comes from communication.
So, how are we gonna fix this?
Department workshop?
Maybe I should set you up with
the city shrink. Any of that sound like fun?
Not really.
Nope.
Prove to me that
you can watch each other's backs...
...and then I'll trust
that you can watch another partner's back.
And don't bother me with this anymore.
So, Dutch, join us.
-I think he's got his own date tonight.
-Actually, I do.
-Thanks for showing me around.
-Thanks for telling me about Peaches.
Come on.
-So, how did it go with Warner?
-I didn't have enough to make an arrest.
Hey.
Honey?
How's Matthew today?
He kept asking where you were,
and I didn't know what to tell him.
I'm sorry.
-How'd it go with the baby-sitter?
-I fired her.
Why?
She created more work.
I had to explain everything to her...
...and she had no idea
how to handle Matthew.
He needs you. We need you.
What am I supposed to do,
quit my job?
Wanting us
to be a family doesn't make me a shrew.
Something important came up.
Something always does.
This isn't working.
-What are you talking about?
-Something has to change.
You'll receive good care
at this place, Maynard.
Where's Lloyd?
He's with us. You'll be better off.
Maynard, why do your kids
hate you so much?
I was a bastard.
-Too late to change my mind about dinner?
-Actually, I made reservations for four.
He just lost it.
You want me to believe
that Hector made that gun disappear?
The evidence points to that.
-Hector Estanza?
-Yeah.
So, Chaco goes free?
Yeah.
I have you to thank, don't I?
I'm the one who hurt your brother.
I would do anything to take that back.
Yeah, I think I could do something
with this hair.
Look....
Tigre, there's something....
We put the gun in Chaco's hands.
We thought it was Hector.
-When I found out who--
-I know.
You made it right.