One-tango-8,
in pursuit of a white, four-door...
...failing to yield, traveling eastbound,
approaching Alton.
One-tango-2,
we will be secondary in the pursuit.
Asking the Sergeant
for permission to take him out here.
One-tango-13, in the area,
paralleling the pursuit.
CHP's trying to get a tag strip here.
There's cross-traffic.
This is very dangerous.
They've stopped. He does not get hit,
goes through that intersection.
There's traffic up ahead.
He's gonna have to take
the wrong side of the road.
Julien!
Don't gun it! Too many people!
He's back on the wrong side.
There's a vehicle!
That was nearly a collision....
"Farmington Cops
Investigated for Stealing Drugs"?
I was sick when I saw that.
The Chief dunked my balls
like doughnuts in his coffee!
Do you know how this got out?
Yeah! You leaked it!
Me?
You act like a crusading cop,
bucking the system.
We're all hurt by this.
I don't know your agenda,
but no one succeeds here by being anti-cop.
I'm anti-criminal,
even if they're wearing a badge.
I must've missed that quote in the paper.
What will you do about
the Strike Team? Suspend them?
What about innocent till proven guilty?
They can't be on the streets
with these charges pending.
And we can't suspend
decorated officers without due process!
Reassign the Strike Team
to the general detective pool.
Give them different partners.
In the meantime,
I'll see if I can figure out who leaked this.
Don't bother.
You want to pack your things now,
or would you like a few days?
"Firing the One Cop Who
Cares about Cleaning Up the Department."
I wonder how the Chief
would like that headline?
You got it all figured out, don't you?
Howdy, partner.
Slumming with us ordinary detectives?
Don't get too excited. It's just temporary.
Promises, promises.
Looks like we're running together today.
Yeah.
There's traffic up ahead.
He's trying to get....
North on Hoover.
He's coming our way.
Block this intersection.
When it's clear, pull out, cross the street.
-Shouldn't I follow?
-No, you're trailing.
Pull up and over, stay parallel.
They'll tell us when to converge.
Time to converge.
What the hell am I supposed to talk to
Shane Vendrell about all day?
It's good to shake things up.
I don't want to. I want my partner back.
Aren't you sweet?
Absence makes the heart grow fonder.
You're gonna miss me, too, right?
I called it in.
Danny.
Roman, pop the trunk.
Got it.
God!
God.
Could have used a higher sunscreen.
God!
The story's worse than you said.
It's all in there.
We're screwed.
Give me till the end of today,
this whole thing goes away.
What? We'll have to make this thing go...
...away.
Heard you guys
found yourselves a crispy critter.
It's a miracle he's alive.
Must have had it coming.
You got to piss someone off
to be tortured and stuck in a trunk.
Nobody deserves that.
He was probably a rat.
Back off, Shane!
Cut it out.
Julien's not a rat.
They run in packs now?
What is your problem?
Let's not make this into a bigger mess
than it already is!
Come on.
Come on!
Lay low, man. Do your work.
Leave this thing to me.
I'm still here.
Julien.
I hear you.
You gotta help me out.
Nothing I can do.
How did that cop know about us?
I don't know.
I pulled some strings,
got you released until your court date.
-You did?
-Yeah.
I just need help with one thing first.
I'm filling out my arrest report,
and I'm a little confused.
When I busted in, it looked like
you had some cop's dick in your mouth.
That can't be right, can it?
You got something to say, say it to me.
Okay.
It's easy to make a mistake,
especially on a bust.
You think you see someone pocketing
two keys of coke instead of ammo.
-lt can be confusing.
-He's not confused about anything.
I'm not taking back my statement.
See?
And what you're saying that
he and me did, it never happened.
It never happened.
What?
Julien. Julien!
You heard him. It never happened.
-He needs me.
-Aren't you full of yourself?.
It's over.
That's not what he said!
That's what I say.
He's got a lot on his mind right now.
He doesn't need you complicating things.
Stay away.
You can't keep us apart.
I've seen your sheet.
Small time con men like you
only care about themselves.
Yeah, well, he cares about me.
You don't want me hauling you
in here all the time.
That's what you care about, so cut him off.
Man, look at this guy.
I ever get that bad,
pull the plug with both hands.
Not me.
What? You'd want that?
No, but it beats the alternative.
Just keep my machines juiced
until the Hoover Dam's out of business.
Detectives?
Dr. Crawford, how's the poor sap doing?
Third degree burns
over most of his body? He's gonna die.
Here are his things.
His skin showed traces
of red phosphorous and hydrogen chloride.
He blew himself up in a meth lab.
I see two, three of these a month.
Every bozo from here
to San Bernardino thinks he can cook crank.
Don't know what you're Boom!
Meth, courtesy of Cupid.
How lovely.
Meth's the drug of the day.
We've got a few ODs in the ER right now.
Could you take us down there for a look?
-He's tweeking.
-Third one today.
Could I see his belongings?
Over here.
May we see the patient's belongings,
please?
Thank you.
Call me if you get more.
I will.
Cupid's busy.
Looks like our mummy cooked up
some crap before blowing himself up.
Let's hope he's dumb and lazy.
No telling how much he churned out.
Got another college kid.
-How do you want to play this?
-We both have our own ways that work.
-Why don't we just take turns?
-Take turns?
We follow one lead your way,
follow the next one my way.
Your way won't land me in the papers,
will it?
-Don't believe everything you read.
-Okay. Who goes first?
Ladies go first.
All I know is the ID of the driver,
so let's start with his family.
Lead the way.
David.
Jorge.
-There's no turning back,
-I know I've burned some bridges.
Now's the time to build some new ones.
How so?
The good news...
...this headline is exactly what we needed
to brand you for the voters.
-lt came out well.
-I've decided to back you for City Council.
I was hoping that's what this was about.
Thank you.
I'd like you and Aurora
to join me for dinner tomorrow night.
Será un placer.
Bien. Bien.
You can meet the rest of your team then.
-I have a team?
-We have a lot of work ahead of us.
The neighborhood celebration
on Cinco de Mayo...
...will make a good
coming-out party for you.
Jorge?
I promise, I'm not in this to lose.
You can't afford to.
Don't believe everything you read.
You got to wonder
where they come up with this stuff.
-Anything break yet?
-Nope.
There's a crack den on Temple
due for a toss. You want to hit it?
I wish I could,
but I've got to go over some open files.
All righty, then.
Danny.
How was the sergeant's test?
I don't know. It's gonna be close.
I kind of froze a little.
I'll bet you did great.
Listen, pass or fail,
I do want to thank you for tutoring me.
Can I buy you dinner tomorrow?
Sure.
Great. Tomorrow night.
You pick the place.
-Can I help you?
-Yes. I'm looking for Detective Gannon.
I've been leaving him messages
for the last two months.
Detective Gannon retired last year.
He was investigating a case.
My husband was murdered.
Here. Have a seat.
Thank you.
I haven't heard anything in ages.
I couldn't understand
why he wasn't returning my calls.
What's your husband's name?
Kyle Kelner.
I'll pull the file.
I'll be right back.
So you lost your husband.
A year ago today.
I'm so sorry.
I don't understand.
I mean,
why would Andy run from the police?
He had a burn victim in his trunk...
...and methamphetamine in his pocket.
This doesn't make any sense.
This is from my daughter's
rubber stamp kit.
You didn't know your husband
was involved?
He's a web page designer,
not a drug dealer.
He and his friend Eric
had been looking for jobs...
...ever since the company
they worked for had gone bust.
Who's Eric?
Andy and Eric went to college together.
I tried to reach him
when I saw the chase on TV...
...but I can't get a hold of him anywhere.
I'm afraid I might know where to find Eric.
I can't even look at him like that.
It was a meth lab explosion.
What?
Meth lab?
I knew that my brother
was having money problems...
...but how was I supposed to help him?
He's the one who went to college.
Now they're asking me to end his life.
What do I do?
Look, thanks for standing up for me earlier.
That's what partners do,
even if you don't agree.
Don't agree with them?
Look, this is a brotherhood.
Everybody here knows that but you.
-You don't know what I've been through.
-You don't tell me.
Decide if you want to stay partners.
If you do, start opening up.
If you don't, talk to Aceveda.
Car's clean.
He already turned me down
when I asked him for a new partner.
Maybe he'll give you a different answer.
There's an unserved warrant.
Year-old lottery ticket.
Weight Watchers coupon.
Like that lard ass would ever use it.
He just dumped
his desk drawer into this box.
The clock ran out on this case a year ago.
I'm not shoveling the ice off the clue trail.
We owe it to her.
No, Gannon owes her.
You want me to fly solo?
No. Looks like it's the only action
I'm gonna get today.
Excuse me?
The "I lost my husband
but I'm still young and hot...
"...and need of an emotional release"
kind of sex?
You're kidding, right?
What?
You've never covered
an accident or homicide...
...and gone back a month later
for a statement?
This one's been hanging
on the vine for a year.
She is ripe.
Just give me two minutes, Fran!
She say you only last two minutes!
About as long as it'll take me
to whup your ass!
I'm telling you what!
Why you wanna go there?
Wait a minute. You guys again?
Weren't you with you,
and we busted you for slashing his tires?
Man, that was in the past!
Today you need to arrest him
for trespassing!
You got to own something
for me to trespass, welfare nigger!
My job is getting nasty with Fran.
Fran, don't do this!
We together now! What you want?
Let me talk! Give me two minutes, girl!
-You don't have two.
-Then give me one minute!
We're through, Hooper!
Fran, don't do this!
She won't give you the time of day.
Stop! He don't deserve you, girl!
Get on inside. Come on.
Come on, now! Don't do this, baby!
Querida?
I'm finishing the marketing plan.
It has to be done before I fly to Houston.
Don't think you're getting any.
Is that any way to talk
to the next City Councilman?
My God. Machado said yes?
We're having dinner
tomorrow night to meet the team.
The team? David!
I can't believe it.
Why aren't you more excited?
This is my shot.
I won't get another.
You won't need another.
Power is an aphrodisiac.
Died about 20 minutes ago. Second, so far.
Third one scrambled his brains.
And all from the same college.
We better find this stuff,
or you'll be stacking them higher.
Ambulances bring them in?
All but that one.
Who brought him?
That guy over there.
Police. You knew the OD victim?
He was rushing my frat.
I'm the Pledge Master.
This part of Rush Week?
-My father's a lawyer.
-Mine was a bricklayer. So what?
Fowler, Kaufman & Rose.
You want to talk to me, talk to them.
We are definitely doing this one my way.
Get the hell off me!
You wanted him to be your brother?
Yeah.
Kiss your brother.
Stop that!
Where'd he get the meth?
Please, no!
-Where'd he get it?
-I don't know!
Fine! Kiss your brother again!
We gave it to all the pledges!
It was supposed to be funny,
sending them to class on speed!
Jesus!
Where'd you get it from?
Effi!
Effi Montecito!
He deals to all the frats.
Good.
Now let me show you
how we haze our pledges.
Detective Gannon left a long list of TBIs.
"To be interviewed."
So we're starting from scratch.
What exactly was your husband's business?
Property management.
He owned condos, rented them out.
And he was found at a construction site?
Yeah. He and his partner Ari
were building a new complex.
Was he meeting someone?
I don't know.
I had just gotten home
from my parents' when the police called.
-I'm sorry.
-lt's okay.
-Here you go.
-Thank you.
Look, I'll get you some chips.
Thanks.
Have you talked to anyone,
like a grief counselor?
Didn't help.
I know some that are very good.
I don't know. It's already been a year.
I'm sure it feels like it was yesterday
when you got that call.
Our dealer Effi's a 25-year-old
still living in his old frat house.
-Can't seem to grow up.
-He'll grow up fast in San Quentin.
Real fast.
It'll take a few hours
to get the warrant. I'll start.
Not a problem.
I got some errands to run, anyway.
What's going on?
This IAD thing's still hanging out there.
-I told you. I'm not changing my statement.
-I'm willing to keep your secret.
-Sure, you are.
-I am!
What do you think,
I want to twist your arm?
-All you got to do is--
-Lie?
It's not a lie. You made a mistake.
We put boxes of ammo in that bag,
not bricks of coke.
I know what ammo looks like,
and blackmail, too.
It's not gonna work.
I got nothing to lose.
My guys have taken fire
from every scumbag in town.
They're going down because some rookie
thinks he saw something?
I did see something.
I'm not gonna let you destroy their lives.
So you're gonna try and destroy mine?
You're not giving me any choice.
Handing in this arrest report's
the only way I can stop you...
...from making a huge mistake.
That report doesn't prove anything.
I don't have to prove you're gay.
In this house, all I got to do is say it...
...and all the gory details.
There you go.
All right.
Vic!
I'm not sure they stole any drugs.
What?
It was dark. They were
at the other end. My view was obstructed.
You never said your view was obstructed.
It was.
You didn't see Mackey put bricks
of cocaine into a weapons bag?
I can't be positive.
You didn't see
Shane Vendrell drive off with that bag?
I don't know for sure what was in it.
-Mackey got to you.
-No.
He threatened you.
We can get him for that.
He didn't.
Then what?
Maybe I let his reputation
cloud my judgment.
Question. "Are you positive
it was two kilos of cocaine?"
Answer. "Yes. "
I'm not sure anymore.
Julien, failure to report corruption...
...and giving false testimony
are both serious offenses.
I'll accept whatever punishment I have to.
Sorry to disappoint you.
Yeah!
I told you it would go away.
-How'd you get him to back off?.
-I reasoned with the man.
You are my personal hero.
Get out.
Sure, boss. I got a big case I'm working.
-What did you do to him?
-To who?
Officer Lowe.
Nothing. Is he okay?
He changed his statement.
IAD hasn't notified me.
If anything happens to him....
Can't see why it would.
Listen, I got to run.
I'm touring a school for my kid.
Sorry your headlines got screwed up.
What now?
Look at this.
"Hoe"?
Goddamn bastard
call her that for everybody to see.
How do you know Hooper did this?
Hooper's not a very good speller.
Look it over. Sign right there.
-So he can't come within 10 feet?
-That's a restraining order.
-This complaint can justify it.
-What if he comes near me?
Then I'll make him my bitch. Now sign it.
-Sometimes I see him at the Vons.
-Vons? What Vons?
-He helps with my shopping.
-Helps you with your shopping? Hell, no!
That stops right here!
Back off. Just let her think it through.
She don't need to think.
-She needs to sign it!
-Okay.
It's all good.
So you were Kyle Kelner's
business partner.
Until he died.
Where were you on the night he died?
I told the detective last year.
I was in Phoenix on business.
Why are you just getting around
to Kyle's murder now?
Unfortunately, the file
slipped through a crack in the system.
Judging from today's newspaper,
I'm surprised any crack slips past you guys.
Those are just allegations.
Sure. Got to stick up for your own.
I understand.
He got along with everyone.
Nice, funny, a great boss, you know?
Wish I could find another one like him.
I haven't had a decent job since he died.
Must be real tough on you.
Yeah.
It's times like this when you need
someone to lean on...
...like a husband or boyfriend.
I'm single.
Our specialized care is made
to meet the needs of autistic children...
...including speech,
occupational, behavior therapies.
The facilities are really nice.
I read that if you put a kid
with other autistic kids...
...it keeps them from socializing,
sort of lowering the bar.
Some people think that...
...but we've seen that autistic children
progress best...
...in a small class
with other kids their own level.
How does this compare with the
public schools? The pilot programs?
You risk Matthew being put
in a typical class with an aide.
What's wrong with that?
Throwing him in the pool
won't teach him to swim.
Here, Matthew will be a leader,
he'll gain more confidence.
So he won't be behind anymore.
We have one spot available.
It's sure to go quickly.
$25,000 is pretty steep.
Our services aren't cheap...
...but you ask any of the parents here,
they'll tell you it's worth it.
It seems wonderful.
I know it's an important decision,
but I suggest you make it quickly.
Excuse me.
Julien.
Reverend, why are you here?
Your captain said you were struggling
with a decision and need spiritual guidance.
For some reason,
thought I might be able to help.
Come on. Police stations
make me nervous. I need a smoke.
I went back on my statement
because I'm not sure what I saw.
Why did you sign it in the first place?
I don't know.
Too eager to do the right thing?
I overreacted.
I know an overreactor when I see one.
That's not you.
What's going on, Julien?
What do you do when the man that you are
isn't the man that you want to be?
Give the man
that you are a kick in the ass.
What's stopping you?
Nothing. I'll be all right.
Only thing better than unfiltered smoke...
...unfiltered prayer.
Just you and God, no secrets...
...nothing in between.
See you Sunday?
Yeah.
Okay, come on, boys.
Of course.
You want to go in there unprotected?
Let's go, ladies. Who's up?
Are you serious?
Tim, you just volunteered.
Who's that?
Who the hell are you?
Decency police.
Let me guess, Effi Montecito?
Yeah.
You're coming with us.
What?
This one we do my way.
If you feel we have time for that.
I thought screwing sheep
went out with New Wave.
We wouldn't really make them do it.
Right.
We just wanted to see who would.
Wait, you dragged
my son here for a schoolboy prank?
Your son's here
on suspicion of drug trafficking.
What?
Dad, it's not true.
So far, three students
at Mission Cross Hospital...
...have died from your Cupid crystal meth.
That wasn't mine.
Apparently he supplies half
of fraternity row.
We have to get his latest batch
off the street before more kids die.
You're dealing drugs again?
Dad, they can't prove anything.
You're 25 years old!
Grow up, will you?
You stupid son of a bitch!
-What the hell's the matter with you?
-Stop!
Your stuff has killed somebody!
Guard!
You know
what you're doing to your family?
Go on! Let them take you!
Go on, you stupid piece of shit!
You see if I'm gonna bail you out this time!
I like doing things your way.
I told them to take the life support away.
Son, I don't mean
to be disingenuous, but I'm sorry.
What's disingenuous mean?
Means you're under arrest.
-For what?
-For shaking and baking crystal meth.
I don't know anything about that.
We talked to Effi.
He rolled on you, you roll on him.
Eric was mixing up a batch,
and it exploded...
...and he was screaming. His flesh was....
We couldn't take him to the hospital.
So you tossed him in the trunk.
Andy was gonna bury him in the desert.
He was still alive.
We thought that he would die
by the time that we got there.
Exactly how stupid are you?
You're six credits shy of graduating
for the last four years.
You're a drug dealer
who spends his free time...
...watching pledges hump sheep,
and he's the stupid one?
Any more bad crank still out there?
Only the stuff that Manny's
holding for collateral.
Who's Manny?
He's who we borrowed
the money from to start the meth lab.
When we couldn't pay right away,
he smashed up my hand...
...and he took half of the drugs as collateral.
How much is half?.
10 pounds.
There's still 10 pounds
of this shit out there?
Goddamn it.
If he hadn't of threatened us,
Eric wouldn't have rushed the last batch...
...and he would still be alive.
Who is this Manny guy?
Manny Sandoval.
Manny Sandoval skated
two murders I should have had him for.
I've wanted this bastard for a year.
If he's so bad,
how come I never heard of him?
Supercop,
you know every criminal on the street?
After we catch this guy, I will.
You want me to give you $20,000?
You can't be serious.
That's what our meth men owe this Manny.
They're both willing to wear a wire.
Nail him at the drop,
get the bad dope out of circulation.
Stop. You're under investigation
for stealing drugs.
I should give you cash?
Don't give it to Vic.
Give it to me so we can save some lives.
When do you need it?
Tomorrow.
So long as we're clear,
I'm giving the money to you.
Hi. I'm sorry to bother you.
I tried to call, but the phone's disconnected.
Yeah.
-Is everything okay?
-Yeah. I just, forgot to pay the bill.
But it'll be on in a couple of days, so....
No problem.
I need to check on one thing,
and I'll be out of your hair.
Did your husband
have business ties to Phoenix?
I don't think so.
I know Ari has family there.
Your husband's partner?
Yeah. He was visiting them
the night that Kyle was killed.
I called one of those
grief counselors you recommended.
Yeah?
Have an appointment on Tuesday.
Good. I'm glad.
-Thank you.
-Detective, do you have to....
Thanks...
...for taking care of this.
Thanks.
My pleasure.
Good night.
'Bye.
I called the Reverend Cook
because I was worried.
I know this is tough.
You shouldn't have.
I don't know what Mackey did or said...
...but I know it took fortitude
to come forward in the first place.
Where's that fortitude now?
I made a mistake.
Yes, you have...
...and I want to help you rectify it.
I don't want your help.
You should contact your PBA rep.
You're facing suspension,
probably termination.
I wish you'd gone down a different way.
We can skip the trip
to Lake Powell this year.
I can go back to work at the ER,
pick up some shifts per diem.
And spend half
the money you make on day care.
We'll lose that spot.
He'll go to school in the real world,
learn to socialize.
I want him in Glenridge.
He'll be happy there. I know it.
You know it, too.
All right. Call them tomorrow.
I'll have to pick up extra shifts.
We barely see you enough now.
What do you want from me?
I'm not mad. We just miss you.
Matthew ruined my notebook.
Let me see.
You know what?
We'll get you a new one, okay?
Why does he do stuff like that?
He never listens.
Matthew listens.
He just understands things differently.
Come here.
See how you make your letters so neat...
...get them to fit inside the lines?
Yeah.
Matthew...
...he doesn't know how to make things fit.
He needs help with that kind of stuff.
Big sister help?
Yeah. Big sister help. Come here.
Big sister help.
It'll be okay.
It's not okay. You don't deserve this.
So much for riding that headline
onto the City Council.
-You're more than just that headline.
-Not to Machado.
-When he hears that the case fell apart--
-If he backs out, what happens to your job?
Gilroy's getting squeezed.
First chance he gets,
he's gonna take it out on me.
There's got to be something you can do.
I can't think of what.
I really thought this was my shot.
I'm so sorry.
I knew twice in one day
was too much to hope for.
"Shoe"?
What are you doing here?
-I told you, I only needed two minutes.
-He bumped into me at the Vons.
Who painted that "S"?
I couldn't scrub off "hoe,"
so I figured that was the next best thing.
-Why are we here?
-Lamar slashed my tires again.
He gets jealous.
I want my name
off that restraining order...
...and put Lamar's name on there.
-That's not gonna be a problem, is it?
-You, come with me.
We hooked up at the Vons!
Apparently,
these guys will do anything for you.
They're serious,
and you're leading them on.
I am not.
Yeah, you are.
Now stop stringing them along.
Just pick one and stick with him.
It's the right thing to do.
Go to Phoenix often, Ari?
Sometimes.
Who did you meet
the night that Kyle was killed?
A business acquaintance.
Did you have dinner?
No, I got in around 9:30. We had drinks.
Did you get a chance to see your family?
Family?
No, not that trip.
9:30. So, you were on the 8:00 flight?
Exactly.
I checked the flight manifests.
Your flight flew out at 10:00.
You want to tell me something, Ari?
You did it, ass wipe! Say it!
Yes, I killed him!
I didn't plan it!
He just found out I was stealing money
from our joint account.
He accused me.
I got scared, and I just killed him.
I didn't have a plan. I didn't have an alibi.
Why didn't you guys arrest me last year?
That rocked! Man, you set him up...
...I knocked him down.
Yeah. You are great.
Don't you just once
wish you worked for Beverly Hills P.D.?
I'll bet you their wires work.
You don't like the WWII hand-me-downs?
You guys still owe me $20--
The lab exploded.
Not my problem.
You want the drugs?
30 percent.
Damn. Did he say it?
I can't hear.
Your brother blew up--
'Cause of you, son of a bitch!
Stop, you goddamn crazy kid! My eye!
He'd still be alive....
What is this, is this a bug?
You taping me, bitch? You taping me?
I'm gonna kill you.
Drop it!
Don't make me kill you!
Self-defense, man!
Crazy bastard was trying to kill me!
Paul just attacked him.
He ruined everything.
-I told you, he's stupid.
-He killed Eric!
Okay, he killed my brother!
This doesn't screw up my deal, does it?
Your informant attacks me
while working a case for you?
My lawyer will buy a new home off of this.
-You were ready to kill Paul!
-But I didn't.
-And even if I did, it was self-defense.
-Why don't we let a jury sort that out?
Some kids croaked on meth, right?
You put me behind bars,
not only won't those charges stick...
...there's a good chance
that stuff gets on the street.
You sick bastard.
Only when I have to be.
We gonna help each other out, or what?
Why would Ari kill him?
He was siphoning off money
from the business.
Kyle caught him red-handed.
He was gonna blow the whistle.
-Thank you, detectives.
-Don't mention it. It's our job.
I'll check in on you in a few weeks,
just to make sure you're doing okay.
I hope you keep that appointment.
This is a lot to take in, I know.
I thought I'd be okay,
knowing what happened.
It doesn't make it any better.
It doesn't change anything.
He's still not gonna be there
when I get home, is he?
I just don't want to be alone anymore.
Listen, Danny, I know this
is short notice, but I have to break our....
Cancel our dinner tonight.
Everything all right?
Yeah. A friend of mine's having a crisis.
It's no problem.
I'm really sorry.
I'll just work a double.
I can use the extra cash.
Great. We'll do it soon.
They swept the whole area.
Garbage cans, dumpsters,
crawl spaces, nothing.
-What about his place?
-No cupid in sight.
Ten pounds of junk is out there.
Enough to kill dozens,
and he's holding all the cards.
This might be a good time
for us to start doing things my way.
And what way would that be, exactly?
Captain. Didn't see you there.
Someone should put a bell
around your neck.
Where are we with this meth thing?
Between a rock and a hard place.
Looks like we're
gonna have to do this Manny's way.
The drugs were
right where you said they'd be.
Lucky guess.
You're welcome for the public service.
Pleasure doing business with you.
You picked the right day
to cross paths with me.
I was handcuffed.
You guys got a lot of rules.
You know something?
You might not have pulled any triggers...
...but a lot of people
are dead because of you.
You're on my radar now.
Okay.
Trust me...
...that's not a good thing.
Just have fun tonight.
They're all dying to meet you.
That's why I'm here.
It kills me, Jorge,
but this whole thing fell apart.
The key witness got cold feet.
The investigation's dead.
I wanted you to hear it from me.
That's not ideal.
But it's not disaster, either.
David, people remember the headlines.
Most times,
they don't even read past them.
-This being politics....
-Perception is reality.
Learning fast.
Don't worry about it,
I live up to my promises.
You're my man. Get used to it.
I see you at 8:00.
How'd things go with Mackey today?
Fine.
Good.
I missed you, too, okay? You happy?
It doesn't matter to me.
How was your day?
Shane wants to hit
the monster truck rally on Friday.
Got to stop meeting like this.
People are gonna talk.
Not about anything they heard from me.
Hey.
It might not feel like it...
...but you did the right thing yesterday.
I'm not gay.
-Julien, come on.
-I'm not.
It's this thing inside of me.
I push it down, it goes away...
...but then it comes back stronger.
I shove it down again,
but it just keeps on coming back...
...till I don't
have the strength to push anymore.
God.
I am so weak.
I hate this thing inside of me.
Julien.
You can't go through life
hating who you are.
I pushed away everyone...
...my partner, my reverend, Tomas.
I'm alone.
No, you're not.
You were there for me.
I'm there for you.
It is so nice
to have someone else cook dinner.
It smells incredible.
Thanks.
One of the keys is basil.
You have to add it just before it's done,
otherwise you'll cook the flavor out of it.
-We wouldn't want to do that.
-No.
Strainer?
Today has been very emotional for you.
There's a lot of delayed grief...
...pent up confusion, misplaced feelings.
I'm not gonna take advantage of that.
You wouldn't be.
Hey.
What's up?
This whole IAD thing....
I shut you out. Looks like I was wrong.
This thing confused a lot of people.
Yeah, I know. It killed my partnership.
It's not too late. He's a good kid.
Maybe he deserves a second chance.
Most of us do.
I'll see you.
Right.
Sir.
Danny.
The Strike Team's back in business,
effective tomorrow.
Did you ever have any doubt?
I did this time.
I'm tired, Vic.
I just can't keep explaining these messes
or cleaning up after them.
Ben.
I'm not gonna let myself get burned.
We're done, Vic.
I just can't have your back anymore.
I thought I owed it to you to tell you.