- How can I come up with the money?
- It's easy, Rondell. Sell drugs.
- Stop snorting your profit.
- Oh, man, don't be like that.
Hey, you gotta hook me up, Kern.
Man, you got Paula so high trying
to get laid, she couldn't even sing.
I'll make it back up to you, Kern.
I always do.
Listen, don't make me beg, brother.
Just hook me up with the 50 grand.
Since when am I a goddamn ATM?
Oh, shit!
Shit! Rondell, you all right?
- Where's this 50 grand?
- Rondell should be here.
We don't ever touch the cash
or the shipments.
- I'm not waiting around here all day.
- He'll be here.
- Thought you knew how to do this.
- We do.
Then what's with the goddamn
amateur hour?
Know how many people want
a crate through customs?
Let's set a new meet for tomorrow.
I'll drag Rondell here myself.
- We'll get this all squared away.
- Tomorrow?
I won't sit on that package.
It goes to the highest bidder.
If something comes into this
neighbourhood, it goes through me.
Guys come up with 50 grand,
you call me.
Oh, I'm gonna kill Rondell.
See, this is why I didn't show.
Bastards tried to kill me!
- Wait till I find who shot my ride.
- Good you got armour.
- Who else did you call?
- Just you. I had some product on me.
What about the 50 grand
to give to Jasper?
- I'm a little short on the 50 G's.
- Short? You don't have the money?
These guys were breaking
in my business!
- Who?
- Them bean-selling, bow tie-wearing...
...skinny-suited, Nation
of Islam terrorists.
- Same guys who shot at me!
- What?
Yeah, they been rousting my
dealers, scaring away traffic.
So yesterday, when
three of them rolled up...
...start preaching and babbling all
sorts of biblical nonsense...
...I swung on the main cat!
- He didn't even see it coming.
- So the Muslims shoot at you?
I figure they come for payback.
Why you been hanging around
me all day, then?
I didn't think they was gonna touch
you. And I don't got no armoured car.
- What?!
- Stay here till I get back.
I'm gonna go talk to them.
Which way to Mecca?
That's the one.
Police. Are you all right in there?
Entering the premises.
Step away from the door.
One Tango 13, requesting an R.A.
And additional units.
We have a possible homicide
and assault.
Roger that, One Tango 13.
R.A. And backup.
She's gone.
Clear.
They nailed his feet to the floor.
What do you want me to do?
Pull the nail out of the floor...
...without pulling it through his foot.
I'll get some towels.
Prop his feet up.
Gun!
Julien!
- Oh, God.
- Oh, Jesus.
Are you okay?
- Yeah, sister, read it.
- No, no, no.
- Excuse me, brother.
- How about you, brother?
Yeah, yeah. Right here.
- How about you, sister?
- Come on, sister.
As-salaam alaikum, my brother. May I
interest you in one of our magazines?
You wandered into the wrong
prayer group, frosty.
We're looking for Xavier Salaam.
- Xavier Salaam.
- I'm Xavier Salaam.
Formerly Xavier Chris. Spent six
years in Chino for manslaughter?
- That's right.
- I'm Detective Vic Mackey.
- We'd like a few words with you.
- I'm happy to cooperate.
I hear you had a little run-in with
Rondell Robinson the other day.
You wanna tell me about that?
I was trying to distribute my magazines
on the same corner...
...that Mr. Robinson's men were
attempting to distribute his drugs.
We fought briefly, it concluded.
- You two kissed and made up?
- There will be no retaliation.
I thought you guys were an eye
for an eye, whacking off hands.
Those are the Jews
and fundamentalist Muslims.
Nation of Islam is
an African-American way of life.
So you didn't shoot up Kern Little's
car, trying to get to Rondell?
The Nation does not murder.
You committed murder.
That was a long time ago.
And it was manslaughter.
- Why this neighbourhood?
- Because it needs cleansing.
What if I said that's my job?
I'd say you were doing it poorly.
- You can do better?
- Yes.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I guess.
Get some rest, son.
Don't bother with that one.
Thanks.
You want someone
to take you home?
- No. I'm okay.
- Okay.
Murder, torture, suicide.
Where to start?
Home invasion. Looks like
they were after the life savings.
Family bank.
Brought their distrust of institutions...
...with them from North Korea.
- Forced entry?
- No, that was us.
Neighbours said they heard
a conversation for five, 10 minutes...
...then arguing, then loud music.
- They recognise any of the voices?
- No, said they sounded young.
What a mess.
We just spoke to Xavier.
I don't get the feeling he's behind this.
- I'm telling you, they did it.
- If not them, then who?
Who else wants you out of the way?
All kinds of rival dealers are
popping up, taking away my business.
I've had shipments stolen. And now
these Muslims messing things up.
What am I paying you for?
Another dealer comes in,
I'm happy to clean up.
But there's no way I'm strong-arming
a law-abiding citizen.
- Find a way to work around it.
- So do something about these dealers.
I will. I'd be trying to come
up with the 50 grand...
...and hoping Jasper agrees
to another meeting.
I can't come up with the cash
till I got the drugs.
Well, he's not coming up with
the drugs until he's got the cash...
...which screws both of us.
So think of something!
Let's sweep up some
of these dealers.
Twist their arms till they tell you
who's running them.
Be a pleasure.
Right there, right here.
He's going, he's going.
Come here!
Where you going? Come here.
Hold on, right there.
Where you going?
Where you going, huh?
- You're Rondell's friend.
- His right-hand man.
I am.
One of your dealers broke him
and took away his Pop-Tarts.
Selling Rondell's dope while he's
out chasing a bunch of bow ties.
- That's a pretty ballsy move.
- You give me too much credit.
I guess we should just apologise,
let you go, then, huh?
- No. We gotta settle this.
- Settle what?
You say you didn't shoot
up Kern's car. We think you did.
- That's what we're gonna tell Kern.
- Not a good enemy to have.
Things gotta change.
The Nation is bad for business
and Rondell wasn't hearing it.
So you figured he'd hear about
50 slugs in the side of Kern's car?
I just know it's gonna take a smarter
man than what we got now.
And you're dumb enough
to think that smarter man is you?
Things are about to get crazy
and dangerous out there.
Well, lucky for you, you'll be sitting
safe and snug in a cage in here.
- You're expecting some kind of reward?
- We solved 23 murders with one bust.
What do we get? No bonus, no time off,
no commendation. What is that?
You broke one serial killer case.
Get off your high horse.
You think they noticed us?
Police. We're looking for Rhee-Soo.
- Rhee-Soo?
- Are you Rhee-Soo?
Is there a place where
we could talk?
It's about your father,
Young-Ho.
Young-Ho?
- Can anyone help us?
- Does anyone here speak English?
You'd better come with us.
No one here speaks English?
- I know it was rough.
- Yeah.
Don't spend too much time asking why.
Vic says if it was Dragon 10 or Flaming
Fists they would've tagged the walls.
So our killers are merely working
freelance? What a relief.
No telling how much they got.
Our victims had a checking account,
but no savings.
They'd deposit $1000 every two weeks
to write checks against.
Father owned a butcher shop
for years.
Probably squirreled away
a small fortune.
We should put out the word
for any kids blowing cash.
- What?
- I should've thought of that. Good idea.
You would have, given time.
Dae, you're here.
Could you do us a favour?
- What?
- We need to talk to this woman.
She doesn't speak English.
Can you translate for us?
- I don't speak Korean.
- Really?
I was born in Torrance.
- Dae speaks less Korean than you do.
- Better call Division for a translator.
Already done.
You feeling all right?
Yeah. Sure.
Then pick up the pace.
You're doing a 12-minute mile.
- Hello, Maureen.
- David Segovia Aceveda.
I knocked but...
A little out of your comfort zone,
aren't you?
I struggled with whether to come here
or not. A phone call didn't feel right.
- I hope I didn't catch you at a bad time.
- She interviewed me two days ago.
When you pursue a council seat,
they open up all your closets.
And I'm your biggest skeleton.
Actually, it was quite healing,
sharing what happened.
And what did you tell her happened?
The ambitious Latino pursued the rich
white girl, got her drunk, tied her up...
...subjected her to sexual acts
against her will.
He continued to stalk her obsessively
until one night she was forced...
...to fend him off with a penknife.
Am I leaving anything out?
Just the truth.
I thought maybe your hatred
for me would...
- It's been 15 years, Maureen.
- Fifteen years later, I still hurt.
- What do you want from me now?
- An apology.
- I'm sorry you felt hurt.
- An admission.
- I did nothing wrong.
- We'll let the public decide.
My friends, they know people
at this newspaper.
One phone call, the whole story
will just disappear.
Then why did you come here?
I thought we could make some sort
of peace after all this time.
Then you wasted a trip.
I have to get back to work.
What happened?
We were gathering peacefully,
then shots rang out.
How's your buddy?
He hit his head diving for cover,
but that's the only casualty.
- Lucky.
- Allah's will.
- Know who did it?
- Rondell Robinson.
- How do you know that?
- Because we saw him.
He was fast and we tried to catch him.
We couldn't, but we will.
No. I will.
You just file your police report...
...and let us handle grabbing
up Rondell.
- I have little faith in your cooperation.
- Sounds like we're working together.
We're not.
You stay out of my way.
That's easy.
We're headed in opposite directions.
My father lost his life savings.
He couldn't protect my mother.
He would've been ashamed.
He must've felt he had no choice.
We think her father knew his attackers.
They talked for a while before.
Does she have any idea
who would do this?
No idea.
We're sorry about your loss.
I'm off in there.
Leave your A game
in your cereal bowl?
Through a translator, there's
no back and forth. No rhythm.
- I say she's lying about something.
- You learn Korean in the last half-hour?
I don't tell liars by listening.
I tell them by watching.
Body language? Come on,
it's a completely different culture.
People are people, aren't they?
I'm sorry to have to tell you this.
Matthew's been wait-listed.
- Wait-listed?
- But you said we were in.
The board had to review
your application.
What's the problem?
The Glenridge families
are a very tightknit community.
The admissions board selected
a family they felt...
- The Demicellis interviewed last week...
- Last week?
I thought the deadline
was three weeks ago.
- There were special circumstances.
- What special circumstances?
Some of our trustees saw an article
in the paper.
- You and some other officers...
- My husband didn't steal those drugs.
- The charges were dropped.
- Yeah, if I really did that...
...do you think I'd still have my job?
- I'm sorry.
There are other programs that
are quite good for autistic children.
We don't want another program.
- How long is the wait list?
- Nine months, a year.
Matthew's behind already.
He's drowning socially.
I really am very sorry.
- Hey, Danny, you got a sec?
- What's up?
Linda here decided to have
a crack party in her El Camino.
That's nice.
Problem is, she likes to keep her
stash where the sun don't shine.
- You up for a strip search?
- Ask some rookie.
You're the only female uniform here.
Come with me.
- Okay, lean over.
- I got my period.
- Keep your mouth shut, please.
- Yo, my lips are sealed.
Not for long.
Put your palms on the floor.
Come on.
You don't have to touch my string.
Hey.
Who's in charge here?
- I'm the captain. Can I help you?
- We have a citizen's arrest.
They were selling crack cocaine
on the street corner.
Go ahead and book them.
I'll need your statement.
This is my statement:
We will not rest until the dealers...
...and the police who provide
them comfort are brought to justice.
Farmington has a veneer
of tranquillity...
...but the dermis is infected.
Could you be more specific
about the dermis?
Those drug dealers that we
apprehended, they might as well...
...have been wearing a sign that read,
I have no fear of being arrested.
- Really?
- I couldn't believe it. It...
It was clear that they
were just soldiers.
The captains and the general
are still at large.
Any idea who they might be?
Hey, Vic.
- What the hell are you doing here?
- Look, this is the only place safe, man.
I tried to kill them bastards,
man, but I missed.
I can't let them find me, Vic.
Vic.
You're a dealer!
You can't be coming where I work!
- They looking for me out there!
- They're looking for you in here!
You're supposed to help me, Vic.
You been telling the Muslims
I'm backing you?
What kind of good is police protection
if no one knows about it, huh?
- Go home. Stay there.
- I can't go home!
They could be waiting for me, man.
Well, go somewhere
because you ain't staying here.
If I go down, I ain't going
down alone, Vic!
- What?
- That's right. You heard me.
You better do something about it.
You better do something.
I've had my suspicions
about Rondell.
Questioned how he so easily
operated within our district.
What cops do you believe
he's in league with?
I'd rather not say at this time.
- Come on.
- Not until there's 100 percent certainty.
The wait won't be long.
Where will you be if I need
to speak with you?
In your lobby. Until we're
satisfied that this matter...
...has been settled, the Nation
is not leaving this building.
Tomas, I spoke to your legal aid guy.
Stealing CDs, look,
what were you thinking?
With your prior record,
he said you could get prison time.
Hey. Say something.
- You abandoned me.
- What?
- You never called.
- That cop told me not to call.
He tell you the same thing?
I wanted you to call.
I needed you to call.
- I'm sorry.
- It's too late now.
I'm going away.
I'm scared.
I screwed up, I know, but...
...where were you for me?
What do we know about the family
that got Matthew bumped?
Banker and his second wife, living
large. The got a house in Brentwood...
...a ranch in Telluride.
So Matthew's stuck because this
rich prick can buy his way in?
It sucks. I'm sorry.
- What about the dirt on him?
- There's nothing. Nothing.
There is nothing.
- What about Ms. Emerich?
- She's clean.
- There's gotta be something.
- She's an administrator.
- She's pristine.
- Domestic abuse, an alcoholic brother.
Give me something I can use.
The only record of her
is a police report...
...that she filed
when her house was broken into.
Well, let me see it.
Excuse us, detectives.
What? I got a million things
going on here.
A million and one.
Xavier Salaam has an interesting take
on how dealers keep managing...
...to slip through the cracks.
He's got his men out doing your job.
Salaam also thinks someone
took a shot at him.
- Rondell Robinson, to be exact.
- Still to be proven.
By five or six eyewitnesses.
Couple of uniforms went by Rondell's
house. He wasn't there.
He shouldn't be too hard
to find, though.
It'll be real interesting to hear
what Rondell has to say.
You doing okay?
You don't look so hot.
- I'm fine.
- Good.
I'll leave you to your work, then.
Maybe it's all in the family.
Rhee-Soo has a son with a rap sheet.
Think the kid went
from loitering and shoplifting...
...to strangling Grams and nailing
Grandpa's feet to the floor?
They probably had 10s of thousands
of dollars in that mattress.
Who else but a family
would know about it?
No way. Robbing the grandparents,
maybe, but nailing the feet?
You rarely see that kind
of sadism amongst family members.
Let's see your list of suspects.
Three Korean male teens just spent
a ton of cash on jewellery.
I wrote the address in English for you.
Thanks.
Hope you found your game
because I'm on mine.
Three boys. Very flashy.
Spent over 7000.
- On what?
- Chains. Men's and the woman's.
- Thank you.
- Have you seen any of these boys?
Him. He bought the biggest bracelet.
He paid for all the stuff in cash.
Probably Christmas gifts
for the rest of the family.
Do you have the cash they spent?
We need it.
- You give me different $7000?
- No. We'll give you a voucher.
- When do I get the money back?
- It's evidence in a murder.
If we retrieve the merchandise,
we'll see it's returned to you.
So I never get my jewellery
back either, right?
- Why did I even call the police?
- You're a good citizen.
Not anymore. Too expensive.
All right, ladies, backs
against the cage. No talking.
You finger yourself after
you finger me? You bitch.
Hey, watch your mouth.
Show her some respect.
Hey, relax.
Come on, ladies, your ride's here.
Move it along, single file.
I don't need you in someone's face
every time they look at me.
I'm just sticking up for you.
Yeah, like you did with that
drag queen who bit me?
What?
Mackelroy just told me about
the blanket party you guys threw.
What the hell were you thinking?
Julien, that guy is seriously hurt.
Why would you do that?
Is that who you are now?
- After what he did to you?
- Exactly. To me.
- You should've stayed out of it.
- He tried to kill you.
He's the criminal, remember, Julien?
After all the problems we had,
I thought the one thing...
...that I could count on was
the fact that you had a good heart.
Okay, boys, your turn. Let's go.
Machado and his hatchet men
had my story killed.
I'm sure there'll be more.
Like the Nation of Islam standing
in your lobby.
That'll be the second one I sell.
I left La Unidad.
I'm freelancing now.
My first sale was to the Times.
It's a piece about an ambitious
police captain...
...who uses aggressive tactics
to hurt people and squelch the truth.
Just like you did 15 years ago.
I thought you'd like
to see a first draft.
Feel free to call with any questions.
If he ain't here,
I don't know where he's hiding.
We used to come up here all the time
when we were shorties.
Yo, Rondell!
Rondell! Put the gun down,
you shithead!
- Vic!
- Yeah, and Kern!
- You two okay, man?
- You shot at me!
- Mackey, let me talk to him.
- Well, I'm done!
Vic, I didn't know it was...
- You shoot at me, you die!
- Vic, man, no!
- No! No! No!
- Chill, man. What you doing!
- No!
- Chill, Mackey. Mackey...
- You wanna join him?
- Vic!
Look at all the people
down there. That's my boy.
- We got history. Chill.
- He could've killed you and me.
- He's a problem.
- No, no!
- No! Chill, man!
- No!
No, Mackey, no! No.
Chill. Chill, man.
He won't be a problem.
I'll take him someplace...
...where these cats won't get him.
Just chill. I'm all over it!
Just chill, all right? Just chill.
Come on, man.
If he's a problem again,
you got a problem.
Next time you better grow wings.
- What are you doing?
- Getting us privacy.
- What for?
- Explain to me why it wasn't...
...the stupidest move of your life to try
to take out Kern Little with Rondell.
Rondell was telling everybody
that you and Kern had his back.
That y'all were dealing out retribution
if any harm came Rondell's way.
Let me get this straight.
After Rondell and Kern...
...you were gonna come after me?
- No way, man. You?
- I knew I could reason with.
- Start reasoning, then.
What do you wanna know?
Why are you a better dealer for me?
I don't use my own product.
Rondell does, more and more.
He's getting sloppy. This Nation of
Islam thing came on when he was high.
- How would you have handled it?
- Let them have the corner.
Move three blocks over.
Dopers follow the dope.
Pissing off the bean pie crowd
gives them a reason to live.
Throw a little bit of that peaceful
resistance right back at them, huh?
Now, if I'm done filling
out the job application...
...let's talk about how
much rent's gonna be.
Actually, 50 grand lets
you move in right away.
Good thing I've been saving.
It's a good thing.
David...
...what's wrong?
- Hang on.
Shit.
I'm sorry.
I just can't seem to focus.
- Varela interviewed Maureen Wilmore.
- Oh, God.
She still blames me
for what happened...
...and now the article
could run in the Times.
Great.
- I went to talk to Maureen.
- What? When?
- Today.
- Why?
I thought maybe
if I could convince her...
But she's sticking to her story.
- What did you expect?
- I was hoping I could reason with her.
Reason with her?
You said she was a crazy girl.
- That was 15 years ago.
- David, 15 years is nothing to a woman.
My guy at the Times says the editor
likes it, but can't confirm it'll run.
What happens if it does?
Change your name to Kennedy, move
to Massachusetts and you'll be fine.
- It's critical, but it's not fatal...
- Isn't this libel?
Technically, yes. The law
presumes a statement is false...
...unless she can prove the contrary.
You show damages, you have a case.
But the damage to you
will already be done.
- What are my options?
- You get this woman to recant.
- I already tried.
- Try again.
She wants me to admit I hurt her.
Apologise for a rape I didn't commit.
- I won't do it.
- If she's willing to make it go away...
...you give her what she wants.
Won't Varela still print the story?
Not if this woman denies it.
It's survival, David.
You wanted in the game.
Now is when it starts to get fun.
- Ms. Emerich.
- Mr. Mackey.
- Look, I understand your frustration.
- Actually, I'm here on police business.
What's that?
I understand you had a ring stolen
from your house about a month ago.
The report said it was an heirloom.
Yes, it was my mother's. I was hoping
to give it to my daughter someday.
- Can I be brutally honest with you?
- Okay.
Hollywood Division's never
gonna get your ring back.
- I figured.
- Let me explain.
The police have the resources
to solve almost any crime.
Just a matter
of making it a priority.
To them, a stolen ring
doesn't rate very high.
I guess not.
I can see it's very important to you.
Maybe there's something I can do.
Looks like they're not budging.
Guess not. Did you find the ring?
I gave your guy
a detailed description.
It hasn't passed through his pawnshop,
but he's checking around.
Guy's kind of whacked. He bet me
50 bucks he could find it in 12 hours.
- Did you take the bet?
- Oh, damn right.
Bad move. You don't know Felipe.
We know your son, Nam Yung,
has been in trouble before.
She only wants to talk to him.
- What? Why?
- Because she doesn't wanna talk to me.
Why?
- Oh, no. You tell her we don't do that.
- Dutch, whatever. As long as she talks.
Fine.
Ask if there's any ill will between
her son and her parents.
- She won't answer.
- Would you let her decide?
I'm sorry. I know she won't.
If she thinks we're prying into
her family, she'll shut down.
- So I can't even do my job now?
- Dutch, just work with it.
We're looking for Nam Yung
and his friends Kenny and Paul.
They were arrested together
in the past.
Do you have any idea
where they are now?
He stayed at Kenny's house
last night.
We talked to Kenny's mother.
She thought they were at your house.
I guess teenage lies
are pretty universal.
I never told that one before.
Detectives, there's been
another home invasion.
Our home-wreckers left
their hammers behind.
This family gave it up.
No one's talking, but whatever
they took, they took it all.
- Who called 911?
- I did.
They don't like to talk about these kind
of things in front of other people.
- What happened?
- They got all our money.
They took my Xbox.
They took the games too.
Well, did you recognise any of them?
Sure, it was my cousin
and his two buddies.
Look, I just want my Xbox back.
Graduation party. Kid's got a gun.
One Tango 13...
...requesting assistance,
8266 Alameda.
You go through the house,
I'll take the side.
Come on, stay out front. Move.
Go. Move.
Julien, wait!
One Tango 13, shots fired!
Move it!
Get back.
I'll shoot, man.
I swear, I'll shoot.
Are you deaf?
I said, I'll shoot you.
Get away from me.
- Go ahead.
- You wanna die?
- Shoot me.
- I said, I'll shoot you!
Shoot!
Julien!
Give me the gun.
- Get on the ground.
- Julien.
I got him.
Hey, you guys all right?
- Nice work, Julien.
- I'm just glad everyone's safe.
Well, it could've been bad.
Who knows, come commendation time,
maybe we'll hear your name.
Way to go.
- Yeah, you're a real hero.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- You're not wearing a vest, are you?
- I forgot to wear it today.
You holstered your weapon
at the scene.
- After the suspect was on the ground.
- I talked to the suspect.
- I made the arrest, all right?
- Did you wanna get shot?
Julien, did you wanna die?
Why? You can tell me.
I do things that can't be forgiven
and I can't stop myself.
I know.
- You have no idea.
- You're gay, okay?
I'm your partner.
I know it's not worth dying for.
- Fighting this is killing me.
- Then stop fighting.
- I would rather die than be that.
- You don't mean that.
I can't go on like this. I can't.
What's up, money?
I got the name of your shooter.
- Who?
- Tio.
- That's Rondell's dog.
- Used to be.
I'll make sure no blood
don't spill your way.
There's more.
- Rondell's out. This kid, Tio, he's in.
- What?
Rondell's been blabbing
you and me are protecting him.
That's just Rondell talking.
Well, that talk got your car shot up
and the Nation of Islam camped out...
...in my back yard trying
to make me the devil.
Rondell's using.
He could've killed us both yesterday.
He nearly messed up a relationship
that's gonna be very valuable to me.
He got one of my acts high.
Ruined the whole session.
Tio's prepared to make restitution.
I'm making the change.
Whether you wanna fight it
or not is up to you.
Me and Rondell, we grew up together,
man. We got a lot of history, son.
People change.
I don't really recognise him no more.
So, what do we do now?
Tell him it's safe to go home.
Then we let the street take care of it.
Freeze! Facedown!
Get your hands behind your back!
Get down!
- We're clear!
- Clear!
When I was a kid,
we just tipped cows.
The three of you decided
to rob your own relatives?
We just wanted what
the other kids had.
- You killed your grandmother.
- No, Kenny did that.
You didn't stop them.
They should've just told us
where the money was.
You nailed your grandfather's
feet to the floor.
Kenny did that too.
Why?
Grandfather kept following us around.
He wouldn't sit still.
- Oh, my God.
- It's beautiful.
- I can't believe you got it back.
- Just have to know where to look.
I don't know how to thank you.
You know how to thank me.
- I don't know. It's a little late.
- Special circumstances.
Look, my family will be
a great asset to this school.
You win.
- You've arrested Rondell Robinson?
- Not yet.
But he's not gonna be a problem
for you anymore.
- He was your problem, not ours.
- Well, we're both on the same side.
I doubt that.
There's nothing I can say
to you, is there?
Admit you're evil.
I'm out of here.
Sure you don't wanna wait
this out at a Best Western?
- Hell of a lot more restful.
- You get your rest, detective.
The peddlers of illegal drugs can hide,
but we know where to find you.
As long as you keep it legal,
you'll get no trouble from me.
You have a good night.
- Thank you for seeing me.
- What do you want, David?
I know you're still upset.
I understand that.
But I need you to tell the truth
about what happened that night.
You need me?
- Don't.
- Remember?
I'm married now.
- Stop it.
- You wanna save your political career?
Then I want you to say it,
say it just once.
Admit what you did to me
so I know I wasn't crazy.
Asshole.
You're recording this?
You're unbelievable.
Varela said it was the only way
to print the story.
Why are you doing this?
I was just a kid.
I wanted to explore sexually.
So what?
- That's right. You wanted to explore.
- You loved it.
Then you go tell your friends
about the crazy white bitch...
...who likes to be tied up
and choked.
- What?
- Two of them came to my room.
They held me down and raped me.
They said they heard
that I liked that.
Oh, my God.
- Who?
- Mark and Peter.
Don't tell me you don't remember.
I don't. Mark and Peter,
I barely knew them.
You knew them well enough
to tell them how to hurt me.
- Oh, Maureen.
- You sent them there to rape me.
- No, I didn't. I am so sorry...
- Don't touch me. You are responsible.
- Maureen, I am so sorry.
- Stay away from me.
You tell that slut you married
I feel sorry for her.
Maureen.
Hey.
- Something you wanna tell me?
- I love you?
Well, I love you too.
Now, how'd you do it?
Do what?
Matthew was accepted
into Glenridge.
- Really? That's great.
- Oh, please. Stop with the act.
Yesterday you were a criminal,
today she calls to set an orientation.
- Fess up.
- It could happen.
- What did you do?
- Nothing any dad wouldn't do.
Come here.
Well, thank you.
Matthew really needs this.
What about the other family?
They missed the deadline.
They broke the rules.
Don't worry. They'll be fine.
They're loaded.
You and the kids come first.
Remind me not to get
on your bad side.
Young black male, shot numerous
times at close range.
No witnesses.
Now we're talking my language.
- Don't tell me.
- Oh, yeah. I think I'm back.
Oh, God help us.
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group