The police department is ordering
you to disperse.
The men are coming under
increased attack.
It's time to pull back
or turn them loose.
I wish I knew.
Send them in.
I'm getting reports of a casualty.
Civilian. Female.
Rescue standing by outside,
affirmative.
- One Tango 13, respond.
- Connor and Adelaide.
- One Tango 13 responding.
- One Tango 19 responding also.
Hey, wait a minute. This is our call.
It's a crazy night out here.
You might need backup.
Hit the lights. Go around the park.
Don't let them beat us there.
- Keep them comfortable and calm.
- You got it.
- You mind sleeping on the couch?
- Hell, no. I've had worse.
- Cool. Just lay low until I find Gilroy.
- Okay.
- They're all asleep.
- Good.
You wanna tell me
why my children are in danger?
- They're not.
- Why are we living like refugees?
- I have to find out a few things.
- I wanna go home.
- We can't.
- Why not? What've you done?
What are you mixed up in? This doesn't
happen to other cops' families.
What are you doing that's worth
making us go into hiding?
I just need the four of you to stay here.
All right?
- We should've taken Caravelle.
- We'd still be at the park if you had.
- Guess we'll never know.
- Hey, was that a false alarm or what?
Oh, my God!
Officer down! One Tango 13!
Officer down! Rudy!
- Paula?
- He's dead.
- What?
- Up.
Come on.
- Get down!
- There's more than one of them!
Up there!
They're gone.
Paula.
- What happened?
- Someone made a bogus 911 call.
When the units responded,
they opened fire.
Thanks, Chris.
Who got hit?
Rudy's dead.
Paula's bad but has a chance. Danny
and Julien were there. They're okay.
Is this because of the dead women
who got stood up by 911?
- Yeah, looks like it.
- I want a shot at the SOB who did this.
Get in line.
Line starts here.
Hey. How you doing?
They killed him,
and Paula's really hurt.
I know.
We traced the 911 call to a cell phone.
Who's it registered to?
Police! On the ground, asshole!
- Hey, hey, hold up.
- Don't move!
Hey. All right. Nobody shoot, man!
- Where's your cell phone?
- I don't know. Maybe I lost it.
You hear about the cops
that got shot, Cyrus?
- Your cell was used to lure them there.
- I say I lost my cell.
Why don't you tell us for the third time
you got no idea how?
Don't get all surly with me.
Ain't a crime to lose your cell phone.
Hey, Dutch. You still on top
of this hit-and-run thing?
Yeah.
Any luck on the whereabouts
of our driver's girlfriend?
- You kept insisting it's a waste of time.
- What? You want me to say it?
Maybe I was wrong. What do you got?
Sedona Tellez used to work in
accounting for the department.
- What, our department?
- Yeah. Down at headquarters.
Two months into the job she's buying
up Farmington property with this...
...Cayman Island shell company.
- Did you cut through the paper trail?
All the land transactions went through
the same escrow company.
- Did you talk to them?
- Without a warrant, they won't let me.
How about letting me
take a shot at it?
Really?
I just wanna keep my fingers busy till
we find out if this guy's gonna crack.
Gilroy's not at home or his office.
The guy's a goddamn ghost.
- He's gotta be somewhere.
- Who knows where he'll be next?
Your house again? My house?
We have to find him before he finds us.
- Maybe he's hiding with the mistress.
- Oh, come on. He killed her.
- We don't know that.
- He threatened your family.
Brings up Terry dying.
He's taking his last breaths.
Will you stop making threats
and start helping me find the guy?
Now, dig in.
When did we start catching guys
by diving into financial records?
If Gilroy's gonna cash in on these
deals, he needs the girl's signature.
When we find this Sedona,
we find him.
Though I walk through
the midst of trouble...
...your hand will revive me.
- You will stretch out...
- Ready?
- Sorry.
- It's all right. I'm...
- You're shaking.
- No. I'm...
Julien, look, it's okay to be scared.
It is. I mean, you were almost
in a situation...
I almost lost my partner last night.
I'm just thankful.
Yeah, me too.
- This isn't the first phone you've lost.
- Excuse me?
I've talked to seven
wireless companies.
You've either had a phone lost or
cloned by each and every one of them.
- Always on the first of the month.
- Bill time.
You sell the phone to some grifter.
You wait a few days, report it missing.
Meanwhile, half of Union Station
is calling up Guatemala.
Or 911. That makes you
a felony accomplice.
Wait a minute, man. All I could tell you
is who I sell the phones to.
I wouldn't get mixed up
in no cop killings or nothing like that.
I mean, you guys
are the real heroes out there, right?
- Stop kissing ass and give us a name.
- His name is Igal.
- He's one of those Jews.
- Those Jews?
He's not American Jew. He's a real
Jew from Jerusalem or something.
- There's been another 911 shooting.
- What?
They got Patrick and Chris.
They're both dead.
- You see that?
- They took his badge.
Chris' too.
Jesus.
You know one of these vultures
saw something useful.
Wanna try the smoke-out?
Yeah.
Excuse me. Detective Vendrell.
Had reports someone
witnessed a crime or the perpetrator.
- What report?
- There wasn't one.
A woman was here when it
occurred. She didn't see the crime...
...but she did see another witness.
She's gonna be here in a few minutes...
...to identify you, so you may as well
come forward right now.
You, stop! Stop right there!
Stop!
Don't make me shoot you, asshole!
- All right, you start talking!
- I didn't do nothing, man.
All right. Fine.
You're not a witness, then you're
an arrest, and this is just enough...
...to make you a trafficker.
- You can't do that.
What? Bust drug dealers?
You just made my quota for the week.
- Come on!
- Okay, look, man, I'll tell you.
- You just gotta get that rock off me.
- The whole truth first.
All right, look. I heard shots, man.
I see two cops go down, then someone
go over and mess with the body.
- Who?
- There's three of them, man.
- Blacks?
- Yeah. Two brothers and a sister, man.
Now, can you take the dope with you?
Please, man. Come on, man.
Have them secure the areas
before going in.
- Our artist just finished.
- How many copies did you run?
- Five thousand.
- Make it 10.
I'll talk to my contacts on the street.
Someone's gotta know these guys.
No one talks to the press but me.
I want every off-duty officer scrambled
and in this building within 45 minutes.
Wagenbach, why are you
sitting there?
I'm working a hit-and-run.
Well, stop. We got cops bleeding in
the streets. Half the district's on fire.
There's no other case. You and
Claudette will run the investigation.
- I was handling this personally.
- Not anymore.
Are you shitting me with this?
You had command of the riot squad
and a lady got trampled to death.
The shootings last night, I stayed out
of it, and now I got two more dead.
- I can't afford your leadership now.
- We're making progress.
Not enough. If you wanna cry
to the chief, give him a call.
But do it downstairs, because
I'm taking over your office.
Pete, I need the case file,
duty roster...
...and a cup of coffee,
not too much cream.
Pete, could you wait for a minute
outside, please?
Stay close in case
I need you, though.
- What do you want, Vic?
- You threatened my family.
If I wanted to hurt them, I could've.
You kept digging into Sedona and our
land deals. I was just refocusing you.
You know what you did.
- You know what I'm gonna have to do.
- You're not doing anything.
Not now. But soon.
You think I'd take you on
without insurance?
Trust me, I got something on you.
You bastard.
You hit that kid,
come begging to me for help?
- Call me friend?
- Stop chasing after me and Sedona.
Do what you do best.
Find these cop killers.
Okay, friend?
Pete!
Get me Donald Graham
on the phone.
I wanna get some of the Southside
boys here until we catch these pricks.
That's all for now.
Gilroy's really got you spinning, huh?
I mean, blame this whole mess
on you and then yank you off it.
We get these guys, he's the hero.
Either way, you're the goat.
Guess you can kiss that City Council
seat goodbye.
- You here to pile on?
- No. I'm here to help.
What if I told you there was a way to
flip things around, make you the hero?
Maybe even put your
political career on track.
- How?
- Help me take down a dirty cop.
Gilroy diverted police units from
that part of town so crime would rise...
...and he could buy property
at a discount?
Led to the murder of those two women,
the riots, the cop shootings.
When he killed that kid
in the hit-and-run with his mistress...
...he was afraid it'd get out.
If that's true, why don't you
go upstairs and arrest him?
Because I can't prove it.
This land deal is a paper-trail
nightmare. I can't begin to crack it.
Your smarts, you could.
You're flattering me,
so this must be a setup.
It's not.
- Gilroy's bad.
- You can't get him on the hit-and-run?
He had the car fixed.
And one of the witnesses
was already killed in a gang hit.
What about the woman in the car?
Sedona Tellez.
Gilroy's mistress is the key. Find her,
she can give him up for the land deal...
...and the hit-and-run.
- Find her yourself.
- Gilroy wants me out on the street.
- And why should I do all your legwork?
Because when I find
these cop shooters...
...I'll let you bring them in.
That way you get the credit
for taking down Gilroy and them.
Sounds like a nice headline to me.
A little too nice. I don't know
what trap you've set...
I don't expect you to trust me.
But I know you're too curious...
...not to check in on it.
Trying to put AT&T
out of business, Igal?
No. I'm just trying to get by.
Each and every one of these phones
is either stolen or cloned.
I am as shocked as you are
to discover that.
I bet. Did you sell phones
to any of these kids?
- I don't know. What did they do?
- They killed three police officers...
...and put the fourth in a hospital.
- What? No.
- These are them?
- Yeah.
And they used your phones
to lure them there.
- No. This is horrible. I have no idea.
- So you did sell phones to them?
One each. Yesterday.
Please, tell me how I can help
you to catch these monsters.
- Give us the numbers of the phones.
- Of course, of course.
Now.
We were at Patrick's kid's party
weeks ago.
- I know.
- Jesus!
Let's hit south of Olympic. I'm giving
a reward to whoever ID's these three.
- How're my kids?
- Good. I rented them a PlayStation.
- Thanks.
- Hey, call Corrine. She's not thrilled.
- Okay. Call me if you find out anything.
- All right. Let's get them! Come on.
- Hey, it's me.
- When are we going home?
- I don't know. Hopefully a day or two.
- Day or two? Are you okay?
- Yes.
- Then what's going on?
I got things coming at me from every
direction. I don't need more problems.
What's happening to this family is the
problem, and you won't tell me why.
Just do nothing.
That's all I'm asking you to do. Just sit
there and do nothing. Is that so hard?
- I'm not your prisoner.
- Look, I'll tell you when it's safe.
Don't bother.
What's up, dog?
Tio! You're out early.
People's nerves are shot.
They need an escape.
Yeah, well, killing brain cells is fine.
Killing cops ain't. Let's go. Showtime.
Know anything about
these 911 shootings?
A lot of people think the cops
had it coming.
- I say we need to work with the police.
- I'm glad you feel that way.
- I need a line on these guys.
- I hear anything...
Not good enough. You're gonna
go out looking, be my eyes and ears.
Something happens,
you'll be my feet and hands too.
You'll have to get
off your corner and get involved.
- Shitheads sometimes brag about this.
- They do, we need to know.
- I'll get involved, see who's talking.
- You do that.
Yes. I wanted information on some
escrow accounts at your company.
Well, who can release
that information?
Good. Now, call him at home and tell
him that Capt. David Aceveda's...
...about to show up there
with 10 officers and a subpoena...
...if he isn't on the phone with me
in about 30 seconds.
- Yes, I'll hold.
- You got a minute, David?
- Yes, sir.
- Listen...
...I'm sorry if I was hard
on you earlier.
- Nerves get a bit raw at a time like this.
- Yes, they do.
And I know how bent up you are
about being pushed aside here...
...but I got something that might
help take the pain away.
Really?
You've always tried to warn me
about Vic.
But until recently,
I figured he meant well.
- Now I'm not so sure.
- What are you talking about?
There was a dead kid the other day.
Jesus something.
It got written down as a gang hit.
I've got a source, though,
says it was Mackey.
- What?
- I know how badly you've wanted him.
And he has a lot of friends
who don't wanna see him hang.
You're the only one
I can trust with this.
Get down!
Lock down the building!
- Hands up!
- Freeze!
Let's see some hands!
See some hands!
- Throw your weapons outside the car!
- You're just gonna kill us.
- I got a clean shot, captain.
- No. No shots until I give the word.
Copycats?
They're Latino, not blacks.
Everyone in the neighbourhood...
...feels like they can take a
free shot now.
Nice job.
That thing we were talking about.
- You interested?
- Mackey?
- Very.
- Good.
Let's talk.
Heard about some punk flashing
a cop's badge like it was a souvenir.
Talking about how he started shooting
and the cops ran like bitches.
- Know where this asshole lives?
- His old man's a heavy biter.
- All loused up.
- Great.
Dad's busy mainlining
and junior's a cop killer.
I doubt Mom's Betty Crocker.
Thanks for the fast info.
Police!
Don't move!
- Jesus Christ!
- What do you guys want?
- We're looking for your boy.
- Sonny? He ain't here.
- Where's your kid?
- I don't know.
Well, you better remember, or you're
gonna be visiting Jonestown.
In a brightly lit, cold cage.
I can get my boy down here,
but, like, what's in it for me?
I still got one vein working.
How much do you need, porcupine?
Two Tango 13, 911 call.
Woman caller reports she's dying.
8811 Lorraine.
That's three blocks from last night.
- Got yours on?
- Absolutely.
All right.
You call for the police?
In here!
Police in the house.
You got here!
What's wrong, ma'am?
Well, my daughter left
and I need to take my medicine.
- What medicine?
- For arthritis. It's over there.
You called us for your
arthritis medicine?
In the brown bottle over there.
Hand it to me.
- Ma'am, 911 is for emergencies.
- Well, this is emergency to me.
- How many?
- Two.
- What?
- Would it kill you to get me water?
Hey, boy. Where you at?
Mama's here.
Yeah. She got Jesus now.
She looks good.
She can't wait to see you.
Okay. All right, son.
He's on his way.
Yes sir...
One of the phones Igal sold just got
used to call an apartment in the Grove.
- Yes. Here we go.
- Okay, roll.
Mama?
What are you...?
Sorry, sonny. I ain't your mama.
Look what we got here.
Looks nice.
This what you used to kill my friends?
Oh, you cop-killing piece of shit!
- Who are the other shooters?
- Kiss my ass, man.
I can't tell you how much I was hoping
that's what your answer would be.
You wanna kill me, sonny?
Wanna kill me?
- Who are the other shooters?
- Dad!
- Sorry.
- What are their names?
- Benji and Twanya.
- Where can I find them?
We were gonna find some abandoned
building to squat in.
What part of town?
Near the Groves.
- Police! Search warrant!
- Hey. Hey, hey.
- Whoa, it's just us!
- We already got him.
What do we got?
- He's one of our cop killers.
- He was stabbing me with that badge.
Asshole.
You look fine to me.
I'm listening.
First you want me to shut up,
now you want me to talk?
How many personalities
you got, lady?
Walking around
pretending to be a man.
- I know what you really are.
- You don't know nothing.
I know that leg's shaking.
Why'd you do it?
Three officers dead.
How many more lives
you plan on ruining?
More the merrier.
Bang.
It is...
...everything in me...
...not to slap you silly.
- Come on.
- No freebies, girl. Now, step off.
- Screw your mother in the ass, Tio.
- Already did twice this morning, bitch.
- Tio, I need another favour.
- You're as bad as her.
- How much money you got?
- A few thou.
Give it to me. I gotta grease a few
wheels. I left my play money at home.
- Come on.
- Can't say I ain't paying my dues.
No, I can't.
Talk to every Boxcar Willie
and bag lady you see.
If our shooters are squatting,
I wanna know where.
- Looks like it'll be raining Jim Beam.
- Make it Thunderbird, it'll go farther.
I'm Sedona Tellez. I heard
there's a problem with the closing...
...on one of my properties.
- Actually, there's not.
Sedona.
I'm Capt. David Aceveda.
- Have we met before?
- No.
But I've got lots of questions.
Very nice. Quite a step up
from your place in Farmington.
I've done well lately.
Thanks to your corporation
in the Caymans.
That's quite the shell game.
If you were going to arrest me,
you would've taken me in.
Not back to my place.
Sure you don't want a drink?
How does it work,
this land scheme of yours?
I speculate real estate. It's no scheme
and it's not against the law.
Unless your boyfriend keeps police
resources from there...
...so it stays a slum,
so you could buy it cheap.
Boyfriend?
Then he pours resources back in,
cleans it up and...
...you get to sell your properties
for a killing.
Wow, I should've thought of that.
I'm sure you did.
Seems a bit complicated for Gilroy.
I don't know a Gilroy.
You worked in his office for two
months. I bet you showed him...
...how to park pension funds into your
account to make your purchases.
Yeah.
I made a few calls this afternoon.
Now, let's talk about
your boyfriend's hit-and-run.
- I understand your anger.
- You don't know me.
Your father's a heroin addict,
your mother left when you were 9.
Am I missing
any of the broad strokes?
The two women who were murdered
across the street from you.
Did you know them?
- Saw them sometimes.
- Is that what this is all about?
Revenge?
- No, no.
- What, then? Just for kicks?
Deal with it.
You murdered three of my people.
Twanya knew the women good.
They looked after her.
Benji and me figured the three of us
should do something about it.
The police didn't kill those women.
Wally Forton did.
They called 911.
- You all took an hour to show up.
- So you kill three people?
Just cops.
Just like you all killed those ladies.
I don't care how right
you think you are.
I don't care what kind of bad life
you had. What you did was wrong.
It's as wrong as it gets.
Vic, this is Sedona Tellez.
- I've been looking for you.
- I've been right here.
She has a lot of interesting things
to say about our assistant chief.
So much for loyalty, huh, lady?
Ben's in love. I have a future.
Gilroy's not the only one
she implicates.
- Meaning?
- Meaning I was wondering...
...what your trap was and now I know.
You didn't think I'd find out
about the murder?
- What murder?
- Jesus Rosales.
The witness to Gilroy's hit-and-run.
- That was a gang hit.
- Are you in a gang now?
What, is she saying I killed Jesus?
She says a cop buddy cleaned it all up
for Gilroy. I wonder who that is.
- Not me.
- You wanted me to take down Gilroy...
...before he could take you down.
You're both filthy in this.
Hey, I had nothing to do
with killing that Rosales kid.
So if I checked out your place
I wouldn't find the murder weapon.
- No way in hell.
- All right. Let's find out.
This is a search warrant
for your place.
Gilroy thinks we'll find something.
Ben...
Ben was at my house yesterday.
I thought he was there...
He must've planted the gun there.
And why would Gilroy have a murder
weapon to an unsolved gang hit?
Because he killed Jesus.
- Oh, you are just full of surprises.
- I was in the room when he did it.
I found him. If I said anything,
it would've looked liked I was in on it.
And we all know
how squeaky clean you are.
- Gilroy had you get this warrant?
- That's right.
This warrant is six hours old.
You haven't searched my house?
I talked Gilroy into letting you
catch these cop killers first.
And then we're moving on you.
Yeah.
Hold on, hold on.
Okay, I got it.
Good.
That was Lem.
They know where
the other two shooters are.
Now...
...are you gonna help
Gilroy frame me?
Or are you gonna go with me
and nail these bastards?
You sure the shooter's inside?
- Thunderbird did the trick.
- Couple squatters ID'd them.
Said the guy told them to get lost,
waved a gun around.
Good.
Now, stay close.
I know what I'm doing.
All right, ladies.
They wanna come peacefully, fine.
If not, they killed Rudy,
Patrick and Chris.
I ain't about the romance
I'm all about the finance
Hey, asshole.
One more inch and you're dead!
Now, put your hands on your head!
Okay.
Okay, it's cool. It's cool, it's cool.
Vic!
Don't! Get down on your knees!
Get down!
Hands on your head!
I'm not gonna tell you again!
- Everyone all right?
- Yeah. We got it.
Great work, David.
You got that warrant for Vic's place?
Right here.
You ready to serve it?
He caught three cop killers, cleaned
up your mess, and you can just...
...stab him in the back.
- My mess?
I practically choked
digging through the shit.
- Mackey's just covering his ass.
- The land schemes? The hit-and-run?
You gonna try laying those
at his door too?
Don't come near this, David.
Especially without any proof.
Everyone's gonna know
what you did.
Last time.
Don't play with fire.
Get out of my office.
If you won't serve this,
I'll find someone who will.
You're fired.
- Anything?
- No.
Check the den again.
- Nothing in Matthew's room.
- Check the garage.
This gun is nowhere.
- I found it!
- What?
- I found it! I found it.
- Where'd you find it?
It was in the central air vent
in Cassidy's room.
Still loaded.
Sedona!
Come on, we gotta go!
Hi, Ben.
I figured you'd be at your place.
Looking for this, right?
Sit down, you prick.
It was just some insurance, Vic.
Yeah?
You should've taken out
life insurance.
Vic, please.
You planted a murder weapon
in my house.
A loaded gun in my little girl's room.
- She wouldn't have found it.
- I found it.
- Oh, you are so over, man.
- Vic...
I'm really sorry about all this.
I mean...
...there's a way out.
- Shut up, you goddamn drunk!
Vic, just drop me and Sedona
off across the border.
We got some money. We'll disappear.
You'll never hear from me again.
I can't let you walk away
from this, Ben.
I'd be giving up my job, my life.
We got a different price tag
in mind.
Oh, yeah?
- Then kill me!
- You damn right.
Well, come on already!
Just kill me, Vic. Go ahead.
But don't act like you're
better than me.
What things have you done?
What've you done,
then covered those things up?
- I'm not like you.
- Not yet.
Not ever.
If you really believe that,
pull the goddamn trigger!
Do it, man.
Come on, it's time, man. Do it.
Well, you're such a saint.
Pull the trigger.
Look, it's all right, man.
It's all right. You two got history.
It's not easy.
Okay?
All right. Let me do it.
Let me do this for you, Vic.
Please, Vic.
Looks like it's starting to work.
Us.
Yeah.
Of course, you never ask me
about my stuff.
I'm always trying to get you to open
up, but you never pry. Why is that?
You wanna talk?
We will.
I'll wait outside,
we'll walk out together?
Sure.
Boss, went by the hotel.
Your family's gone, man.
- What?
- They're gone!
Two of the shooters have been
detained, the other is dead.
Captain, can you comment on the
arrest of Assistant Chief Ben Gilroy?
The facts will show that
Assistant Chief Gilroy chose a path...
...that led to tragic circumstances
for the city.
Corrine!
Cassidy!
It's me. I'm really tired.
I don't know where we're going, but...
I know you'll
wanna find us, but...
... if you still have love for me,
you won't try...
... for a while, anyway.
I'm sorry.
I can't comment at this time
until we have more information.
- One more follow-up question.
- There you are.
- I'm a sucker for a good show.
- Well, for us the show's over.
Husband shot his wife
because she lost his car keys.
He's already in custody. Wanna
pick up some food on the way?
Are you dragging me to that
Chinese place again?
- I got a thing for egg rolls tonight.
- You got it every night.
How about spareribs, roast beef,
anything else?
Oh, no.
Oh, that's okay. Okay.
Oh, God!
Goddamn it!
Do these arrests put you in the front-
running for the City Council elections?
In my experience, people hate being
told who to vote for. I wouldn't...
...declare me the winner quite yet. I've
enjoyed my underdog status up to now.
No...
But today's events can't hurt, right?
Let's focus on what today's events
really mean.
Three officers gave their lives
in defence of an institution...
...that their boss betrayed
for personal gain.
It's a scandal and an outrage.
The curse of corruption
has left its mark on this department.
Now we start the difficult task
of healing.
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group