You done already?
I need someone to listen to me.
- I'm busy. Maybe one of the uniforms...
- I said I need someone to listen to me.
Okay.
Did you wanna report a crime?
I've lost track of all the crimes.
- I don't understand...
- I've lived here all my life...
...keeping my complaints
to myself. But no more.
My apartment has been broken into
seven times in the last four years.
Seven times.
And you never catch anyone!
You have got graffiti and cuss words
on every single wall that you see!
I've got needles on my sidewalk,
beer cans on my lawn...
...and I stopped ducking at
the sound of gunshot years ago.
We can drop smart bombs
down chimneys half a world away.
But some sicko gets released from jail
because of a computer screwup...
...and rapes my niece.
How does this make sense?
I see yellow police tape
everywhere that I go.
And it's all sirens and helicopters
and searchlights.
You've got mothers
killing their children...
...children killing strangers, maniacs
flying airplanes into buildings...
...and I just want life to go back
to the way that it should have been.
What are you doing
to make us feel safe?
I love the action, but what
are we doing in Watts?
We got eight people dead.
Nine, if you count the foetus.
- Gang war on steroids.
- Chief doesn't like headlines.
If my ass is on the line,
I want my best man covering me.
Appreciate the compliment...
...but won't Northwest get pissed
with me and Shane on their turf?
- The lead detective is Carlos Zamora.
- Never heard of him.
He's a comer, but he's raw.
Built his reputation working with
gangs. Knows them inside out.
- He know how we work?
- Let him do his thing...
...you do your thing. I don't care,
as long as it gets cracked.
Carlos, Vic Mackey. Shane Vendrell.
- Thanks for helping.
- What gang were they in?
- "Toros". Biggest and baddest here.
- Cameras catch this guy?
Just for show.
VCRs weren't hooked up.
- Who's the mom-to-be?
- Lucy. She was Train's girl.
- Train?
- Train Guttierez. He runs the "Toros".
Well, Train's gonna
wanna retaliate bigtime.
We find who he's targeting,
we find who did this.
I'll talk to Train, make sure
his guys don't do anything stupid.
What makes you think he'll listen?
I used to be a "Toro" back in the day.
I've been able to keep
a pretty good lid on things.
Looks like the lid just got blown off.
The owner said there's
a high-school kid...
...who sweeps up at night.
Wasn't part of the body count.
- Kid call in sick?
- No. He should've been here.
Name is Jaime.
You seeing this?
- Goddamn Oprah Winfrey hour.
- Paging Dr. Phil.
No wonder Gilroy called us up.
A gang war's about to explode and he's
playing grief counsellor to the soldiers.
You gotta let me handle this, Train,
me entiendes?
He's right. We'll handle it.
I'm working this case with Carlos.
Who would wanna start a war with you?
- Things been peaceful, eh.
- Until tonight. So who was it?
- I told you, we've been handling things.
- Right.
- What's that bulge in your jacket?
- Yo, chill, dog.
Come on, man. What? What?
Concealed weapon.
- Suspicious white powder.
- Daily double.
So do I have to search all you guys,
or do I get some answers?
Is it the blacks, Chinese, "Los Mags"?
Who're we talking about?
The blacks. Wet Willie. He's been
making noise since he got paroled.
What do you know?
A clue.
Hey!
Why are you shaking down these guys?
They trust me.
- Yeah. I saw the circle jerk.
- You treat them like people, it works.
So does treating them like the killing,
dealing, thieving scumbags they are.
Mop-up boy went MIA tonight.
See if you can track him down.
- Where you going?
- Talk to Wet Willie.
I can do it. I know where
to find Wet Willie.
Hey, this might be your district,
but it's my world.
Different ZIP code, same pinheads.
Describe what you witnessed then.
Mackey put four bricks of cocaine into
evidence bags, two into weapons bags.
- Then he gave it to Shane, I think.
- You think?
You "think" is not "I'm sure." I called
IAD because you said you were sure.
- Okay.
- This is serious, Julien.
There's no point in doing
the right thing...
...if your testimony is vague.
- I know.
Now, did Mackey give Shane
the cocaine then or did it happen later?
- No, it happened then.
- Then say that.
The statement you give to Frances...
...Mackey's lawyers will twist
it into anything but the truth.
- Do I have to say this in open court?
- Hopefully not.
It won't be good publicity
for Vic or the department.
If it goes the way I've planned,
they'll take a plea.
- They'll lose their jobs?
- Oh, yeah.
Jail?
Julien.
Are you okay living with that?
What's fair for them out there
has to be fair for us in here.
"Facing Autism"? What's up with that?
That's Corrine's book.
A kid in Matthew's class
just got diagnosed.
Oh, man, that's tough.
Family must be devastated, huh?
Yeah. I had this cousin
who was retarded.
Autism isn't the same thing
as being retarded.
What is it, like "Rain Man", freaking out,
counting matchsticks kind of thing?
No. It's not the same thing.
You don't care to educate yourself,
why don't you keep your mouth shut?
Describe what you saw at that point.
Detective Mackey placed four bricks
of cocaine into two evidence bags.
He then took two bricks
and placed it into a weapons bag...
...which he immediately handed
to Detective Vendrell.
- Hey. I thought you were off today.
- I am.
- What are you doing here?
- Taking care of business.
I'm glad I caught you. I've been trying
to figure out how to handle this thing.
- And I had this idea...
- I don't wanna talk about it.
Julien, I'm your training officer.
You owe it to me to at least see if...
No offence, but I'm gonna go
my own way on this.
Okay, here's Wet Willie.
Take his buddy.
Keep him out of my way.
Go.
Wet Willie! Police! Stop!
- I said stop!
- I'll be with you in a minute.
Goddamn it! I said stop!
- You got the medicine?
- Right here.
Now, what do you want?
- What you sweating me for?
- I'm a cop. Slow down.
Slow down. Right here.
Hands behind your head.
- I didn't do nothing.
- Ever?
Or in the last 10 minutes, Kunta Kinte?
Suck my dick.
- What'd you say? Suck your what?
- Screw you.
So you've been
with your sick kid all night?
- He's been throwing up all over me.
- The mom can back you up?
My girlfriend, her sister, her friend,
the nurse at the free clinic. Man, why?
Never mind.
Suck your what? Suck your what?
- Hey. Shane!
- What's going on out there?
- Suck that, you piece of shit.
- Shane! Shane!
- What are you doing?
- Patty, call the police.
- Shane! Let's go!
- Call the police.
- What's going on out there?
- Get the licence plate!
- Are you out of your goddamn mind?
- No!
We're trying to prevent the war,
not start one, you stupid...
Goddamn.
The guy was a pain in the ass.
You're being a huge pain in the ass
lately. Should I take a piss on you?
- You're out of control.
- You want me out, say the word.
And don't think I won't!
You've gone over those things
10 times already.
He's a serial killer. Sally won't be
his last victim unless I catch him.
- You're obsessed.
- I'm dedicated. Hey, hey.
Come with me. You're too dedicated.
You need a gimme
to cleanse your palate.
- Low-priority files?
- Pick a card, any card.
What's the point of this?
We take half a day,
we make some citizen happy...
...and go back to your serial-killer
case on a winning streak.
- I don't have time for games.
- You're running in circles.
Now, I've got the cure. So pick a card.
My mother's being
robbed by a psychic.
- A psychic?
- Her name's Frida.
She's bilked my mom and her
friends out of thousands of dollars.
What's the scam? Tainted-money con,
third-party ritual, elixir machine?
She claims to talk to my dead father.
My mom took out a second
mortgage on the house...
...to pay Frida for contacting
the spirit world.
But that's supposed
to be my house someday.
- Well, that is a problem.
- I know. What are you gonna do?
- Any luck with Wet Willie?
- He's not the guy.
We better find out who is before Train
makes a guess and starts shooting.
- Got a line on our missing mop-up boy.
- Yeah?
A gangbanger friend of his called
me and told me where he is.
- A banger just called you up?
- I told you, man, these guys trust me.
Jaime's bragging he saw the shooter
come out of the gun club.
- Great. Where do I find this Jaime?
- I got this one. Wanna back me up?
Just follow my taillights.
You sure you don't want one of these?
You look awfully tense.
I just testified before IAD.
I don't get why you'd complicate
your life by narking out another cop.
Because in my life,
I take personal responsibility.
You might wanna try it sometime.
Ouch.
Skipping out on restaurant bills,
outstanding warrants.
- You don't even have a job.
- I make money here and there.
I'm a cop. I know what
"here and there" means.
If this is what you're like,
I can't be around you.
I really think you could use a beer.
When this housesitting gig ends,
you won't have a place to live.
- Oh, whatever will I do?
- I'm serious. Do you even have a plan?
When was the last time
you even applied for a job?
What's your plan? To keep pretending
you're something you're not?
- It's not that easy.
- I'll try if you'll try.
- Jaime?
- Nah, Jaime left.
Try again, smart-ass.
Finish your drinks somewhere else.
Jaime, we hear you saw
the gun-club shooter tonight.
What colours was he wearing?
Stop posing for a picture
and start yapping.
- You saw the shooter, right?
- Maybe.
- What gang was the shooter in?
- You know who the shooter runs with?
No.
You're not blind,
and you only seem half stupid...
...so I bet you got a good guess
who this guy's affiliated with.
Tell us.
- You guys ain't listening.
- What gang was the shooter in?
The white people's gang.
Our shooter is white?
- Early to mid-30s.
- Gringo with a grudge.
- There goes our gang-war theory.
- More headlines the chief won't like.
The Latino community is on edge.
Raoul Jiminez is on his way
to hear our progress.
Jiminez? He run out of janitor
strikes to organize?
What pisses you off more?
That he fights the establishment...
...or that he usually wins?
Thanks for the new partner,
by the way.
- It's a hate crime.
- We don't know what it is yet.
A white man kills eight Latinos, and
you don't know if it's a hate crime?
My people are scared.
What are the police doing?
- We got a drawing of the shooter.
- Even the artist won't vouch for that.
Our witness didn't see much
past the white skin.
Release it to the press. Maybe
someone will recognize him.
It's so vague, every Anglo on the street
is gonna look like a suspect.
- Now you know how we feel every day.
- Please. Save it for the microphones.
I think it's important the public
knows who the enemy is.
It's a waste of time, Ben.
Release the sketch.
Since when do we kowtow
to the "Mexico First" crowd?
If we don't include him,
he'll make our lives hell.
Let him try.
Have you driven around the city
lately? He's the majority now.
- We're still wearing the badges.
- Yeah, for the time being.
How is screwing up an investigation
gonna keep Jiminez off our backs?
I'm counting on you not to screw it up.
Bring in this killer and we keep
our badges another day.
- Hey, no one's taking mine away.
- We're dinosaurs, Vic.
And make no mistake,
the meteor's coming.
Your son says you're being
swindled by this psychic.
Frida's not a psychic,
she's a medium.
She predicted Gene would
go to the police, didn't she?
Yes. She said Gene was waiting for
me to die so he could get my money.
You do know these so-called
psychics are all frauds, right?
Well, most of them are, but not Frida.
She brings me messages from Frank.
- Frank?
- He was my husband. Cancer got him.
How do you think Frank would feel
if you lost the house you lived in...
...to keep paying this medium?
I'd pay anything to talk to Frank.
- Detective Mackey? I'm with...
- IAD. Yeah, I remember.
An investigation has been initiated
into your actions on April 2nd.
Look over these charges and decide
if you'd like a formal interview.
Vic. We got five people shot dead
in a family grocer's, all Latinos.
- This one's in your district.
- I'll have to get back to you.
Here they come. Secure the front.
Don't let anybody else in, okay?
- Officer.
- Detectives.
- What happened?
- Guy came in blasting.
Killed everybody in here
except the owner in back.
He heard the shots, came out with
a baseball bat and ran the shooter off.
- Where's the owner now?
- He's pretty upset. This was his son.
- My boy.
- You were back here?
- Yes.
- And you grabbed the baseball bat?
That baseball bat over there?
Now the shooter, he was white?
What happened after
you chased him out?
- He got away.
- On foot? He didn't get into a car?
- No.
- Well, which way did he run?
I don't remember.
There's blood on this bat.
Did you hit him with it?
I guess. I don't remember.
Our bad guy may have ran away,
but this being L. A...
...I'm guessing he drove here.
Check the plates on these cars. Match
them up and see what stands out.
You want me doing grunt work?
Yeah. Because, A, it's important...
...and B, I don't really feel like
hearing you talk this morning.
I got a 10-square-block
perimeter being roped off.
If he's on foot and bleeding,
we'll get him.
Oh, gee, I wonder what
took them so long.
Can I help you?
We're investigating complaints
about your business practices.
I offer a money-back guarantee
to those who are unhappy.
Very few people request it.
Six hundred dollars for a candle?
Looks like the kind I get
at the 99-cent store.
The candle itself is ordinary.
It's the blessing ceremony
that makes them so valuable.
Blessing ceremony.
What does that entail?
Taking the price tag off,
sticking it on a shelf?
We'd like you to come with us,
answer a few questions.
You yearn for a young woman
who doesn't yearn after you.
What? You see I'm not wearing a ring,
you figure a guy who shops at the...
...99-cent store is single and has the
hots for some woman out of his league.
Is now when I fork over a week's
salary for a candle, or...?
She's someone that you work with
or work close by.
Come on, let's go.
You're wasting your time
with her, you know.
Frances will ask about
the night you stole the truck.
And this'll clean the slate
on all my charges, right?
Right. So long as you tell the truth.
- So how do you want me to do it?
- Do what?
Tell my story. I mean, you're paying,
so you get to pick.
I can be all sweet and innocenty, like:
I don't know what possessed
me to steal the truck that night...
...but when I found those bags of
cocaine inside, I got so scared.
Or I can be all biker-chick,
master-thief girl.
Like: I ripped the Navigator,
was on my way to get it chopped...
...and I stumble across
these two keys of blow.
- How about sincere and honest?
- Not my best one.
- Don't get too cute with her.
- But I am cute.
- Are you involved with anyone?
- Excuse me?
Well, my most recent lover
just died of a drug overdose...
...thanks to high-octane stolen coke,
so I find myself sexually available.
If by involved you mean married with
a baby girl, then the answer is yes.
Damn. Think of the things I could get
away with if I was banging a captain.
Stay out of trouble so I don't
have to see you again.
- Oh, but you wanna see me again.
- No, I don't.
If I was 18 and single,
maybe it'd be a different story.
Oh, I would've chewed you up
and spit you out when you were 18.
I wouldn't be so sure.
The other shop owners
tell the same story.
They heard gunshots,
but didn't see anything.
Nobody looked out and saw
which way this guy went running?
- That's what they say.
- That doesn't pass the smell test.
Vic!
This is the only car whose owner
is unaccounted for.
Check it out.
- Spare ammo.
- Who's the car registered to?
- A George Michael Klassen.
- Nice to meet you, you sick prick.
All clear.
Oh, goddamn it.
As I was going through the truck,
I found...
...some guns and two bags of cocaine.
Okay, let's go back
to stealing the vehicle.
You saw Detective Vendrell
park the truck, get out...
...and go inside the building.
-Yes, ma'am.
And no one went in or out of the truck
between the time...
...he left it and the time you stole it.
No, ma'am.
It's always sad when the people
that you expect to enforce the law...
...break it themselves.
Canvass the place. Find out
if anybody saw a car pulling out.
We found two bodies inside.
They're George's in-laws.
- Oh, my God.
- But his wife and son, they're not here.
We're afraid George might have
taken them with him.
Any idea where your brother
might have gone?
No.
Any place he might feel
comfortable hiding?
- No.
- This is important.
We have to find him before
he does any harm to them.
Well, I can't imagine George
would ever hurt Myra or Brady.
Can you imagine him killing
15 people in cold blood?
Well, that's different.
I mean, you have to understand.
This used to be a nice place to live.
Clean, safe.
George just got fed up being
surrounded by all the spics.
Can you blame him?
Klassen's picture's plastered
all over the news.
He can't step outside without
somebody spotting him.
That doesn't help us save
his wife and boy.
I'm more concerned about what
you're doing to stop the next attack.
Everything we can.
We know who he is. We got his car.
We got units on his family and
friends. We got every base covered.
Waiting around for him to make
his next move isn't gonna cut it.
Where you going?
Hey, as long as he's got it all covered,
I'm gonna go check on something.
Getting a nice tan?
About all I'm good for, I guess.
- You find any blood out here?
- Nope.
So there was blood on the bat
and nowhere else?
There's some blood in the store
unconnected to any of the victims.
Show me.
Shooter loses this much blood and
doesn't drip any on the pavement?
Maybe he went out the back.
- SID check it?
- Beats me.
Looks like somebody did
a nice little sweep job.
Yes, it does. Makes you wonder why.
You know, Houdini wanted desperately
to believe in the paranormal.
Couldn't abide the fakes and frauds.
Spent his life trying to debunk them.
Still held out hope, though.
Before he died, he gave his wife
Beatrice a secret password...
...that he promised her he'd try
to send her from the afterworld...
...so she could tell the difference
between phoneys and the real McCoys.
When he passed away,
Beatrice travelled the globe...
...met with every gypsy, psychic,
tarot-card reader she could find.
Not one of them
ever got the password right.
Houdini should have
had a little more faith.
- Faith?
- On Sundays they call it Christianity.
The afterlife's no different.
Church only takes you for 10 percent.
You've been wringing these ladies dry.
If they refuse to press charges,
you can't touch me.
If I find out you still have your hooks
in these women...
...I'll find other charges to press.
- Fire code violations.
- Parking tickets.
Zoning laws. You name it, I'll find it.
How's your future looking now?
What do you want from me?
It's time to get some new marks, honey.
What the hell is he doing?
- You arrested the shop owners?
- Brought them in for questioning.
- Why?
- Their stories didn't make sense.
Leon's son died four hours ago. How
much sense is he supposed to make?
If he knows something, we need it.
You don't interrogate a grieving father!
And you don't get answers from
people by passing around hugs.
You don't get them
by pissing on people either.
We've got a racist madman
targeting Latinos...
...and you want to interrogate
the victim's family?!
When you trade your megaphone for a
badge, that's when I'll seek your input.
I insist on witnessing the interviews...
...to ensure these men and women
aren't mistreated.
- No.
- Excuse me?
I've included you as a courtesy.
It's time to give my men
the space to do their jobs.
His wife and 10-year-old son
are missing.
- My son's dead.
- You're not telling me the truth, Leon.
- Yes, I am.
- You know something.
No.
If you're lying so you can get to your
son's killer before us to get revenge...
...I can't let that happen.
- I don't know anything.
Then why are you and the other shop
owners all telling the same lie?
And why did someone sweep the path
in the back alley after the shootings?
Leon?
You can tell me.
What did you really see?
"Nada". I didn't see nothing.
I just talked with Frances. You've got
her looking into the Strike Team again?
Yes.
You ever plan on telling me about it?
I didn't wanna bother you with it
until things were more definitive.
I got a problem in this squad, David.
My captain and my best cop
aren't getting along.
We stand for different things.
Well, you better make friends,
or I'm gonna have to make a choice.
And I don't think
you're gonna like that choice.
Maybe you should read this
before you make any choices.
You're gonna need a signature
on this here...
I've been getting some very strong
signals at this desk.
Gee, the desk that
I work at? Spooky.
I'm getting an S name.
Is there a Sarah?
Sorry, no Sarahs.
Or a Sally.
I think there's a Sally.
Do you know who I'm talking about?
You going through my desk?
Reading my file on Sally?
No, I didn't.
Frida! There you are!
- Are you all right?
- Fine.
Yeah. Let's all talk in another room.
Follow me.
She has a message for you.
There's an innocent woman and
an innocent kid in danger out there...
...and you're not telling me the truth!
- Yes, I am!
Someone's holding a gun
to their heads right now...
...and you're stopping me
from finding them.
I'm not.
You might as well be pulling
the trigger. Tell me the truth!
- I am!
- He doesn't know anything.
Yes, he does.
- You gonna pull the trigger on that kid?
- Vic!
What does that make you?
- What if it was your boy?
- My boy's dead.
That's because I couldn't stop the
racist pig from pulling that trigger.
Don't be like the man
who killed your son.
- I'm nothing like him.
- Then show me. Show me.
I heard the shots...
...the shots that killed Favian.
When I came outside, the man
was standing there with his...
With his back to me.
I hit him with a baseball bat.
Knocked him out.
What did you do with him?
My friends heard the noise.
They came over.
They dragged him out the back.
That's why we swept up afterwards.
- What did you do with him?
- He killed my boy.
- I know.
- So I wanted to kill him back.
I know.
I couldn't do it, though.
I didn't have the courage.
So, what did you do with him?
We gave him to the "Toros".
I couldn't kill him...
...but I knew they would.
Oh, shit. The in-laws were killed
after the grocery shootings.
- So Train or his guys killed them.
- They got the wife and kid.
God help you.
Look out! Heads up!
- Where's Train?
- Get him off me!
I can't do that, Lucas.
You went too far. What did you do?
- He had it coming.
- Did the wife and kid have it coming?
- We were making things better.
- We didn't start the killing.
Where's Train keeping his family?
You wanna tell me
with your teeth or without?
He's not gonna let you
beat me down. He's one of us.
Not after what you did. Now, where
do we find this guy's wife and kid?
You didn't see this coming.
You didn't see this.
- Please don't hurt him.
- What? What? You wanna kiss me?
Please, don't.
We'll do anything you want. Just... No.
- Let go. Please. George!
- Don't touch my mom!
Brady! No!
- Train! Don't do this, Train!
- Put it down!
- For Lucy.
- No!
He had to pay.
And who's gonna pay now?
Who's gonna pay?
We all pay, man.
He's gonna pay for the rest of his life.
You don't want to. Trust me.
It's okay. You're all right.
We've gotta get Vic Mackey
off the streets.
- Have you taken his statement yet?
- No.
- But you have to admit, it looks bad.
- Very bad.
We need to keep this thing
under control.
How can we?
The chief is gonna have a heart attack
when he hears about this.
If the press gets ahold of it...
Goddamn it.
This is the last thing I needed.
I'll talk to my people, make sure
there are no leaks on this end.
Yeah, me too.
Okay. Good.
I just need a few days to figure out
how to handle this.
- What's going to happen to them?
- What do you think?
They handed a man over
to gangbangers to be killed.
They handed over a hatemonger.
Their actions led to three people
being killed.
And a woman being sexually assaulted
in front of her 10-year-old son.
- They couldn't have foreseen that.
- They conspired to kill a man...
...and then tried to cover it up.
They're victims. My group won't let
this department turn them into martyrs.
I thought martyrs
are what brought in the donations...
...and got your name in the papers.
I'll see they don't spend
one day in jail.
They probably won't.
I should get going.
Can I give you a lift?
No, I got one.
Thanks for the offer, though.
Offer's always good.
Sir, do you have a minute?
Sorry. I missed dinner.
What can I do for you?
I don't think that Julien and I are
turning out to be a good match.
- Really?
- I just think he might be better off...
...with a different training officer.
Finnegan's not riding with anyone.
- I could take the next candidate.
- Julien's going through a tough time.
He needs you now more than ever.
You're as good as we have.
You'll work things out.
- How could you do this?
- It was a mistake.
We were gonna use the coke
for an undercover bust.
I didn't do the paperwork.
When it got stolen with the truck...
- Is that what you plan on telling IAD?
- Come on, what do they have?
- A car thief as a witness? Please.
- She's convincing.
Plus, there's the officer who saw you
take the stuff in the first place.
They've established chain of custody.
From you to the truck to the OD victim.
Shane was the one in possession
of the drugs.
- He's the one that got the truck stolen.
- Ben, no!
I don't have the juice anymore
to protect all of you.
Shane had the drugs.
We lay it all on his doorstep.
It's either that or you two
can share a cell.
You don't have to like it,
but it's time to serve him up.
- I was just about to close.
- What was Sally's message?
- She says not to give up.
- I haven't.
She says you're the only one
still fighting for her.
What else did she say?
You have something for me?
An IAD file of a current investigation
my people are trying to cover up.
Dirty cops? Why give it to me?
You'll see it gets the publicity
it deserves.
And if you leak it to the press,
it'd look self-serving.
You want it or not?
Of course.
Don't worry, David. I'll make sure
they spell your name right.
That's my book.
The reason I have it is because
Matthew has autism.
- We found out a few weeks ago.
- Oh, Jesus.
- Oh, Vic. Vic, I'm sorry.
- It's been tough. Lot of work.
You know, the one thing
I've learned is...
...I goddamn love that kid
more now than ever.
Hey, he's got problems, you know...
...but I'm never giving up on him.
I'm not giving up on you either, Shane.
I'm gonna have to get a little creative
on this "past job experience" section.
Creative's cool. Just don't lie.
Though I might need a few glasses
of wine to get that creative.
Let me just skip on down here to the...
What's this? References. References.
It wouldn't hurt to have a glowing one
from a respected city police officer.
- What, you're not gonna help me out?
- I can't.
Unbelievable.
Good enough to suck,
but not good enough to vouch for.
That's not it.
I know. You won't even come out
to my perspective employer.
- What kind of lie is that?
- I can't.
I'm just not ready to tell anyone.
The people in my life... I can't.
- You said you were trying.
- I am.
- No, you're not.
Do you know what it takes for me
to keep coming back here?
I mean, I was taught...
I was told to believe things.
In spite of those beliefs, I keep
coming back here night after night...
...because I care about you.
See?
I'm trying.
Just being here is trying.
Police.
Tomas Motyashik?
You have an open warrant
for your arrest.
Let's go.
Don't worry.
Your boyfriend'll lock up.
Won't you, officer?
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group