Is there anything
you're not allergic to?
Sheet metal.
This coke's really pink?
No, not really. It just looks pink
in the right kind of light.
- Cool.
- Yeah. It's Peruvian.
Rondell said the street ain't seen blow
this strong since Grandmaster Flash.
What's that?
Never mind.
How much time are they giving these
days for installing an illegal wiretap?
Not as long as some of
this fruit's been here.
These Third World cavemen
ever hear of a Ralphs?
- Shane. Shane, Shane, Shane.
- Here we go.
- Yo.
- Yeah. Bakers are home, boys...
...and they're coming through
the front door. Exit the ass.
This is gonna be a sweet
win for us, boys.
Aceveda gets a gold star,
we get a little breathing room.
- Rondell gets product.
- The retirement fund keeps growing.
- Who's saving for retirement?
- Can you say "ski-doo"?
All right.
Hey, we're wired.
The Armenians speak Armenian.
- Theo Chorlian?
- Yeah?
Professor Gaffney says
you'd be the perfect guy...
...to help us with
a special investigation.
- What kind of special...?
- You'll love it. Come with us.
He'll meet you back
at the dorm. All right?
These guys are
Eastern Armenian.
- So?
- So they got accents.
You understand what
they're saying or not?
The gardener delivers six loaves
of Agien white bread?
- Does that make sense?
- When and where?
Will arrive here
tomorrow night, 9:30.
- At the bakery.
- Bakery? What kind of bread this is?
- Thanks, kid.
- What's this all about?
- Who are these guys?
- National security.
Don't tell a goddamn soul.
You've been a big help.
Thanks.
Okay, Bingham,
here's the story.
You were driving these gothic
goons back from LAX...
...when you overheard them talking
about the shipment of cocaine.
I won't bore you with the details.
Being such a concerned citizen...
...you felt compelled to share
this information with the authorities.
All we need now is for you
to sign your statement.
Here you go.
Anything to take
a bite out of crime.
Judge Weiss is waiting.
Well, thank you for helping us
get our nice legal warrant.
- Feels good to do the right thing.
- Yes, it does.
- Showtime?
- There's seats still available.
I saw the warrant,
heard you were rolling out.
I'm backing you up
with a few uniform patrols.
That's not how we do it.
Well, that's how I do it. I wanna make
sure everyone comes home this time.
The more the merrier.
Good.
- Somebody here to see me?
- Over there.
- What are you doing here?
- Well, I'm here to report a hit and run.
- What?
- I was struck by...
...a beautiful black man
driving a big red...
- Not here. You have got to go.
- Look, you haven't called.
- I just wanna make sure you're okay.
- I'm fine, now go.
Why are you
shutting me out then?
I'll call you later.
I don't wanna just hear your voice.
I wanna see you.
I'll stop by if you leave right now.
Okay.
But if you don't show,
I'm gonna be back here tomorrow...
...and the day after,
and the day after that.
- Danny.
- Hey, Dutch.
Here are those notes and study
guides for the sergeant's exam.
Great.
The test is at 7 a.m. In San Pedro.
What's up with that?
Lack of sleep thins the herd.
I barely know my name before 8.
Got lesson plans, practice tests.
I organized it all.
Should make it easier
for us to review it.
- Thanks. This is a big help.
- When do you wanna go over that?
- Tomorrow night good?
- Good for me.
- 9:00, my place?
- Your place, perfect. No distractions.
A study date? What kind of
backdoor con is that?
I'm helping her study
for the sergeant's exam.
Unless the first question is,
"Will you sleep with me?"...
...you're wasting your time.
Okay. Hang back.
Once we're inside...
...cover the exits.
I'll call you out.
Police, freeze!
Put that gun down!
Get it down!
Put the gun down!
Put your hands in the air!
Put them on your head!
On your head!
Put your hands on your head!
All right, we're clear.
We're clear.
- He's done. Cuff him.
- Ronnie.
- All right, call them up.
- We're secure.
One dead Armenian,
three to take home.
- Copy that. Code Four. Code Four.
- We're Code Four.
King, call for a body wagon.
- Cover that door.
- I'm there.
- Cover the back.
- Okay.
No one in or out not wearing a badge.
Mike, come with me.
- That don't look pink.
- It's not the right kind of light.
Get this stuff downstairs.
- Load them up.
- Thank you, sir.
Easy with that. Don't spill it
all over the place.
Hey. Jesus Christ here was
the shooter. Keep him separate.
Gotcha.
Come on.
Okay, Ronnie,
you got the ball.
You know how much fat
is in that cookie?
Yeah, yeah, whatever.
No, I'm serious.
Those are sugarcoated lard balls.
- Have you looked at your waist lately?
- Come on, Shane.
Get to it.
- Bag it.
And...
...bag it.
Don't want my kids to end up
in U.C. Northridge hell.
- Hey, I went to Northridge.
- Majored in "Where's the Keg At"?
- That's funny.
- Deliver this package to Rondell.
Right.
Hey, nice job, guys.
Way to go, guys.
Four bricks of Peruvian pink, people.
Hey, angel.
- What?
- You're five hours late.
- It's work.
- Yeah, well, I have to go to work too...
...in about five hours.
- Hey.
What? We just took down
some bad guys.
- I'm feeling it.
- Well, it doesn't mean I have to.
- Just give me 15 minutes.
- A marathon.
- 15 minutes. 15 minutes.
- All right.
- Four keys. Nice bust.
- Yes. Very nice.
- Don't see any money in the log.
- That's because there wasn't any.
- Major drug deal and no cash?
- Nope.
Just a million in powder,
a killer and two drug collars.
Sorry. Slow night.
I guess if that's what you put
in the book, then that's what you found.
Look, it was a delivery, not a buy.
Why is it that no matter what I do,
you always assume the worst?
Have you given me a choice?
Believe it or not,
we want the same things:
Taxpayers safe,
bad guys behind bars.
I just wanna make sure
we're going about it the same way.
I know you blame me for Terry's death.
It was my command.
- I deserve that.
- Yeah, you do.
But what happened that night...
...if I could change it, I would.
I can't.
Neither can you.
You gotta be shitting me.
You're a cop.
Why couldn't you call it in?
- It's complicated. Police issues.
- What's that mean?
You have no idea how bad
I need for you to be quiet right now.
- We've been down this block 3 times.
- Unless you see a black Navigator...
...there should be nothing
coming out of your mouth.
- Black Navigator...
- Not funny!
- No, a black Navigator.
- It's not funny!
Hey.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey, pull over!
Pull... I'm a cop!
I'm a police officer!
Pull...
I swear to God.
- Pull over! Hey! Pull over! Pull over!
- Shane.
- Pull over right now! Goddamn it!
- Oh, my God.
- Pull your car over!
- Shane.
Pull over! Right there!
Pull over! Yeah!
Stay there. Right there.
You, come here!
You understand English?
Come here.
- Right now.
- Take the truck, man! Just take it!
- Don't shoot us, dude.
- Shut up. I'm a cop.
What'd we do?
You stole a police vehicle,
you little shitheads.
It's my mom's car.
Tampons.
No.
What? What?
- Let me do that.
- I got it.
- You make it too strong.
- Okay.
You're up early.
Thought I heard Matthew
having a nightmare last night.
- Did you hear Cassidy coughing?
- No.
I think she's getting
what the baby had.
- The doctor's at 3:30.
- I know.
- Hey.
- Good morning, Corrine.
- Morning.
- What are you doing here?
- I kind of lost the truck last night.
You know,
the one with the stuff inside.
What?
I'm gonna go check on Cassidy.
- You lost the Navigator?
- Somebody stole it.
- With the drugs inside.
- Yeah.
- Where were you?
- At Amy's.
You stopped to get laid?
What the hell were you thinking?
I was thinking about getting laid.
- I'm sorry.
- Sorry doesn't cut it.
I was wrong.
- So, what do you wanna do now?
- We got about four more hours...
...before that truck is
on the way to Mexico City...
...in about 10,000 pieces,
and our score's out on the street.
Call Lem and Ronnie,
get them to the clubhouse.
Nobody steals from us.
That quick, it had to be a pro.
- It's being chopped as we speak.
- So they have the drugs.
- And I'm out 50 K.
- We're all out 50 K.
- Maybe they're just letting it cool off.
- You hold onto that little dream.
Go to Rondell.
Tell him what happened.
- Tell him what happened?
- He'll hear about it anyway.
- All right.
- You, come with me.
I can't wait to tell Rondell.
Vic, my man.
- Officer Hoffman.
- Vic.
- Hollywood.
- What's up, Hoff.
- What you got yourself?
- Green Jeep.
Had a couple nibbles, no bites.
What can I do you for?
- Who's chopping the big trucks?
- What kind?
- Navigator.
- Year?
- Brand new.
- 2002 Lincoln Navigator.
A few places offhand. Currently the
demand is greater than the supply.
- Where's demand the greatest?
- Hold on, hold on.
Slow day.
Look, main shop is in your part of town
where they chops those monsters.
Skinny Polish prick. Mark Wojo...
Wojohowitz or something like that.
- Don't tell him I sent you.
- Thanks, man. I owe you.
If you need another guy
on your team, man...
...maybe you'll toss my name
in the hat. I could use the action.
Who knows? Might be a new spot
opening up any day now.
Well, all right.
So many rocks, so little time.
Nothing like the bust
last night, though, huh?
That was a big one.
- What was the final score on that one?
- Four bricks.
Four?
Mackey sure knows how
to pull them out of his ass.
You might as well talk to us.
We've got four cops who saw you
blow your buddy's brains out.
You know what that means?
One of them could
get hit by a bus and we'd...
Still have three cops who could
put you away for first-degree murder.
You listening to me?
Add that to the trafficking...
Charge and, well, your prospects
aren't looking too pretty.
Tell me where you
got the drugs.
Tell me about your buddy Margos,
and his drug connections.
- You listening to me?
- I say something funny?
What if I stuffed big blue bananas
in your ears and set them on fire?
Any of this getting through?
This guy ignores me almost as much
as my kids did in high school.
- Nothing?
- No one's talking.
- They're all terrified of him.
- Anything on the prints?
Only Dizarian's came up on Interpol.
Lokely's got a Glendale address.
He's been questioned,
but not charged in...
...Kosovo, Bogotá, Sri Lanka.
- Frequent flier.
He just came back from a 36-hour
holiday from Chiclayo, Peru.
Harvest-time.
- Get a warrant to search his place.
- Yeah.
Revenge? Crime of passion?
He insult your mother?
Having a bad hair day?
Let me know if I'm getting warm.
- Yeah.
- This Universal Studios?
- What? No.
- What, you mean this ain't City Walk?
- Are you guys for real?
- Looky here.
Looks like a vehicle being
stripped for illegal distribution.
I'll be damned.
In plain sight too.
- It's a good thing we're policemen.
- No way.
Think that Universal thing's
gonna hold up in court?
Well, maybe, maybe not.
In the meantime, it looks like...
...we'll have to return these
to their owners...
...and bring you in,
Polish prick Mark.
- All right, what do you guys want?
- Blue Navigator.
- Don't have one.
- You get any offers last night?
Answer the question.
- I get to keep these?
- If you make me happy.
A guy Ricardo called.
Wanted to unload a Navigator.
- Ricardo have an address?
- Yeah. He's in Silver Lake.
Where in Silver Lake, asshole?
Must like you, officer. It's the first
thing this faggot's said all day.
- Hey, Dutch.
- Hey.
You interviewed that Armenian, right?
"Interview" would imply that
a conversation took place.
- This guy didn't say a word.
- He did to me.
- When?
- Just now.
- What'd he say?
- I guess it was Armenian.
It sounded something
like "hamal v otcar."
- Hamal v otcar.
- You okay?
- Yeah. That guy just creeps me out.
Don't let him.
He's behind bars.
- I'll check on this.
- Thanks.
What the hell?
- Who are you guys?
- Shut up.
I'm trying to sleep here.
Where's the Navigator
you tried to unload last night?
How'd you get in my bedroom?
Look, I didn't jack it.
It was Dina.
- Who's Dina?
- Girl I'm trying to break into the game.
He's trying to bone.
- Where can we find Dina?
- Who are you guys?
Hey, call Lem and Ronnie and
have them bring you over to Dina's.
- Where are you going?
- I got somewhere to go.
- Where?
- You're not exactly...
...in a position to question
my decisions.
Just call me when you
have Dina or the drugs.
- Officer Sofer.
- Detective Mackey.
- What you got there?
- Notes.
Sergeant's exam.
Dutch is gonna help me out.
Dutchman isn't pulling the old
I'll-help-you-study...
...you-help-me-get-laid
manoeuvre, is he?
- He'd like to help me pass.
- He'd like to help you out of your pants.
Last night, Shane ran in
for a Slurpee and managed...
...to get our police-issue
vehicle jacked.
- Ouch.
- Yeah. Had our weapons in it too.
That stuff hits the street and gets
traced back to us...
...Aceveda will put Shane's balls
in a vice. And mine too, probably.
- What's the vehicle?
- 2002 blue Navigator, fully loaded.
I'd like to bring it in
personally, quietly.
Keep my eye open
and give you the heads up.
Thanks.
So is that what Shane's calling it
these days, a Slurpee?
I guess so.
Detective Wyms, I was hoping
I could talk to you.
- About?
- Advice.
Well, shouldn't you be going
to your P-3 for advice?
I'd rather talk to you.
- Why? Because I'm black?
- No.
Better not be because
I remind you of your mother.
No, ma'am.
I mean, detective.
Never mind. I'm sorry
to have bothered you.
Officer.
What is it?
I think I may have seen another cop
do something illegal on the job.
- And?
- And I don't know what to do about it.
You're talking about jeopardizing
two careers here: His and yours.
Mine?
Nobody likes a rat, especially one
who hasn't proven himself.
- So I should keep this to myself.
- No, I didn't say that.
You gotta ask yourself if it's something
bad enough to risk that kind of heat.
Is it something you can't
live with holding?
You're certain there
were six bricks?
Six or seven.
Definitely more than four.
- You did the right thing.
- Yeah.
- I know it wasn't easy.
- No, sir.
We'd be a lot better off with more
men like you and fewer like Mackey.
So, what happens now?
Can you check on when
the blue Navigator was checked in?
Don't have to. Wasn't.
Supposed to be in five hours ago.
Wilshire's been asking for it back.
- He's supposed to be the best.
- They say that about every doctor.
- Yeah.
- Is Shane with you?
No. Why?
Just got a complaint from a woman
who said a police officer...
...fitting Shane's description,
assaulted her son at gunpoint...
...claiming he stole
a police vehicle.
You sure she's not
some crackpot?
Where's that blue Navigator
you signed out last night?
Don't know.
I'll ask Shane when I see him.
- I need that truck back now.
- Loud and clear. Gotta run.
- Sorry.
- Quite all right.
Why don't you both have a seat.
So, Mr. And Mrs. Mackey,
how are you both doing today?
You tell us.
How'd the testing go?
The past three sessions have
gone well. You're very lucky.
Matthew is a charming,
intelligent little boy.
He also has autism.
- What?
- Autism.
- Oh, God.
- Wait a minute.
He's a little shy, behind a bit...
...but autism? Jesus.
What does that mean?
It's a hard word to hear, but it's also
a very misunderstood word.
- Matthew's a beautiful child. He's...
- I know my son is beautiful.
- I understand what you're feeling.
- Really.
I have two autistic boys of my own.
- Two?
- Oh, man.
Yes. I felt everything
you're feeling twice.
What's gonna happen to him?
- He's going to grow up.
- What about school?
He may be best served
in a special program.
Special? What do you mean, like
blue-bus special? That's not my kid.
I mean, look at him.
He's just Matt.
I knew something was wrong.
He could stay in his present
school with some speech therapy...
...and special-skills instruction.
- Is he gonna be normal or not?
With the proper support, he will be able
to make gains to the best of his ability.
And with intervention,
the prognosis is very good.
He's just gonna need a lot of love
and work to get there.
He's got the love.
What kind of work?
Jesus. I'm sorry. I'm a cop.
- What?
- We are so screwed, man.
Aceveda just put a statewide
APB out on the Navigator.
What's up?
Roommate said this Dina girl went to
go get waxed. She didn't know where.
- You got anything more vague?
- What should we do?
Aceveda gets ahold of this truck, he's
gonna do a chem match on the blow...
...our fingerprints
are all over the bricks.
We'll all crash and burn
because of you!
Christ, Amy's not even that hot.
- Come on, Lem.
- No, bull!
He's right.
You boned us.
Oh, thank you for the support, assholes!
Cut it out!
We're not going down.
- You understand me?
- Yeah, yeah.
All right. Ronnie, you stay here
and wait for Dina.
Lem, they got a bunch of those
wax places over on Olvera Street.
We'll check the muff rippers
over in Little Tokyo. Let's go.
Well, if the DA is not gonna file...
- You check out Margos' place?
- Yeah.
You think this guy was spooky before,
you should see the way he lives.
- What'd you find?
- Nothing incriminating.
Just a couple hundred maps,
six dictionaries in five languages.
- Scanner, digital camera, GameBoy.
- Incense, meditation books.
- Disposable diapers.
- A whole case of microwave popcorn.
- Hey, no microwave.
- No microwave.
- No fridge, no stove.
- No plates, silverware.
- No soap.
- No toilet paper.
No more.
This guy just gets better and better.
- Break almost over?
- Yeah.
Did you get a chance
to look at those notes?
A little.
A lot of stuff to absorb.
Don't put it off too long.
I won't.
Hey, Dutch, any luck
with that translation?
You know, it's a phonetic spelling.
Armenians have this
Eastern-Western dialect thing.
- What did your guy say that it meant?
- This is by no means definitive.
But what Margos may have
been saying was...
...delicious feet.
- Excuse me?
- Delicious feet, yeah.
- Oh, God.
You probably just
heard him wrong.
Hey, hey.
Let's go.
Don't move.
Jesus.
He snapped his neck.
Let me guess. You're not talking.
Get them out of here.
And call Central, have them
get this guy out of my building.
Step outside the car by opening
the door from the outside.
Okay.
- Sorry.
- Step outside.
- I'm so sorry.
- Turn around.
- Put your hands on the window.
- Look, I...
I know it's not your problem, okay...
...but I'm sorry.
My dad's drinking again...
...and I had to grab my brother
and bolt out of there this morning.
It was so crazy.
God, I was so scared.
Well, sorry. Listen, is there anything
we can do for you?
Yeah. I just need to pick up my brother
at school before my dad gets there.
I mean, God knows
what he'll do to him.
If you could just let me go...
Always pick up your abused brother
in a stolen vehicle with bogus plates?
Damn.
- One Tango 13, copy?
- Hey, hold up on that.
Stand by.
What?
Told Vic I'd give him the heads up
when we found the Navigator.
- What for?
- I don't know.
- He wants to be the one to bring it in.
- It's an APB. We have to call it in.
Look, I owe Vic one. Hey!
Where are you going?
You two look like you
needed some alone time.
Get in the car.
One Tango 13, we have a confirmation
on that stolen Navigator.
Roger, Tango 13.
I'll notify the watch commander.
I can't risk a bad mark on my jacket
this early in my career.
Anything touched?
No, sir, we secured the scene
and made the call.
Okay.
Lock box.
Nothing.
Goddamn it.
He called it in before
I could stop him.
- Are you kidding me?
- What's his problem?
Look, he's just learning.
Look, the good news is
they didn't find those weapons.
- Did he find anything?
- Just Dina.
Looks like I located
your missing truck.
Was hoping I'd save you the trouble.
- All's well that ends well.
- Yeah.
- You're in deep, Dina.
- Yeah?
Shoplifting, assault.
Now grand-theft auto.
- What's next?
- Thinking about the police academy.
Why don't you go
get me an application.
You think this is a game, little girl?
This is real time in real prison.
Okay. Are you going somewhere
with this scared-straight angle?
Or is this where I tell you how my
daddy used to crawl into bed with me?
I wanna know what
you found in the Navigator.
I heard someone call you "captain."
I mean, isn't a stolen car case
normally a little below your radar?
You wouldn't be here...
...if I didn't have what you wanted.
- Where are the drugs?
They're safe.
Tell me where, and I'll make sure
the auto theft goes away.
Until I see it, I don't say it.
In writing, signed by the DA.
- Hey. That the car thief stuff?
- Yeah.
Hey, I hear you're
looking for another stripe.
- Yeah. See you.
- All right. Good luck.
Thanks.
She made three phone calls
after she stole the truck.
Two to her roommates and the other
to a pawnshop in Echo Park.
- Pemble & Pemble on Esther.
- Head for Esther in Echo Park.
- Man, do I owe you one.
- Please. At best, I'm even.
Stop staring at my feet,
you Balkan freak.
- "What"?
- Nothing.
Danny.
Come with us.
I think Aceveda got Dina to talk.
I gotta go.
- Damn it.
- What?
Hey, man, we're not closed yet.
Yo, sprechen sie Englisch, skinhead?
I said, we're not closed yet.
In 30 seconds I'll either know
what I wanna know or you'll be dead.
- Dina.
- I don't know a Dina.
- How come you have our guns here?
- Talk!
- Dina called for Freddy.
- Who's Freddy?
French guy.
Helps me out with the night traffic.
- Where are the drugs?
- I don't know. Maybe Freddy took them.
Not good enough!
I swear to God, man, I don't know!
Why would I cover for him?
Jesus Christ, he's French.
Where can we find the frog?
Looks like Freddy
couldn't hold his sugar.
Power of the pink.
- Blew a goddamn vessel.
- Oh, that's nasty.
All right, go through this place. Make
sure there's nothing here to tie us.
Vic! It's Aceveda.
Hey, let's clean up Freddy! Here we go.
- Oh, shit. Clean him up.
- Wipe it all down.
Tray. Here's the tray.
Here's the tray. Coming through.
Yeah, yeah. Is that it?
All right, all right.
Run this. Good, good.
- You got it?
- Clean fingers.
- What's going on here?
- It must've been a hell of a party.
- What happened to him?
- Looks like an OD. Found him that way.
- Been dead a while. Really dead.
- Yeah. We were about to call it in.
You were about to call it in.
What are you doing here?
Fair question. Tracking down the guns
from our stolen ride.
- Yep. All's here and accounted for, sir.
- Can't have them hitting the streets.
- Didn't want them in the wrong hands.
- Where's Mackey?
Hey. Thought he wouldn't mind
if I used the can.
What are you doing there, captain?
I'm looking for something.
- Where is it?
- Don't know what you're talking about.
Hey, treat yourself to a full
cavity search if you like.
I'll see you back at the barn.
Turn it inside out.
Every inch.
- I thought you were working.
- Yeah. I gotta go back.
Just snuck out
to tuck in little man.
Better hurry.
He might already be asleep.
Okay.
- How you doing?
- I'm all right. I'm just a little tired.
Yeah. I know.
Don't worry, we'll get through this.
What did you get for 38?
I answered C.
No, it's B.
Have to report the infraction
immediately to the commanding officer.
- There's no latitude on that.
- Stupid rule.
Would you turn in your partner
on something like that?
I know how I'd answer on the test.
Hello? Hi.
No, are you okay?
No, come on over. Okay.
- Everything all right?
- Yeah.
A friend of mine is having a crisis
and she wants to come over.
- She okay?
- I don't know.
- We got a lot of work done tonight.
- Yeah.
Hey, you're a good teacher.
- See you tomorrow?
- Yeah.
We'll dive into administrative
and procedural.
It's dry stuff, but you can't pass
without nailing it.
- Good night.
- Night. I hope your friend's okay.
Yeah. Yeah, me too.
Okay.
Thanks.
Sorry about today, it was such a faggot
thing to do. Showing up at your work.
Don't do it again.
I won't.
You gonna sit?
I really am sorry.
I'll make it up to you.
I can't be the person that you want me
to be. I shouldn't even be here.
- You've never come back, have you?
- This is stupid.
What's stupid are the late-night cruises
and anonymous hummers in your car.
What?
I read a page of your diary?
You don't know anything about me.
Things that I believe, things that I see.
- You're a good person.
- I'm doing a bad thing.
You deserve to be happy.
You ever read the Bible?
Scripture teaches...
Never mind.
You came back.
Start listening to yourself.
- You're here late.
- I'm e-mailing my girls.
Just got a call from Central.
Margos Dizarian
escaped from the paddy wagon.
What? How?
Jimmied open the back door, dove out
at 40 miles an hour in his cuffs.
- Disappeared down an alley.
- Jesus.
- I know.
- That's a special kind of crazy.
Very special.
Just thought you should know.
I wish I didn't.
God knows where he is right now.
You okay?
Not really.
I'm just kind of all over the place.
- Job?
- Yeah. And I...
Brutal day.
Come on.
Where are you?
I don't know.
I got something going on with my kid.
You don't wanna hear it.
Let's talk about something else.
Yeah.
Oh, you've gotta be shitting me.
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group