- Let's go! On the ground!
- Get down!
Police! Down!
Cethru, how many times
do I gotta tell you?
Firearms and alcohol
are a dangerous combination.
- See?
- Get down on your knees.
I said, get down on your knees.
Cethru is upgrading his merch.
Some of these might actually shoot.
Hey, Vic.
- Wishing your cock was that big?
- Man, these are beautiful animals.
I can't believe they just let them
rip each other apart.
- Just dumb birds, brother.
- Where they taking them, man?
- Three little letters: KFC.
- Come on, those are my best birds.
- Shut up. Move.
- Wait. Come on. I can help you, man.
Cethru's smalltime. You want guns,
I'll hook you up with the big guy.
Yeah? Who we talking about?
Listen, call off the butchers,
and I'll tell you.
Why don't you tell me first.
Pazi Arombula.
Is that big enough for you?
- You know where Pazi is?
- He loves birds.
- He's in town for Dos Días de Sangre.
- Two Days of Blood?
It's a big summer cockfight, all right?
I get you inside. You get Pazi.
Last I heard, those pits were filled
with Filipinos and Mexicans.
I get some of my best fighters
from rednecks in Louisiana.
- He'll blend right in.
- Blow me, chicken man.
Pazi Arombula, huh? He is bigtime.
I'll tell you when and where.
Check it out. Is it all there?
We're cool, man.
Here.
Tony!
Stop!
Pazi's a gunrunning scumbag,
who's wanted...
...by Mexican, federal, state
and local authorities.
He's got close to a 3 million-peso
bounty on his head.
Three million? Let me see that.
Oh, Vic, you gotta let me go undercover
and clean up this grease stain.
Last time I let you go undercover,
you got beaten up by a stripper.
I was jumped by her thug boyfriend,
and she was a dancer.
Shut up!
Vic, you got a minute?
Yeah, sure.
I'm surprised to see you. What's up?
- You and I, we've had a rough year.
- Yeah, we did.
One rough year out of 20 years
of friendship. That ain't bad.
With those percentages,
I'd still be with my first wife.
- You're better off with Nancy.
- I know.
- What's up, Ben?
- I was in a hit-and-run tonight.
I think I killed the guy.
- You didn't stop?
- I got out to check on him...
...and his gangbanger buddy
took some shots at me.
I panicked and hightailed it.
Oh, man, what am I gonna do?
- Tell the truth. If he took shots at you...
- Vic, I been DUI four times.
I got it hushed up.
Word gets out that I killed this guy,
nobody's gonna believe I wasn't drunk.
- Oh, Christ, Ben.
- Imagine me in prison, Vic.
Now, I know as rough
as we left it last time...
...you can't want that. Right?
Can you help an old friend?
Ben, give me the keys. Shane, tell
Suvani repairing this blue Mercedes...
...is top-priority and top-secret.
I want it good as new by tomorrow.
- Right, boss.
- Lem, get Ben home.
- Okay.
- I'll find out who's on the case...
...make sure it never hits you.
Thanks, Vic.
It was some slide.
Impact dragged him 75 feet.
- Maybe you ought to call Guinness.
- No, record's over 30 miles.
This isn't even a footnote.
Anthony Nuñez, dealer extraordinaire.
Witnesses say he and a friend
worked the corner over there.
- Where's the friend?
- Didn't stick around.
- What about the car?
- It's a blue Mercedes, four-door.
Witness was vague. Guy driving, little
Latin number in the passenger seat.
High-end sedan. If it wasn't tricked-out,
he didn't live around here.
He must've been
in a hurry to get home.
I'm having trouble. Do you know
how to run this program?
- Are you doing okay?
- I'm fine. Thanks.
If you're not ready to go back out,
I understand.
No, really. I'm okay. It was just
a one-time thing. I'm fine now.
You sure?
I know you're worried because you
have to ride with me, but I'm okay.
- Yeah, well, it's my life too, you know?
- I know.
So say something
that will make me feel better.
- I'm not gonna hang you out.
- And?
And I'm gonna speak with my reverend,
sort through things.
But my head is in it 100 percent.
I heard you guys scraped a
dope-dealing banger off the pavement.
- Not pretty.
- Crash-test dummy got an ID?
- Claudette, can I borrow you?
- What for?
- A double homicide in the Grove.
- Some morning.
You need me? I can pass
the hit-and-run off to Walt.
Just Claudette.
I'm going over there too.
It looks like it could be
a messy situation.
Come on, we'll ride together.
- I'm still waiting.
- Yeah.
Victim's name's Anthony Nuñez.
You know him?
Oh, after summer vacation
was over, we stopped writing.
That area, he's probably a Toro.
Anything on the driver?
White guy, blue Mercedes, señorita
in the passenger seat. That's it.
- There was a passenger.
- Good news is, neighbours have seen...
...the car parked in the area at night.
Sounds like a little love tryst to me.
Toros do this thing
called a toss-and-shoot.
- What's that?
- Toss a rival banger in front of a car.
They fire off a few rounds. Scare the
driver, make it look like a hit-and-run.
Maybe the driver killed the guy,
didn't wanna get caught?
Why don't you let me
give you a hand with this.
You wanna help me?
Ever since you rolled that serial killer,
you're the man around here.
- Right.
- C-note says this is a toss-and-shoot.
- Gonna tell us what's going on?
- Can I have your attention, please?
Now, people, please. Please, please.
We need you to listen.
Give us some time to go inside
and determine what happened.
We'll make an announcement
when we know something.
Sweet Jesus. What's burning?
It's the garbage disposal.
The motor burned out.
It looks like they were killed
with a meat tenderiser.
Killer panicked,
tried to dispose of the body.
The victim in the sink is Tanya Kramer.
The other is Violet Roosevelt.
- Any witnesses?
- Well, the walls here are pretty thin.
A lot of people heard the screams.
- Captain.
- Yes?
There's someone downstairs
who can identify the killer.
Down there.
- Karen Mitchell?
- You know her?
Yeah, I met her a few times
during Morgan's re-election campaign.
- Karen, hello.
- David.
- Councilman Morgan couldn't make it?
- He's in Sacramento moving.
- He asked me to come and be his eyes.
- Of course.
- So if you need anything, just ask.
- Well, I appreciate his help, yours too.
This is Maya Duffy. She saw the killer.
- Can you describe him?
- His name's Wally Forton.
White guy. He was dating
Tanya's daughter.
- What happened?
- What happened is, they called 911...
...and it took you
over an hour to show up.
- Over an hour. Are you sure?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
We heard Tanya up there screaming
at Wally. She called 911.
- And he didn't leave?
- No, he went outside...
...waiting around for 20 minutes or so,
and then he went back and killed them.
- An hour. Can that be right?
- I'll have to review the 911 tapes.
If it was a black man breaking in,
it wouldn't take no hour.
Everybody gets equal treatment
from this department.
Why are they dead, then?
Ma'am, come with me, please.
I'll take the statement.
- Go by the car.
- Whatever.
They'll want answers, and frankly,
I think they deserve them.
Wally's girlfriend might be in danger.
We need to find him, her or both.
I pulled the dead guy's known
associates. Recognise anyone?
That's the guy's buddy right there.
He's the one that shot at me.
Jesus Rosales. Yeah, he's a Toro.
Warrants for possession and intent
to sell narcotics. No wonder he ran.
- Can you find him?
- Who are you talking to here?
He got a good look at me. What if he
decides I'm his bargaining chip?
We'll make him a better deal.
So when were you gonna tell me
you were shagging a Latina?
- I didn't wanna get her involved.
- She couldn't be more involved.
- Was she driving?
- No, it happened just like I said...
...except she was with me.
- Who is she?
Sedona Tellez. I've been seeing her.
- What about Nancy?
- We're all perfect?
Dutchboy's picked up her scent.
You're gonna have to send her away.
Okay. Good idea.
Hey, Vic, she's not just some lay.
I love her.
Melissa left for the gym
about two hours ago.
- Was she alone?
- Yeah.
What about the boyfriend, Wally?
Have you seen him?
Wally. Oh, honey,
he's a cutie-pie for a white guy.
- You know him?
- Sort of. I hear them some nights.
- Hear them?
- Doing it. Honey, he's a screamer.
He's louder than she is. I thought
they split up, but I guess not.
- You know where we might find them?
- He came back about an hour ago...
...Looking for her.
I told him that she was at the gym.
Hey, our road kill pissed off a couple
of Los Mags a couple of days back.
It's looking more and more
like banger payback.
I found her.
- Who?
- The mystery woman.
I talked to a pizza delivery guy.
He's seen a blue Benz...
...on numerous occasions
at 2538 Mercado Avenue.
Sedona Tellez. She's our babe.
- What are we waiting for? Let's go.
- There's no one home.
But a neighbour swears
she jumped into a cab...
...with a bunch of suitcases
earlier this afternoon.
This is starting to get interesting.
Who knows if it's even the same Benz?
Maybe she just went on vacation.
Or she and the boyfriend skipped town.
Don't worry, I'll get them.
Cool.
Pazi's a badass with connections
to half a dozen gangs.
Why are you risking your life
to get off a misdemeanour?
Those cocks, I hatched them myself.
I raised them. They're all I got.
Okay. You get me in, set up a meeting.
Tell Pazi I'm willing to trade
feathers for hardware.
Trust me, if Pazi likes your chickens,
he'll trade anything to get them.
Good. So we got a plan, right?
Can I go home now? Am I free?
Let's just say that you're on parole
till this thing gets done. Understand?
Yeah, okay. Let's go to my yard,
and I'll teach you...
...everything you need
to know in the ring.
- Bottled water?
- The most important part of their diet.
- The poison out of my tap will kill them.
- I hear that, man.
- What kind of bird is he?
- Kelso, champion line. Never been cut.
Those three are Boston Roundheads,
the Solabina...
...and the blinker's a Johnny Jumper.
- Blinker?
- Blinker.
Oh, man, that's sick.
Hey, you got till tonight, man.
Learn as much as you can.
Pazi's gonna wanna know
how you raise these birds.
Jesus. B12, vitamin K supplements.
They need all this stuff?
- If you want them to win.
- What's his name?
It hurts too much.
I stopped naming them.
They're all called nugget.
That's not funny, dude.
I mean, these are innocent creatures.
They are kind of beautiful,
though, aren't they?
I mean, in a snack food sort of way.
Jesus.
- Open warrant. Let's make this easy.
- He didn't do anything.
Look, kids, I'm in no mood to play.
Come on.
- Where you going, homes?
- Back off. I'm a cop. Back off.
If this was a real arrest, you would
have brought more. Let him go.
- He'll be out in 12 hours.
- I say he's out now.
Don't do it. It's not worth it.
I don't wanna shoot anybody today.
That's up to you.
- Gonna kill us all, ése?
- No, just the one who wants it first.
Hey! Get your hands in the air!
Back off! Back off.
Walk. Come on.
The witness at Melissa's gym
saw them leaving together.
- By force or willingly?
- The guy wasn't sure.
Karen Mitchell's here.
She's only gonna get in our way.
You could talk to her.
Tell her to back off.
- Me?
- You said you met her a few times.
You know, rumour is, she's Morgan's
handpicked successor for his seat.
- Really.
- Which means that she would be...
...running against you in the primary,
but you knew that.
As wedge issues go,
two dead women is a bad one.
You wanna catch the killer
and cover your ass...
...but if you can't do both,
this is about catching the killer.
Karen.
I was hoping you had
some new information by now.
Unfortunately, no.
- Well, what about the 911 tapes?
- They're on the way.
We've been trying to find Melissa
Kramer before she gets her own tape.
Well, I'd like to listen to them with you.
Two women are dead, David.
I hope we're not playing politics here.
Jesus, we need your help
with something.
Now, we're sorry about your friend,
but that was an accident.
You dragged him halfway
down the block.
I saw your rap sheets.
You and your friend are no saints.
- Jesus, you know who we are?
- Cops.
No, we're not just any cops.
We're good friends to have, Jesus.
You ever get picked up for selling rock,
we're the guys to know.
- Yeah, if I keep quiet.
- If you keep quiet.
- Okay.
- Good.
You just made a smart decision.
I'll tell you what, Jesus.
I'm gonna write down a number.
You get scooped up,
you call me anytime...
Jesus Christ!
What did you do?!
- What the hell's the matter with you?
- I had to.
- Put the gun down, Ben.
- Relax, Vic.
- We don't have to worry now.
- He was cooperating.
- I was supposed to trust him?!
- He was innocent!
- He was a problem!
- Jesus Christ, Ben!
What did you do?
Nothing you haven't done.
- What?
- Terry Crowley. Any bells ringing?
You don't wanna say it, fine.
But I helped you get clear on that.
- Oh, man, this is your problem.
- It's our problem.
- No.
- His buddies saw you take this guy.
Now he's dead.
I picked you for a reason, Vic.
You've been through this.
Now help me get clear.
I appreciate this, Vic.
Drop this guy in Los Mags territory
and make it look like a gang hit.
That's smart. Yeah.
When this lands on your desk,
just bury it.
Hey, look, Vic, I'm sorry
about how this went down. I am.
Now just keep Dutch off my ass,
and we're home free.
Vic, you and me. We're good, right?
No, not today.
That's two for 25 right there, pops.
That phone is 10 bucks. No problem.
Got change for everything.
- What can I do for you officers?
- Got a complaint about your yard sale.
- What kind of complaint?
- You've been robbing neighbours...
...and forcing them to buy
their property back.
Well, that's a lie.
All this here, this is all mine.
- The person said differently.
- Oh, yeah? And who was that?
They didn't give their name.
They said everyone's scared of you.
- You got any proof this stuff is yours?
- You got any proof that it ain't?
Look, officers, I'm just trying
to have a yard sale here, okay?
- There's nothing illegal about that.
- There is if you don't have a permit.
City-approved. Please believe it.
- Dookie?
- That's me.
Does any of this merchandise
belong to any of you?
If you speak up,
you'll get your stuff back.
If you guys are all done,
I've got business to attend to.
I'm gonna be keeping
my eye out on you, Dookie.
Stop by anytime.
I got great bargains for you two.
Watch it, pops. You touch, you buy.
You know the rules.
What, are you kidding me?
That's 10 percent.
I only get 20 percent, Einstein.
Ten percent is half my fee.
- You sure about that?
- Hey.
Lem, this is Jojo Rizal.
He's a bounty hunter.
- Bail enforcement agent.
- Curtis Lemansky.
Jojo here's gonna help us
with this Pazi deal.
- Help us?
- Yeah, like a piece of Pazi's bounty?
Cops can't collect bounty, dude.
I figured a way around
that little problem.
- What, the problem of us being cops?
- Bring me Pazi, I split my fee 50-50.
- No way.
- Come on. That's like 400,000 pesos.
That's gotta be, what?
A couple hundred grand?
- Try 50?
- Fifty?
- That's about right.
- Damn, Mexico.
- You know what? It's still worth it.
- No way. Forget it, man.
- Okay.
- Hold on. Hold on one second.
- What?
- I'm looking out for our interests.
Jesus. For once, can't we just do
what we're supposed to and then stop?
Hey, when you guys figure out
who's wearing the pants...
...why don't you beep me.
Oh, your cock's out.
Damn it.
Is that who you see yourself as?
A gay man?
Of course not, I'm just confused.
These urges, I can't beat them down.
So, what I'm hearing is,
you really wanna change.
That's why I'm here.
I was ashamed.
I didn't know what you'd say.
What's important is your commitment
to God, to your faith.
I know.
So, what can I do?
There's someone I'd like you to meet.
Vic, I researched our missing
femme fatale, Sedona Tellez.
Waste of time, Dutchboy.
Taggers found the victim's amigo...
...dead in a Los Mag tunnel.
Told you, gang hit all the way.
- What buddy? Jesus Rosales?
- Yeah.
- I've been looking for him.
- Well, stop.
Girlfriend bolts, friend gets hit.
There's something else at play here.
- What?
- Sedona Tellez is listed as a CEO...
...of a corporation based
in the Cayman Islands.
Its sole purpose? Buying up
real estate right here in Farmington.
- You're kidding.
- Nope. Not bad for an accountant...
...living in a one-bedroom
in slum town.
- Now this Jesus is dead?
- Yeah.
He was a Toro. I'll start with his crew.
Usually runs with five, six other guys.
- How do you know that?
- I have contacts.
- You do?
- Believe it or not.
- You found all this out since 4:00?
- Pretty good, huh?
- Too good, Dutchboy.
- Well, I have a rep to maintain.
You're gonna put me right out of a job.
One, two, three.
Let's go. Come on, come on, birdie, go.
Go, birdie, go. Go! Take him down!
Go, take him down!
Take him down, birdie!
What about it?
Who's ready for round two?
- What a badass!
- What, you saw Pazi?
No, man, Frank. He gets in there,
and it's like he's possessed.
This goddamn cock won 700 bucks.
- You named him?
- Frank.
- What? It's just a first name.
- Pazi was a no-show?
Yeah. Yeah. Gabo heard he's coming
tomorrow. You ready for round two?
You're sick, man.
Where's the police? Where are you?
Try to remain calm.
The police are coming.
- He's back again!
- Now!
- Who's back?
- Wally Forton.
At this point, it's been 47
minutes since the initial call.
- Jesus Christ.
- Somebody help us!
- Ma'am?
- Unbelievable.
- Help us!
- Mrs. Kramer...?
- Help!
- Are you still there?
- Bitch, you did this!
- Mrs. Kramer, are you okay?
Help us!
How does something like this happen?
It's a manpower issue.
We only had two units assigned.
One was responding to a heart attack.
The other was involved in a pursuit.
- Why only two units?
- It's a new policy.
Saturating areas with more patrols.
- While other areas go unprotected?
- Not unprotected.
Statistically, it's smart policing.
A larger concentration of units...
...in one area reduces crime
by 65 percent...
You believe that?
What happened today was an anomaly.
Tell that to the family
of those two dead women.
Usually, there's adequate backup.
David has the discretion
on how his units are assigned.
So you're the one who's responsible?
- You're blaming me for this?
- Payback's a bitch, huh?
- Thanks for tossing me a softball.
- This policy's your idea.
It's been in place for six months.
You had no problem with it...
...as long as you were sending the
patrols to Latino neighbourhoods.
- Wait a minute. This is not my mess.
- It is now.
So you better fix it.
- Vic, good to see you again.
- Business as usual, huh?
For the both of us.
Julien, I need a hand.
- I need your help with something.
- I'm done helping you.
Hey, I keep your secret every day,
just like I promised, right?
Every time you need something,
you'll twist a screw?
You're gonna help me
with something right now...
...or you're gonna see
just how hard I can twist.
This guy walks into the middle
of you and your friends...
...pulls a gun and walks off with Jesus?
- Yeah.
- Any idea who he is?
- Detective.
- Yeah?
- You're needed.
- I'm in the middle of something.
Captain said it was important.
I'll be right back.
- Where is he?
- I didn't talk to him.
I just had the message passed to me.
You listen and you listen quick.
Los Mags pulled your guy out.
You ID me, you'll be stone dead
15 minutes after you leave this station.
You hear me?
- Hey.
- Vic.
Thought I'd sit in.
Hope you don't mind.
Not at all. Anyway, you were
about to describe the guy.
Well, answer the man.
I didn't get a good look.
What did you see?
- He was wearing Los Mags colours.
- Los Mags?
A goddamn gang hit.
I told you it was boys in the 'hood.
He couldn't look you or me in the eye.
Kept scratching the top of his right...
- Wagenbach, stop.
- He's lying.
- A skin allergy means he's lying?
- He's covering for the Benz guy.
I can't believe this. Give it up already.
Even if you're right,
the driver is still a witness to a murder.
- I still have to find him, so let me.
- You don't need the witness.
Vic, follow up your gang lead.
I'm gonna track down the driver and his
señorita's Cayman Island connection.
Or is that gang related too?
Add units seven, eight and 10.
I don't want to...
...spit in the Grove without
hitting a police car.
- Put the Riot Squad on tactical alert.
- We found Melissa Kramer.
Where?
- You think she's in on it?
- I don't know.
Let's hope she's not down the disposal.
Forton brought
the woman here two hours ago.
They're in Room 19.
He had a bottle of champagne.
- To celebrate?
- Or to tenderise.
Police, freeze! Get your hands
where I can see them!
Oh, my God! Wait!
What did we do?!
- Wally Forton, you're under arrest...
- Stop it!
...for the murders of Violet Roosevelt
and Tanya Kramer.
- Murder? Wait a minute. What? Wally?
- They were just getting between us.
Read him his rights. Twice.
We're forever, baby. Forever!
They're dead?
- Caught the guy, huh?
- Yeah.
Nasty business
down there in the Grove.
Is that a joke?
Well, tell Gilroy I'm not laughing.
- What are you talking about?
- Like you don't know.
Pretend I don't.
Gilroy's diverted manpower
to other neighbourhoods.
Crime went down everywhere,
except the Grove.
Now he's letting me swing for
the department on these two murders.
- Well, I didn't know.
- Well, now you do.
Tell me something.
What would be in it for someone
to buy up property in the Grove?
- Is this a real question?
- Pretend it is.
Well, that area's been ignored.
Crime's up. Land's cheap.
Other than that,
there's no reason to buy there.
- Why? Who's buying up land?
- No one. I'm just asking.
Did Gilroy say something?
I saw the two of you.
No, it's just a stupid idea.
If I get a good one, I'll let you know.
I was inflicted with homosexual urges
just like you.
I was tested constantly.
I used to think that I was gay,
that I had no other choice.
I even cursed God for doing it to me.
You ever heard of sexual-reorientation
therapy, Julien?
I read an article about it once.
Homosexuality is a disease
similar to alcoholism or drug addition.
The church offers programs
to combat these compulsions.
Through discipline, treatment, the
urges can be suppressed, eliminated.
- Really?
- I'm married to a beautiful woman.
I have a child on the way...
...and my wife and I both lead
a fulfilling, spiritual life.
- Is it that simple?
- No.
It takes hard work,
commitment, God's help.
- But I'm finally happy.
- Really a matter of what you wanna do.
- I don't wanna feel like dying.
- Jesus wants you to live, Julien.
- I'm tired of living like this.
- You don't have to anymore.
Oh, shit. Come on, now.
Come on, man. Come on!
Come on! Come on!
Oh, shit, man. No, no, no.
Come on, man. Grab him right there!
Oh, come on, now. No, no.
Sweet Jesus, just...
Get him right now! Underneath!
Underneath!
No! He doesn't know when he's down!
Get him. Come on!
Sweet Jesus! Come on, get up!
What the hell happened?
You lost, ése.
He's all right, man. I'm telling you.
Hey, Shane, man,
I'd like you to meet Pazi.
Gabo tells me you're interested
in making a trade.
Yeah, that's right.
- He was impressive.
- He's dead.
He is mismatched against that Jumper.
It's how he died that counts, huh?
Hey, man, he died good.
You gonna hook me up
with some firepower?
I need to see your other birds, Gomer.
Then we will talk, huh?
What's your grain mixture?
Sixteen percent protein,
10 percent whole corn...
...and 9 percent scratch grain.
That's good.
- These all you brought with you?
- No, I got more back at the motel.
I got some Polaroids there on the front
seat if you wanna see them.
Hold it! Drop it, drop it! Drop it, ése.
Easy.
Drop it! Man, what are you thinking?
Get your hands where I can see them.
Dude, what are you doing?
I thought chloroform
was supposed to knock them out.
Guess this works better.
We were to wait until he
showed us the guns.
We take this guy in,
his case will be tied up for years.
I say we turn him over to the Mexicans,
where he'll be hung by his balls...
...and we make a few pesos
in the process.
- We were gonna play this one straight.
- How we changed our mind.
If you'll excuse me.
You've been manipulating police
resources...
...to crash land value
in this neighbourhood?
These flats have been
spiralling down for years, Vic.
Your mistress has been buying up
property in this area like she's Disney.
But it's not for her. It's for you.
Two women are dead because
of your little scam.
- And that banger?
- He had it coming.
You're playing violins
for these dope dealers now?
What's phase two?
Send me to clean up the area,
and you sell it off at a profit?
You and your boys
never supplement your income?
Look around, Ben. Where's the good
in what you're doing?
The good is, I'll cut you in.
- Where's your girlfriend?
- Gardner Bungalows, over Sunset.
- Just like the old days, huh?
- When do I start getting my paydays?
Soon. Real soon.
Hasta la vista, amigo. Different kind
of cockfighting where you're headed.
Yeah, you said it.
You lied to me, man. You lied.
I'm not doing anything
the Mack-man wouldn't.
- I'm just branching out.
- You lied to me.
Look, this is 25 G's, brother.
Ten for you, 10 for me and five for Vic
because he's Vic.
- What about Ronnie?
- Screw Ronnie. He's off the clock.
If you don't want it, I'll share it
between me and Vic.
Look, you do this to me again,
I'm gonna kick your redneck ass.
Don't even give me that look, bro.
- I spoke to my reverend.
- Good for you. It helped?
God has a plan for me.
I'm gonna start this program...
...where I'm gonna be taught
how to reconnect with women.
- God's gonna make you straight?
- God's offering me a cure.
It's called sexual-reorientation therapy.
It really works.
You give me back my microwave.
I'm not kidding.
Pump your brakes, all right?
Welfare don't make you special.
- You got to pay like everybody else.
- I am not scared of you.
- Ma'am, what's the problem?
- He keeps taking our stuff...
...and make us buy it back.
That is my microwave!
- No, it ain't.
- Do you have any proof?
Sure. After he stole it the last time,
I carved my initials on the back.
E.B. That's me. Emily Berry.
Officer, she's lying.
E.B. Stands for excellent buy.
I mark all my best stuff like that.
How about my picture frame, then?
That is not your picture frame,
but you can get it for $10.
If that's your picture frame, how come
that's me and my granddaughter?
Dookie, you wanna turn around?
There's gotta be
some miscommunication...
- Let's go. Let's go.
- Oh, come on, grandma...
...ain't no love for Dookie?
None. Go.
All right, everybody.
Show's over. Come on.
Take what belongs to you
and just go on home.
Hey, come on. That's mine.
That's mine. That's my VCR.
- Come with me.
- What's the matter?
- Someone leaked the 911 tapes.
- Shit.
It's all over the press.
We got a situation brewing.
- Bad?
- When we get there, you do the talking.
Coming from you,
a plea for peace will sound more...
Black.
- What did you get on Gilroy?
- Checked out that hideaway.
- And?
- The mistress never checked in.
- Another lie? What is he doing?
- Maybe he stashed her someplace else.
- Or slashed her someplace else.
- Oh, Jesus Christ.
- I took Gilroy for a quiet drunk.
- It's the quiet ones you worry about.
He doesn't see a way out.
He just needs to calm down.
If that doesn't work, then what?
He's got you on the same hook
as him for that murder.
- Yeah?
- Hey, it's me. Where are you?
- Still at work.
- Dinner's almost ready.
- I'm gonna have to miss dinner tonight.
- Vic.
- I'm sorry.
- Oh, you're kidding, right?
- Sweetheart, I can't make it.
- But Ben's already here.
- What?
- Come see the bowl I made in art class.
- Gilroy's there?
- In a second, Cass.
You invite him to dinner,
and you're not gonna show?
- Let me talk to him.
- Corrine!
Hey, buddy,
you gotta stop working so hard.
- What are you doing at my house?
- This case you're on, it's a dead end.
Ben, what are you doing?
- Why did you go looking for that girl?
- Hey, you lied to me.
- Where is she? Is she still alive?
- We were back in business.
- You should have just left it alone.
- I'll leave it alone now, Ben.
- No, you won't, Vic. I know you.
- Come see the bowl I made.
- Okay, sweetheart.
- Ben, this is between you and me.
- You leave my family out of this.
- You should have left Sedona out of it.
- Spend more time with your family, Vic.
- You tell him.
- You'll lose them before you know it.
- Come on.
- You think about what you're doing.
- Here I come, doll.
No! No! Goddamn it!
The sheriffs can get there
faster than we can.
911 for no one
Where were the cops?
I know you're angry.
This is a serious problem.
- Be no problem in Beverly Hills.
- It won't be a problem here again.
- You have my word.
- Ain't no hour wait in Bel Air.
- We need to resolve this peacefully.
- Detective Wyms is right.
Violence will only undermine
what we need to do here.
- What we need is some new cops.
- What we need...
What we need is a new plan.
One that will protect all of us.
All units, pull back now.
Get the Riot Squad down here.
Get them down here now!
- Are you okay?
- Vic, what's going on? They broke in.
- Where are the kids?
- In here. Why are these sheriffs here?
- Where's Gilroy?
- He left. He said he'd take a rain check.
- Okay. Thanks, fellas. I appreciate it.
- Come on, let's go. I'll walk you out.
Let's go.
Daddy's okay.
Pack bags for you and the kids.
You're not staying here.
- What? This is our house.
- It isn't safe.
- Why not?
- I'll explain it later.
- Explain now! What's going on?
- Corrine, don't ask questions. Do it!
Come on, come on.
He crossed the line, man.
He's done.
- Daddy.
- Hey, hey.
- Where are we going?
- It's okay, sweetie.
We're just gonna take a little trip.
Riot Guard. Let's go. Let's go.
Move. Come on.
Move. Let's move.
Pull back! Everybody pull back!
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group