Previously on Bionic Woman
This saving the world thing...
I'd like to give that a try.
Anything else?
What are you doing?
I'm trying to buy back your love
because I've been working so much.
You get some bad ideas in your head
these days, don't you, Sarah?
It's the bionics, isn't it?
They've changed me.
Turned me into this thing.
We think Sarah Corvus might be working
with Anthony Anthros.
Will's father?
He escaped from prison.
He tried to sell bionics
to the highest bider.
Am I ticking time bomb too?
I guess I just want to know the truth.
About everything.
I don't like secrets, Jamie.
You're not gonna kill me twice, are you?
Oh we all know,
that if your training is worth a damn,
I should be able to take this crowbar
and swing it as hard
and as fast as humanly possible...
This is what you call
"studying at Rachel's house"?
Who the hell is she?
Nobody.
- Jamie, stop!
- You lied to me!
You looked me right in the face
and you lied.
- You're a piece of work!
- Are you insane?
This is the thanks I get
for buying you those jeans?
What the hell is wrong with you?
You're 15.
- What do you think you're doing?
- I'm living my life, Jamie.
- It's none of your business.
- Yes, it is my business.
Do you know she's 15 years old?
You could go to jail!
- You said you were 18.
- Shut up!
We're going home.
What did you do to my toe?
It's my toe,
and why does it hurt? What happened
to the self-healing anthrocytes?
Well, you're an early prototype, Jamie.
As time goes on, we're gonna discover
countless imperfections.
That's so not reassuring.
And you're giving me the creeps.
You keep staring at it.
Do you have a foot fetish?
Actually, no, Jamie, I do not.
I'm pretty much just a simple boob man.
You did this surveiling your sister?
She lied right to my face.
Just looked at me and lied.
"I'm going to Rachel's house."
Well, that's what teenagers do.
They lie. They get tatoos.
They have wild sex,
and then knock off liquor stores.
Your toe is screwed.
I'm gonna have to shock that thing
into submission.
Now this shouldn't hurt at all.
On three.
One.
- You suck!
- Here's what I think.
You cannot be grudge a teenage girl
the opportunity
to make out in parked cars
with older guys.
It's the lying.
Is it this righteous indignation
just a...
tiny bit hypocritical considering
you're a $50 million weapon
- leaving a double life?
- That's mean.
I don't really care so much about
what she does.
I know she's gonna make stupid mistakes
and all that.
I just don't want her to lie to me
because
then I can't help her.
That sounds good.
Tell her that.
Check it out.
- Good as new.
- You're a genius.
Let's keep this between us, okay?
- Sure thing.
- Thanks.
I'll see you,
and I'll raise you all in.
Everything.
That's a lot of coin.
You know, people say
that men take all the risks.
I'm here to tell you it isn't true.
You all turn out to be a bunch
of scared litlle boys.
It's disappointing.
It really is.
Sarah, put your hands on your head.
My guess's the fun's over.
This is my boyfriend.
It's an on again off
again sort of thing.
You know how it is.
I kill all those people.
He shot me in the head.
Our friends call us the Bickersons.
Isn't that right, honey?
But you know what they say.
At the end of the day,
the most important thing...
in the world...
is love.
I knew the game was fixed.
I'm sorry.
You owe me $27,269.31
for the toe.
How'd you find out about that?
Your bionics represent
the most advanced form
of biotechnology known to man.
It was developed to protect
the human race,
not spy on your delinquent sister.
I find your whole proprietary attitude
about my body
to be deeply inappropriate.
How's the toe?
Take a look at this.
My name is Marc Stevens.
I'm an american doctor
working in Paraguay.
I'm being held against my will.
They say that they'll kill me unless...
A group that calls themselves
the "sons of the red sand" took Stevens
in Ciudad del Este two days ago.
- They claim he's CIAn.
- Is he?
He's American.
That's enough for them.
He's got some incredibly
sensitive information,
and they're gonna behead him in 48 hours
unless the CIA admits he's theirs,
which they won't.
So why is this our problem?
You mean besides he's an american
who would get his head chopped off?
I mean, why isn't the military
sending someone in?
Paraguay never passed
any anti-terrorism laws.
They're not about to let the US mount
an operation on their soil.
- But we can?
- The two of you can.
Anything that looks like
special OPS is out.
But an american couple moving
about the city?
I wanna help this guy, but I don't think
I can fly off to Paraguay right now
- Becca...
- Becca'll be watched 24/7
by a surveillance team.
Okay, I'm in.
Just... What am I gonna tell Becca?
You'll think of something.
The eggs!
You were cooking?
Who are you making breakfast for?
You.
Why are you making me breakfast?
About last night.
- I just want to clear the air. I was...
- Fine.
Look, I'm sorry I lied to you.
Yeah, I mean, shouldn't have done it.
It was dumb.
Besides, that guy's a creep anyway.
Mean, usually
those internet chat room guys,
you know, they turn out
to be reasonably cool.
Oh, my God!
I'm kidding.
God, you think I'm retarded?
- No, I don't think you're retarded.
- Yeah, you do.
So what's going on with you?
Carly invited me up to Napa to...
celebrate her getting into law school.
That should be fun.
- We land on an airstrip.
- An airstrip?
Is that different from an airport?
Yeah, it's dirt.
I have an asset in place, a local cop.
He's gonna help us
locate Stevens when we get there.
How can you land a 747 on a dirt runway?
No, it's not a 747.
It's a little gulfream.
Really?
You okay with that?
Yeah, I'm good.
Do you have anti-anxiety meds?
Sedatives? Anything in that area?
Hi, Jamie.
How's it going?
You look great.
How's Becca?
Stevens is running out of time.
We have to go now.
Jonas will take care of her.
Okay?
We're almost done.
I'm just getting started.
Let him go, Sarah.
Take him to the infirmary.
You're not helping yourself.
Reflexes.
Your reflexes were recalibrated
through sensory neurons
with your original surgery.
That was hostility.
You noticed.
A girl likes to be noticed.
Let's cut to the chase.
You're having hand tremors,
night sweats, anxiety, paranoia.
Even paranoids have enemies.
The bottom line is the medicine Anthros
gave you barely gave you any relief.
The truth is it probably made you worse.
And you're gonna fix me?
- My hero.
- It's not what you want.
From you?
I want nothing.
Kill me or let me go.
You know, I tried that once before.
It didn't work.
This time I thougt it'd help.
You don't know how.
Will was working on upgrades.
I want Anthony Anthros.
You tell me where he is,
you get your life back.
You're full of crap, Jonas.
And you're getting worse.
Who made me this way?
You're a liar, Jonas!
A liar playing God!
My contact has a very good idea
where Stevens is being held.
He's gonna meet us there.
Hook us up with some transportation...
You okay?
I'm scared of flying.
I couldn't find any drugs,
and I think getting wasted
before a mission is a bad idea.
I just think you know, a hunk of metal
in the sky. Counterintuitive.
Okay.
Let's talk about something else.
I'm upset because I keep lying
my sister about my job.
You're protecting her.
You're not lying.
If she knew the truth about you putting
your life on the line, I don't think
- she would be able to handle that?
- I don't think I buy that.
- Everybody should know the truth.
- The world doesn't work like that.
But then how can you have trust?
Trust and full disclose
is not the same thing.
You trust me right?
- Relatively speaking.
- But what do you know about me?
What have I disclosed?
- It is supposed to make me feel better?
- All you need to know
is that we are a team
and that I have your back.
Isn't that enough?
Thank you.
Easy, tiger. Easy...
That's your bionic hand.
Sorry.
We must hurry.
No one can know we've met.
Remember,
Paraguay is a complicated place.
We have no law against terrorism.
This group has
a legimate business interests.
Kidnap and ransom is legimate?
All the perimeter doors are alarmed.
The only other access is
through the venting system.
But it's blocked by an exhaust fan.
It'll take your head off
before they will.
Thanks.
We'll keep that in mind.
If they catch you,
I don't know you.
My police won't help you.
My opinion, for what little
it's worth, this is suicide.
But you americans know all
there is to know
about handling these foreign
situations, yes?
He's an optimist.
OK, we get in, we get him, we get out.
Sure, easy
there wasn't supposed to be an alarm.
Just get us in.
You know how to disarm it?
Stevens' life is ticking away.
Just do it.
Trust me.
You're a machine. Don't think about it.
Even if it's not real,
it's still attached.
I'd like to keep it that way.
Give me a second.
You see?
Matter over mind
What now?
Are you crazy?
What the hell are you doing?
I suggest you follow my lead
or you'll be shot.
You told me I could trust you.
Beauty is supposed to be
the mark god sets upon vertue.
And are you god in that homily
She got less virtue
than she bargained for.
I know you don't want to believe this,
but every step of the way
She had no bigger supporter than me.
Why make her your enemy?
She needs help.
Will came up with a fix
before he was killed.
Swap out the nerve bundle infuse
new anthrocytes.
She knows where anthros is.
He's been giving her treatment.
Maybe if you fed her, she'talk.
Chicken, egg.
Be her friend, Jae.
You want to help her?
Help her help herself.
At least we're together.
You're out of your mind.
We're about to be executed.
They want to make an example out
of us to stevens,
or they make an example out
of him for us.
Either way, that gets us to him
I need you to lose the fear
and go bionic.
if I told you what I was going to do,
you would've backed out!
Friends of yours?
I believe, Dr. Stevens
that you don't believe
what whappen to you if you don't decode
the contents of your flashe drive.
Which is nothing compared to
what will happen to her.
Please, I'm working as fast as can.
Perhaps you need a little inspiration,
it's a multi-level asymtric encryption!
It's gonna take time.
Now could be a good time, Jamie.
Jamie, now!
Jonas says he can help you.
And he's got every reason to lie.
He's also a man of self-interest.
You're valuable to him.
He's playing you.
Getting off watching this dance.
Or you're playing.
I want you to know you can trust me.
I want you back.
We all want something back.
Believe if Jonas could help me,
I don't trust him.
You trust me?
Bring me proof
that jonas is telling the truth.
That they made advancements
they can use to fix me
I might remember
where he can find anthros.
Take this rope.
We'll tie him and take him.
take the rop tie his hands up.
We gotta move.
What are you gonna do to him?
No worse than
what he was going do to you.
You want answers, right?
And when you're done,
Take him down to the fan room.
What about you and Stevens?
What about me?
He stays.
What are you talking about?
You deciphered the flash drive.
- You were stalling.
- You read it!
What was on the flash drive?
Tell me.
You.
Blueprints, materials, everything
there is to know about bionics.
If you know what was on that drive,
you know who gave it to me.
To decipher, not to read.
This doesn't make any sens
we came here to save him.
And we would have.
I'm not gonna say anything.
Yeah, until you're caught, tortured,
or your brother is taken.
They put a machete to a pretty girl's
neck and you were gonna give it up.
I was trying to save you.
Take him down to the fan room.
So you're just gonna kill him,
is that it?
Jamie, go.
Go!
Far end of the building, fan room,
I'll meet you there, go.
You let him go, he talks,
you're in the crosshairs.
A target for people to catch
and dissect. You won't last a month.
Then I won't.
Are you okay?
You've been hit.
Go through.
Thank you.
- What you did back there.
- Stupid
I'm gonna get us both killed.
I have no plan. You know that, right?
There'll be supplies in here
for your wound.
- We can't stop.
- No, you can't keep going.
Can you get the lock?
Can you see what numbers to push?
Your eye, can you tell what numbers?
2 5 6 9.
These are usually four digit codes.
That gives us 24 combinations.
Let's try it in reverse.
Highest probability.
All right.
Who gave you the flash drive?
I have a contact.
A voice on the phone.
When he needs help, he tells me
where to pick things up.
What about the terrorists?
Do you know who hired them?
I assumed it was just them.
Somebody tipped 'em off to
what I was doing.
Your body's in shock.
You really are a doctor?
It's not just a cover?
Yale medical school.
Two-year residency at walter reed.
Specialty in espionage?
I was always kind of a savant
with word games and puzzles.
How many words can you make out of the
letters in yoo-hoo, that kind of thing.
I was showing off one day at Walter Reed
and a CIA guy recruited me.
How bad?
The human response to a foreign
object is to repel it
And fight it like an infection.
But you...
Aren't human?
You have anthrocytes.
The files say they're designed
to keep your body
From rejecting the bionics. So they work
to incorporate what's foreign
and not repel it.
Doesn't sound so bad.
The anthrocytes are moving the bullet.
It could damage other organs.
I need to take it out.
Now.
She could be dead.
No, she's not.
She's still green.
- It was your idea to send her in, Jonas
- And you nearly got her executed!
You know the risk involved better
than anyone, buddy.
No, willingly surrendering a $54 million
bionic woman is not in my play book.
Well, it got us inside to get stevens
and the flash drive.
You don't have the flash drive,
and you don't have Jamie.
Well, how about I get off the phone
so I can go and find her?
- You better.
And Antonio?
You treat her like she's expendable
again, I won't be this nice.
Do not tell me how to do my job.
I'm gonna go and get your girl back.
What are you doing here?
Nice to see you too.
- Seriously, what are you doing here?
- Is everything okay?
Yeah, I just borrowed these from Jamie.
Is she home?
No, she's in Napa...
With you.
Excuse me?
Exactly.
What are you looking for?
What you promised Sarah.
Proof of Will's upgrades.
You told me to get her trust.
I'm trying to get her trust.
You didn't trust me.
There's nothing here.
No files at all.
What is going on, Jonas?
I don't know.
So you lied to me?
I told you will was working on
fixes, not that I had them.
Apparently, the files are on a
flash drive in Paraguay.
How?
I don't think we knew Will
as well as we thought.
Ah, damn it!
Sorry.
Not what you want to be hearing
from your surgeon.
Are you holding up?
I've been sitting here thinking
about all the lies ve been told.
All the lies I've been telling,
even to myself.
How do you make peace with it?
You don't.
You do what you can.
Sometimes you pay a price.
Three years ago, a lie I deciphered
lead to a bombing raid in Iraq.
87 civilians killed.
Another 113 injured.
I'm sorry.
So I came to triple border...
To atone.
Doctoring people who have nothing.
What about the CIA?
Occasionally they ask a favor.
But now I only succeed at deciphering
those things that I can live with.
I can live with.
If you had told the terrorists what you
knew about me, they might've let you go.
Yeah, and I'd have given them the
technology to do what?
And then who would they
have sold it to?
Do the files say why it does that?
It stops after a few minutes?
What?
It's your bionic interface...
Failing...
And being reset.
It keeps happening.
It's inherent in the system.
And?
The anthrocytes function like
an anti-rejection drug.
But over time,
they become fatigued.
So they'll replace them?
On the flash drive,
they've talked about
a five-year...
projection.
Until what?
Bionic systems cease to function.
What does that mean?
You're gonna die.
You can lead a horse to water,
but you can't make him drink.
So that's where we're starting.
With horses?
Mr. Ed won't drink, you grab him by
the mane, force him under.
Hold him there long enough,
he'll swallow.
The point is to interpret the saying.
You do know your horses.
You and your sister had one
when you were little.
Am I right?
And Anne named it Coco?
What happened to Coco?
People who live in glass houses
shouldn't throw stones.
Or have sex without curtains.
Me, I like throwing stones.
Wakes people up.
You're caught between a rock
and a hard place.
Now you're just trying to be funny.
Actually, I'm just trying to do my job,
which as much as I don't like it,
it means trying to understand you.
I'm messed up, honey.
See, now we're getting somewhere.
Does that make you all warm
and cuddly inside?
You should know I don't
do warm and cuddly.
You're caught between a rock
and a hard place.
Well, we both know how
that ends, don't we?
Three.
Three?
You can make three words out of yoo-hoo.
Oh, yoo, and ooh.
Actually, nine.
You know, what I said...
I'm sorry.
No, it's good to hear the
truth for once.
- He's coming.
- Who?
Quick.
Around the back.
Here.
Hold on to this, wait here.
- Wait, what are you...
- Just do it.
There is no fix, is there?
Jonas is predictable, if nothing else.
Tell me you love me.
I love you.
Let him go!
Stand down, stand down!
Sarah, stop.
Seriously, is that the psychological
way of talking me down?
- Let Jae go.
- And you'll what?
Help me?
- Where is he?
- Gone.
Jamie, where is he?
You were gonna kill him.
I was just doing my job.
You kept me completely in the dark.
Sometimes that's what the job requires.
I refuse to believe that killing an
innocent person
could ever make things right.
Yeah, well, that information on
the flash drive could save you.
What we were doing here was for you.
You think cause I cost $50 million,
my life is worth more than his?
Oh, we can talk about that later.
Give him up now.
No.
No!
Stevens is what we call
collateral damage.
Killing him saves you.
Maybe one day you'll understand that.
You want Stevens...
You're gonna have to get through me.
And this time you'll have to do
it without a crowbar.
I find this inappropriate
workplace behavior.
- Now who's being inappropriate?
- You don't want to fight me.
You know what I'm capable of.
Just because you're a machine
doesn't mean you can't be beat.
That hurt?
Yep.
You've gotta get out of here...
She took that pen from the tech.
The one with the multi-fractured hands.
She figured you'd never help.
The point is moot.
She's gone.
So is Will's flash drive.
Seems Jamie and Antonio had
a misunderstanding.
That can be dangerous.
Antonio's doctor can attest to that.
So if... If Will's work is gone,
then what?
Sarah's gonna die?
I wouldn't want to be in her shoes.
I have never been snowboarding.
That seems insane to me now.
I can't believe I've lived my whole
life never having done that.
My friends all head up to snow together.
Usually in february.
You should come.
Oh, you know.
Can't plan that far in advance.
Like to live in the moment?
Go for it.
See it, want it, take it never
look back at the carnage.
Exactly.
Life's too short.
You have no idea.
What do you say you and
I get out of here?
Okay.
Five years?
Listen, five years is a lifetime in
technology, Jamie, it's generations.
You didn't think I had a right to know?
Yeah, I just didn't want to tell you.
- I wanted to protect you from...
- No, stop.
This is my life.
You will not treat me like this.
I'm entitled to know
you will not lie to me.
- It's disgusting.
- You're right.
You're right I'm sorry.
My sister.
We will find a way to fix this.
Jamie, look at me.
I will fix this.
I'll fix this.
How was your trip?
Good.
Yeah, you have fun with Carly?
Yeah, we hung out.
It was cool...
Look, are you, like, having an affair
with a married man or something?
What?
Carly dropped off your shoes.
God, you know, I mean,
you're just like dad.
You make these big pronouncements,
but I can't even trust a word you say.
And you think that I'm the liar?
Look, what is going on, Jamie?
Just tell me, okay?
I need to know.
I deserve to know.
I can't.
I love you the most.
Remember when mom used to say that?
Yeah.
Only she'd say it so we could both hear.
Now I love you the most.
And I want to tell you everything.
But I can't, I...
Trust... It's supposed
to be a two-way street.
Yeah, I know, and it sucks.
But you have to trust me, Becca.
My new job is...
It's complicated.
I just...
I need to know that you're
never gonna leave me.
I will never leave you.
Transcript: swsub. com
Synchro: bbd1980, Kasius, IceFre@k