Previously on Bionic Woman
If I had the pleasure to take
this monster down, I'd along
- from that roof-top.
- You've done this before, haven't you?
You wanna tell me why you knew
he was arriving at the airport
before Jonas even called me?
Just trust me.
They know you were here.
They're sending more agents now.
Antonio is communicating
with the assassin.
You're gonna have to bring him in.
Actually, you're gonna
have to bring him in.
You wanna tell me
what the hell is going on?
- I heard you with the assassin.
- I'm not working with the assassin.
But I do know her.
- She saved my life.
- Why the hell should I believe
- any of what you're saying?
- You gotta believe me on this one.
Julia, stop!
- Take the shot, Antonio.
- Shut up, Sommers.
He just had such a rough exterior,
you know?
You think that he doesn't care
if you're having a rough day or not,
But he does.
Or he did.
To Antonio Pope.
It was an honor to know him,
to work with him.
I'm gonna miss you, pal.
I slept with him once.
It was amazing.
Come here for a second.
So you doing okay?
Yeah, I'm good.
Because, you know, someone died,
someone who was...
A friend of yours,
who you cared about so...
You know what,
I'm getting used to it.
Honky with the dread is off the hook.
How do you think I would look
with those, honestly?
I can tell
when you're rolling your eyes.
Can you tell when I don't care?
Touché.
Why aren't you asking me who this guy is
and why we're following him?
Why aren't you peppering me
with questions?
- Fine, who is he?
- He's a bad guy.
Why is he a bad guy?
Because he does bad things.
This is starting to sound
like phone sex.
If this is what phone sex sounds
like to you, you're doing it wrong.
- You have no idea, do you?
- What about, sex?
No, none, zero.
I do know that women cry
a lot afterwards.
- Who the hell are you?
- Shut up!
What the hell was that?
How'bout you shut the hell up.
We'll get to Berkut, you can ask
your questions to somebody who cares.
- Would you just get up on your own?!
- She's totally pms-ing.
Get up!
Transcript: swsub.com
Synchro: mpm, michvanilly, Kasius, IceFre@k
Hey, it's me.
Sorry we keep missing each other.
Had another long day at work, and I...
just need to hear a friendly voice.
You know, I'm starting to...
get really confused about
what I'm doing and why.
Now I have to go upstairs, and...
put on a big smile, and see my sister,
and pretend like everything's okay.
Anyway, you're probably working too,
so, well...
Call me later.
What is he doing here?
He's doing dishes.
Why?
I don't know. He's your boss.
Why don't you go talk to him.
Hey, you wanna dry?
Becks, could you give us a minute?
I don't know what you're doing,
but this is my personal space.
Your sister watches way too much tv.
This is the home of a depressed person.
I am working all hours,
and you come here
- and critize my housekeeping?
- I came over here
because I'm concerned about you.
You've been through a lot.
You need to take some time off.
Is this 'cause I kicked that guy's ass?
It's because Antonio was your friend.
And he died.
And you need time.
Work is the only thing
holding me together right now.
If I stop and think about everything
that has happened to me,
- I'm gonna go crazy.
- I understand.
But it's not a good strategy, Jamie.
I'm no asking you, I'm telling you.
You're gonna take a vacation,
and Berkut will pay for it.
I don't take handouts.
Okay, then you can make
a delivery for me.
I need to get a briefcase
to a man in Montana.
You give it to him,
take a week off.
- Do you like to hike?
- You sure that's it?
It's just a briefcase.
Antonio used to say a briefcase
is never just a briefcase.
Yeah, well...
Antonio's dead.
Are you mad at me?
Seems like you got something
on your mind.
That's the most you've said
for the past two days.
What are we doing?
I mean, why is it okay for me
to suddenly ditch school?
You're not ditching school.
I wrote you an excuse, so it's fine.
We're just taking a little trip.
That's what we're doing.
I mean, you mope around the house
for a week, not taking care of yourself.
And, mean, clearly something is wrong.
And now, all of a sudden,
we're on this trip.
What's gonna be accomplished?
You think we're gonna have deep talks
and bond?
Yeah, that's exactly
what we're gonna do.
We're gonna talk, take spa treatments,
grab some food,
make memories.
It's gonna be great.
What are you doing here?
I want you to train me.
Train you to what?
I want to learn how to fight.
Aren't you supposed to be
at a Star Trek convention?
I'm serious, Jae.
What happened to your eye?
- JR.
- Who's JR?
He's
my older brother.
Sometimes he gets a little physical
with me.
Aren't you a little old
for your brother to be picking on you?
I'm also a little too old to be living
with my parents, but I'm working on it.
So why does he hit you?
He's just always been
a little jealous of me.
Why?
I just have to make a call.
- Don't you have to go to the bathroom.
- I do, I just need to make this call.
For work?
Look, it's the last one
I'm gonna make, okay?
After that, I'll give you my cell.
No more.
- Really?
- Really.
All right.
Sorry.
You're Jonas' girl?
Just say it so I can get out of here.
I give you the briefcase and go.
- So, all the rumours...
- Would you just say it?
You really have x-ray vision?
Yeah, I do.
Just say it.
In 1972, a crack commando unit was sent
to prison by military court
for a crime they didn't commit.
They promptly escaped
from maximum-security stockade
to the Los Angeles underground.
Still wanted by the government,
they survive as soldiers of fortune.
You have a problem,
no one can help,
you can find them,
maybe you can hire the A-Team.
You want me do the theme song for you?
Have a nice life.
You're registered in the Green Party?
What?
Are you actually gonna vote
for Dennis Kucinich?
- How do you know this?
- Visual caller ID.
Anyone calls my line,
I see their photo,
date of birth, social security number,
criminal record...
Nathan set it up for me.
Is that legal?
How's the vacation going?
Your guy's a nut job.
Is it done?
Bye, Jonas.
Thank you.
- You sure you don't miss your phone?
- Not even a little.
Your thumbs must go through withdrawal.
You haven't texted anyone in,
like, an hour.
Leave me alone.
So what are we gonna do?
There's a million things to do.
There's horseback riding.
There's a spa.
There's friggin'ballroom
dancing classes.
There's meditation with gems.
That sounds different.
How'bout we go up to the room,
order some room service, turn on the tv.
You know, eat, get really fat,
so no one will love us.
God, I love you.
Come on, let's go.
Switch.
- Okay, how can I help you?
- Our on demand isn't working,
and tv's
really important to us.
- We'll send up an engineer. What room?
- 108.
- You're 108?
- Yeah.
This guy has been
calling for you for the past hour.
He ask me to go to your room
and knock on the door.
But I told him
it against hotel policy.
He's a very pushy man.
- Sorry.
- You break it, you have to pay.
Excuse me.
Front desk.
Please hold, sir.
No, sir, I will not...
Please hold.
It's him.
Should I transfer it to
one of the courtesy phones?
- Yeah.
- Just over there.
Jaime, why did you
turn off your cell phone?
'cau you told me
need a vacation,
- so I turned my cell phone off.
- I told you to take a little time off.
Not to go off the grid.
I'm not off the grid.
It's a four star hotel I'm at.
Listen, I got a problem. My guy's
gone quiet. He never checked in.
- Oh, Jonas.
- He's a little unstable.
- No kidding.
- So can you look in on him for me?
Listen, I would never ask you to do this
if it wasn't an emergency.
- He's staying in room 203.
- He's staying here?
Yeah, I know.
I was surprised too.
He seemed like more
of a seedy motel kinda guy.
- Can you do this for me or not?
- Okay.
I was booking us spa treatments.
She kept me on hold for ten minutes.
Becks, you know, I was
thinking about what you said
and I know
you're not stupid.
I know I've been acting
weird tely, and anything. And... what?
Okay, stop talking.
Because listen, okay I met this...
- Nick. This is my sister Jaime.
- Jaime, this is Nick.
- Hey, Nick.
- Nice to meet you.
Well, I'm starving.
You wanna go get some breakfast?
Great, you two
grab a table,
and I'll run upstairs
and book the spa appointments.
In case you're looking for this,
don't even bother.
- I'm insulted.
- Okay, isn't he cute?
- Super cute.
- And we hate all the same things.
I mean...
Hello?
Oh, my god.
Yeah?
Jonas, he's dead.
He's laying right in front of me,
and he's dead.
How?
Maybe it has something to do with
the hypodermic needle
sticking out of his arm.
Damn it.
Obviously I'm on the job now, Jonas.
So just fill me in.
- No, I'm not gonna do that to you.
- What was I delivering?
- Who the hell is this guy?
- It's not your problem, Jaime.
Oh, my god.
He's an assassin?!
- Were you gonna have somebody killed?
- What was in that briefcase?
- Don't worry about it.
- Don't worry about it?
- The guy lying here dead.
Someone is gonna
come in and find him.
Listen, put him in the bathtub.
Get a bunch of ice
and some air fresheners,
and I'll send someone down
to deal with it as soon as I can.
I can't believe
this is happening.
What am I supposed to do
with the briefcase?
Put it in your room, I'll have
someone deal with that too.
Jonas, I'm here with my sister.
She's with you?
Nothing's gonna happen
to Becca. All right?
I promise you.
Good Morning.
Hey, we were about
to send a search party.
Sorry,
I was on the phone
to the spa,
and then I just passed out.
- We have treatments at 5:00.
- Oh, okay. Cool. Sweet.
Is it cool if we go with Nick and
his dad on a gondola ride at 1:00?
- You want to go on a gondola?
- No.
- No, no we won't.
- But, his dad's making him go,
so I thought we'd go
for moral support.
- We'd love to.
- Cool.
- Nick.
- Hi, dad.
Been looking
all over for you.
Well, I'm right here.
These lovely ladies as an excuse
to avoid that gondola ride,
- are you, s**rt?
- No, dad.
- They're gonna come too.
- Great.
The more the merrier.
I'm Vincent Aldridge. I'm Nick's dad.
- Hi.
- Nice to meet you.
Come on, it not that painful.
Give us a smile.
This is why I told you
I didn't want to work with Javier.
I've got a body on ice, a target
in play, and nobody to squeeze.
Well, then you
just make it right.
- Hi, I'm Jaime.
- I'll call you back, man.
- I'm Matt. How's it going?
- Could I have your cellphone for a sec?
- Yeah, sure. My minutes are minutes.
- Okay.
- I'll be right back, Mike.
- Matt.
- Hello.
- Jonas.
I... I opened the briefcase.
The target's son is now flirting
with my sister.
We're all supposed to being
on a gondola ride at 1:00.
- Who is he?
- He's a very bad guy, Jaime.
And you're
way out of your league.
Can you just fill me in
on everything?
Okay, he's a nuclear engineer
who's about to sell technology
to the north koreans.
He's posing as an accountant.
What kind of technology?
He's developed a more efficient way
to enrich plutonium.
It'll give 'em weapons-grade
fissile material that's 99% pure.
You're looking at man
who's about to hand
North Korea nuclear bomb.
- Don't they already have one?
- This one would work.
By the way, who...
- Who the hell is matthew clarkson?
- I have no idea.
Whose phone is it
that you're calling me from?
Oh, it's the valet guy.
Looks like a dweeb.
- Okay. Hey, thanks, Mark.
- Matt.
Yeah.
You're not so much of a dweeb.
Thanks.
So it's like boom. Twist.
Back.
- There you go.
- OK. All right. I can.
- I can take little bit more if he's...
- Give him a little bit more.
I can take a little...
All right, let's do this.
All right, I can take a little more.
What'd you...
- Easy, easy.
- Oh, god.
It's all
the weapons around...
What are you doing? I've been looking
all over for you.
Jae's teaching me
how to fight.
What happened
to your eye?
- Oh, my brother...
- I actually don't even want to know.
So listen.
We've locked in on the engineer in
Montana, but I can't find a button man.
- What are you gonna do?
- I'm going to montana.
- And you're coming with me.
- Why am I coming with you?
- Is he ready?
- Yeah, he's got a couple of moves.
- R... ready? What?
- It's actually only one move.
He'll be all right.
You're my backup.
If I miss the target, go center mass,
Then put one in his head.
- What? I'm not...
- I'm kidding.
- I'm not that guy.
- I'm kidding. I'm kidding.
I need you there in case Vincent
has some of his research,
we need to figure it out.
- Go get some kevlar.
- Some kev...
So, Jaime,
- What line of work are you in?
- She sells timeshares.
No kidding.
I have a timeshare in St. Barts.
Six weeks in the winter. Three bedrooms,
right on the beach, pool.
It's fantastic.
Unfortunately, I can't use it this year,
and I'd like to sell it.
But since they introduced
that new tax clause...
I'm sorry to intervene, Mr. Aldridge,
but we kind of have a no work hole
- in effect right now.
- I'm sorry. I completely understand.
Gotta play too, right?
Yeah, sometimes you mistake
your job for your life.
Which isn't
such a bad thing
if you love
what you do.
- Do you love what you do, Mr. Aldridge?
- Are you kidding me?
I wake up every morning with a giant
smile plastered on my face
because I love what i do so much.
Jaime, please, call me Vincent?
Who are those guys,
Vincent?
Oh, well believe it or not,
there are some people out there
who don't love
what I do.
Who would have thought accounting
could be so controversal.
Yeah.
What time is it?
Oh, boy, you know,
I've got to get you back
to the room, sport.
I promised your mom you'd call.
And, I believe you two ladies
have some spa appointments.
Watch your step, ladies and gentlemen.
- Maybe we'll see you guys for dinner?
- Yeah.
Sure.
Come on, Nick, let's go.
- What was that about accounting?
- What?
Nick's dad never said
he was an accountant.
It was a real conversation stopper.
Okay, I'm gonna go shower and warm up
before we go to the spa.
Jonas, I think I messed up.
I think I got made.
Is that what you say?
This guy Vincent, I think he made me.
Okay, that's a problem.
Yeah, I know it is. What do I do now?
You're gonna have to take him out.
Take him out where?
Jaime, listen to me.
He knows who you are.
He's not gonna wait long. You
have to kill him before he kills you.
Okay, I'm all robed up.
You ready for the most relaxing
three hours of our lives?
- Totally.
- Let's go.
Let's go.
Heat wraps or...
Rejuvenating facial.
Yeah, your skin's too young
for anything else.
Right this way, miss Sommers.
So I'll see you in three hours.
Yeah, we probably won't even recognize
ourselves, we'll be so pretty.
I have to leave.
If you could make sure she stays
in that room for the next three hours,
I'll make it worth Your while.
- Okay.
- Thanks.
- I don't think I can do this.
- Trust me, I understand.
Do you have any advice?
I do, but you're not gonna like it.
- Don't think of him as a person.
- That's gonna be hard for me.
I just spent two hours
on a gondola with him and his son.
You gotta think about what could
happen if you don't do it, jaime.
It does get easier.
That's what scares me.
Thanks, jae.
- Hi.
- Yes.
- I need to talk to Vincent.
- I'm sorry, he's not here.
I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
Well, if I could just take a look,
that would be...
okay, we can do this
the easy way or the hard Way.
You're coming with me.
It's on the left.
Did you do it?
No, I couldn't do it.
I was nowhere near being able to do it.
You know, in an hour and 45 minutes
Becca is gonna walk through that door.
So can you tell me
what I'm supposed to do?
I need you to calm down and
put him on the phone.
He wants to talk to you.
Vincent, Jonas Bledsoe here.
Nice to meet you over the phone.
You with me?
Yes, I'm here.
The way I see it,
you've got two options.
Number one, I kill you.
The other one is you talk.
And by "talk" I mean
you tell me everything
I need to know to keep
this technology out of north Korea.
Which would you prefer?
It doesn't matter to me. I just need
to know whether or not to wear gloves.
I understand your son is with you.
I'll talk.
But you've got to get me out of here,
or my own people will kill me first.
And my son comes with me.
Done.
- Where are we going?
- Little change of plans.
Do you wanna get my car, please?
- I called for Mr. Aldridge's car.
- Fine.
- I'll drive.
- Thank you.
What's going on, dad?
You're gonna have to tell
him sooner or later.
I can raise my son without your help.
Thank you.
It's nothing you need
to worry about, Nick.
Does it have something
to do with your job?
- You hear that?
- Hear what?
- Get out of the car.
- Why?
Get out!
- Get out.
- Dad, it won't open.
- Open the door.
- I can't open it!
- Open the door!
- Dad, it's stuck.
Come on. Come on.
It's all in the wrist.
Somebody tried to blow up Vincent's
car with him in it.
- Is he okay?
- Yeah.
Where are you?
- Five miles south of the hotel.
- How are you fixed for transportation?
- I stole a car.
- That's my girl.
Look, we're heading west on the road.
I think we're being followed.
Well, slow down and see if he passes.
We should... we should get away more
often together, road trip.
- Shut up.
He passed.
A good tail is always from the front.
- You hungry, Sport?
- No.
Who are you? And how the hell
did you rip that door off my car?
Maybe you should be happy
I did and not ask questions.
You saved my son's life.
Thank you for that.
- He's a sweet kid.
- He takes after his mom.
I think I've lost him.
Maybe he deserves to know
the truth about his dad.
Maybe your sister deserves
to know the truth about you.
It's a different situation.
Hello.
- Did you get the plate on that truck?
- X-u-v-0-5.
Well, it's here, and so am I.
Get out of there and meet me up front.
We need to move now.
- Let's get you out of here right now.
- What about my son?
We'll pick up his mother
and protect them.
You can speak to 'em after
you've made your statement.
Jaime! Jaime, it's Matt!
- Who's that guy?
- The valet guy.
The guy whose
phone I used to call you.
The guy whose phone you used
looked nothing like this.
- Clean this up for me.
- I'll take you back to the hotel.
It's gonna be all right. The Berkut
guys are on their way.
Now, Nathan.
I'm worried that if I keep lying to her,
i'm gonna lose her.
So don't lie to her.
I don't want her to think I'm a freak.
Listen, I never said
you couldn't tell her.
You've got to do what's right for your
family. I found that out too late.
The question you have to ask yourself...
Is is she ready to hear it?
Anything has to be better than this.
Maybe, maybe not.
See, here's the thing,
every person who knows
is a potential source
of information for people
who might want to scrap
you for parts or technology.
Teenagers aren't exactly known
for their discretion.
And if...
If you're at great risk,
then so is Becca.
- It's complicated.
- Yeah.
I think either way she's lucky
because she's got you for a big sister.
Thanks.
How was yours?
- It was great.
- You look great.
Yeah.
Look, I wouldn't tip your girl too much.
I'm sorry, you don't look any better.
That was, like, three hours for nothing.
Thanks. Come on.
- Nick never said good-bye.
- No?
No. That's okay though,
I wasn't that into him anyway.
- Oh, this trip had learning.
- Hey.
Yes, it's more fun to be with a
guy who gives you the time of day.
Good for you.
And I'm glad we came.
I had fun with you.
Maybe we could do this again sometime.
What?
What? You're freaking me out.
Is there something on your mind?
There's something I should tell you.
What?
There this guy who I work with who died.
I didn't even really know him that well,
but...
... what I realized is
it's really affected me.
- Was he a guy you liked or something?
- No, it wasn't like that.
I'm really sorry.
- Why didn't you tell me about this?
- I didn't want you to worry about me.
- Well, that was really stupid.
- I know.
Jaime, you can talk to me
about this stuff.
- I'm stronger than you think I am.
- Okay.
Now, is there anything else you
want to tell me?
No. Nothing at all.