I... didn't want to.
I'm not in control.
I know.
Tell me you love me.
I love you.
We're out of Stoly!
Becca!
- What?
- The music's too loud.
What now?
Why is the door locked?
What are you doing?
Where is it?
Where's what?
You're not allowed to be near a
computer plugged into a phone line
Or would I have to show you
the court order.
- Why don't you email it to me?
- Becca.
Go ahead, tear the room apart,
do you see a computer in here?
No.
That means the only thing that it's
in here that doesn't belong
is drum roll please, you
I'm driving you to school
in ten minutes.
Too easy.
That's not real food.
You're not a real mum.
What's your problem?
You know, dad didn't try to control me.
- Dad trusted me, OK?
- Dad dropped you off on my doorstep.
If you want to live with dad,
live with dad, if you can find him.
Here's what to do.
Look for a big protest rally.
Then find the nearest bar.
You think you remember, but you don't.
The victim of a Baghdad car bombing.
Needed transplants,
and facial reconstructions.
This triathlete was told
he would never compete again.
For some women, bigger is better.
What these people have in common
is that they have each on some level,
... altered themselves.
But where is the threshold?
When is it okay,
to intervene in God's work?
This question is the very
cornerstone of bioethics,
and we're gonna spend the rest
of the semester dealing with it.
Come on, Will.
I am a bartender and a dropout.
- You're a professor.
- And a surgeon.
How can you take me seriously?
What makes you think
I take you seriously?
Do you?
Why are you with me?
You're different.
From what?
When your whole life's planned out
for you while you're still in the womb,
it kinda kills the mystery.
And then you came along,
and you were...
- ... unexpected.
- Unexpected?
The one choice my father
didn't make for me.
I gotta run.
- We're still on for dinner?
- 8 o'clock?
Make it 8:30, I have to go to the lab
for a few hours.
While we're on the subject,
why are you with me?
You're not entirely uncharming.
It's insulting.
The last time I left you alone,
you started a fire.
- The microwave was broken!
- We don't have a microwave.
- Look, the weird!
- They're my friends.
- Then they're your weird friends.
- Please, for me.
Tomorrow night.
Double feature?
Deal.
You look rocken.
I brought pheromones.
I gotta go, I'm gonna be late.
- Be good.
- Have fun.
I think there's a pretty good chance
the grant could come through.
The institute's indicating
it's a done deal.
And I hear Paris is great
in the spring.
You're not happy.
Of course I'm happy.
Because I think you should come with me.
I can't.
- Why not?
- I have a job.
Jaime!
And a life!
- We're talking Paris.
- And I have responsabilities.
- Did I mention it's Paris.
- I'm pregnant.
Yeah, that's what I said.
I don't want you to...
I just...
I know this isn't something
you just spring on someone
except for the part where that's exactly
what I'm doing to you right now, and...
I know you're in a place
where you can't even think about it,
and God, I'm only 24,
it's not, I mean, I said to myself,
- there's only one thing to do, but...
- Five months, fourteen days.
That's how long we've been dating.
Jaime, if someone had asked me
five months and fifteen days ago...
if I believed in love at first sight,
I would've said I absolutely did not.
And the very next day,
I would've been proven wrong.
- Will...
- Marry me.
So I'm thinking Coltrane
if it's a boy...
Billie if it's a girl.
You don't have to do this, you know.
Actually, I'm pretty sure
you have to name them.
- I mean you didn't have to...
- I know, but I'm still asking.
So what does that tell you?
Jaime.
That's not an internal bleeding.
Extensive crush injuries
to right arm and both legs.
- She's coming up!
- I need 5 more grams of Dazol.
You're gonna be OK, baby,
we're gonna put you back to sleep.
It's gonna be all right.
I promise it's gonna be okay.
Multiple compound radial and ulnar
fractures to the right arm.
- Severed brachial artery.
- Right arm's a shredder,
we're looking at complete
A-K amputation of both legs.
There were vascular damages.
Catastrophic.
- Loss of fœtal heartbeat.
- Dr. Anthros.
EP's falling. 80 systolic.
- Prep her.
- Dr. Anthros!
Do it!
Why didn't somebody stop him?
He has full clearance, we didn't have
the authority to stop him.
That's the price you pay
for working with a so called genius.
'Cause he must have left his IQ
in the car.
Debreeding the ulnar nerve.
Significant damage.
Should I intervene?
No.
This operation's patient
doesn't officially exist.
We have deniability,
it's a freebie.
We can always terminate later
if need be.
Meanwhile, get Jae.
It will have to be resected
to its branch point.
Radial nerve appears to be intact.
Forgive me, Father,
for I have sinned.
The doctor. Did you kill him?
It was like a ride at Disneyland.
Which one?
I've never been.
I'll take you.
You'll love it.
It's all fat people,
fat children
walking around aimlessly,
too stupid to know the difference.
Do you miss it?
The way things were.
If I could remember,
I'm sure I would.
Do I remind you of her?
Your skin.
Tell me you love me.
Jaime.
What happened?
There was an accident.
You're okay.
My baby...
What about the baby?
Oh God!
There was no permanent damage.
You'll be able to get pregnant again.
Why can't I feel my legs.
Okay, Jaime, I need to tell
you something.
What's happening to me?
I need to tell you about
what I had to do.
- You need to listen.
- I can't feel my arm!
Listen to me, Jaime.
Both your legs, and your arm
had to be replaced.
Also, your right ear and right eye.
Molecular machines.
Anthrocytes...
have been substituting
for one eighth of your blood cells.
Now, you should have lacerations
bone-deep all over your face.
But the anthrocytes are healing you.
At an exponential rate.
All of you.
We're making you better.
It was a dream.
The bionics enhance baseline
human strength.
And then some.
What have you done to me?
- Why did you do this to me?
- You were going to die.
Sir!
Born Jaime Wells Sommers.
Van Horn, Iowa.
February 23rd, 1983.
Mother deceased, cancer.
She's clean except for a sealed
court record from 1998.
What's in it?
- It's sealed.
- Unseal it.
I'm working on it.
I think she's a good candidate.
Let's pretend I'm solliciting opinions.
Why?
She's stable.
I pulled up an old Minnesota
multi-phasic personality inventory.
I liked what I saw.
Plus the situation with her sister
shows loyalty.
And she's smart.
I found an old IQ test.
How did she do?
A little better than you.
Sir.
Jae, can you train her?
Well, the last one
we screened, tested,
and there was psycho evaluation,
and she was a soldier.
Look where it got us.
We always talked about
non military applications.
- Here's our chance.
- Your opinion is invalid here,
you're too close to the subject.
This from the guy who played house
with the last one.
Let's get fresh data.
I want you to sit her down.
All right.
Yeah, I once had a wolf.
A wolf only makes a good pet
if it thinks it's a dog.
Your girlfriend...
We're keeping her here
against her will.
How long until she realizes
that no one
can make her do anything
against her will?
You're talking about killing a human.
I'm talking about killing a wolf.
You know what scares me about you?
Your father.
He seemed normal, too.
If I'm anything like my father,
you just made a big mistake.
All right,
we have to get you to rehab.
- What for?
- Rehabilitation.
I am not the one performing
human experiments,
and keeping people prisoner.
You rehabilitate yourself.
- I'm Ruth.
- I'm pissed.
Good.
We're here
to talk about our feelings.
How do you feel about me
being kept here against my will?
I was speaking editorially.
Actually, we're here
to talk about your feelings.
Something no one seems
to have any regard for.
Curve balls will do that.
You can have
all the contingency plans you like,
and then someone goes
and does something like this,
- and we all have to stay after school.
- And talk about our feelings.
- Your feelings.
- Right.
After all, feelings are what got us here
in the first place.
You like to draw.
- True or false...
- I have a sister.
She's staying with your landlady.
She thinks you're skying in Vail.
This is where you stayed.
It looks nice.
"We had fun.
"Except for the part where...
"Will injured his arm
skying into a tree."
Does this mean I'll be going home
at some point?
It means
that we have a contingency plan,
should you be going home
at some point.
We also have a plan,
should you not.
True or false.
"You can't teach an old dog
new tricks".
You would have done the same thing.
You never met my wife, did you?
For two years,
I watched her die in the hospital
while they disassembled her.
And the whole time,
I knew all I had to do to save her
was bringing her here,
but saving my wife was not the mission.
Ruth says she's stable.
How long until she's combat-ready?
She's a civilian.
Everyone has to sing for their supper
around here,
haven't you figured that out yet?
How long until the rest
of her implants come online?
- She likes to draw.
- I don't care.
I think you'll care about this.
Who did they bury?
I mean, did you ever see the body?
You showed this to anybody else?
- Just you.
- Keep it that way.
General alert! General Alert!
I can't protect you in here.
- We want you on the outside.
- Why should I trust you?
'Cause I'm the only one
you can trust.
Go back to your life
like none of this ever happened,
- I'll work it out with them.
- What about you?
Go. Now!
All right, I'll have those faxed
over to you by Friday afternoon,
and we're still on
for that meeting tomorrow?
Okay, good.
Yeah.
Mommy!
There's a lady out there running
really fast. Like as fast as a car!
Sweetie, what did I tell you
about making things up?
I just thought it was cool
that a girl could do that, that's all.
Let her go.
- What the hell did you do?
- You won, all right?
For the program...
I'll make her understand
what's at stake.
- Just let me have time...
- Time to what?
Letting her go is not a bad idea.
If you want her loyalty,
give her freedom.
Or the illusion of freedom.
All right.
Everybody, stand down.
- You're making a mistake.
- Listen to me.
The accident wasn't an accident.
According to the autopsy,
the driver's neck was broken
an hour before the crash.
Which means someone else was driving
that truck, and we need to find out who.
Jaime. It's will.
If you're there, pick up the phone.
I need to talk to you.
Jaime, please.
There are things I need
to tell you about.
Before they happen
Nice of you to show up!
I'm sorry.
Now what for?
For leaving and not telling you first.
How was skying?
It was fine.
Dad used to always say "Don't leave
anything until it's been denied"
Don't lie to me, OK!
We both know you don't ski.
So, where were you?
I can't tell you.
- Coffee.
- Sure.
It's no smoking.
What are you?
A forest ranger?
Something like that.
It must be scary.
Alone in the forest.
Just you, and the animals.
Not if they know who's in charge.
Wait up!
Guard!
We both know you're working
in a supermax prison
a thousand feet below Florence.
We both know this is a place
where they stick people
when they outlive their usefulness.
- I don't know who you are.
- If you don't do exactly what I say,
my brother's gonna carve your wife
Barbara up like Venus de Milo.
Oh God, Bobby
Help me.
How did you do it?
Do you know what they call creatures
that can live comfortably
in environments considered lethal,
say... for instance...
a thousand feet
below the Earth's surface?
- How did you do it?
- Extremophiles.
I'll do an impression of one
for you. Ready?
- How did you...
- What?
How did I do what?
Sarah Corvus is still alive.
And you came all the way here
to tell me that.
Let me do
another impression for you.
Impression of a man
who's been stabbed in the back.
Stripped of his rights,
and thrown in a hole like a dog.
Sarah Corvus is a time bomb.
We both know it.
Well, time bombs
only matter to those who have time.
Goodbye, Jae.
Please give my regards to Will.
Tell him Daddy says hello.
Guards!
If I may make an observation,
you seem way too innocent and sweet
to be behind a bar.
You should be out there
with the rest of 'em.
Finally. I'm not the only person
who feels that way.
- What can I get you?
- Beer.
On the house.
Thank you.
Don't I know you?
We met very briefly.
We didn't even actually meet.
- Where?
- Guess.
Are you all right?
- Yeah.
- Let me take a look at it.
It's okay.
Are you okay?
Come on.
Your husband will never know.
Please.
Are you all right?
Let me help you.
Juste breathe.
It's like that.
The first time the ear and eye implants
come online.
It's too much information.
You have to learn how to focus it.
And turn it off and on at will.
You're a fast healer.
The anthrocytes are doing their job.
Who are you?
Jaime!
Tell everyone
Sarah Corvus says hello.
Yo!
Lookin'for somethin'?
You need somethin'?
Come here, baby.
I got what you need.
Please.
Please don't.
Don't...
- Are you okay?
- Tell me what you put in my head.
I almost killed a man,
I didn't even know what I was doing.
What did you put in my head?
Microscopic chips have been implanted
in your cerebral cortex.
My father... He developed
the technology for the military.
The program was meant to help
amputees in the Gulf.
Of course, he saw the combat
applications immediately.
You made me into a soldier!
You're hard wired for highly
specialized warfare, yes.
- I was gonna kill him. I would've.
- You didn't, you're still in control,
- and with the proper training...
- Training?!
We're the only ones
that can protect you.
Let me protect you.
How can you protect me
if you're scared of me?
I never meant for any of this
to touch you,
I didn't, I just...
I couldn't bear to loose you.
That isn't even me.
Yes. It is.
Hey!
Hey.
I have to get back to Becca.
I can't keep leaving her like this.
What are you people doin' anyway?
It's complicated.
Try me.
The world's further along
than anyone wants to admit.
Technology is at the point where
science fiction isn't fiction any more.
We keep that technology
from getting into the wrong hands.
Who gets to decide right from wrong?
What about Sarah Corvus?
- Where does she figure in all this?
- Where did you hear that name?
Where did you hear the name, Jaime?
Will!
- I'm... sorry.
- Just hold on, okay?
Where is she?
I need everyone.
Time out!
The anthrocytes in our blood
can filter out
any impurities in our lungs.
Fringe benefits of being a freak.
What do you want from me?
Honestly, I'm not sure.
Jogging partner?
Who are you?
Without being too melodramatic
about the whole thing,
I'm Sarah Corvus.
The first bionic woman.
So, what did they replace?
I figured the eyes and the ears.
What else?
Me, they did both arms, both legs.
Only one eye.
Anthros wasn't sure
about the optical interface.
So I did the other one myself.
Part of my chest, too.
I'm cutting away all the parts of me
that are weak.
Time in.
You only have one bionic arm.
You should really do something
about that.
You gotta have to do
a little better than that.
How am I doing now?
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
We have a 39 year old male caucasian,
gunshot victim to the left shoulder.
Request assistance
from Mercy General.
Will gonna make it?
Miss Sommers!
Just wanted to get a look at you.
Who are you?
We have 50 million $ worth
of my property inside you
so I guess you could say
I'm your landlord.
What do you want from me?
I don't know. Maybe you died 3 days ago,
and you haven't realized it yet.
- Is that a threat?
- There are no free agents here.
Sooner or later, you'll have to make
a choice. It goes something like this.
Heads, you loose.
Tails, you die.
Welcome in the game.
If we do this...
whatever this is.
We do it on my terms.
If that's not okay with you...
I know what I'm capable of now.
So you send whoever you send.
And I'll bury one guy after the next.
You understand me?
By the way.
Sarah Corvus says hello.
Tell Jae we have a candidate.
What are you doing?
I haven't seen the moon
in a thousand and twenty three days.
It hasn't changed.
Let's go.
We've got a work to do.
Transcript: Herb Synchro: Herb & Bbd1980
Adaptation: IceFre@k