Previously, on the last seven seasons of...
Seven ?
Geez, is that right ?
Seven years of Stargate ?
Shouldn't we get a cake or something ?
Transcript: StargateDanielFriendly.Net
Adaptation SRT VO: HonnyVore & Team SG-66
Thanks to SG1 Quebec
Fine synchro:
nicotr
Thank you all for this award
Two years in a row.
Two !
Can you believe it ? Can anybody believe it."
It's hard to turn on the TV and not see Stargate
Now, if you're anywhere in the United States or
Canada, North America, it's just always on.
I know worldwide it's a huge success.
I know the DVD's are selling like crazy.
Hello Australia. I'm Amanda Tapping
Sorry... Cut !
Stargate's been on for a very, very long time.
It is a legend amongst scifi fans.
First thing I think you gotta get to have a hit show,
is someone like Richard Dean Anderson.
He's a hit.
And then you surround him with a competent cast
of characters that have a chemistry with each other.
I'm really proud of the show. I think it's a great show,
and I would never have imagined that we would have had
enough juice to keep going this long.
A huge thankyou to the fans. Because of them, we're back.
Bottom line America.
Stargate SG1 is way better without Doctor Daniel Jackson"
True story. A few day's after that segment aired,
the people at Stargate contacted Pierre
and offered him a part on the show.
One thing that's made SG1 what it is,
is the fact that audiences have wanted to bring
hose characters into their living rooms every week,
for coming up on eight years now.
Stargate SG1 is a worldwide phenomenon,
but after seven years and a hundred and fifty plus episodes,
who can remember everything ?
Let's recap shall we ?
There was a portal that you could instantaneously
transport into another planet from.
Where the series picks up,
Stargate is in the possession of the Air Force.
A team is put together, made up of
Colonel O'Neill, Captain Carter,
Doctor Jackson and Teal'c.
Clip from "The Lost City"
- This?
At.
- That is at?
- You can stop.... that.
I'd purposefully made the character
a bit dense, but that's almost cheating for me.
Clip from "Chimera"
- Most of the guys I have
dated recently, have died.
So much has happened to this woman.
Most recently, she's got herself a fella,
for the first time in seven years.
It's quite funny for me as an actor
to look back on.
Season one basically, he was a mute,
and now this year
it's just like, yak, yak, yak, yak, yak !
It's like he has a talk show or something.
Clip from "Orpheus"
- Colonel O'Neill has officially informed me
that...I have my..."Mojo" back.
Over the course,
they've had over a hundred adventures.
They've made a few enemies along the way.
There is the bad guys called the Goa'uld.
The Goa apostrophe, uld.
Clip from "Chimera"
- Now that is not normal.
The hooded characters all look like this.
"I am very evil!"
Clip from "Ascension"
- I just took this form now so that we could relate.
Actually, I used to look this way before my ascension.
A race of beings known as the Ancients,
which we've started to loosely find out about,
over the course of the eight years
that the show has been on the air,
created the Stargate.
"That's an excellent, excellent concept"
The Asgard are one of our allies.
They're grey aliens.
They're very powerful.
The Goa'uld were kind of afraid of them
for a little bit, and they
protected Earth for a long time.
"That's what us Asgard's do!"
Anubis attacks in all his ships
and Daniel Jackson who also is
an Ancient at the time, cos he ascended
was gonna stop him with his Ancient powers.
You could see it in the actual shot.
He throws his hands out at Anubis,
who's been kind of egging him on.
Oma Desala grabs Daniel Jackson
and takes all his clothes off and
throws him on this planet, naked.
If you're gonna come back,
come back naked.
But don't do it in parks in Surrey
in February in Canada,
because whatever was there,
gets smaller.
We left things in a lurch last year.
We did film something that could
have served as an ending.
We've been so many places.
Spent so much time with the franchise,
we wanted to be able to do it in
a more prepared way.
And we ended up during this year.
But hold on.
Stargate is spawning.
Stargate Atlantis is here,
and you're about to get a look at the new series,
the new cast,
and the new bad guys.
Huge set.
As you can tell.
Over there, we have one of the
biggest sound stages in the world.
The set's are just fantastic.
They're just great.
It helps me to paint a larger picture
of my world.
I've never been so excited in my entire life.
Generally any opportunity my character gets
to hit on someone in a scene,
generally I'm doing that.
The evil wraiths.
The evil wraiths. They're very scary.
They're essentially, life suckers.
I love what you do with those tentacles.
The race scared the "[BIP]" out of me,
"[BIP]" to be honest with you.
I'm Amanda Tapping, and you're getting
The Lowdown, from Stargate to Atlantis.
We've been travelling offworld through
the Stargate, for the past seven years.
Of course, after being together so long on the show,
the cast of SG1 have become much more than just co-workers.
We're a family.
A dysfunctional and eccentric one.
A cliche actually.
Things have happened. Things have changed.
Natural evolution of a show.
Now that we're into our eighth season,
something had to happen,
and they were so desperate,
they made me a General.
I think O'Neill as a General,
is actually kind of refreshing for Rick,
because he gets to experiment on things
he never did before, like sitting down.
He's much rather be out doing something,
than answering phones or dealing with paperwork.
Of course we play that up a lot in the early episodes.
He's not out there doing what he does.
Blowing up people and mouthing off,
and then mouthing off and blowing up people!
We said, no, he can blow up people by remote,
and mouth off to people by remote!
Clip from Space Race
"How many times have I told you,
Don't get caught by the bad guys."
We are after all the Air Force and will wield
those things, but I'm not preponent of guns, at all.
Quite the opposite.
There's the running joke about
shooting any one of the larger
pieces we have in there.
Everybody tends to get wood.
It may be balsam, but it's wood.
Clip from "Grace"
- Lately the dating scene has been a little stale
but then again I am marooned on a space ship!
Today, Carters on board a replicator ship,
getting tortured by Fifth.
The return of Fifth.
It's also torturous because
it's freezing cold in the studio today.
We saw our breath when we came in this morning.
We're having a heatwave outside,
but for some reason, it's freezing cold.
Which of course is the day that I,
Amanda, have to be on set half naked.
"We don't have much time to share"
Nudity's not one of my forte's, so all in all,
... a little tense.
Clip from "New Order"
- I never intended to abandon you.
You gained my trust, then you used me, and left me behind.
There's some good career things
that are gonna happen for Sam.
It's gonna give her a lot more responsibility.
We'll touch on how she handles that new responsibility.
You shall see. I shall see.
I haven't even read any scripts.
Pete the stalker. There's a lot of talk about that.
I have never gotten so much hate mail,
as in the months following the airing of that episode.
It was quite amazing.
There's a huge fan response.
Some very negative. Some quite positive.
A lot of the fans like it. A lot of the fans thought it was
great that you could see this other side of her that
you've never seen, and that she's not necessarily
comfortable with.
ou know, the flirty girly side of Sam.
Clip from "Chimera"
- This was romantic.
Watching a man dance around in the rain with an umbrella?
Just because there were no guns or car chases.
Or nudity.
Yeah, well your chances of that
are slim to none now.
I think there's real chemistry between him and Amanda.
The characters work together,
and sorry to say it, but you're gonna see
Pete Shanahan back for season eight.
Personally, I don't know what's gonna
happen with Pete, I have no idea.
A lot of people thought Pete was too much of a stalker.
I don't think he's a stalker. He's a cop
and he's used to investigating things,
and he really cares about her,
and wanted to find out what her secret was.
I don't know that much about Pete to be honest with you.
Apparently he's no threat to O'Neill.
You have to really consider yourself lucky to
have eight straight years of employment,
eight straight years of employment, on a show like this.
Eight straight years of working
for, and with people that really are concerned
about you, not just as an actor, but as a person.
Don't ... give me the eye brown.
He just had this beautiful, you know, massive head,
... hairless head.
And now he runs the risk of blending in.
Hopefully, before this is all said and done,
I will have hair. "(2003)"
You know at the beginning of those geo pet commercials,
when they take the seeds, and they just kind of
spread them over the top of the armadillo,
or whatever the heck it is, the dog or the puppy.
That's kind of where he's at right now.
He's at the seed spreading thing.
I think it's just a matter of time before Chia Teal'c
becomes a merchandise item and we start
to see that, that is gonna waft up.
The show has undergone a transition period.
So it didn't seem so outlandish now,
that Teal'c would have hair.
There are stories being written, that kind of deal
with him becoming more Earthlike.
The people of this town are behaving strangely...
Even for humans.
I know that he's also trimming all his body hair.
Which is nice, because that makes you look bigger.
What I like to do is use doll house furniture in my bedroom,
and I always find that, that makes me look gigantic.
You know they are getting bigger "(Pecs)".
Because I'm getting older, and it's harder to be thin.
Actually, all it is, is that I'm the butt of more jokes now.
Homecoming
- That planet you guys found me on was nice.
People were simple, life was quiet.
That's quite a way to make an entrance.
I realise that I'm quite pale, actually, on film.
Anyway, I didn't get too many
offers after it aired, about...
any video's or special films to make, or anything,
so I'm assuming that it wasn't so bad,
but it wasn't so good either.
Clip from "Lost City"
- Come on! Tell them how deep you are.
You'll be lucky if you understand this.
My depth is not material to this conversation.
Daniel Jackson is a mystery wrapped in an enigma,
that kind of walks around in a circle, with a riddle.
Clip from "Enemy Mine"
- You found all this and you didn't contact me?
We were going to...
They've been moved.
Daniel... go to your happy place.
They're having a meeting about my
behaviour on set, right now.
A lot of people are invited.
It's just something I have to do every now and again,
because they get sick and tired of dealing with my crap.
Next, The Goa'uld, and other alien bad asses.
Throughout the history of Stargate, we've had to deal
with a lot of creepy destructive alien thugs and bugs.
But the studio executive's rarely visit us anymore.
Well in season eight, the bad guys are back,
and they're mad.
They're mad as hell,
because they don't have recurring roles.
The Goa'uld have been the bad guys since the movie.
I don't think anyone expected them to be such an
evergreen villain. Variations on a theme,
of an egotistical,
technology grabbing,
parasite thing, in some
slaves body, bad guy.
Clip from Children Of The Gods
We started to meet individual Goa'ulds.
The most... dastardley of which, was Apophis.
I've always liked Apophis,
maybe because he was my first.
So you hold a special place
in your heart for your first bad guy.
If you watch the movie, he talks like this.
That's my best imitation.
His eyes would glow, and he'd look over
his shoulder a lot. He'd go like this a lot.
(Looks over shoulder)
Clip from Full Circle.
"I know who you are, Daniel Jackson.
But you know not, who I am"
We've come up against an uber Goa'uld,
by the name of Anubis.
What he has done is, he has found a way to ascend.
The 101 begins with Goa'ulds. But Anubis,
that's where you begin your PHD in Goa'ulds.
Anubis is a whole new level of bad guy.
The guys who play the super soldiers, are two of
the biggest human beings on the face of the Earth.
But they are Anubis drones,
that have a very single minded purpose.
So it's always fun to see them,
because they can't really see that well,
out of the helmets.
So it's always an adventure to
see how certain scenes are gonna go.
Especially when it involves a lot of walking,
or a lot of movement with them.
Clip from "Abyss"
- Death will only offer a temporary escape.
I can revive you again and again...
a thousand times if need be.
Baal, who has a lovely goatee, great cheekbones, very
handsome. Could be an underwear model.
I like our little bit more sophisticated
villains. We have a villain called Baal.
Baal will figure heavily in the ultimate
fate of the Goa'uld.
You'll see him do a little bit of bragging.
A little bit of boasting.
Some threatening, and he may kill some people.
As far as Baal goes. I know he's based on an
Egyptian God. I just don't know the God of what.
The God of pouring acid into O'Neills shoulder.
We've also had some fun times playing villains
that have entered our characters bodies,
and taken over that. You expect this character to behave
in a certain way, so you try to follow
him and trust him. All of a sudden you see
that he's really out for himself.
Clip from Absolute Power
Daniel, in an episode called Absolute Power,
became a bad guy.
Along the way, we also created the replicators,
who began as bug creatures that make
more of each other, and replicate.
Hence the name.
They were originally not our enemy.
They were the enemy of one of our allies,
the Asgard, another alien race.
Replicators exist merely to increase their numbers and do so without prejudice.
They are no more evil that a virus.
A really evil virus.
Then they got scarier, when they
became human form replicators.
I hate them. I hate working with them.
But Fifth is going to prove to be
a very interesting bad guy.
Patrick Currie is a wonderful actor,
and a great guy. So we have a lot of fun.
He's so pretty.
He's the prettiest bad guy we have.
My brothers and sisters, will devour
entire civilisations, in order to replicate.
The replicators are the bad guys.
Bad bugs.
On the other side, the best
character I've had to work with is...
who's the little guy, the little puppet?
Thor.
Thor and Andy Mikita, have a chat.
So how do you like this new ship ?
Well it smells like dog food.
But apart from that it's ok.
He is the franchise,
and actually, my pet.
Peter DeLuise did the voice of Loki, and
Michael Shanks offered us the voice of Thor.
So you know you've got guys
who can play, sort of, sly moments.
People didn't know it, for the longest time.
I kinda wanted it to be a big secret,
but they let the cat out of the bag.
Who's the favourite director so far,
that you've worked with ?
Ooh, that's a tough one... ahh....
Thanks a lot, after all I've done for you,
that's the kind of recognition I get.
Ok... You, it's you.
You're my favourite.
Ow !
Sorry, I never know my own strength.
Sorry.
That freakin' hurt.
I'm gonna call my attorney.
The Replicators will soon consume all that they can within our home galaxy. Yours will be next.
He's quite capable of doing his own voice.
But for some reason due to...
timing issues and issues of scheduling,
they can't actually get him to track his own stuff,
and I don't think he likes
to do any stuff in post.
I think he should just get off his high horse
and do his own voice, one of these days.
But he won't, so....
So you think the Goa'uld are bad ?
In the new scifi series,
Stargate Atlantis,
they've got some really nasty, evil aliens,
and here's your exclusive first look.
The bad guys ? I still haven't figured out,
who the hell they are.
They're strange, they're scary.
They're called the Wraith,
and they're part of a very strange
extra-terrestrial culture that feeds on lifeforms.
They're essentially, life suckers.
They feed off of life energy.
They're the one's who ended up
virtually destroying the Ancient race,
so...
it's our job to just irritate
them as much as possible.
We've got a serious enemy, and we
piss em off pretty good, right from the start.
They happen to be in a dormant state.
And we actually,
like knocking over a beehive,
we've suddenly triggered off this
very dark entity in the universe,
so we're running for our lives,
most of the time.
They're terrifying.
I respect them.
I fear them,
and I hate them.
There's nothing worse than them,
you'll see.
They're crazy, they're scary.
!!! PAS DE TRANSCRIPT !!!
They're nuts,
I'm scared of them, that's it.
hey're really resiliant.
I've killed a number of them.
They all come back to life.
I guess that's scifi you know ?
They keep coming back to life.
I gotta get a bigger gun,
probably.
Next on the Lowdown, an exclusive
look at the new world of Atlantis.
Producing Stargate SG1 each week,
is like living in dog years.
For every season we do,
we age seven years.
So we're all actually 49 years
older than you might think.
Probably my only demand as,
I guess, the head of a show,
is just to make sure that
people enjoy coming to work.
So far they all seem to.
It's insane.
We're shooting all over the map.
It's weird because they're now in
stage six, which was one of our stages.
And so at any given time,
when you're standing inside the studio,
you see the red light flashing,
and not know which show is shooting.
I'm ok with longer hours,
because I have a TV in my office,
and I think, as we speak,
I'm having a toilet installed in my office,
right where my desk chair used to be.
The most exciting thing about being
able to produce a show like Stargate,
especially in season eight is, you're really
pushing the envelope on all kinds of filmmaking.
Mainly in the use of computer
generated effects and compositing.
Matte paintings, and just combining
all those elements together.
Create new worlds,
different worlds.
Unique, original, creative environments.
Clip from "Hereos"
- Close the iris...
Open the iris...
That's pretty much my job right there !
One of the first things we had to address,
was obviously replicating the look from the feature film.
we had to try to replicate
the look of the puddle.
It's a great device for a series,
because you instantly walk through this portal,
and be exposed to these various types of cultures.
Getting to that point was really interesting,
and that's just been an evolving process
and we've finally got something good there.
The next phase that we tried to make
strides in visual effects, was Thor.
This servo here is for the various blinks
but also a lot of different expression,
you know, widening the eyes, narrowing the eyes,
and that has to be co-ordinated at the same time.
The replicator shows that
we've done over the years,
have been nominated for Emmys
and Gemini's and things, so that's been
really, really great, to be involved in.
It's just a great testing ground, to try
and realise those kind of futuristic visions.
It's so much fun, doing this show.
And especially because most of the time
I get a lot of the big two parters.
The rule when you get a big two parter, is that, every four
and a half seconds, something has to explode.
hat's sort of a rule that I made up,
but it's a good rule I think. It's one I try to stick by.
Adventure's important.
Going out into space is important.
Going out into space is important,
and ancient civilisations,
all that stuff is cool.
But if you don't care about the characters,
it's all meaningless.
You know, it's too bad I can't
show you a preview of season eight.
Various clips from season eight.
- He sacrificed himself to save us, all of us.
Thor, you're the only one
who can save Colonel O'Neill.
A Goa'uld wants to arrange a treaty with us?
Not just one Goa'uld. All of them.
This year, you're gonna get even more Stargate,
with the premiere of Stargate Atlantis.
I'm talking about a whole new galaxy,
a new world, and an awesome new look.
It's kind of like, new shoes, only better.
For Atlantis, we went up to this glacier,
and shot the opening title
sequence for the pilot.
And also the drone attack on
John Sheppard and Jack O'Neill.
I spent close to, I'd say,
6 1/2 to 7 hours in the...
...helicopter itself,
just riding around for the joy of it.
He had such a good time up there,
... and Joe Flanigan as well.
I actually have to admit that that's one
of the high points of the whole eight years.
Out with the old, in with the new.
Talk to me in eight years ?
Who's gonna complain about doing a
bunch of chopper scenes with Macgyver.
I love it.
"That was different"
"For me ?
Not so much"
Now look at this. You are watching the
entire set of Stargate Atlantis being built.
These people never took a break.
Except of course for a hockey game.
Finally we discovered the Lost City Of Atlantis,
but there's a few changes I wanted to make.
!!! PAS DE TRANSCRIPT !!!
The sets are just fantastic.
They're just great.
It helps me to paint a larger picture of my world,
and this is vastly different from where
I come from, Teyla comes from.
We're having loads of fun,
and they have done so much work.
It's a beautiful set, and we hope
that we can keep your interest,
after fabulous Stargate.
Hello, and welcome fellow space travellers.
I've snuck into the control room here, just to give you
guys a little basic rundown of the way things work here.
First off, you'll notice that all of
these panels are lit from below.
Some people think that's a lighting issue,
and that it makes these look more realistic.
More sort of scifi.
Actually, the reason they're lit like that,
is because,...
...I can place coffee on here and it will
remain warm throughout the scene.
This very high tech looking device.
Usually used to connect to the rest of the Atlantis city,
is actually a direct connection to
my manager and my agent.
When the obvious problems occur
with other cast members,
possibly a tuna sandwhich that may not be
tasting quite right. That sort of stuff.
This over here ?
This here actually, most people believe that this is
a 3D map of the Lost City of Atlantis.
Not so.
As it turns out, this is a beautifully
rendered 3D map of my Malibu home.
You'll notice that the bedroom
is the largest section in the centre,
and let me tell you, it gets a lot of action.
Atlantis is a really challenging project.
There's a lot of really challenging,
a lot of difficult things in it.
The main one is the city coming out of the water.
Water has always been difficult.
We know the water's gonna be difficult,
so let's just admit that.
But let's try and come up with the
coolest looking shots that we can.
We've decided to bring the city up at sunrise,
because it's difficult.
They needed to come up with an adversary,
... the Wraith, ...
who were sufficiently powerful, that
they could have defeated the Ancients.
But who are sufficiently stupid, that we
can outwit them on a week to week basis.
That's pretty tricky.
It comes out in the first episode,
that the Wraiths can project illusions.
Where you think you see them,
but they're not really there
They travel in these ships.
Here are some of the first charcoal sketches
of what we thought would be the
Wraith fighter craft, and the mother ship.
The mother ship is massive,
and it has landed on a planet.
It's been there long enough,
while they slept,
that trees have grown on the
actual ship itself, obscuring it.
So you don't realise what you're into until
you're right on their front doorstep,
and then of course, it's probably too late.
You want the real lowdown
on the new Stargate Atlantis ?
Stay tuned.
The best part about it is running around,
with large artillery pieces.
Stargate grows from SG1,
all the way to the Lost City of Atlantis.
Show creators Brad Wright and Robert Cooper,
tell us how easy that was.
The first thing you have to understand,
is that Brad has had several plans.
- There have been a lot of plans.
- I've planned.
Originally, it was more of a hand-off,
and now both worlds had to co-exist.
And not step on top of each other.
More importantly, we didn't want
to have a situation where
the solution in one universe,
would be "let's call the other guys!"
It made Robert and I think a little bit,
about what we originally had in mind for Atlantis.
To set Atlantis in
another galaxy entirely.
If this is not the lost city, then where is it?
The place that we find at the end of Lost City,
is not the Lost City of Atlantis,
but an outpost left behind,
when the city left Earth millions of years ago,
and flew off to the Pegasus galaxy.
Our specific mission is that we've essentially
found The Lost City Of Atlantis.
We have to tap into this Ancient City
and Ancient technology,
and stuff like that.
So we're here for quite a while.
What is "Atlantis" all about? What is the mission?
I dunno! I haven't read that one yet!
Atlantis is a one chance trip,
that Earth has,
to get into a new galaxy.
We have just enough power to get out there,
we do not have enough power to get back.
So we have found ourselves in a new galaxy,
in an unexplored city, and
it's a very international team.
The whole purpose of this is knowledge
and understanding humanity
on the widest scale available,
and how that will teach all of us individually
and everybody back on Earth,
more about ourselves.
I can't get into specifics,
or I'd have to kill you.
We should be wiping the slate clean,
and we should give our new heroes a chance
to deal with new problems and new enemies.
So putting them in this other galaxy,
really allowed us to say, ok,
we're starting from scratch.
These people are going on a brand new adventure.
Starting a new show with
a new cast can be really tricky.
Lucky for us, we have a group
of talented, dedicated actors,
who don't know what the meaning of serious is.
The character I play, is major John Sheppard.
There's a little bit of irreverance in this guy.
He's out to have fun, this is an adventure.
But he is somewhat reluctant to get involved in this.
Clip from "Rising part 1"
- I told Doctor Weir that, well, I'd think about it.
So? Well? What?!
At the beginning of our two hour pilot,
he's not the hero of this show.
Clip from "Rising part 1"
- You know, this isn't about you,
Sheppard, it's a lot bigger than that.
Right now, at this very second,
whether I decide to go on
this mission or not seems to be about me.
Over the course of the two hours,
he becomes the hero,
he really takes leadership
and takes ownership of the team.
Clip from "Rising part 1"
- Why did you become a pilot?
I think people who don't wanna fly are crazy.
And I think people who don't wanna go through
the Stargate are equally as whacked.
The best part about it is running around,
with incredible
special effects, ...
and large artillery pieces.
It makes up for something that's missing in my life.
I don't wanna talk about that.
Doctor Elizabeth Weir. She is an interesting choice,
as the head of Atlantis crew,
because she doesn't come from military at all.
She comes much more, from political
science, from human relations.
So she went from dealing with United Nations,
to aliens that we have communications with.
So she's still a virgin with all of this,
and I think one of her strengths
is that she's aware of that.
I think she's a bit of
a hippy idealist in her heart,
for there to be just peace,
love and understanding.
This chair controls the most powerful weapons
in all of humankind. I'm afraid of the thing.
We put the civilian,
the person with the moral code,
in charge of the expedition,
and made the military guys subordinate to her.
Clip from "Rising part 2"
- It will totally undermine your leadership, so as ranking military officer, I ...
Alright, just shut up and listen to me for a moment, alright?
As a woman, if you are very,
very strong, you can be considered
a diva or a bitch.
Clip from "48 Hours"
- God, you're a jerk.
I wish I didn't find you so attractive.
I always had a real weakness for dumb blondes.
David Hewlett plays McKay.
He and I had this really interesting antagonistic
dynamic between our characters.
He was in a couple of episodes.
Last we saw him on SG1, he'd been sent off to Russia.
Now even worse,
they've sent him to a completely new galaxy.
It's kind of sad, because she's got
this kind of horrible crush on me.
I'm trying to let her down easy.
I'm not even going to make any bones about it.
Carter is smarter than McKay.
It's not hard to be smarter than me.
My character has got the book learning,
but not the practical knowledge,
which is what is nice about the
Stargate Atlantis stuff.
Now he has to prove that not only has he got the smarts,
he's got the courage to back it up.
Which actually it doesn't in most cases.
Clip from "Rising"
- From what we've been able to ascertain, the city is powered by three zero-point modules.
Two are entirely depleted and the third is reaching maximum entropy.
When it does, it'll die too and nothing can reverse that.
All of the characters have a very good
sense of humor about themselves.
Except maybe my character,
who's just funny to laugh at.
Teyla, we encounter her in the Pegasus galaxy.
She's from a planet called Athos.
And she is the leader of her people.
She's strong, she's intuitive,
she kind of has a second sense about her.
She is a great fighter,
a great warrior,
and a wonderful protector for people.
The Athusians are actually an interesting blend
of native and primitive, with technology.
Clip from "Rising"
- I am Teyla Emmagan, daughter of Turgan.
There is an immediate connection
between Teyla and Sheppard.
I don't think Teyla is one to
trust people easily, but
for some reason she immediately trusts
Sheppard.
Lt Ford is a young cat, but he's very adamant
about his position.
He's definitely the weapons expert and
the military force on the team.
Never lose your gun - it's always by your side -
like a good woman, or a good man,
or a good dog, or a good goldfish.
He put himself on tape, and put it up on a site,
and we ended up looking
at his audition on a little mpeg file.
Robert and I are staring
at this tiny little screen going,
"this guy's really good. I love this guy."
He managed to make it back to the base and
was ordered to report to his commander. Instead,
he climbs in another bird and
went back for the Captain.
So when I came in here and
looked at the new Stargate,
I was like, oh my God !
What have I got myself into.
Clip from "Rising"
- What's it feel like?
Hurts like hell, sir.
You get the chance to play a guy who's
into guns, and he goes and he runs and someone says,
"Oh, there's a bad guy," and he goes, "I'll handle it."
I like being that guy.
Lt Ford is the man.
You'll learn to love him.
You'll love him before you learn.
Next on The Lowdown.
An exclusive look at Stargate Atlantis.
We do have clips to show, don't we?
I'll love it.
Ok, hopefully the TV system that blessed
Stargate SG1 with great global success,
ill do the same with
upcoming Stargate Atlantis.
This team has a new gate
and an all new mission.
I just wanted to be able to contribute in some way,
and help make the transition a little smoother,
as a credible, as a seed to start a new franchise.
Let's see what I have in here.
I have a cellphone.
I actually get reception in Atlantis,
which is amazing.
I'm gonna walk round going,
"Can you hear me now?"
Everybody on Stargate, it was such a joy
to work with them, because these people,
it's in their blood now.
They're just so comfortable with it.
Everyone from the actors to the crew.
So you walked in and you just felt safe.
They're being so welcoming and warm and funny.
That is an incredible gift.
We just feel we have this big brother saying,
"It's ok. Come on."
Stargate's been on for a very, very long time.
It is a legend among scifi fans.
What's nice about Stargate Atlantis is,
that it's not a replacement to SG1,
it is a compliment to it.
Fantasy and scifi and what makes
that realm so exciting,
is that it's endlessly fascinating.
Anything could happen,
and everything is possible.
That is what is so exciting about Stargate and
what is so exciting about this show.
How do I like being on it ?
I love it !
I think...
that if there is a level of expectation for the
show to fill the shoes of something like SG1,
the producers are probably feeling
that responsibility, not me.
I'm having fun.
Let them worry.
Clip from "Rising"
- Me, I like Ferris Wheels, and college football,
anything that goes more than two hundred miles per hour.
Sir, that's not gonna mean anything to them.
Well feel free to speak up.
I'm just trying to break the ice.
Major John Sheppard.
We're gonna be working very closely,
being as I'm second in charge to him.
Shoot lot's of Wraith with him,
and get shot a couple of times.
Fall and say some scientific jargon
I don't know, and all sorts of bits.
Clip from "Rising part 2"
- So little fear. Is it valour? Or ignorance?
I think she'll be the one that most quickly
deciphers and translates and tries to be the bridge.
At this point I don't know any though.
Come back in a week.
I'll do a haiku in Wraith!
I get to be off Earth for a little while.
You know how troublesome Earth can be from time to time,
so it's nice to get a little escape.
We walk through a wormhole,
and all of a sudden we're in a completely different world,
different elements.
There's so much to anticipate and look forward to.
It's fun, it's colourful.
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Atlantis. Please remain seated until the puddlejumper's come to a complete stop.
Most of the time we get serious, our work seems harder.
I think these guys know what they want,
and they know how to do it.
That's nice, and once again,
I have no responsibility.
I'm Amanda Tapping, and as promised,
here's an exclusive look at the new Stargate Atlantis.
Only on Scifi.
Looks good doesn't it ?
Various clips from Stargate Atlantis.