Previously on Stargate Atlantis...
- It's heading here.
- What's it doing?
It's scanning us.
The dart sent a transmission into space
and self-destructed before we got to it.
- We scanned the area...
- What are those?
- Wraith hive ships.
- Where are they headed?
If they maintain direction and speed,
they'll be over our planet in two weeks.
We knew they were coming.
Now we know when.
- That's something.
- That's something?
It means there's still time, Rodney.
There's no reason to panic... yet.
- Where there is time, there is hope.
- So, recommendations?
- Other than panic?
- Other than panic, yes.
I realise this might not be cool,
but we should consider M7G-677.
- As a possible evacuation site?
- No. I'm suggesting we take their ZPM.
Their only protection from the Wraith?
A planet populated mostly by children?
He raises a valid point.
The ZPM is nearly depleted,
but it could be of some use to us.
You asked for suggestions.
It's a matter of survival.
I see. Well, we're not quite there yet,
and as long as I'm in charge
we will never be there.
I agree. If this is to be our end, it is best
we face it with both dignity and honour.
- I have an idea... in addition to panic.
- Let's hear it.
It's a long shot,
but I think it's most likely worth the effort.
- It'll mostly be my effort, so...
- What is it?
We can send a message to Earth
through the Stargate.
- Excuse me?
- Do we have enough power?
Not to send a person.
We couldn't maintain the wormhole.
If we tied together
all our power-generating capabilities,
we might be able to establish a wormhole
long enough to send a message.
- How much time are we talking about?
- Approximately 1.3 seconds, give or take.
- That's not much time.
- Time to say SOS.
It's enough time to send a message in
the form of a high-compression data burst.
I helped refine the encoding
for the US air force.
Colonel Carter can decipher it
on the other side.
- You're suggesting this now?
- It probably won't work
and could overload
our naqahdah generators.
Well, then, we can't take the risk.
No power, we won't have a chance in hell.
There are three Wraith hive ships on the
way. This calls for desperate measures.
Besides, I've been working out
ways of minimising the risk.
Assuming it's possible,
how much information could we send?
Everything. Mission reports
from all the senior staff, stuff on Atlantis...
- All that. One second?
- 1.3.
If I finesse the compression ratios,
you'll be looking for things to add.
- Do it.
- Doing it.
Elizabeth, you realise that if Stargate
Command was able to send help...
I know. They would have.
But we must report what we've learned
here, about Atlantis, about the Ancients.
- The Wraith.
- Exactly. We have to warn Earth.
- Even if it's the last thing we do?
- Especially if it's the last thing we do.
They don't seem threatening
as dots on a screen.
We need to do recon
and see what we're up against first-hand.
- How?
- I've tracked their progress.
The Wraith ships
go in and out of hyperspace periodically,
because their technology is limited...
- Or they're stopping to feed along the way.
- The point is, the pattern is predictable.
I can guess with some certainty
that they'll be making stops
here, here, and here.
The ships are light years away. How
will you reach them by puddle jumper?
We take a route where Zelenka thinks
they'll drop out of hyperspace
and we watch them pass by.
- That's good.
- You know, I have my moments.
Teyla and I were just deciding
which planet to go to.
I know the people of this world.
Their Stargate is in the open
and so accessible by ship.
You can remain undetected by the Wraith
as they go by your position?
Stealth mode.
They won't know we're there.
OK, go, get what intel you can, and get
back before Rodney sends his message.
- I need you here.
- Won't even stop at the duty free.
If you get the idea to take
the Wraith ships on yourself, Major,
I am hereby ordering you not to.
- Believe me, you don't have to.
- Still...
Don't take on an alien armada
single-handedly. Understood.
Father, Teyla's here!
- Teyla.
- Orin. It has been many days.
Too many. Look at you.
You're so different.
Much has changed since my last visit.
- This is Major John Sheppard... and Orin.
- Pleased to meet you, uh...
- The harvest is still months away.
- Yes, I know.
We have not come to trade,
but to deliver a warning.
We believe the Wraith
may be on their way.
We don't know that,
but we're about to find out.
Yes.
It seems they're awakening everywhere.
Tell your people to take precautions
in case they do come.
I will, but you know as well as I do, Teyla,
that the Wraith will track us down
wherever we go.
- There will be no escape.
- What about through the Stargate?
The cullings are taking place
on many worlds. None are safe.
Even we have taken in refugees.
If they do come, stay far from the Stargate.
Take your family to the far tree line there
and wait for us.
- Teyla.
- One family, Major. That is all I ask.
- I'm sorry, Orin, I can't make that promise.
- It will be the very least we can do.
- If there's time.
- Then we must hurry.
Children, we must prepare.
We have our city specs, mission reports
and tactical assessments all ready to go.
What else?
I've included data we've been able
to decipher from the Ancient database.
Really? That is incredible.
- My algorithm is extraordinarily efficient.
- Oh, please.
It must be in order to fit all that data
into 1.3 seconds.
.3 seconds, actually.
- We have a whole extra second to fill?
- Mm. A whole extra one, yes.
Is it enough
to include personal messages?
Uh... sure. I mean, several hours of video.
Much more if it was strictly audio.
I think it'd do wonders for morale.
Especially now.
I could tell my grandma
what I've been up to.
If your grandmother
had security clearance.
But for now you can tell her
that you're well and that you miss her.
This is all very charming,
but I have work to do. Shouldn't I, um...?
Lieutenant,
maybe you'd like to handle this.
Give everybody a few minutes
to send a message to their loved ones.
- I'd love to, ma'am.
- Off you go.
When Zelenka and I tie
Jumper Four's engines into the grid,
- we'll be able to do a low-power dry run.
- Good.
- Rodney?
- Mm?
- You don't want to send a message?
- You know what?
Maybe with all my spare time,
I'll record a message myself.
- You?
- Yes.
Good, good.
This wasn't supposed to be
a rescue mission.
- Orin was a good friend of my father.
- I agreed to warn him.
If someone close to your family, a dear
friend, was in danger from the Wraith,
- would you have not done the same?
- Not if it jeopardised the mission.
So we give up that
which makes us different from the Wraith?
I agreed to stop and pick him up if there
was time, but only if there was time.
I'd like to be saving everyone
in the damn galaxy.
- It's just one man and his children.
- I agreed to help if there was time.
You can only fight the battles you can win.
Whoa.
Let me get this thing turned around.
They're heading for the planet.
OK, recording. Plenty of battery.
So why am I not seeing anything?
Oh... stupid.
OK.
Hi, Grandma, Grandpa.
It's me, Aiden... obviously.
I'm talking to you
from a place far, far from home.
I'm good, though.
You don't have to worry.
Life here is... pretty routine.
I'm hoping that I'll be able
to get home sometime soon,
but, you know,
if... if I'm stuck here a while,
I want you to know that I'm good.
I'm doing things...
I'm seeing things I never thought I'd see.
I wish I could tell you all about it.
Who knows?
One day, maybe, I'll be able to,
but I want you both to know...
that you're right here.
Always. All the time.
Even flying full out,
we're just ahead of the armada.
- I can't risk putting down for Orin.
- I see.
I'm gonna take us out of stealth mode
for the pass-through. Dial the gate.
Hang on. Incoming wormhole.
The Wraith dial in to prevent victims from
using the Stargate as a means of escape.
So we're stuck here.
Once the ship is rendered invisible again,
we will be safe.
I need to get the intel
about the Wraith fleet to Atlantis.
They will keep dialling in through the night
at the very least,
but if we wait where
I told Orin and his family to meet us...
That's where I'm headed.
I'm not very good at this.
The only people to see it
will be your family.
- Aye, and you and the US military.
- Well, give it a shot.
- What shall I say?
- Uh... Uh...
- "I miss you. I wish you were here."
- I wish who was here?
- Who do you wish was here?
- Nobody. I wish I wasn't!
I've got a lot of people to get to.
All right, er...
I suppose I could say hello to my mother.
Good. There you go. All right, you ready?
OK, go.
Hello, Mum.
I hope this message finds you well.
I trust your petunias
are in full bloom by now.
I hope you're keeping up
with that ointment.
If you've adhered to the regime,
the fungus should have cleared up by now.
- What's wrong?
- Dude, fungus?
On her toenails.
You said no one would watch this.
- Yeah, but fungus?
- What, then, shall I talk about?
- It's your mother. Tell her you love her.
- I can't. I get emotional.
- So?
- She's very delicate, my mother.
As sweet a soul as you'll ever meet,
as pure as the driven snow.
If I get upset, she'll get upset.
I can't have that.
We're not live. If you don't like
what we put on tape, we can do it again.
- We can?
- Sure.
Oh. Well, I suppose I could do that, then.
All right.
Here we go.
Um... Mum...
I miss you terribly.
I can't do this!
Come on, Orin, show up.
What?
Not long ago,
you would have left him behind.
Well, the situation has changed.
Lieutenant Ford suggested
we steal from a community of children.
They have a ZPM
and we can bring them back.
Only to face death in Atlantis?
Ford and I are military. We've spent
a lot of our lives learning how to survive.
I have spent my life surviving the Wraith.
Part of that training is knowing
who you can and can't save.
And that decision is yours alone?
I said that I'd wait for your friend
if there was time. Now there's time.
- What else do you want from me?
- Too much, I fear.
It's gonna be a long night.
Failsafe.
You didn't say anything that
would require security clearance, did you?
Security clearance?
- This is hard to sit and watch.
- There's nothing we can do.
We could do a lot.
It would just be the last thing we ever do.
We are far outnumbered
and the gate is still inaccessible.
But if we save Orin and his family,
we will have done something.
Something.
I'm gonna miss you, kiddo.
I can't wait to take you
to a basketball game
and watch Kobe and Shaq
take another title home for the Lakers.
That's it.
- That's it?
- What else am I gonna say to a kid?
- It's your brother.
- I may not see him again.
- Why make it any worse?
- That's not what this is about.
That's exactly what this is about.
Don't sweat it. I'm happy
I got the chance to say goodbye.
- Yeah, but you didn't say it.
- Not in so many words.
- Lieutenant Ford.
- Ready to record your message?
Already done. Actually, I took the liberty
of doing mine in private.
- Now, it may require some editing.
- Editing?
Yeah, I went on a bit.
I used the entire tape.
- You talked for an hour?
- I found it therapeutic.
I've come up with
several valuable insights,
but I've only slept six hours
in the last few days, so, um...
- Who's it for?
- Humanity, my sister...
I don't expect you to cut it down too much.
There is gold in here.
So just make sure mine's last.
If the gate holds the connection,
we won't have wasted the time.
- Well, I'll look forward to it.
- Well, enjoy.
Gold.
And in five... four... three...
This is Dr Rodney McKay speaking
from my base of operations
in the lost city of Atlantis,
located deep within the Pegasus galaxy.
I record this message
on the eve of our darkest hour.
As I speak, an alien armada
of biblical proportions is on its way,
bent - dare I say hell-bent, in keeping
with the metaphor - on our destruction.
We will do our best
to stave off their attack,
but I am afraid that defeat
is all but inevitable.
i and the other members of my team
face the most horrific deaths imaginable
as our very lives are... are sucked
from our chests in a... in a... horrific...
OK, um...
OK, starting again, starting again.
Um, Ford, just cut that, all right?
What about, uh...?
- What is that?
- I've never seen such a thing.
- I'm gonna check it out.
- You may be discovered.
- I'll make a point not to.
- Major.
I just want to see whatever that is.
Just stay here
until Orin and his family show up.
And in five, four, three...
My friends, I'm Dr Rodney McKay
of the Atlantis expedition,
and as the facts of our heroic struggle
against the Wraith
and our untimely demise
are already known to you,
in that light,
I'd like to pass along some final thoughts.
Now, my extensive education, training
and experience in the field of astrophysics
has given me a unique perspective
that few on Earth,
or, well, on any other planet,
for that matter, can match.
I'd like to take a few moments now
to pass along that perspective to you.
I'll begin with a few observations
on a subject
that is both near and dear to my heart.
Leadership.
Mr and Mrs Markham,
my name is Dr Elizabeth Weir,
and your son
was a member of my expedition team.
It is with deep regret that I inform you
that he was killed in the line of duty
just a few days ago.
He died in the defence of others, and
his sacrifice may have saved many lives...
..and her keen curiosity
are some of the qualities
that your daughter displayed during
her duties as a scientist on my team.
She and several of her colleagues
died suddenly just a few weeks ago.
I am not at liberty
to reveal the cause of her death,
but I can tell you
that during her time here,
Dr Dumais was a part
of something very profound.
She saw and did things
she never would have dreamed of...
He died bravely, while defending others.
I confess I didn't know him
as well as I could have,
but I know he was well liked
and respected among his peers.
And I was told of how often
he spoke of his family.
I do wish I could tell you more.
I'm sure you understand,
as a military family.
Are you done, ma'am?
Just give me a moment,
please, Lieutenant.
I am keeping busy with my job.
I work hard, like everyone else,
to ensure the success of this expedition,
and to please
the leader of our science team...
No, no, no, no, no. This sequence first,
and then the secondary code.
Unless you're trying to blow us up.
If so, good work.
He does not always remember my name,
but I have enjoyed working for him.
What is this? Kiwi?
Who made this? Did you make this?
He's a very honourable and brave man.
Ow! Ow! OK, cramp,
cramp, cramp, cramp, cramp... Ow!
Until then I will continue
to serve at his pleasure.
I once caught mono
kissing a girl in algebra club.
I missed an entire month of school.
Still, the kiss was... something,
so it was probably worth it.
April Bingham. Cute blonde.
God, see, I love blondes. Especially
with the, uh... the short hair. Mm...
Samantha Carter, if you're watching,
the torch is still burning.
Sadly, soon to be extinguished,
but, you know,
you should know I think you are just so...
Well, you're great,
you're really, really great,
and you're the hottest scientist
I've ever worked with.
There's probably not a night
that goes by that I don't find myself...
OK, Ford, let's lose that,
and let's get back to, uh... leadership.
Run, children! Run!
Hurry!
- Who will be watching this?
- Anyone you're sending it to.
Family, friends, loved ones.
- Will anyone from Atlantis be viewing it?
- No, messages are private.
- You can get as mushy as you want.
- All right.
Uh, this is a message for General
Jack O'Neill of Stargate Command.
It is my duty to inform you of what I
consider to be serious errors in judgement
among the leaders of this expedition,
most notably Dr Elizabeth Weir.
Her actions have
repeatedly and recklessly
exposed the people of this expedition
to extreme danger,
leading us directly to the grave situation
we currently find ourselves in.
You know what?
How about you record
your whining in private?
Fine.
I've recorded her questionable activities,
which I would like to detail for you now.
Quickly! Quickly!
Run for the trees!
Never cared for dogs. Too much work,
too needy, too unpredictable.
You leave one door open
and they're gone.
You look for them, it's no use,
and since your father
refused to buy a licence,
the animal shelter can't track them.
God knows what happened
to that little guy.
Now, cats...
now, that's a whole different story.
Cats are self-sufficient, dependable.
You shake the box, they come running.
A cynic would say it's because of the food,
but my cat, he enjoys my company.
It's very comforting
to come home from work
and have a familiar face waiting for you.
Still, I digress. Where was I?
Uh... right. Leadership.
Keep going! Keep going!
Over here!
It is all right. I am a friend.
Please, hurry. This way.
Hurry. This way.
- How many of you are left?
- I don't know. The Wraith are everywhere.
Here, drink this. It is water.
Orin... Have you seen him?
Not since before the Wraith arrived.
Thank you.
- We must go. The Wraith will find us.
- No, they will not.
Our ship has a shield which makes it
invisible to them. You are safe here.
Just rest.
We will leave soon.
I'd like to say something to the families
of every member of this expedition.
I wish I could tell you more
about what your loved ones are doing,
and someday I hope you find out,
because you will be amazed,
but I will tell you that I could not be more
proud of each and every one of them.
Their heroism has amazed me.
Their resourcefulness has staggered me.
- Rodney, go!
- Going!
Now!
We face a terrible enemy
and an uncertain future,
but if we are never heard from again,
know that your loved ones
did not face that uncertainty alone.
We are facing our future together.
Major.
It's pretty ugly out there.
- Is this Orin's family?
- No.
They have not seen Orin
since the culling began.
The village is wiped out.
The gate just shut off.
We should be able to get out of here
before the Wraith can do anything.
Please, Major. Give Orin more time.
If he was able to get here, he would be
here by now. We've got to get back.
Go. I will stay and search in the daylight.
You can return for me later.
- You can't do that.
- I consider Orin as family.
- I am sorry if you do not understand...
- That's not the point...
With you or without you, I am staying.
You won't make it.
Then I ask that you stay as well,
just a little longer.
Allow something good to come of this.
All right. We'll give it a little more time.
I know you worry about me, Mum,
but somehow we've found a way
to rise to each challenge,
so I wouldn't fret about my safety.
It's the people here, from dozens of
countries, all connected by a single bond.
We represent the people of Earth,
and if there's one thing I know about
we Earthlings, we're a scrappy bunch...
You can't say Earthlings.
Your mother doesn't have clearance.
She knows I'm from Earth.
It's not a bloody secret.
- Oh, right.
- Sorry, Mum. Anyhow...
Authorised using a prisoner
to test an experimental drug,
in clear violation
of the Geneva Convention.
Lowered the Stargate shield
when the authenticity
of incoming travellers was in question.
That's another sight
I'll die without having seen.
When you've travelled as much as I have,
you'd think that missing Niagara Falls
would be no big deal.
There's a lot of movies I wish I'd seen.
Never saw Grease, even though
I fancied Olivia Newton-John.
Always wanted to see Gandhi.
Only saw the first half of The Sixth Sense.
My sister...
Ford, if you cut everything else,
just, um... keep this part, OK?
Jeannie, it's your brother, Rodney.
Obviously.
I want to say, um...
I want to say something. Uh...
Family is important.
I've come to realise that, because
the people here have become a...
kind of a surrogate family to me.
I know I've never really been
the poster child for that kind of sentiment,
but when one's contemplating one's
own demise, one sees things more clearly.
I really do wish you the best, you know,
and I'm sorry we weren't closer.
Perhaps, um...
if by chance I make it out of this,
perhaps one day we can be,
and I would like that.
Now, if there's time, I'd like
to go back to the subject of leadership.
Someone's coming.
Orin!
- Orin!
- How big is his family?
- He must have met others.
- That'll be a problem.
- I didn't think you'd be here.
- We would not have left you.
We found others on the way,
and more further behind.
- How many more?
- 12, perhaps more.
In here! This way!
Quickly!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
- We'll fit as many people in as we can.
- Hurry! Come on!
Straight ahead. Straight ahead.
- Hurry.
- Come on!
- Run!
- It's all right. It is all right.
Get down!
- Are you all right?
- Yes. I'm fine.
- Are our guests comfortably settled in?
- Yes.
Good.
- So tell me. How bad is it?
- Bad.
Each hive ship acts like a carrier group,
with cruisers
and hundreds of darts escorting it.
Grodin's downloading the sensor readings
right now.
I have never witnessed a culling
that took so many.
We saved a few. That's worth something.
Rodney, are we ready
to send our message?
- When you are.
- OK.
Lieutenant Ford is recording personal
messages from all the team members.
- If you'd like...
- I'm good.
OK.
Along with a short note of my own,
I recorded messages
to the families of the people we've lost.
- That's a good idea.
- There's one I thought you'd like to do.
OK, whenever you're ready,
sir, go ahead.
I'm not sure
if Colonel Sumner's parents are still alive.
I'm not sure he even has a family
back there. Not all of us do.
But if he does have a family,
they should know
that he died with honour and courage
in the performance of his duty.
He carried the burden of a leader
and he carried it well.
I didn't get the chance to know him well,
but I know this.
Considering the type of man he was
and what we're up against,
yeah, I wish he was still here.
Not a day goes by
that I don't think of you, Simon.
There's so much I want to tell you
and share with you, but I can't.
I know this is unfair.
So much you don't know,
and putting your life on hold for me...
so don't.
All I ask is you take care of yourself,
and know that, wherever you are,
my heart is looking after you.
So take care of yourself, lots of sleep,
remember your daily walks
and keep up with your prescription.
Well, that's about it.
I'll say goodbye now...
and, Mum, I do love you.
Bye, Grandma, Grandpa. I miss you.
Goodbye, bro.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Simon.
We have unscheduled off-world activation.
Linking now.
Receiving transmission.
Who's it from?
Atlantis.
Subtitles by Lecavalier
For the BST