Major Sheppard.
Major!
- Continue.
- Going easy on me, huh?
I assure you, Major, I am not.
Continue.
You OK?
- Yes.
- Are you sure?
It's usually me
picking my butt up off the mat.
I have not been sleeping much.
I've been having nightmares
about the Wraith.
You're not the only one.
It has not been so bad
since my father was taken.
According to Dr Zelenka's calculations,
we have less than one week
before the Wraith arrive.
- I want options.
- Besides crying ourselves to sleep?
Not me. I haven't slept in days.
What do you have to show
for your sleepless nights?
We've uncovered defensive
weapons systems beyond the shield...
- Our best option is the control chair.
- I was gonna say that.
- You were taking too long.
- It may not be our best chance.
- Gentlemen.
- Power will be our biggest problem.
We haven't initialised the chair yet,
let alone determined if we have the power.
OK. Keep me posted.
Sergeant Bates,
where are we with our Alpha site?
We've completed the security sweep
and are ready to establish base camp.
Awaiting inspection by Major Sheppard.
- Right after lunch.
- Good.
Are the Athosians
prepared for an evacuation?
Yes, but many believe there is
no other world safe from the Wraith.
- They want to stay?
- There are cullings all over the galaxy.
We have spent our lives hiding.
The difference here being
we do intend to destroy the city
rather than let it fall
into the hands of the Wraith.
Anyone left on the mainland
will be cut off from the Stargate for good.
Thanks to Rodney's discovery
of the control crystal,
we can take that with us and hopefully
use it to access Earth in the future.
We understand that, Dr Weir.
I'm sorry...
The people of Athos wish you to know
that they too will help defend the city.
- That is very honourable, but...
- Please!
We can't possibly stay and fight.
I disagree. I think it's entirely
within the realm of possibility.
There are tens of thousands
of life-sucking aliens
in advanced spaceships
on their way to destroy us,
and we have 200 people, mostly scientists
who've never even fired a gun before.
Shockingly, for the first time ever,
I have to agree with Kavanagh.
All I'm saying is
let's not give up just yet.
What was that we were supposed
to all remember? Something important.
- The Alamo.
- Granted, you guys are scientists.
No one will put you on the front line,
but science can turn the tide of war.
- Look at the A-bomb.
- Not exactly our proudest moment.
The Wraith aren't here yet, and until then
remain focused on what you do best.
Like I said off the top,
if there are any options, I want them.
That's all.
Teyla?
Hi.
Kate Heightmeyer.
Yes, right. I knew that. I'm sorry.
No problem. Mind if I join you?
No, of course not.
Strange how the memory
just goes away when we're tired.
- You are a doctor, right?
- Psychologist, actually.
And that is different than Dr Beckett?
Quite, yes.
I deal with the mind.
I help people with emotional problems
like anxiety, depression,
post-traumatic distress.
Needless to say,
I've been pretty busy since we got here.
I can imagine.
I'm sure you do a lot of the same things
that I do for your people,
but it must be very hard on you,
always having to keep such a brave face.
From strength comes hope.
Without hope, my people would be lost.
You must feel you have to be
outwardly strong for us as well.
I know that your value and your loyalty
have been questioned by a few in the past.
What I'm trying to say to you is
if you ever need to talk, I'm here.
Did Major Sheppard ask you
to speak with me?
- Yes, he may have...
- I'm sorry.
I do not mean to be rude,
but I'm fine. Really.
I appreciate your concern.
Major.
- Teyla.
- What did you tell Dr Heightmeyer?
What you told me, that you couldn't sleep
because you were having nightmares.
- I confided in you.
- You're in my team, so my responsibility.
And I only told one person, whose job is
to deal exactly with this sort of thing.
- There is nothing wrong with my mind.
- Nobody said there was.
It's hard enough with your people
without them thinking I'm crazy.
- Nobody thinks you're crazy.
- That is not the point.
Look, Teyla,
you may wanna sit this one out.
- What do you mean?
- Rodney's staying back.
Ford and I are gonna check out
the Alpha site before we move in.
My people will be forced
to that planet as well.
And I'll make sure it's safe for everyone.
Look, I'm not saying there's
anything wrong with you, God forbid,
but you admitted that
you were a little off your game.
You snapped at Dr Weir
for no good reason.
Now you're biting my head off for caring
that it's three days since you slept.
I'm sorry, but I do not need any help.
The Wraith are coming.
I need to do something.
OK. Good. I suggest you take a nap.
- Teyla.
- Dr McKay.
I was just...
We're seeing each other.
You and Dr Heightmeyer?
Well, you know how much
I love women with great... minds.
Just don't say anything to anyone.
- Your secret is safe with me.
- Right. Very good. Excellent.
- Dr Heightmeyer?
- Teyla. Come in.
I'm sorry to bother you.
- Is it all right if I...?
- Of course. Please, have a seat.
I guess I'm not really sure
how this is supposed to work.
Just relax.
Tell me whatever's on your mind.
I have been having bad dreams.
I feel...
Everyone is afraid.
I do not know why I'm bothering you...
Could you always sense the Wraith?
Yes. Since I can remember.
What does it feel like?
It feels like a deep cold
that comes from within.
I first felt it when I was a girl.
I could not breathe,
and I did not know why,
and then we heard the darts.
Do you feel that way now?
I have had a knot inside me
for some time now.
As I understand, their ships
are still a great distance from Atlantis.
Can you really sense them
from so far away?
This feeling is a little different
than in the past.
Perhaps it is because
it is always there now.
I am getting used to it.
Never before in my lifetime
have so many Wraith been awake.
Do many of your people have this ability?
Some.
Among those few, some can sense
the Wraith stronger than others.
I am among the first
to know they are coming.
That makes you special.
How does that make you feel?
- I have not given it much thought.
- Why not?
Why do some people
have blue eyes and others brown?
Tell me about your nightmares.
It was me.
You were standing over yourself?
It was me, but it was not me.
I was a Wraith.
People waste a lot of time
trying to interpret their dreams.
They're just another way our brain thinks.
There are no hidden meanings.
We forget most everything
we dream about.
Our conscious mind is capable
of deciding what's most important to us.
The fact that, on some level, I see myself
as a Wraith is very disturbing to me.
I think this special ability you have,
this talent for sensing the Wraith,
connects you to them in your mind,
maybe in a way you would like to deny.
You said you hadn't given it
much thought. I don't think that's true.
What am I supposed to do?
I cannot change it.
Probably not,
but the unknown frightens us.
We all like to feel in control,
even though most of the time
our power over most things
is just an illusion,
but I find the more we know
about something,
the more we can convince ourselves
we are in control of it.
I ran every test I could on all of you.
You and your people
are the same as we are.
I have no explanation
for your special superpowers.
- I only have one.
- I've seen you fight, my dear.
This ability is something that
is passed on through family lineage.
- Does that not make it biological?
- It would seem so.
But without samples
from everyone in your family,
I would have little chance of identifying
what causes the anatomical response.
It'd be difficult.
Any chance you would have time
to fly me over to the mainland?
If you're willing to take your life
into your own hands.
I'd love a break.
You've changed, Teyla.
- My hair is shorter.
- It's more than your hair, dear.
I can still see the little girl
who used to paint me beautiful pictures
while she sang the songs of the Ancients.
I have not been her in a long time, Charin.
No, but even Teyla,
leader of the Athosians,
always found the time
to come and visit with poor old Charin.
I have missed your tuttleroot soup.
But I suspect it's more than my soup
that has brought you here.
You've come to pluck me from my tent
and take me to yet another world.
Not yet,
but it seems we may have to evacuate
again soon, at least temporarily.
Did you allow yourself
to expect differently?
I still believe that we can one day
be free of the Wraith.
You can save such stories for those
whose bones aren't failing them.
Charin, do you know
why I can sense the Wraith coming?
You were born to it. There have been
a few in every generation.
I know, but has no one ever wondered
how that is possible?
Some believe it was a gift
from the Ancestors.
And you?
Your father asked me not to tell you.
My father is not here any more.
No other living Athosian knows of this,
for good reason.
Please, tell me anyway.
My grandfather used to tell a story,
no one has ever heard the like
before or since,
about the few who once returned.
Returned?
There was a planet.
As was expected, every so often,
the Wraith came, villagers were taken.
But there, on this particular planet,
on several occasions,
the taken came back.
Some believed the Ancestors
had returned their loved ones,
that they had been blessed with a gift
that made them unwanted by the Wraith.
Others even told tales of how the taken
had somehow vanquished the Wraith,
but soon the taken began to be feared.
- Why?
- They spoke of hearing voices.
Many began to behave strangely.
Some became violent, even murderous.
Well, it doesn't sound like
the Ancients were responsible for that.
The villagers turned on the taken.
It was a massacre.
All but a few were killed.
The rest were ostracised and sent away.
After that, no others that were taken
from that village ever returned again,
but those few who survived,
they are the ones
who Charin believes passed on the gift.
- And one of the taken that survived was...
- My lineage.
I have the address to the planet.
Charin says the village is long gone.
All that is left are ruins.
- Still I wish to go there.
- Now?
I believe this must be
coming to light now for a reason.
Maybe we can find evidence
of what really happened.
There are a lot of things
we need to get done.
Maybe there is a way to fight the Wraith
we have yet to discover.
Perhaps my ancestors
were simply not enlightened enough
to recognise their gift for what it was.
Doesn't hurt to take a look around.
- Sir, there's nothing here.
- I know.
- It's dark. Shouldn't we be getting back?
- Just give her a minute.
- Sir...
- I need her to put this behind her, sleep.
We all do, so whatever it takes.
- Rodney?
- I've got something here.
- Really?
- I don't know.
I've got a little...
You've got a little what?
Hey, McKay, you've got a little what?
What?
- It's OK when you guys make fun of me.
- Rodney?
Picking up a faint energy signal.
It's getting stronger.
- It's coming from here.
- There's nothing here.
- The magic Ancient device hasn't lied yet.
- It's solid.
- There's definitely something weird here.
- Weird how?
- How about that?
- Teyla! Teyla!
Maybe if you got a good running start,
really slam into it.
- How'd you do that?
- I do not know.
I was just looking for a way out.
- Looks like the inside of a Wraith ship.
- What the hell were they doing here?
- Rodney.
- Elizabeth.
You found a Wraith laboratory?
Looks that way.
Some sort of hidden secret facility.
It's obviously been abandoned
for a very long time.
I pulled this data recorder
from one of the computer consoles.
The Wraith were experimenting
on the people?
- No idea. Hoping this will tell us.
- Why the secrecy?
The Wraith can take people at will
and do whatever they want with them.
Here we go.
There.
Now... that means
absolutely nothing to me.
Last time I saw one of these, it showed
a galactic positioning system for ships.
- More pictures than symbols.
- I wonder...
Just so you know, you didn't
finish that sentence out loud.
- Well, this is obviously a language.
- Wraith language?
That would make sense.
I'd love to have a look through this.
Knock yourself out. I gotta get back
to the control chair anyway.
- Why could only you access the doorway?
- I don't know.
Only a Wraith can enter a Wraith facility?
- I'm not a Wraith.
- What does it feel like to be a Wraith?
I feel hungry.
Remember what happened
last time I sat in one?
- There's nowhere near enough power.
- Then why bother? It's quite late.
We are trying to determine how much
power is required to operate the systems.
- And it needs to be on.
- You have the gene now.
I can't analyse the data
while keeping the damn thing activated.
- You analyse it.
- Rodney doesn't think...
- Gentlemen, how's it coming?
- Well, not good.
- This won't help. Carson, I need you.
- Thank God.
- We're using him.
- Is someone hurt?
- You were right.
- Lovely. About what?
Your theory of the Wraith evolving
after the Ancients arrived in Pegasus.
- Pay up.
- How do you know?
- Wraith language is derived from Ancient.
- That doesn't...
Rodney, please.
That's not why I need to see you.
I've been able to translate
the first part of the log.
Really?
- We'll try Dr Kusanagi again. Now.
- OK.
Thank you.
Good morning. You look like I feel.
Well, we've been up all night.
You wanted to see me?
- You'd better sit down.
- What is it?
Well, I translated the first part
of the log you brought back and...
Are you sure
you don't wanna have a seat?
The Wraith were conducting experiments
on your ancestors.
It was just one Wraith, actually.
He was doing it against the wishes
of the other Wraith, in secret.
What was he doing?
I think he was trying
to make their food source
more compatible with their species.
- I do not understand.
- It was very easy to miss.
I couldn't even make the comparison
necessary to isolate the specific strand.
We needed Wraith cells, which we got,
but also a mapping of the genetic
code which wasn't 50% complete...
Please.
Tell me.
You have some Wraith DNA
in your genetic make-up.
- Teyla is part Wraith?
- A very small part.
She's as different from us as you
because of your Ancient gene.
- And some other things.
- Bates is gonna go nuts.
- Let's keep this one under our hat.
- Teyla is concerned how we will react.
You think this Wraith scientist
was trying to make humans more tasty?
The log indicates that he wanted
to make the feeding more efficient.
You said they had genetic characteristics
similar to humans.
They do, but they're still closer to the bug
that attacked Major Sheppard than us.
- We weren't gonna mention that again.
- Sorry.
Also interesting is the fact
that the Wraith language
appears to be a derivative of Ancient,
which suggests that the Wraith evolved
after the Ancients arrived in Pegasus.
The Ancients unwittingly allowed humans
to evolve on a planet with insects on it.
At some point, the insects fed on humans
and incorporated our DNA into theirs.
The Wraith are an evolution of that.
So you're saying the Ancients
actually created the Wraith?
- By accident.
- Or negligence.
It doesn't matter.
The more we know
about Wraith physiology,
the closer we get to a weapon that can
attack them and leave us unharmed.
Yes, but all we know is that the Ancients
might have created the Wraith,
and why Teyla can sense them coming.
Fabulous, mystery solved,
but that doesn't stop them from coming.
Rodney's right. Let's get back to work.
Thank you.
I know it is not my fault.
There's nothing I can do.
The fact is, I'm really no different now
than I was yesterday or last week.
But you feel different.
Yes.
The thing that I am most worried about
is how people will perceive me.
My father told people that it was a gift,
I was special, but in a good way.
I could help my people by warning them
of the Wraith's approach.
He did it to protect me, but I think that it is
why they first turned to me as a leader.
As you said, you're no different
than you were yesterday.
Yes, but now they have reason
to fear me.
Even with Major Sheppard in the chair,
we weren't able to...
What? What is that?
Something you said made me wonder...
- There are more important...
- Why did that Wraith stop experimenting?
- What did I say?
- I don't remember.
It's a good point. I'm just wondering
what I said. What have you got?
At first I thought
the other Wraith caught him.
- They didn't?
- He stopped on his own.
Why didn't the Wraith want
these experiments taking place?
- Exactly.
- They were intended to improve things.
- That's it.
- I just said it.
- Will you stop?
- Here's the most interesting part.
The Wraith communicate
using a telepathic network.
I noticed that.
Thankfully, they can't seem to read
the minds of humans, though.
What does this have to do
with the experiments?
By combining even small amounts
of Wraith DNA with humans,
the scientist was giving the humans
Wraith mental abilities.
The subjects of his experiments
could hear the Wraith communications.
The voices that the people heard were...
Were Wraith. Exactly.
It must have driven them mad.
The Wraith scientist couldn't find
a way around it, so he gave up.
Why let them back
into the general population?
He thought that interbreeding with
normal humans might dilute the effect.
Before he realised, it was too late.
When the other Wraith did find out
what he had done,
they wiped out all the people on the planet.
But not before several test subjects
had been ostracised and forced to leave.
How does this help us?
Teyla may have more than just the ability
to sense the Wraith coming.
You think Teyla might be able
to tap into this Wraith psychic network?
If she can, we'll be able to gather
all the intel we ever needed about them.
I have never been able to hear
the thoughts of the Wraith.
According to the notes, those who were
given the Wraith DNA had the ability.
You've never actually tried before.
You didn't know you could read
Wraith minds. Who would want to?
I would not even consider
asking you to do this
if I didn't think it could provide us
with vital information.
I just do not know what to do.
Dr Heightmeyer has a theory.
I think it's possible
that through several generations,
people have developed a mental barrier
to the thought projections of the Wraith,
a self-defence mechanism.
- If we can get past that...
- How?
We have a process called hypnosis.
Dr Heightmeyer can lead you through it
and Dr Beckett will remain on hand
at all times to monitor your physiology.
The Wraith are far away, are they not?
Yes, and McKay has some doubts
about the range of this telepathy.
But, as you said,
you can sense the Wraith now.
If that's a bleed-through effect
of a greater latent ability,
then it may be worth
trying to break the barrier.
It's not something
I would ever recommend doing
under any other circumstances.
But these are far from normal
circumstances that we're in, Teyla.
If I can somehow provide us with
something, their strategy, a weakness...
...I see no other choice.
OK, I think we're ready.
Are you?
OK, I want you to breathe...
...nice and deeply, and try to relax.
Dr Beckett's going to administer
a mild sedative.
We should still be able to communicate.
We can wake you at any time
using a low-grade electrical current.
It won't hurt at all.
Just say "out" and we'll end it.
Now, focus on this light as I speak.
The feeling you get from the Wraith
is a cold, dark feeling deep inside you.
I want you to think about that.
Look for it in your mind.
Now, close your eyes and listen to it.
Don't resist.
Go to that place where it lives.
What do you hear?
Nothing.
Your father was taken by the Wraith.
Do you remember sensing it that day?
- Yes.
- Think back to that feeling.
Now listen.
What do you hear?
Noise.
Voices, so many voices, whispering.
Listen closely. Listen for one.
- I can see.
- Tell us what you see, Teyla.
I am on a ship.
- I am walking.
- She can see what's happening?
The Wraith's thoughts
may include what they're seeing.
There are other Wraith,
and they do not notice me.
I am in a room full of people being
preserved so that they can be fed upon.
Aargh!
I am feeding. I am killing him!
Stop. Beckett, stop.
It's OK. It's OK. You're here, in Atlantis.
Teyla, I... I had no right
to ask you to do this.
- Get these things off of me.
- Settle down. I have to take this off.
I can't put her through this.
It's too much to ask.
You might feel differently
once the hive ships show up.
- Why did you make them stop?
- Excuse me?
I was on one of the hive ships
headed here.
I could hear them. I could see.
It was working.
- You were watching them feed.
- Yes.
I actually felt one of them feed,
but I can handle it.
- I can help us.
- I never should've...
I am going to try again.
I am walking through the ship.
I am in some sort of control room.
Er...
You are all so pathetic.
Something tells me
that's not Teyla talking.
Nothing can stop us.
Wake her up.
- You are all going to die.
- Now!
What happened?
Dr Beckett has her sedated.
I would like some time
to let what she's been through sink in.
She may be in shock. I have no idea
what the long-term effect will be.
She said she could see
some type of control room.
- She just needs to get a better look.
- You were there.
A Wraith had control of her.
Incoming wormhole.
Sergeant Bates' IDC. It's the Alpha site.
This is Sergeant Bates. Code red.
We're under attack!
Lower the shields.
Move it, move it!
- That's it, we're clear!
- Raise the shield!
Is everybody OK?
All off-world personnel accounted for.
That planet isn't safe any more.
They dropped a device by the gate
as we were leaving.
They're tagging the planet.
If we evacuate,
we need a new place to go.
It was uninhabited.
Why did the Wraith want it?
I don't know.
It's almost like they knew we were there.
I was close. I was so close.
I really think if I had another chance...
You don't have to prove anything.
I think this could make a difference.
I saw a hologram.
I think it was a map, maybe a battle plan.
Their battle plan is to wipe us out.
I'm not so sure that is true.
They want something from us.
- Yeah, they wanna eat us.
- No, something more.
- They are desperate.
- Really?
Yes, it is surprising.
They are confident
in their dominance over us,
but mainly because
there are so many of them;
too many to sustain for long.
They have all awakened early and
there is not enough food to go around.
It was just a feeling.
The voices were so hard to separate.
You don't remember
one speaking through you?
No, but I remember
the feeling just before it happened.
- Next time...
- Dr Weir won't let there be a next time.
If that's true, chances are it was Teyla
who gave away our location to the Wraith.
- There wasn't time.
- Maybe they had a ship in the area.
I admit asking Teyla to connect
with the Wraith may have been a mistake.
With respect, there's no doubt about that.
Take it easy, Sergeant. It's not like
she wilfully gave away our position.
She wants to try again.
She was close to something big
she's convinced we need to know.
I'm sorry. I'm not sure Teyla's
thinking about what's best for herself.
She could compromise us further.
We have more to gain from the Wraith
than they do from us.
She wants to do it. There may be
nothing we can do to stop her trying,
so isn't it better if we're all there?
OK. Close your eyes and relax
and listen for the voices.
Teyla?
- Break the connection.
- It's not working.
- No!
- Teyla!
I hope we haven't caused her
psychological damage.
Teyla's strong. She's been able to hold it
together after what she's been through.
There you are. Major, Dr Weir.
Carson, how are you feeling?
Doozy of a headache, but I'll be fine.
Teyla's awake.
She wants to see both of you.
Teyla, can I get you some water?
No. I am so sorry.
- I thought I could prevent...
- It's all right. Everyone's fine.
We are concerned
the Wraith can connect at will.
It has never happened before.
No, I am sure
I have to connect with them first.
I saw their plans, the route
their ships are taking to get here.
- That's good.
- There's more.
They do not just want Atlantis.
- They know about you.
- What do you mean?
Sumner. The female Wraith
wasn't just feeding on him.
- She was interrogating him.
- That is why they're all waking up.
That is why they are coming here.
They know that Atlantis is the only way
to get to a new, rich feeding ground.
Earth.
Subtitles by Lecavalier
For the BST