Previously on Stargate Atlantis...
Major Sheppard,
who are all these people?
I am Teyla Emmagan,
Daughter of Tagan.
If the Wraith haven't touched your world,
you should go back.
We'd like to, but we can't.
I don't see a life form like this
dying of natural ageing.
You trespassed upon our feeding ground.
You don't know what you have done.
- It's Major Sheppard's IDC.
- They've only been gone a few hours.
Atlantis, this is Sheppard.
We're coming in hot.
Lower the shield.
Raise the shield.
McKay!
Medical team to the gate room!
I got a pulse.
How you feeling?
I can't feel anything. I can't talk.
- You can't talk either.
- That's what I said.
Your body experienced an overload
to its sensory and motor nervous system.
What?
You took one of those Wraith stunners
in the face.
It's quite fascinating, actually.
The Wraith weapon
impedes a fire of neurons...
- I'm paralysed?
- The paralysis is only temporary.
Don't worry.
You'll be up and about in no time.
Good thing that Wraith weapon is only
designed to incapacitate, or he'd be dead.
What?
Major, could I see you for a second?
Hello? Hello?
- He's gonna be fine.
- I've heard.
- I want to know what happened out there.
- The same old thing.
Which makes it the fifth time
your teams encountered the Wraith
out of how many missions?
Nine. So probably not a coincidence.
I think it's pretty damn obvious now.
We've got a spy in Atlantis.
Could you please not do that here?
My foot is still numb, if you'll excuse me.
At least your mouth still works fine.
All right, let's get started.
- Shouldn't we wait for Teyla?
- Teyla wasn't invited.
She's a member of my team.
- She's also an Athosian, sir.
- So?
If we've been compromised,
as indications suggest,
one of them is probably responsible.
We're talking about Teyla.
- I don't like it either...
- Good.
..but the safety of this base
and its personnel are my main concern.
As they should be yours.
The Wraith have shown up on five
of the nine planets your team has visited,
and given that
two of those worlds were unpopulated,
we can assume they have been alerted
to your missions by someone on this base.
If that is so,
then why hasn't Atlantis been attacked?
Good point.
Maybe we should stop
using the Stargate indefinitely.
- We can't do that.
- Why not?
- We need ZPMs to power this place.
- They seem to be running fine.
When the Wraith do show up, and
they will, how do we defend ourselves?
Or get back to Earth?
This is the only Stargate in the galaxy
that can reach Earth.
We'll have to use the self-destruct
before the Wraith take the city.
Bottom line, we need to use the gate.
We've got to find out
who's responsible ASAP.
We should confine all non-base personnel
to the south side of the complex.
- Are you kidding?
- That's the minimum.
- If Colonel Sumner was still...
- He's not.
- I am.
- Yes, sir.
We're not gonna start
treating anyone like prisoners.
Well, that's good.
But steps should be taken to safeguard
the more sensitive areas of this facility.
It's only reasonable.
No-go zones should start
with Stargate operations.
Labs, power generation
and the jumper bay.
I'd like to meet
with every Athosian on this base.
I only know a handful by name.
I'll set up interviews
when we're done here.
In the meantime, all gate travel
is suspended until further notice.
- Sorry, you can't come up.
- I'm on my way to see Dr Weir.
- That area's off limits.
- Since when?
I believe there's been a misunderstanding.
I was unaware a meeting had been called.
Let's take a walk.
- What is happening?
- There may be a security leak on Atlantis.
- Are you certain?
- Not certain certain, but pretty certain.
- We have to take temporary precautions.
- Such as?
Like suspending gate travel,
tightening security...
getting to know your people a little better.
You suspect an Athosian?
Dr Weir wants to meet them.
It's not personal.
It is in the sense that
she wants to meet them personally...
You know the horrors my people
have faced at the hands of the Wraith,
yet you question their loyalty?
Teyla, that's not fair. People are running
around Atlantis that she's never met.
I know each one of them.
I would stake my life on their innocence.
Perhaps you've noticed that
every time we step through the Stargate,
bad guys try to kill us.
- I'm getting tired of it. How about you?
- That does not mean...
Look, all we're asking for
is a little cooperation, that's all.
You shall have it.
Halling, how's Jinto?
Well enough for a boy
confined to his living quarters.
I'm sorry. It's temporary,
but it is a necessary precaution.
So I've heard.
Then I assume you know
why we've arranged these meetings?
The same reason my people cannot
go offworld or enter parts of the city.
- You no longer trust us.
- The truth... We don't know who to trust.
Information about offworld excursions
has obviously found its way to the Wraith.
- Obviously?
- They can't be lying in wait everywhere.
They are tracking our movements
and we need to find out how.
Your help would be greatly appreciated.
Then by all means.
How can I be of assistance?
Thank you.
You've been offworld three times?
I've been a guide for Sergeant
Stackhouse's reconnaissance team,
helping establish relations between your
people and our former trading partners.
Stackhouse reported he lost track of you
on a couple of these outings.
I did visit some close friends.
Interesting. Two of your visits predated
Wraith attacks by approximately a day.
- What are you suggesting?
- Nothing.
You think I would betray my own people?
Jeopardise my son's life?
- No one is making accusations.
- I disagree.
You have concluded
an Athosian is responsible.
Because it can't possibly
be one of our own people.
No?
We just need to clarify a few things.
Then allow me.
I lost my closest friend in the Wraith attack
that forced us from our home world.
Selana, the woman you just spoke to,
lost both her parents.
You'd be hard pressed to find an Athosian
who has not experienced loss
at the hands of the Wraith.
These are the people you accuse.
We are not accusing anyone.
I came here expecting an interview.
Not an interrogation.
- I don't think it's too much to ask.
- What is it?
- Buck up. I'm trying to run a diagnostic.
- Sorry.
We are stranded
with limited resources in another galaxy.
The nearest Bob's Big Boy
is 300 million light years away.
If you have to eat my favourite food
twice in a row, so be it.
- You enjoy military rations?
- I know, it's weird. Hospital food, too.
I don't like airplane food
because you can't get seconds...
Hello.
- What is it?
- A new command subroutine.
What is its function?
I don't know
because I've never seen it before.
I'm gonna cross-reference this
with the Ancient database.
I'm gonna grab the...
- What did you touch?
- Nothing.
No, I...
- I had no idea the roof could do that.
- Neither did I.
The gate room has been closed to us.
We no longer have access
to the medical facility without escort.
We're under constant surveillance.
- How long must we put up with this?
- It's already been too long.
I'd have expected
to be included in this.
As we would have expected you
to take a stand for us.
They will protect everyone on this base.
That includes all of you.
A Wraith collaborator threatens us all.
- You support the decision to confine us?
- Halling, we are their guests.
We're more like their prisoners, but
unlike prisoners we can choose to leave.
- Where would you go?
- Do you not mean, where would we go?
Our friends in other worlds
would take us in.
For how long? Good trading partners
do not necessarily make good hosts.
- There are many worlds.
- No world is safe.
Nor is it safe to remain. They will
continue until they find someone to blame.
You know none of our people
could be responsible.
- Of course.
- Then we have nothing to fear.
- You trust Dr Weir that much?
- I do.
- More than you trust your own people?
- No.
I understand her responsibility.
Halling, we have met with the Wraith
offworld so often and so quickly,
there must be a reason
beyond coincidence.
Give them a chance to find it.
I do not approve
of some of their measures,
but I do know that in the end
they will help to prove our innocence.
Atlantis is far more than shelter. It is hope.
Not only for us, but for everyone
who would stand against the Wraith.
We must not abandon that hope.
They may reside here, Teyla,
but they are not the Ancestors,
no matter how much
you wish them to be.
- Sir?
- Ford.
They got the sunroof open
on the jumper bay.
- Yep.
- You're planning to take a jumper out.
I figure that's what
the door on the roof is for.
Anyone else call shotgun?
Just gonna drive around the planet,
check it out.
You're just checking out the planet?
Never mind. That's cool.
I got better things to do than
cruise around the planet in a spaceship.
- You're like a kid, you know that?
- Yes, sir.
- I brought something to eat on the ride.
- What?
How about a nice turkey sandwich?
Let's go.
Send in whoever's next, please.
Teyla. I wasn't expecting you.
I was surprised to be left off your list.
I didn't feel it was necessary in your case.
On the contrary.
You should have spoken to me first.
You're right. I should have.
I can tell you anything
you need to know about my people.
Is it possible you don't know them all
as well as you think?
I empathise with you, Dr Weir.
As leaders, we often
have to make difficult decisions
in the interests of those we serve,
but many of my fellow Athosians
are not so understanding.
I know. But there's nothing
I can do about that now.
People can suspect my motives
for these meetings all they want.
You and I need to agree
that we have a problem.
I have to do what I can to solve it,
and right now that means
talking with every single person here.
You should know
there is talk of leaving Atlantis.
I hope it doesn't come to that.
Not all change is for the worse.
This is Jumper Three.
We are go for bay launch.
Jumper Three, you are good to go.
Yes, we are.
It's strange not pulling any Gs.
Yeah. Kinda miss it.
Although at this rate of acceleration,
we'd be dead by now.
- Yeah?
- Oh, yeah.
Without inertial dampening, we'd be hit
by so many Gs our eyes would pop,
skin would come off our faces,
our brains would hit the back of our skulls
and our internal organs
would be crushed into these chairs.
What about that sandwich?
We're orbiting the planet. We'll advise
when we're back in radio range.
Copy that, Jumper Three. Good luck.
- We still haven't named the planet.
- I'm sure the Ancients have a name for it.
How about Atlantica,
something like that?
Didn't we agree you weren't
gonna name anything any more?
Sir...
Is that... land?
Yes, it is.
I wonder how big it is.
- Big.
- Really big.
- It's huge.
- Define huge.
15 million square miles. Well, give or take.
That would make it the size of...
I have no idea, but it sounds huge...
- How long would it take us to get there?
- 25 minutes by jumper.
I saw some sweet breakers
on the south tip.
There may be surfing in our future.
We should get soil and water samples.
Arable land could solve
our food-production problems.
- I was thinking of something else.
- Not surfing?
No. We can't resume offworld missions
while the Athosians remain in the city.
You want to dump them
on the mainland?
- We're not sending them to die.
- How would you know?
- It looked wild.
- Just now we were going surfing.
That was after we check for monsters
and bugs and other space-related things.
I can't imagine it's worse than their home.
That may be failure of imagination.
A survey would tell us
what we need to know.
You're not seriously thinking about this?
We're the reason
they had to leave their planet.
- This is a complicated situation.
- What does that mean?
It means I'm not about to rule anything out
at this point.
Dr Weir. Is it true
you've discovered land on this world?
Yes, it is.
- My people wish to explore it.
- You would?
- We're not welcome here.
- That's not true.
It will make us useful as long as
we have no access to the gate.
- We don't even know if it's safe.
- We can determine that...
for both our people.
Up until now you've been insisting
on access to the Stargate.
Now you're proposing
to cut yourself off from it?
We cannot leave... and we cannot stay.
- The mainland gives us a third option.
- I see.
- You said this was a temporary measure.
- Yes.
You have the means to assure us passage
between Atlantis and the mainland
when you decide
to resume use of the gate.
If we resume our missions
through the Stargate
and stop encountering
the Wraith at every turn,
it will prove
that there is an Athosian spy.
And when you continue to encounter
the Wraith at every turn,
it will only prove our innocence.
Have you discussed this with Teyla?
Teyla has made her decision.
I understand you're not coming with us.
Dr Weir has arranged for communications
between Atlantis and the mainland.
Should you ever need assistance...
Thank her for us.
I hope...
I don't want anyone to believe that I'm...
Teyla.
The time has come.
Go safely.
And you.
I've never been separated
from my people before.
It must be hard,
but you know you'll see them again.
Do you doubt
you will one day return to Earth?
I can't afford to have doubts.
You mean you cannot afford
to let them show.
You're still a leader, Teyla.
You're doing this
for your people and for their future.
They know that.
Anxious to step through the gate again?
- Yes, I am.
- We all are.
- Like us to bring back anything?
- No.
- Groceries? A new outfit?
- No, just yourselves in one piece, please.
Dial it up.
Be safe.
Well, good stuff?
I can't begin to tell you
how fascinating this is.
Anthropologist fascinating
or actual fascinating?
Maybe fascinating isn't the right word.
Maybe not. How much longer?
We'll probably need to come back.
There's just so much here.
I can see that.
Is there any way to speed things up?
Sure. Find me someone
to translate some of the runes.
- Did you say there were natives here?
- They are very shy.
They've probably gone into hiding.
Can you coax them out,
have them give us a hand?
It is unlikely, but I could try.
Lieutenant, go with her.
- It would be better if I went alone.
- You will be alone. With Ford.
Maybe they're not around.
They are near,
but you are a stranger to them.
They will not come out if you are with me.
They are not a dangerous people,
Lieutenant. I will be fine.
All right. I'll wait here.
Call me on the radio if you need me.
Wraith! Get back to the gate now!
Teyla!
Major, what's the situation?
We're taking fire. You'll have to
circle around to get back to the gate.
- Teyla's not with me. She went to...
- Find her. Get back.
Move out!
Argh!
Yamato! McKay! Grab the major.
- What about Teyla and Ford?
- Now!
Shut it down.
They're right behind us.
OK. On three. One, two, three.
- We have to go back.
- Teyla? Lieutenant Ford?
- Still there.
- You have Wraith all over the gate.
We can't just leave them there.
- How many?
- It's hard to say.
We need to mount a rescue operation.
I am not gonna send anyone
through that gate until I have all the facts.
How did Teyla and Ford get separated?
They went to make contact
with the natives.
- And whose idea was that?
- Mine. She was following my orders.
- Shouldn't you be back in the infirmary?
- No, I'm fine. I didn't take a full blast.
- Why didn't you go with them, Major?
- The natives are easily spooked.
Teyla thought we'd scare 'em off.
- Teyla did.
- What's that, Sergeant?
She was absent during the ambush.
- So was Ford. Maybe it was him.
- I'm just stating a fact.
Sergeant, I am only
gonna say this once.
With all due respect,
reprimand me if you wish,
but it's been six times
your team's been compromised.
Only one Athosian
knew about this last mission.
Unscheduled offworld activation.
It's Teyla's IDC.
Receiving a radio transmission.
This is Teyla.
Lieutenant Ford has been wounded.
The Wraith are closing in on our position.
Put down that shield
and we could have a Wraith attack.
Atlantis, please let us through.
Lieutenant, can you confirm the situation?
He is unconscious.
Our situation grows desperate.
We have no choice
but to go through the Stargate.
Who knows what
she'll bring through that gate with her.
Open up the damn gate!
Lower the shield.
If she were helping the Wraith,
why bother bringing Ford back?
In fact, why bother coming back at all?
She's of more use to them in Atlantis.
As for apparently rescuing Ford...
She carried him through the damn gate!
- We still don't know what happened.
- Oh, that's enough.
- It's my job to express concerns.
- I've heard enough.
I believe you're putting
your personal feelings...
You're dismissed.
Yes, sir.
- What?
- I put him in charge of security.
Yes, you did, and if you want
to dismiss me, go ahead.
Why don't you go and see
how Lieutenant Ford is doing?
You want me to go through her stuff?
We're looking for weapons,
transmitters, recording devices.
Anything beyond
the Athosians' level of technology.
And then we move on to a strip search?
Just do it.
We were on our way back when
we came under fire. Didn't even see them.
We returned fire then broke for the gate.
I was hit from behind.
- She saved my ass.
- Of course she did.
Major... Ford, how are you feeling?
Pins and needles all over?
Welcome to the club.
No, I managed to dive out of the way
of the stunner blast.
- I hit my head on the way down.
- Hit your head?
Major, I need you to see something.
I'll be fine.
- What the hell is this?
- It was a request from Sergeant Bates.
I'm gonna bust him.
Teyla has nothing to do with this.
The thing is, he was right.
- Bates was right?
- I was as surprised as you are. Look.
It's her locket. It's a transmitter.
It's been broadcasting a signal.
- I wouldn't even have noticed...
- I found it.
- What?
- Back on her planet the first time we met.
Teyla took me to the old ruins.
That was half-buried in dirt. I gave it to her.
I lost this years ago.
The locket isn't powerful enough
to send a signal far through subspace.
My guess is there are relay devices
on certain planets
that pick up the transmission
and alert a hive ship.
- The planets where we were attacked.
- We owe a few people an apology.
Teyla had no idea
she was giving away your position?
It was a present from her father.
She lost it when she was a kid.
It was dormant
until Major Sheppard picked it up.
How come they weren't attacked
back then?
- I said it was dormant.
- But if it was activated by touch?
You're not listening.
I said Major Sheppard activated it.
To the Wraith,
Teyla is just another human being.
They have no interest in her.
Now, Major Sheppard...
- Has the Ancient gene.
- Exactly.
At one point the Wraiths
and the Ancients were at war.
The Wraiths made a device
to detect Ancients.
Some Athosian thought
this would make a nice little necklace?
How could I know that?
What am I, Answer Man?
It wasn't Teyla.
Or any other Athosian, for that matter.
If that's the case...
we can use it against 'em.
- You seem nervous.
- No, I'm doing this.
Yes, you are.
I just said you seemed nervous.
I thought you said,
"You don't have to do this."
I'm doing this, despite the fact that feeling
hasn't returned to my extremities.
- You're late.
- Sorry.
Now, given the Wraiths'
regenerative abilities,
killing one
requires some amount of effort.
Capturing one live is another deal.
For these options to work,
your Wraith must be on the ground.
The ruins around the Stargate should
force the Wraith to come through on foot.
In which case...
you'll be able to use these.
This is a stun grenade.
It contains aluminium
and potassium perchlorate
that, when ignited,
produces a high-pressure wave
that will overwhelm the target
with intense light and sound.
If that doesn't get his head ringing,
in addition... you've got your taser.
With a range of 15 to 20 feet,
it delivers a high-voltage charge
that limits the body's electrical signals,
temporarily paralysing the victim.
Major, this is Ford.
What you got, Lieutenant?
We got company.
Four of them.
- All right, then. We go as planned.
- Yes, sir.
- You still seem nervous...
- No, no. It's good. All good.
Teyla.
This one's ours, boys. Tasers!
Self-destruct. Take cover!
Major! Dr McKay!
- You OK?
- I'm fine. This is... This is fun for me.
Easy. Don't go blowing yourself up.
Teyla. Excuse me.
I hoped to catch you
before you headed back to the mainland.
- I hear they're doing well.
- Very well.
Halling says they're planting crops
for the next harvest.
- I'm glad to hear it.
- I will tell them what has happened.
Hopefully we will be able
to put the past week's events behind us.
Yes. I am aware that the last few days
have been particularly difficult for you.
I believe, Dr Weir, that in your place
I would have done the same.
Thank you.
Again? Your kind is persistent.
I would have thought
you'd given up by now.
Hell, I've got all the time in the world.
Now, you, on the other hand...
The Ancients were pretty good at shields,
weren't they?
I give you a week. Maybe two, tops.
You waste your time.
I will provide you with no information.
I wonder what hurts more:
the gunshot wound or the hunger?
Because I'd love to help out,
but how did McKay put it?
We can't meet your dietary requirements.
When I am free,
you will be the first that I feed upon.
Okey-dokey.
I'm gonna go make myself a sandwich.
Human.
You think you've won a victory
by my capture,
but by bringing me here
you've only hastened your own doom.
It's only a matter of time before
the others of my kind come to rescue me,
and when they do, there'll be
nowhere in this world you can hide.
Stay positive, now.
Subtitles by Lecavalier
For the BST