They are called the Genii. They are simple
people, but good farmers and fair traders.
- They look friendly enough.
- I have often traded with Tyrus.
I'm bringing them in.
All operations to silent mode.
If people could just learn to keep
their secret underground hatches locked.
So, the whole farmer thing is just a front.
- The next culling was decades away.
- We're looking for allies.
We had hoped to test our first
atomic weapon five years from now.
- Do we have that much time, Sheppard?
- No.
How does a Wraith ship's computer
help you?
This interface device
shows the location of Wraith ships.
- You know where to deliver bombs.
- The Wraith must not know we were here.
- Help!
- Leave him!
Please!
- Where's my father?
- He did not survive.
By leaving him to die,
it's as if you killed him.
You do not want to make an enemy
of the Genii.
Haven't been to the mainland in a while.
How's everybody doing?
Halling believes the first crops
will have a good yield.
You still miss home?
There is still talk of returning,
even though the Wraith have scorched
Athos in revenge for our resistance.
Maybe in time this place
will begin to feel like home.
Do you see that?
That can't be a storm.
It stretches across the whole horizon.
I've never seen that from so high.
I've seen a lot from this altitude,
but not that.
This is Jumper One. We're changing
our heading to investigate a storm.
Major, this is Weir. We didn't copy that.
You're breaking up.
I said there's...
..weather forecasting.
Did he just say weather forecasting?
- Do all storms look like this from above?
- No.
This must cover 20% of the planet.
- Is it headed towards the mainland?
- Tracking towards the settlement.
And after that?
Straight to Atlantis.
This planet
is basically the same size as Earth.
Hurricanes on Earth
never get as big as this boy
because once they hit the shore
they slow down.
Without as much land mass to slow
it down here, it's gaining momentum.
- Both of them are.
- Both of them?
- We saw only one.
- It only looked like one.
According to the Ancient database, every
20 or 30 years the sea gets very warm.
That, for rather boring reasons, means
hurricanes are more likely to occur.
- Like El Niño, the ocean...
- Like I said, rather boring.
- Focus.
- If there are a bunch of hurricanes,
the likelihood of two colliding
is increased.
It's more like a merger. They are
intersecting and combining their power.
And... it's headed right towards us.
You said the Ancients experienced
these storms every 20 to 30 years.
Atlantis must have some precautions.
The Ancients were protected by the shield
or submerged deep enough in the water.
OK. Strike those options.
What else have we got?
Nothing. It is a real threat.
The high winds alone will wreak havoc.
Come on, guys.
This city's been around for a long time.
Storm surge is inevitable.
By moving over a land mass before hitting
us, there is a greater risk of tornadoes.
This is Atlantis.
They've gotta be able
to handle that... right?
- No.
- Why not?
The people who built this city
had a force field
capable of holding back anything
nature or the Wraith threw at them.
Without that protection,
Atlantis is remarkably fragile.
Even our conservative calculations
project widespread damage.
- Flooding could sink the city.
- How could something this big just sink?
- The Titanic's passengers asked that too.
- Yes, well, let's not.
What you're saying is
if Teyla and I hadn't discovered this...
We would be in even bigger trouble.
- What's the plan?
- We have 12 hours until the storm hits.
So... we plan to have a plan...
- Yeah.
- ..by then.
We start investigating evacuation plans,
both on the mainland and offworld.
McKay will come up with something.
He's setting himself up to be a hero.
Maybe Rodney is, but Dr Zelenka
seemed genuinely concerned.
So, I find a friendly planet that
wouldn't mind putting us up for the night?
Exactly. Take Ford,
see what you can work out.
I don't have the right boots for this.
I was just meant to come
and inoculate some wee babies.
We need all the hands we can spare
before it comes.
The storm could destroy our settlement
as well as our crops.
- If a few of us remained...
- Homes can be rebuilt. People can't.
Which is why we must do
what we can now.
The entire population of Atlantis.
At most, yes.
Only for a day. Two at most.
We are happy to trade with you
for a share of our crops, but this...
I know it's a lot to ask, but... I'm asking.
What do you offer in return?
I guess we'd owe you one.
- One what?
- A favour.
We're in trouble.
If you're a friend, you'll help.
If not, tell me now
so I can ask somebody else.
But who else would take in so many?
I want something of value in return.
Oh, you do, do you?
We can go find any uninhabited planet.
They're usually uninhabited for a reason.
You know that, or you would not be here.
Still, I'm sure you could find
another world to take you in.
You're just so short on time.
One day you're gonna run across
a problem and need our help.
- Isn't that right, Lieutenant?
- Yes, sir.
And we've got lots of ships and weapons
we can help with.
- You're saying we can be your friends or...
- I much prefer friends.
That is of value to me.
One night. Two, tops.
We bring our own blankets.
- Very well. You may send your people.
- This won't be forgotten.
I'll go back, tell everybody the good news.
- We'll send word once we know more.
- I look forward to it.
- I thought of that.
- He may be on to something.
I've already thought of it. It doesn't...
The naquadah generators
could power sections of the city,
but some areas need to be secure, so
not much power is left for anything else.
- The city breaks apart...
- We could relocate some of them.
If only we had a magical tool
that could slow down time.
I left mine on Earth. What about you?
You're not pleasant
when you're like this, McKay.
- I'm always like this.
- Exactly.
I got a green light from Smeadon.
I'm not sure how pleased he'll be
if we get stuck there.
- It's not gonna happen, right?
- We can always gate off to another planet.
- Comforting. Thank you.
- You sure we can't go to the mainland?
Everywhere is in the storm's path.
My people are evacuating even now.
The mainland's the size of North America.
Will the entire continent get hit?
I'd rather not owe Smeadon any favours.
If we lose Atlantis,
we're left without access to the Stargate.
- McKay will come up with something.
- I will try, but I am not Superman.
Was anyone seriously thinking that?
- No, sir.
- Never.
Fine. The storm will affect over 70%
of the mainland, and Atlantis isn't safe.
If you want everyone to live,
you gate them offworld.
Relay Station Two,
prepare to receive transmission.
RS Two
awaiting transmission. Over.
I need you to relay a message
to Cowen of the Genii.
Tell him we have something to trade.
- This could be going faster.
- Our people are hunters.
Many are returning from great distances.
Others do not want to leave.
They know how serious this is?
Even I would have a hard time
believing in the strength of this storm
if I did not see it from space.
Do what you can to speed things up.
In the Czech Republic
we don't get hurricanes.
We don't get many in Canada.
We once had one called Hazel.
- Hazel?
- 40 years ago.
- That's interesting.
- Not really.
- No, not really.
- I was once almost struck by lightning.
Lightning?
What is the one thing
keeping us from having a shield?
- That...
- Power. What does a storm have lots of?
- Power.
- In the form of...
- You wanna build a windmill?
- Electricity.
Atlantis is designed to withstand lightning
strikes. There are rods everywhere.
They are channelled
into grounding stations.
Those grounding stations
discharge electricity back into the ocean,
keeping Atlantis safe from electric shocks.
Many of the hallways allow a low-voltage
transfer of power throughout the city.
- Which means...
- I'm getting there.
Let's say the grounding stations
weren't around.
If lightning struck,
the halls would be super-charged.
- You want...
- If we disabled the grounding stations...
- Which we can.
- ..every time lightning struck,
Atlantis would experience
a massive power surge. That energy...
- If channelled correctly...
- Of course.
..could be used to charge up
the shield generator.
The more severe the storm, the more
energy, and the shield runs longer.
- It's an ingenious plan.
- I have to agree.
But we have no way
of storing all that energy.
Once the lightning stops striking...
- No way of charging the generator.
- Back to square one.
So, the city would survive?
- A 90% chance...
- 70.
- 80% chance.
- So, we should still evacuate.
- Not just for Zelemka's pessimism.
- Zelenka.
If it works, the city will be
highly charged with electricity.
The only safe place once the lightning
strikes is in the control room.
We must evacuate everyone offworld
for the storm
and execute the plan with a small team.
OK. Good. Get on it.
- To the grounding stations.
- Power distribution centres.
- Good point. I get ahead of myself.
- Yeah, OK...
Commander Kolya. Chief Cowen
needs to see you immediately.
- I'm not to be disturbed while training.
- He said immediately, sir.
- Still haven't turned up?
- I'm afraid not.
They're hunting.
No one has been able to get in touch.
- How many?
- Three. Two boys and a young woman.
Let's take our jumper and find them.
They are hunting in dense vegetation.
We would be unable to land.
- Jumper Three is ready to go...
- Go. I will give the hunters more time.
I'll stay with you.
OK, I get the point. We'll wait.
- They're not ready.
- Yes, they are.
You commissioned me to train men
who on the most treacherous day
guarded this facility
or performed a reconnaissance mission.
They are not yet a strike force.
This is the rarest of opportunities.
In the next hour
there will be under ten people on Atlantis,
most of them only scientists.
Surely you can accomplish our goals
and get out before the storm hits.
If all goes well. But we don't train
assuming all will go well.
We cannot afford
to pass up this opportunity.
- You wanted my opinion. I gave it to you.
- And I value that opinion.
The Atlanteans possess materials that are
vital to defeat the Wraith. We need them.
I need them.
Ready your strike force.
That's everybody.
Just over four and a half hours
till the storm hits.
Let's get down to the labs.
Evacuate the people on inbound
Jumper Two as soon as they come in.
I'm finally at the point
where I don't mind the taste of it.
I was raised on this brew.
Burned away whatever taste sense I had.
So, you think you can teach our farmers
a thing or two?
Yes, that's what I was saying, yes.
Most people think that farming is planting
good seed in well-tilled soil, which it is.
It is, but there's also more,
and that knowledge is here.
You want to trade these marvellous skills
in exchange for a piece of my land?
- I do.
- I think I'll need something more.
Who are you?
Tell me the sequence of numbers
to enter on this device.
I can't tell you that.
It's not worth dying for.
But you don't understand.
It's my hand that you need
to put in the code. That's how it works.
And the shield of the Atlantis Stargate
will be lowered?
Yes. What is this? Who are they?
- Bring him to the gate.
- They're friends.
- Make sure he will enter the code.
- He will.
Do as they say
and we'll see about that piece of land.
You have done a great service
for the Genii and will be rewarded.
There are hundreds of lightning rods
placed around the city.
- Wait.
- What?
- Why?
- Why what?
Why are there hundreds of rods? Wouldn't
the shield protect against lightning?
Yes, but running the shield all the time
is only good for draining power.
- Right.
- You're aware there's a time element?
- Yes, it's been brought to my attention.
- There are lightning rods around the city.
All the energy they capture is routed
into four main grounding stations.
These ground that energy
into the ocean below us.
- Instead of sending electricity to ground...
- We power the shield.
- How?
- By directing it into the shield generators.
- The city can handle that?
- Yes... theoretically.
Like dinosaurs turning into birds,
or Theory of Relativity theoretically?
What? Somewhere between.
Elizabeth, you take Grounding Station
Two. I'll take Grounding Station One.
Major, take Stations Three and Four.
- Where are Stations Three and Four?
- Here and here.
- And we are...
- Here. Yes.
I need to start on the subroutines
and Elizabeth has knee trouble...
Wait. Are these things
even close to a transporter?
- Uh, yes, Elizabeth's is.
- And mine?
- It's a brisk walk away.
- By "brisk" you mean "far"?
- By "walk" I mean "run".
- OK.
Radio once you get to your first station.
All right. Let's do it.
Hurry! Move! Come this way! Hurry!
- You OK?
- Here it comes.
OK, sit here. Strap in as best you can.
It's gonna be a bumpy ride.
- Let's get outta here.
- I'm not certain it's a good idea.
- What?
- Look at it out there.
- We are ready.
- Let's wait it out.
We're safe if we're in here.
We've got rations and plenty of water.
Yeah, especially outside.
I hope you're right. We won't be able
to change our minds if you're wrong.
It'll be cosy.
I'm here!
I told you to contact me
when you got to the first one.
I am at the first one, Rodney.
Oh. Sorry. Already done mine.
- Great. Good for you.
- Me too.
Good for everyone.
- Where are you now?
- I'm at the damn grounding station.
- No, not you.
- I'm in the transporter.
- There you are.
- There I am.
Glad you're having fun.
What do I do?
There should be a keypad on the console.
- Got it.
- Put in the Ancient equivalent of 031547.
That do it?
- Yeah.
- Good.
One to go. They seem to have
the same separation code.
Repeat with the next one.
Meet us in the control room.
Roger that.
- Bacon.
- You wish you'd brought bacon with you?
It's the food
that makes other food worth eating.
You wish you'd brought bacon
to another galaxy?
You asked me...
- Offworld activation.
- No one should be back until tomorrow.
Attack on Manara.
Wounded incoming. Lower the shield.
- They're broadcasting an Athosian IDC.
- Please, before it's too late.
- We are lowering the shield.
- Get the OK from Dr Weir.
They're under attack. Lower the shield.
Dr Weir, there's been an attack on Manara.
- Athosian party incoming with wounded.
- We're on our way.
- What happened?
- They were everywhere.
Check the weapons.
Secure the room.
These men could have been overpowered.
We need the Atlanteans to be cooperative.
Secure the room.
Cover the entrances.
Apparently
there's wounded incoming.
It doesn't make any sense.
They said it was Wraith-related?
We'll ask them ourselves in a second.
Hold on.
What the hell is going on?
Dr Elizabeth Weir.
- Yes.
- And you must be Dr McKay.
That is him.
Where is Major Sheppard?
I'd like to know
Major Sheppard's whereabouts.
You seem to know a lot about us.
- Who are you?
- The Genii.
There's only one thing you need to know.
As of right now,
we are in control of Atlantis.
Jumper Two, this is Sheppard. Come in.
Jumper Two, do you copy?
This is Ford.
We're waiting out the storm in the jumper.
- You're still on the mainland?
- Yes, sir.
We got a situation.
A small Genii strike force has gated in.
The Genii? The folks who wanted us
to build them an A-bomb?
They've got Weir and McKay hostage
and have control of the gate room.
- You're breaking up. Did you say hostage?
- Affirmative.
We're on our way.
- What do you think you're doing?
- You heard him.
Look outside, hotshot.
We're not flying through this.
McKay and Weir were taken hostage.
I can't sit here and do nothing.
Neither of us are real pilots. It was a bad
idea an hour ago. It's an idiotic one now.
- We must take our chances.
- Dr Beckett is right. We're no use dead.
Major, this is Teyla.
The hurricane is in full force outside.
We could attempt to fly through it,
but it's doubtful we'd make it.
And we have three young passengers.
- That's bad news.
- I'm sorry.
So am I. Just stay put till it passes over.
- Sir...
- It's OK, Lieutenant.
Get your ass back here as soon
as you can. I could use some backup.
Good luck, sir.
Who are you?
Commander Acastus Kolya of the Genii.
This Atlantis is extraordinary.
More than I ever imagined.
What have you done
with the rest of my people?
I'm quite sure
they have no idea we're even here.
- Then they're safe?
- Yes.
How were you able to bypass the shield?
With a time-tested combination
of strong drink and weak minds.
There was a time when our two peoples
considered becoming allies.
Why are you doing this?
You're in possession of supplies
we vitally need.
Hand them over without difficulty
and we leave peacefully.
- Or?
- We're both intelligent people, Dr Weir.
I'm sure there's no need for me
to demonstrate the strength of my resolve.
Which supplies did you have in mind?
All of your stores of the C4 explosive.
All of your medical supplies.
The Wraith data device
you stole from my people.
And one of your ships.
- Is that all?
- No.
Where is Major Sheppard?
He's on the mainland.
What you're asking for is not easy.
We've diverted a lot of power
to prepare for the storm.
The armoury's safety doors have shut,
so we can't...
Just so we're clear, I know you lie.
Just give him what he needs.
He needs the C4, the medical supplies
and the Wraith data device. Give it to him.
None of that's worth dying for.
Step away from the console.
I was just leaning.
Your request is unreasonable.
You can't possibly need all our C4
or all our medical supplies.
You're in no position
to tell me what is reasonable.
How do we know you won't kill us
once we give you what we need?
You don't.
Please show my men where they can find
what they're looking for.
- What are you doing here?
- I understand I'm being held hostage.
I mean here in Atlantis.
Why did some of you stay behind?
Oh. Tie up some loose ends.
- Like what?
- Make sure everyone got out OK.
- Isn't that for someone less important?
- You'd think so, wouldn't you?
- You have a plan, don't you?
- I got lots of plans about lots of things.
I'm interested in your plan to save the city.
I never said anything
about saving anything.
Not yet.
Where's Teyla Emmagan?
- You know Teyla?
- Is she here? In the city?
No, she isn't.
You must be Sora. I read the Genii
mission report. I'm sorry about your father.
- He'll be avenged.
- Teyla didn't kill him.
- No. She left him to die.
- She had no choice...
Are you finished?
All of the information we downloaded
from the Wraith ship is still on this device.
- What did they do to you?
- I tried to keep my mouth shut. I couldn't...
What's the meaning of this?
- I honestly have no idea.
- It's a radio.
The arrow points to the talk button.
- This is Commander Kolya.
- Kolya. That's a hard name to pronounce.
Is that a first name?
My name's Major John Sheppard.
I have hidden the C4 where you will never,
I repeat, never, find it.
When I hear that the prisoners have been
safely released and gated off Atlantis,
I will help you find it.
- He's good.
- Yes, he is. I'd do what he says.
- Your offer is very generous, Major.
- Yes, it is.
However, Dr McKay recently told me
there's a plan in action to save the city.
- He did?
- He did.
I understand one final grounding station
needs to be deactivated.
Uncouple the grounding rods at Station
Three, assist in reactivating the shield
and you and your friends
can leave unharmed.
Wait a minute. I thought all you wanted
was C4 and a jumper.
Why raid a city
when you can seize it, Major?
Atlantis will be ours or the ocean's.
You choose.
We should have heard something
from the major.
- He may not have had a chance.
- I hate not knowing what's going on.
- Why would the Genii attack us now?
- We didn't exactly leave on the best terms.
We stole some of their gear
and didn't give them C4 as promised,
and they think Teyla killed one of them.
They believe so falsely. The fact that they
chose our weakest hour is no coincidence.
Someone must have told them
we'd be diminished.
- There must be a way back.
- Those winds are blowing at 110 knots.
We're not going anywhere, son.
Thank you for seeing me.
This city was designed to be inhabited
by the Ancients and their descendants.
Although there is limited functionality for
those who do not have the Ancient gene,
only those who have it
can revive the city to its true potential.
- And you have this gene?
- No, but many of my team do.
The Wraith are slowly waking.
Soon this galaxy will be in a war the likes
of which our generations have never seen.
A war that you expedited.
Disagreements like ours
will no longer matter.
The only thing of any consequence
will be how prepared we are
and what defence we are able to mount.
This city holds many secrets
which could help us win that war.
But only if my team
are here to discover them.
So, fine, take whatever you need
for your people,
but if you don't leave us this city,
you're hurting yourselves in the long run.
You believe your people,
who are not even of this galaxy,
are closer to the Ancients than we are?
Your arrogance is astounding.
We will take this city,
we will mount a defence and we will win,
with or without your help, Dr Weir.
Sir, he's at the grounding station.
- The commander's here.
- He's just standing there, sir.
- Do not approach until he's finished.
- Yes, sir.
Use lethal force only if necessary.
- You told him he would be unharmed.
- Let's hope he doesn't put up a fight.
He's stopped. He's not
at the control panel. He's looking around.
- Hold your fire.
- Those control panels are fragile...
Let me tell you what you did wrong, Kolya.
A: You lost two of your men.
B: You damaged the switch before
I could separate the grounding rods,
which I'm sure you're gonna get
an earful from McKay for.
And C: You lost all of
what little credibility you had with me.
You know how big a setback that is?
I may not be able to activate the shield...
- You killed two of my men.
- I guess we're even.
I don't like even.
I'm not finished yet.
Neither am I.
Say goodbye to Dr Weir.
The city has a self-destruct button.
If you hurt her, I'll activate it.
Nobody'll get Atlantis.
Even if it exists, Major, you need
at least two senior personnel to activate it.
I'm taking one of them out of the equation.
Kolya?
I'll give you a ship.
I'll fly it out of here for you myself.
Kolya?
Subtitles by Lecavalier
For The BST