- Dr Weir.
- Peter.
- You see? Nothing.
- Carson, get back here.
Nothing happens! It's a waste of time!
Excuse me, Dr Weir.
He's not even trying.
He discovered the gene
this technology responds to.
He wishes he never had it.
- Really?
- Can you believe that?
- We could test you a third time, Rodney.
- That's very funny.
We've only a handful of people genetically
compatible with Ancient technology
and, despite your heroic efforts
to interface ours with theirs,
we need all of them
to sit in this chair, including Dr Beckett.
He's afraid of the thing.
This chair controls the most powerful
weapons known to us. I'm afraid of it.
But every time someone sits in it, we learn
something new about the Ancients.
- Dr Beckett should be proud of his genes.
- It is a random characteristic.
This really bothers you,
this whole gene thing?
Oh, clearly I am overcome with envy
Just the people I need to see.
Come with me.
We've gotten closer to locating the Lost
City, but were looking in the wrong place.
We thought we had a Stargate address -
six symbols
that determine where
the Ancients went after Antarctica.
Recently, we determined
a seventh symbol.
- The point of origin, Earth.
- That's not it.
- Then your address must be incorrect.
- Not incorrect. Incomplete.
What are you saying, Dr Jackson?
It's an eight-symbol address.
It's further away than we imagined,
but it's not out of reach.
- Atlantis?
- Atlantis.
I think we can go there.
Apache, Blackhawk, Cobra, Osprey.
It's a lot of training for the Antarctic.
The one continent I'd never set foot on.
It's one of my least favourite continents.
I kind of like it here.
- You like it here?
- Yes, sir.
Be there in about 10 minutes, sir.
We've been through this.
I'm not your man.
- Keep moving.
- I'm a medical doctor.
- There's nothing to be afraid of.
- I break these things!
This has survived
for millions of years. It will survive you.
Now sit down,
close your eyes and concentrate.
Nothing!
This time... just try to imagine an image
of where we are in the solar system.
I think I feel something.
- It could be lunch-related.
- Shut up and concentrate.
Watch out!
What did I do?
Get us back down there!
All inbound craft,
we have a rogue drone
that could seek a target on its own.
Land immediately. This is not a drill.
It's too late. Hang on!
Break right!
- I said right!
- I'm getting to that, sir.
- I told you I was the wrong person.
- Just do something!
- Like what?
- Carson...
concentrate on shutting that weapon down
before it hurts someone.
- I can't see it!
- Pull up. Pull up!
- What about now?
- Now's good.
Shut it down!
- Sir, what the hell was that?
- Wait for it.
Get out!
I think I did it.
- That was different.
- For me... not so much.
The drone appears
to have been incapacitated.
General O'Neill's helicopter
is unharmed and on its way again.
- Seven minutes out.
- Thank God.
Holy crap!
- Jack!
- Daniel!
- Warm welcome
- It wasn't me. How did you...
Keep my ass from getting blown up?
The exceptional flying
of Major John Sheppard. He likes it here.
- Exceptional? You like it here?
- Let's say you start talking real fast.
Weir's in here.
Hey! Don't touch anything.
Yes, sir.
I figure the Ancients packed up and left
between five and ten million years ago.
In their... flying city?
Yes.
What?
Flying city?
Well, keep in mind
this is the race that built the Stargates.
They did everything big.
So, why did they leave?
Um, who knows?
On Earth, they suffered from a plague.
Maybe some of them were trying to start
over, seeding life in a new galaxy.
- The point is, we know where they went.
- Pegasus.
Yes. It's a dwarf galaxy in the local group.
Is there any hope
of actually meeting them?
Well, who knows,
but isn't that reason enough to go?
I've been choosing members
for this expedition for months.
- I'm not the one who needs convincing.
- Well, I'm convinced.
- Have fun.
- It's a little more complicated than that.
We need the Zed PM to power the gate.
- What?
- The ZPM. He's... he's Canadian.
- I'm sorry.
- The Zero Point Module, General.
The power source
you recovered from Proclarush Taonas.
It's now powering the outpost defences.
I've determined it generates
its enormous power from vacuum energy
from a self-contained region
of subspace time.
That was a waste
of a perfectly good explanation.
The answer's no.
I shut my eyes and saw it.
I felt this power I've never had before.
I had it dancing across the sky.
It was magical, it really was.
I don't know where it came from.
I just tried to concentrate
and the drone shut itself down.
So you were the one?
Me?
You're the one who fired that thing at me.
Look, we're doing research,
working with technology light years
beyond us, and we make mistakes.
I'm incredibly, incredibly sorry.
- Next time, be more careful.
- That's what I said.
- What the hell was that thing, anyway?
- The drone?
- The Ancients built it to defend the place.
- The who?
You do have
security clearance to be here?
General O'Neill just gave it to me.
- You don't even know about the Stargate?
- The what?
Gating to another galaxy
requires enormous power.
- Yes. Find another way.
- There's no other way.
You think there are
more of these... zed things in Atlantis?
Yes! And who knows what else.
This isn't just anyone.
These are the gate builders.
The potential wealth
of knowledge and technology
outweighs anything we've come across
since we stepped through the Stargate.
Well, with the amount of power you need
to make this trek, odds are it'll be one-way.
Yes, we know, but the benefit to humanity
is far greater than the risk, General.
A risk every one of
my expedition members is willing to take.
We think the gene was used
as a sort of genetic key, if you will,
so that only their kind could operate
dangerous or powerful technologies.
Some people have
the same genes as these Ancients?
The specific gene is very rare, but, on
the whole, they look very much like we do.
In fact, they were first.
We're the second evolution of this form,
the Ancients having explored this galaxy
for millions of years. Please, don't.
Why? What are the odds of me having
the same genes as these guys?
Quite slim, actually. Dr Weir!
Don't move!
Who is this?
- I said don't touch anything.
- I just sat down.
Major, think about
where we are in the solar system.
Did I do that?
We could be on our way to discovering
an entirely new Ancient civilisation.
Best-case scenario, we meet
actual Ancients who are willing to help us.
But if we don't...
General, we need him.
- Sorry, Doc. I need Daniel here.
- I'm talking about Major Sheppard.
Oh. Don't you have a dozen or so people
already who can use Ancient technology?
Yeah, with concentration and training,
but John Sheppard, he does it naturally.
- I checked into his record.
- The black mark in Afghanistan.
- He was trying to save lives.
- Disobeying a direct order in the process.
I have read your own file, General. Please.
Right.
OK. It's your expedition.
If you want him, you ask him.
That's the thing. I have.
Really?
This isn't a long trip,
so I'll be as succinct as possible.
- Well, that's pretty succinct.
- Thank you.
I told Dr Weir that, you know...
I'd think about it.
And?
So? Well? What?!
With all due respect, sir,
we were just attacked by an alien missile.
Then I found out I have some mutant gene.
Then there's this Stargate thing
and these expeditions to other galaxies...
This isn't about you, Sheppard.
It's a lot bigger.
Right now, at this very second, whether I
decide to go or not seems to be about me.
Let me ask you something.
- Why did you become a pilot?
- People who don't want to fly are crazy.
I think people who don't want to go
through the Stargate are equally whacked.
If you can't give me a yes by the time
we reach McMurdo, I don't even want you.
Simon, if you're watching this,
it means the president was kind enough
to grant you security clearance.
I'm not going on a diplomatic mission
to another country.
I'm going
to another planet in another galaxy
by means of a device called a Stargate.
Millions of years ago, there was
a race of beings we called the Ancients.
They created a network of these Stargates
throughout our galaxy
in order to travel freely
among their worlds.
We don't know why,
but they left for another galaxy
five to ten million years ago,
taking their entire city along with them.
That city was called Atlantis.
I have been assembling
an expedition team to try to find Atlantis
and, hopefully, the Ancients
who left Earth all those years ago.
I want to do this, Simon, with all my heart.
You know me well enough to know I could
never turn down an opportunity like this,
but I wanted the chance to tell you...
The cellular customer you wish
to reach is outside the coverage area.
No kidding.
I narrowed it down to three things.
After a week, it just fell into place.
Does anyone else here speak whatever
language these guys are speaking?
I just need a couple of minutes
to finish my work and you're not helping.
You've got five minutes
to get it going or I'm leaving.
Everything in here has been
double-checked and triple-checked.
- Leave it alone.
- Colonel, I don't answer to you.
- He said the same to me, sir.
- That's what your side arm's for.
The eight-chevron address tells our gate
to look for a point outside of our galaxy.
We won't know until it locks.
- Are we there yet?
- Just waiting on Dr McKay.
It should work now. That's got it.
OK, Sergeant, give it a try. The ZPM
should light up when it senses the gate.
Oh, yeah!
Colonel.
Can I have everyone's attention, please?
All right, here we go.
We are about to try to make a connection.
We have been unable to predict
how much power this will take
and we may only get one chance,
so if we achieve a stable wormhole,
we're not gonna risk
shutting the gate down.
We'll send in the MALP robot probe,
check for viability and go.
Everything in one shot.
Every one of you volunteered for this
mission. You represent a dozen countries.
You are the world's best and brightest.
And in light of the adventure
we are about to embark on...
you are also the bravest.
I hope we all return having discovered a
whole new realm for humanity to explore,
but, as all of you know,
we may never be able to return home.
I'd like to offer you all one last chance
to withdraw your participation.
Begin the dialling sequence.
Let me make myself clear, Major.
You are not here by my choice.
I'm sure you'll warm up to me
once you get to know me, sir.
As long as you remember
who's giving the orders.
That would be Dr Weir, right?
Chevron three encoded.
- Chevron four encoded.
- Nice.
Thank you.
Chevron five encoded.
- Chevron six encoded.
- This is it.
Seriously, Doctor, calm down
You're embarrassing me.
I've never been so excited in my entire life.
Chevron eight is locked.
Send the MALP.
We have MALP telemetry.
- What is it we're looking at?
- Switching to zero locks.
The radar indicates a... large room?
Structurally intact?
Sensors say there's oxygen,
no measurable toxins.
We have viable life support.
Looks like we're not getting out of this.
Dr Weir, you have a go.
Thank you.
Sir.
Let's go, people! We don't know
how much power we've got.
Security Teams One and Two, up first.
All other personnel
will follow on our signal!
Once on the other side,
keep moving, clear the debarkation area!
- On my lead...
- Hold on, Colonel!
We go through together.
Fair enough.
- Jack, it's not too late for me...
- No.
- I can just grab my... kit.
All clear. It looks good.
Expedition Team... move out.
What does it feel like?
Hurts like hell, sir.
Whoo-hoo!
Teams One and Two,
secure the immediate area.
Everyone else, find an open space
and park it until instructed otherwise!
Who's doing that?
Security Teams, any alien contact?
- Negative, sir.
- Team Four. Negative, Colonel.
The lights are coming on by themselves.
That's everyone.
General O'Neill?
Atlantis Base offers greetings
from the Pegasus galaxy.
You may cut power to the gate.
They look like ships.
- Spaceships!
- I love it!
Dr Weir? You have to see this.
I have a lot of things to see.
Just be careful.
- I didn't touch anything.
- Relax, Major.
It's like the entire complex is sensing
our presence and coming to life.
This is the control room.
Obviously their version of a DHD.
- Obviously
- This could be power control systems.
- Possibly a computer interface.
- Hey, why don't you find out?
Dr Weir, Colonel Sumner.
Can you meet me? Three levels down.
Right away.
We've only secured
a fraction of the place. It's huge.
- So it might really be Atlantis?
- I'd say that's a good bet.
Oh, my God.
We're underwater.
I'd say we're under
several hundred feet of ocean.
If we can't dial out, it's a problem.
- Colonel. Dr Weir.
- We're underwater!
Yes, I was just coming to tell you.
Some sort of force field is holding it back.
That is impressive, isn't it?
Uh, Dr Beckett
has found something you should see.
..in the hope of spreading new life in
a galaxy where there appeared to be none.
Soon the new life grew and prospered.
It's a hologram.
The recording loops. It's my second time.
- What have we missed?
- Not much.
..exchange knowledge and friendship.
In time, a thousand worlds
bore the fruit of life in this form.
Then one day our people set foot upon
a dark world where a terrible enemy slept.
Never before had we encountered beings
with powers that rivalled our own.
In our overconfidence,
we were unprepared and outnumbered.
The enemy fed upon the defenceless
human worlds like a great scourge
until only Atlantis remained.
This city's great shield was powerful
enough to withstand their weapons,
but here we were besieged
for many years.
In an effort to save the last of our kind,
we submerged our great city
into the ocean.
The Atlantis Stargate was the one and only
link back to Earth from this galaxy
and those who remained used it to return
to that world that was once home.
There the last survivors of Atlantis
lived out the remainder of their lives.
This city was left to slumber...
in the hope
that our kind would one day return.
Huh.
So the story of Atlantis is true.
A great city that sank in the ocean.
Just not on Earth.
The Greeks must have heard it
from one of the surviving Ancients.
I don't like the fact
they got their asses kicked.
Let's see it again from the beginning.
Stop! Turn it off!
- Power levels are dropping like a stone!
- What does that mean?
If we don't stop everything we're doing
right now, we're dead!
Please tell me this is not my fault.
- No.
- Thank you!
The city is powered
by three Zero Point Modules.
Two are depleted,
the third is reaching entropy.
- When it does, it'll die too.
- Just tell me the bottom line.
The force field holding back the ocean has
collapsed to minimum sustainable levels.
Look, you can see here and here where
the shield's failed and the city is flooded.
This section is likely more protected
because of the Stargate.
What if it fails completely?
It's a matter of when, not if.
Colonel Sumner, order your security team
to stop searching the city immediately.
Security teams, back to the gate room.
- That's not gonna be good enough.
- How much time do we have?
Hours, days if we minimise
power expenditure.
- What about our own generators?
- We're working on it.
But the equations
are coming up far short.
- So we need to find more ZPMs.
- How do we do that if we can't search?
- If there were more, we'd detect them.
- Can we use the Stargate?
- Not enough power to reach Earth.
- Maybe somewhere in this galaxy.
That's relatively easy.
Fortunately, some Ancient technology
still uses good old-fashioned buttons.
We've accessed the Stargate controls
and a library of gate addresses.
That's not all. Look at this.
Just like the iris on the Earth gate.
Using power, using power, using power.
At least we won't have uninvited guests.
Colonel, assemble a team. We need
safe harbour or another power source.
Lieutenant Ford, gather security teams...
- Major, I'd like you to go along.
- Yes, ma'am.
All right. Pick an address and start dialling.
Chevron one encoded.
Rodney...
Fine.
Ready MALP 4 for offworld recon.
The MALP reads full viability
and no immediate activity
around the Stargate, but it's pitch black.
We'll use the tried and true system
for identification of inbound gate travellers.
Let's move out!
Aaaargh!
Please! Don't hurt us!
Please! They're just playing!
- Everything OK here, Sheppard?
- Yes, sir. Just a couple of kids.
Halling.
- I don't know what that means.
- It's his name!
Oh. Halling. It's nice to meet you.
- Are you here to trade?
- Trade.
Yes. We're traders.
How many times have I told you
not to play in the forest after dark?
I'm just glad you're safe.
Teyla will wish to meet with you.
Come.
Parker, Smitty, you're on gate duty.
Dial Atlantis Base and tell the doctor
we contacted the indigenous people.
Sir, if you don't mind my asking,
I noticed you got a problem
with Major Sheppard.
My problem, Lieutenant, is with his record.
I don't like anybody who doesn't follow
the proper chain of command.
Yes, sir.
- What was that mask you had on?
- It helps you see in the dark. Check it out.
- Whoa!
- Let me see!
- Whoa! Can I have it?
- No.
- What's the mask you've got on?
- This? Wraith.
Wraith? What's that?
- You don't know?
- What world do you come from?
- Can we go there?
- I'm afraid not.
I come from a galaxy far, far away.
- It's Halling. I bring men from away.
- Enter.
These men wish to trade.
Ah! It's...
It's nice to meet you.
I am Teyla Emmagan,
daughter of Tagan.
Colonel Marshall Sumner.
Major Sheppard.
Lieutenant Ford.
- We have very few specific needs.
- We do not trade with strangers.
- Is that a fact?
- Then we have to get to know each other.
Me, um... I like Ferris wheels
and college football,
anything that goes over 200mph.
Sir, that won't mean anything to them.
Feel free to speak up.
I'm just trying to break the ice.
They can't help us.
I'd rather not waste time.
Each morning, before dawn,
our people drink a stout tea
to brace us for the coming day.
Will you join us?
I love a good cup of tea.
There's another thing
you know about me.
We're practically friends already.
We didn't see it until the sun came up.
Looks more promising than anything else
these folks have to offer.
Plenty of shelter, nice little valley.
Location, location, location.
- The City of the Ancestors is not safe.
- We can handle ourselves.
- The Wraith will come.
- Who are these Wraith?
We have never met anyone
who did not know.
You have now.
If the Wraith have never
touched your world, go back there.
We'd like to, but we can't.
See, here's the thing, ma'am.
We've got into a bit of a bind.
We may need
a safe place to stay for a while.
We have long believed that the Wraith
will come if we venture into the old city.
But it is a belief
we've not tested in some time.
Gentlemen.
Look, I don't care what they say.
That city is worth a look.
Not to mention the possibility there could
be ZPMs there that they don't know about.
What if the Wraith are the enemy
in the Ancient hologram?
All the more reason for us
to have a defensible position.
Stay here and find out what you can.
Ford, report in to Weir.
Tell her we'll have answers in a few hours.
Yes, sir.
Well, I guess it's just you and me.
And him.
Your leader looks through me
as if I were not there.
Do I?
No.
- You truly cannot return to your world?
- No.
Then there is something you should see.
How much further is this place?
Not far.
- Tell me some good news, Rodney.
- I can't do that.
The shield has
held back the ocean for centuries.
And would have kept going,
but our arrival changed that.
It's nothing more than a thin shell.
- We stopped exploring.
- The damage is done. The city's flooding.
- Even occupying this room drains power.
- We need to evacuate as soon as we can.
You're saying we have to
abandon the city?
The sooner we leave,
the longer that shield holds.
I used to play here as a child.
I believe it is where the survivors hid from
the Wraith during the last great attack.
Let me, uh...
We mastered fire long ago.
I guess so.
What's this?
I lost this years ago.
- How did you...?
- It was just lying right over there.
It was reflecting off the light.
Someone's been busy, huh?
The drawings in the caves are extensive.
Many must date back
thousands of years, or more.
Does this represent
the destruction of your city?
This drawing far pre-dates that.
So, what?
Someone knew it was gonna happen?
I believe it happens again and again.
The Wraith allow our kind
to grow in numbers.
And when that number reaches
a certain point,
they return to cull their human herd.
Sometimes a few hundred years will pass
before they awaken again.
We've visited many, many worlds.
I know of none untouched by the Wraith.
The last great holocaust
was five generations ago,
but still they return, in smaller numbers,
to remind us of their power.
It's a hell of a way to live.
We move our hunting camps around.
We try to teach our children
not to live in fear, but it is hard.
Some of us can sense the Wraith coming.
That gives us warning.
We should go. It will be dark soon.
Man, days are short here.
Major Sheppard, this is Colonel Sumner.
Colonel,
Major Sheppard is out of radio range.
Where the hell is he?
Teyla wanted him to see something.
Defensive positions!
Colonel, we have gate activity here.
Colonel, three bandits headed your way.
Take cover!
What is it?
The Wraith!
Just leave it!
Jinto, come! Jinto!
Fire on that target!
Teyla!
Colonel, they're on the ground!
They're all around us!
Teyla?
They're not really there.
Do not trust your eyes. The Wraith can
make you see things that are not there.
We must hurry.
This is Sheppard.
What you see on the ground is an illusion.
Concentrate your fire on the ships.
Fire at the ships! Fire at the ships!
- Bates, snap out of it!
- They're everywhere, sir!
Take that thing down!
Teyla... Teyla?
Sir, the colonel's been taken.
The gate's coming on again.
Two enemy ships approaching.
Let 'em go.
Look at the dialling device.
Burn those symbols into your mind.
Son of a...
Help! Help me!
I can't find my father.
- Here it comes.
- What am I looking for?
There. Another part
of the force field just failed.
I don't think we have much time.
How are we doing? If we can just
buy ourselves another day, maybe...
The city is sacrificing parts of itself
to maintain these areas,
but catastrophic failure is inevitable.
Not in my wildest dreams did I hope to find
the Lost City so completely untouched,
so pristine, and we have no choice
but to walk away from this?
- In order to save it.
- Save it for whom?
We don't have enough power
for a message.
- We'll just be missing, presumed lost.
- We'll find a power source in Pegasus.
We got no idea what's out there.
We can't wait. It is time to go - now.
Attention, all personnel. This is Weir.
Stand by for immediate evacuation!
Dial the gate!
We've got an incoming wormhole!
Lieutenant Ford's identification code!
Let 'em in!
Step in, folks. Move away from the puddle.
Major Sheppard!
Major Sheppard, who are all these people?
Survivors from the settlement.
We were attacked.
Sumner and some men were taken.
What's going on?
- We are in no position to help anyone.
- What's going on?
- We're about to abandon the city.
- We can't go back there.
The shield is about to fail
and the ocean will crash in on us.
Do you have a better place?
- Jinto, have you another address?
- Yes, many.
He's just a boy.
- I am Jinto.
- She's pleased to meet you.
The shield is collapsing!
I'm dialling an address!
- No! Wait!
- She's right.
We're moving!
We're on the surface!
I was hoping for another day.
It looks like we just got
a whole lot more than that.
Let's not waste it.
People, listen up. No one sits down
until they clear two pieces of equipment.
Now, let's go.
The last Zero Point Module is depleted,
but limited power has returned
now we're not holding back an ocean.
Life-support systems are working,
but the atmosphere is breathable,
notwithstanding the inevitable allergens.
Can our generator supply enough power
for defensive purposes?
- Not even close.
- Without a shield, we're target practice.
I'm acutely aware of that, Major.
When can you tell me where the Wraith
took Colonel Sumner?
With the six symbols we got,
there are hundreds of permutations.
720.
Yes. I knew that, of course.
I'm just surprised you do.
Take away the coordinates
you can't lock on and that's it.
When you find it, send a MALP.
Major? A word.
Oh...
Let me guess. You're not gonna
let me rescue my people.
You don't even know if they're alive.
You don't leave people with the enemy.
The fact that we're having
this conversation in private lets me know
that you know damn well it's wrong
and will undermine your leadership.
- So as ranking military officer...
- All right, shut up and listen to me.
Come on.
What do we know about the Wraith?
One thing we do know is that they are
the enemy that defeated the Ancients.
When we first began to use the Stargate
on Earth, we got in serious trouble. Why?
- I don't need a history lesson.
- They didn't consider the ramifications.
They took our people! How should I react?
And we're defenceless!
You said so yourself.
How do you know some half-assed rescue
mission won't bring them right back here?
Maybe it will.
But it's the right thing to do.
Why? Because it is!
- John...
- Let's turn tail and pack up. They'll come.
- You don't know that.
- Our people are in enemy hands, Doctor.
It is just a matter of time before
the Wraith figure out this is our base.
I just need more information.
- Maybe we could negotiate a peaceful...
- Peaceful? Are you kidding?!
We weren't there for more than a few
hours before they showed up.
Is it possible they came because of you?
And that one of these people
tipped them off?
- It's possible.
- That is the kind of snap decision I mean!
They're not all bad people.
If we're gonna stick around here,
we need friends.
OK. I see your point.
Now you see mine.
I will not authorise a rescue mission
unless I am sure there is at least
a remote chance of success.
I'm not sending more good people,
including you, to their deaths.
OK.
- Are you all right?
- Where are we?
Any idea what to expect?
No.
Your friend said the Wraith would come
if we went down into the ruins.
- You should have heeded his warning.
- How do I know he didn't tell them?
Someone comes.
I'm Colonel Marshall Sum...
No! Please!
- Take me in his place!
- No! Take me!
We're the ones you're after, right?
I'm their leader.
They have no need to explain themselves.
Yeah, I got that.
- We're receiving visual telemetry.
- I can't see anything.
No atmospheric readings at all.
- Hey, what was that?
- Rotate the camera.
- Well, there goes that MALP.
- It's in space!
On the far side of the galaxy.
- You're sure this is the right address?
- It's the only one we could get a lock on.
Very well. Shut it down.
I'm sorry.
Come with me, Major.
- Think you can fly it?
- What do you say we find out?
Dr Beckett, what was it
you wanted me to see?
These cells have none of the normal
human-inhibiting proteins whatsoever.
That gives them
an incredible ability to regenerate.
What about the movement
Major Sheppard saw?
As far as independent behaviour,
I'd say it was from a residual command
language in the severed nerve endings.
All right. Anything else?
The being this arm belonged to,
if I was a betting man, I'd say it was old.
- Very, very old.
- How old?
As long as the cells
are properly nourished,
I don't see a life form like this ever dying
of natural ageing the way we do.
And they'd be bloody hard to kill.
I don't like the sound of that.
I don't blame you.
- What is that noise?
- I don't... He was right here!
Major!
You wanted a tactical advantage.
All right. So you can fly that thing.
It doesn't mean you can pull off a rescue.
Doctor... this is why you brought me here.
- Ready?
- I have no idea.
This technology is so far beyond us,
we haven't a clue what we're dealing with.
For all we know, we could... Yeah. Ready.
All right, boys. Get ready to go.
Gateship One, ready to go.
Gateship One?!
A little puddle jumper like this?
It's a ship that goes through the gate.
Gateship One.
- That's wrong.
- Dr McKay thought it was cool.
Oh, OK. Well, it's official.
You don't get to name anything...
ever.
Flight, this is... Puddle Jumper.
We're go to launch.
I thought we were going with Gateship.
- Negative, Flight.
- Stand by.
It's a ship that goes through the gate. Fine.
Puddle Jumper, you are clear for launch.
Dial it up, Lieutenant.
Be safe.
Wow!
This is cool.
- Looks like you got the hang of it.
- I tell you what.
A lot of fighter pilots
would kill to fly this thing.
It's like it reads your mind.
- Did you do that?
- I was just wondering where we go now.
I'll take that as a "yes".
- How do we find them once we land?
- I've been thinking about that, too.
Now I'm thinking
about a nice turkey sandwich.
Worth a try.
Lock and load.
All right. Teams of two.
Learn what you can
and lay down defences as you see fit.
I want to be able to light this place up.
Two clicks, you're clear to talk.
Do not engage the enemy!
You're with me.
You must feel hunger by now.
I thought getting in would be the hard part.
That's the first one we've seen.
The moving dot should be him.
Go over there.
Yeah, that's you.
So, we got ourselves a lifesigns detector.
We can name it later.
- Major?
- Shh!
- Are you all right?
- How did you find us?
- Is my son alive?
- He's well and waiting for you.
- Where's Colonel Sumner?
- Taken by the Wraith.
- We don't know where.
- How about when?
- Not long.
- I knew something had to go wrong.
This is Stackhouse. Go ahead, sir.
How about a diversion in a little bit?
Make some noise.
Yes, sir.
Rig up enough C4 to blow a hole
and get these people out.
I can find the colonel with this.
There aren't many Wraith around.
I should be able to do this. If I'm not back
in 20 minutes, blow the cells and get out.
- You're the only one who can fly us out.
- And I'll fly us all out of here.
- I'm saying I should be the one to go, sir.
- 20 minutes. I'll find him.
What do you call yourself?
Colonel Marshall Sumner,
United States Marine Corps.
So little fear.
Is it valour?
Or ignorance?
We travel through the Stargate
as peaceful explorers.
You must eat,
yet you resist your hunger. Why?
- Why did you take my people prisoner?
- You trespassed on our feeding ground.
Feeding ground?
All living things must eat.
In this I am sure we are similar.
You feel hunger even now.
I can sense it.
Yet you resist.
- Why?
- Why do you care?
Hunger...
is distasteful.
It looks to me
like the food didn't agree with him.
There we are quite dissimilar,
Colonel Sumner.
We don't require...
our food to agree with us.
What do you call your world?
Earth.
It is not among our stars.
- No.
- Tell me of Earth.
How many more are there of your kind?
Thousands?
Millions?
More?
Our feeding ground
has not been so rich in 10,000 years.
Your will is strong.
This one...
begged for its life.
Is that the kind of treatment I can expect
for myself and my people?
As I have said,
all living things must eat.
Then we're done talking.
I think not.
Kneel.
Aaah!
I have not tasted such strength...
in so long.
Go to hell!
Earth first!
How many years must I take from you
before you tell us what I wish to know?
Or shall I take them all?
Where is this new feeding ground?
I won't!
Bring him!
How's the hand feeling?
Much better.
I'm sorry to hear that.
How did this come to you?
I don't remember!
Light it up!
Cover!
That has to kill you.
- How did you find me?
- Tread marks. Standard issue. Let's go.
You don't know what you have done.
We are merely
the caretakers for those that sleep.
When I die, the others will awaken.
All of them.
What's she talking about?
How many are left?
Sir, we need to leave.
- Bates, we're on the go.
- So are we. Colonel Sumner?.
Negative!
Dr Weir?
We're getting reports in from
all over the city. Pretty interesting stuff.
We've only provided power to certain
sections, but the things coming up are...
I should never have let them go.
For what it's worth,
you made the right decision.
Give them time.
Major, the jumper is secure for
the moment, but we have a big problem.
Lieutenant, take our six.
I'll take them back to the jumper.
Be right behind you.
- There's nothing there!
- I saw something.
Only what the Wraith wish you to see.
Firing your weapon reveals our position!
Get in!
- Thank you, sir.
- Try not to make a habit of it.
We have incoming!
OK. Now what am I thinking?
- Everybody OK back there?
- We are well enough.
I hope that was the hard part.
Crap!
I don't think
we've gotten to the hard part yet.
What can we do?
- We're safe if they can't see us.
- They don't have to.
There's only one way for us to go.
The minute we activate the Stargate,
they can shoot blind and blow us away.
- Then how can we get through?
- Draw them away and double back.
Be prepared to dial the gate on my mark.
Do you see anything
like a weapons console over there?
- Try and go invisible again.
- It must be damaged. Dial the gate.
Offworld activation!
Raise the shield!
- Get ready to punch in your code.
- What's the range on these things?
Do we have an identification code?
Nothing yet.
Enter your code! Hang on.
- I'm reading Lieutenant Ford's IDC.
- Let 'em in!
A few more seconds!
- We're going too fast!
- I know.
Reactivate the shield!
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to Atlantis.
Please remain seated until the Puddle
Jumper comes to a full and complete stop.
- I guess this is home now.
- I guess so.
I'm thinking of a little place
with an ocean view. Out of the way.
Major, Lieutenant.
I thought the occasion
merited opening this.
Compliments of General O'Neill.
Cheers.
- You did good, John.
- I don't know about that.
Hey, there was no way
you could have saved Colonel Sumner.
I have to live with it.
I'm beginning to think you're right.
I have made things much worse.
I haven't made us many more friends.
No?
Look around you.
I agree, Major Sheppard.
You have earned both my friendship
and that of my people.
With our help,
you will make many more friends.
How come I never make friends like that?
You need to get out more.
We're in another galaxy.
How much more out can you get?
Is there lemon in this?
One more thing, Major.
There's something I'd like you to sleep on.
- I have thoughts...
- About what?
Who the members of your team might be.
- My team?
- You are the ranking military officer now.
Or do you need to be reminded of that?
We need to get back out there,
do what we came to do.
You realise that could get us
into all sorts of trouble?
Right?
Subtitles: SDI Media Group
ENHOH