I've never seen so much nothing.
I've never walked so far to see it.
How was I to know the only structures
would be around the Stargate?
There's the gate. Dial it up.
The energy readings here
are the same as they were a mile away.
I think we should stay for a while.
- I thought you hated these suits.
- I do, but the readings are amazing.
It's all around us.
- Yet you cannot explain it.
- Not yet.
- You can't figure out a way we can use it?
Let's call it a mission.
There's such a thing as pure science.
Not everything has to be useful.
You said the energy readings indicated
the presence of a civilisation.
There are no buildings,
no people, no nothing. Just fog.
It's not technically fog. There's
no water vapour in the atmosphere.
And I don't think we need to wear
the Hazmat gear.
Now you tell me.
Dial the gate.
- Let's move out.
- Wait. Hold on.
- You wanted useful?
- What are you talking about?
When the wormhole connected
there was a wild fluctuation.
It looks like the gate is actually
drawing power from the atmosphere.
- So?
- So this field goes on for miles.
It may envelop the planet.
It's a lot of energy.
- How much is a lot?
- In terms of joules or ergs?
- In terms of lots.
- Well, lots and lots.
Enough to open a wormhole
back to Earth.
I thought only the Atlantis gate
could dial Earth.
Yes. It has an additional control crystal
allowing an eighth chevron to lock.
- Probably a security measure.
- It doesn't matter.
With the crystal,
I can make the other gate work.
You're suggesting we remove it
from our DHD and bring it to M5S-224?
- Yes.
- Isn't that risky?
- I'll be fine.
- She means in terms of breaking our gate.
The control crystal is useless
without enough power.
You said you didn't know
where the energy comes from.
I believe it is being generated
in the atmosphere.
- The fog?
- Yes.
- You said it wasn't fog.
- Whatever it is.
- How do you know?
- I don't.
But the fog is the only thing around
and the energy readings were constant.
OK, even if you can pull this off,
we have to assume the Earth gate
lacks a power source
capable of establishing
a wormhole to Pegasus.
Whoever went would be taking the risk
of it being a one-way trip.
- Someone will volunteer.
- You?
I would only go if I knew there was
a good chance I could come back.
We can send a message
to Stargate Command that we're OK.
We've gathered a lot of intel.
We should send it.
If we can. Even if it's over a radio.
All right. That's it.
How easy is it to put that
in the other DHD?
The Atlantis's DHD is unique.
There isn't an empty slot waiting.
- Meaning?
- It may require some disassembly.
- You wanna take the DHD apart?
- I'll put it back together.
Don't you risk
disabling the other Stargate?
Only if I screw up,
which is extremely unlikely.
- 840 years.
- What?
How long it will take us
to come get you by puddle jumper.
But you would do that, right?
- Of course.
- It won't be necessary.
- However, I may require some assistance.
- Major?
- Lieutenant?
- Yes, sir.
- Atlantis, this is McKay.
- Go ahead.
- We're ready to begin work on the DHD.
- You're sure about this?
Positive. We'll deliver good news.
- Good luck.
- Back in time for supper.
Right.
Let's get started.
Come in.
Hi. Do you have a moment?
Yeah, sure.
War And Peace.
That's some heavy reading.
Back on Earth
when I was getting ready for this mission,
I realised I might be here for a while,
so I figured, "Why not bring along a book
that takes a while to read?"
- Page 17?
- I'm right on schedule.
Hm. It's kind of what I wanted
to talk to you about.
Home. Going home.
- Oh.
- McKay's right.
If this works and we establish
a wormhole back to Earth...
If this conversation is going where I think,
you can put your mind at rest.
I'm not going anywhere.
I haven't read my book.
Look, all I'm saying is that
you are the person who is best qualified
to brief General Hammond and the others
about the Wraith threat.
Well, maybe so,
but I think I'm needed here.
- Good.
- But if you wanna go, I understand.
- Are you saying I'm not needed here?
- I said I'd understand.
Well, thank you, but I made a commitment.
Of course, in all fairness, life-sucking
aliens weren't part of the brochure.
- Regardless, I'm staying.
- Good.
Wouldn't be the same without you.
- Would you want to go back?
- It doesn't matter what I want.
- Why not?
- Atlantis can't afford to lose me.
I'm their expert in gate theory, wormhole
physics and a myriad of other sciences.
I'd love to see my grandma.
She thinks I'm in Afghanistan.
Whoever goes should command
the respect of the SGC,
have the patience and knowledge
to bring them up to speed
and find a way to bring the cavalry back.
You're saying
you're invaluable everywhere.
It would create a void if I went,
but you'll know that
I'll be spearheading the effort to return
with reinforcements, fresh supplies
and Big Macs for all.
- I feel better already.
- Yeah. Good.
Good.
Major Sheppard,
have we heard back from Dr McKay?
- Not yet.
- Word of the discovery has spread.
- I've noticed.
- It is to be expected,
faced with the prospect of being reunited
with loved ones, returning home.
Yeah, I'd love to go back.
You would consider leaving Atlantis?
If I knew I could gate back here,
I'd go in a heartbeat.
- It would be good to see your world.
- You could help with the briefing.
- I would like that.
- You know about the Pegasus galaxy.
Then there's those cool Earth things -
football, Ferris wheels.
Oh. Do you remember
the last of the popcorn we ate?
- We could get more.
- If we knew we could return.
Unscheduled activation.
It's a radio transmission
from Dr McKay.
- Rodney?
- Elizabeth. I'm done.
- The component's installed in the DHD...
- Well done.
- What about the energy readings?
- Same as before.
The gate's drawing power
from the atmosphere.
- OK, you stay put. We're on our way.
- Right.
So, are we ready?
What's there to be ready for?
It's a big moment and we haven't
been in contact for some time...
- Hooray.
- Go ahead.
Please work.
Stargate Command, this is Dr Elizabeth
Weir of the Atlantis expedition.
Do you read?
I repeat, this is Dr Weir. Come in, please.
This is Sergeant Harriman
of Stargate Command.
Whoever you are,
this better not be a joke.
No joke, Sergeant. I'm sending
my personal IDC for confirmation.
Sorry. We're just a little surprised
to be hearing from you.
- Understandable.
- The iris is open. Clear to come through.
Thanks, but we're not ready
to risk a one-way trip.
Doctor, things have changed
around here.
The Asgard are fitting Prometheus with
engines that can reach other galaxies.
We were manning a mission
to find out what happened to you.
Is he serious?
- Are you serious?
- Yes, ma'am.
Come through now and you could be
back in Pegasus inside of a month.
Well... who's going?
Welcome back to Earth.
While the Pegasus galaxy
does hold many dangers,
I feel its potential rewards
justify the risk
of maintaining a continued presence
on the Atlantis base.
Your preliminary report has given
the Pentagon cause for concern.
If the Wraith are as powerful as you say,
they are an enemy
even more dangerous than the Goa'uld.
Some say it would be prudent to cut our
losses and abandon the Pegasus galaxy.
- You can't...
- This is a race that defeated the Ancients.
Over the years, Stargate Command
has encountered a number of threats
that could well have destroyed
this world.
That never stopped you from continuing
to send teams through the gate.
By the time SG-1 had returned from their
first mission, the damage had been done.
We'd already alerted the Goa'uld
to our presence.
In the case of the Wraith, however,
we have a choice.
So we're just going to turn tail and run?
The Pentagon would prefer to call it
a strategic withdrawal.
How can we be sure
they won't come after us?
They feed on human life forms.
They know there's a smorgasbord here.
I don't think we have a choice.
We need to explore the opportunities for
technological advancement in Pegasus.
Not to mention our responsibility
to the other humans who live there.
- Responsibility?
- We did wake up the Wraith.
While that would have happened
eventually without our interference,
our access to Ancient technology puts us
in a unique position to help those people.
We can't just walk away.
Rest assured your recommendation
will be considered at the highest level.
General, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Major Sheppard.
I'm surprised the briefing went so quickly.
- You were very thorough, Major.
- Thank you, sir.
I thought you'd be enjoying
some well-deserved R & R.
I was going to arrange
some transportation.
Consider it done. Anywhere you like.
That's very generous.
You've done your country a great service.
You deserve it.
Thank you, sir.
Well, how's our patient doing?
We're all done, Major. She's free to go.
I was afraid you had abandoned me.
Just setting up our ride.
So, where are we going?
We should start
by getting you a new outfit.
Hello, Simon.
My God. When did you...
I missed you.
You have no new messages.
Huh. Must have been
a power failure or something.
Anyways...
There is nothing wrong
with your television set.
Do not attempt to adjust the picture.
We are controlling the transmission.
We will bring up the volume or whisper.
- Hi.
- Thank you, Major.
- You're welcome.
I have traded in many market-places
on many worlds...
- Countries. Countries.
- Yes, of course. Countries.
But here there are so many
different items to choose from.
You seemed like you were having fun.
Hours and hours of fun.
But you have picked out a nice outfit.
Thank you.
I wonder... if we had never
suffered the Wraith,
would my people have created
a civilisation such as this?
I'm starting to wonder
about a few things myself.
- What?
- Nothing feels wrong to you?
I don't mean one thing,
I mean... everything.
I do not understand.
Excuse me, could you take us
to the Green Moss Park area?
- Sure thing.
- Thank you.
I think I'll have a better idea
of what's bothering me once we get there.
Hey, Sedge! Did you miss me?
Did you miss me?
More than you can imagine.
I don't know how many times
I watched that damn tape you left me.
- I wanted to tell you in person.
- No, you didn't.
- You were afraid I'd talk you out of it.
- I was afraid you'd try.
When you said you couldn't say where
you were going, my first guess was Korea.
My second guess was Israel.
To be honest,
the Pegasus galaxy didn't make my list.
I am sorry.
I know.
I imagine my security clearance
doesn't let you tell me what you did.
- No.
- Or when you'll be leaving again?
No.
At the very least
you could promise me that...
..you'll take this with you.
Simon.
It's beautiful.
Looks nice.
Thank you.
Is something wrong?
No, I'm sorry. Just when you kissed me...
What are you talking about, Elizabeth?
Hello.
General. What...
Yes, I understand. Thank you.
Hang on.
Oh, hey. I was in the middle of a
power nap and I'm not wearing any pants.
I didn't think you knew where I lived.
- Air force.
- Right.
Look, I can't really...
I have a date with a girl in 302.
She's been taking care of the cat
while I was away.
- Apparently she... misses me.
- Rodney.
I know, trying to pawn my cat off
on a neighbour and I end up with...
- What?
- I got a call from General Hammond.
There was an accident on the Prometheus.
We can't go back to Atlantis.
I was just gonna come home, unwind,
then start work on a solution.
An hour ago it hit me,
like Archimedes in the bath.
Except I wasn't in the bath.
I was on the couch watching...
- Dr McKay.
- Forget Prometheus.
I have figured out how to establish
a wormhole connection back to Pegasus.
- I'm gonna need the ZPM.
- It's been depleted.
No. Last time it had to establish and
maintain a wormhole back to Atlantis.
This time it just needs enough energy
to establish a brief connection.
My calculation is approximately
3.5 microseconds.
That hardly seems enough...
When we set foot on M5S-224
before the wormhole shut down,
I picked up energy fluctuations.
I assumed it was an effect
of the gate's residual energy signature.
But that can't account for the variances.
There's one explanation. The gate
must have been energised on our arrival.
It doesn't just drop power on outgoing
wormholes, but incoming ones.
We just have to make a connection.
3.5 microseconds.
The minimum amount of time
to confirm a lock before the gate kicks in.
You'll forgive me, Doctor.
This all seems a little far-fetched.
Think of it like calling someone
who will accept the charges.
- All you have to do is dial.
- I'm sorry, Doctor.
You won't lose anything by letting me try.
I just want to run a couple of tests.
All right. I'll have the ZPM
delivered to the lab.
Thank you.
Dr Weir, I wasn't expecting to see you.
I've been thinking about what happened.
Thank you.
I know it's a setback,
but I don't think we should give up yet.
- If we get the Prometheus repaired...
- She was severely damaged.
We lost 20 crew members.
She won't be flying again any time soon.
So we ask the Asgard
for one of their ships.
I'm sure that when the Asgard
are in a position to help, they will.
General, I only came to Earth because
I was assured I'd be able to get back.
I am not about to abandon
my expedition team.
I'll see what I can do,
but I'm not making any promises.
You gotta talk to somebody about this
for me.
Sorry. If those are the orders you received,
it's out of my hands.
I can't abide sloppy work.
Your people
must double-check their results.
- Dr McKay.
- Yes, Lieutenant.
- I'm being transferred.
- Congratulations.
I was with my parents and a sergeant
shows up with new orders for me.
They wanna ship me back to Antarctica.
Do you know something that I don't?
Last time I checked,
the Prometheus was damaged
and our only ZPM
couldn't even run a car stereo.
- I thought you'd find another way.
- There is no other way.
You're gonna have to deal with it.
Thank you.
Would it be so bad if you had to stay?
I'm sorry, Simon.
I know none of this is fair to you.
It is tough to compete with
the greatest adventure in human history.
I don't blame you for going.
Thank you.
But I still feel guilty.
And now I feel guilty about being back.
Because of the people you left behind?
No. I should have stayed at Atlantis.
Major Sheppard should have been
the one to go.
Oh, yeah.
Just like I left it.
So much space for just one person.
Well, a guy's gotta have a lot of space.
I bet there's still...
Perfect.
- Nice and cold.
- And this is...
It's called beer.
Is all this... for recreation?
Yeah. I got pretty much
everything you can imagine, don't I?
What is it?
I was just thinking again...
..about Dr Weir
and everyone else on Atlantis.
Of course. I am sure she is fine.
As I am sure they are all fine.
Yeah. I'm sure.
- You have those test results for me yet?
- We need more time.
What are you talking about?
Let's see what you got.
Wait a minute.
What is this, some kind of a joke?
- I told you we need more time.
- These don't make any sense.
We don't think the ZPM
can open the wormhole.
You wouldn't know that from this.
It's complete gibberish.
Get outta here. I'll do it.
Go.
You've got to be kidding me.
Thank you for coming in again.
- Was there a response to my request?
- We won't need help from the Asgard.
It turns out Dr McKay has discovered
how to open a wormhole back to Pegasus.
He has? Why wasn't I informed?
Doctor, the Atlantis mission
has been reassessed.
What does that mean?
In light of your intelligence
concerning the Wraith,
it's been decided that the Atlantis presence
should be military.
- Our allies have agreed to this?
- They did.
As soon as Dr McKay
can establish a wormhole,
we intend to send reinforcements
along with a new commanding officer.
I'm sorry, Doctor,
but you've been relieved of your duties.
OK, wait. I am not saying there shouldn't
be an increased military presence,
but the mission must remain the same,
and if Major Sheppard were here...
We've spoken to Major Sheppard.
He dialled in to check on your progress.
We informed him of the situation
and he agrees with us.
He wouldn't do that, General.
I know John Sheppard.
Apparently you don't know him
as well as you thought.
He stated categorically it's the only way
to ensure the security of the project.
- Let's get outta here.
- Why?
You wanna see Earth? It's out there.
I thought you'd want to spend time
in your home. Visit with friends.
There is an idea.
Hey!
Mitch. Dex.
You didn't think you could
pass through town without seeing us?
You gonna invite us in or what?
Yeah, sure. What the hell.
All right! Hi, I'm Dex.
- What is this?
- Is there a problem?
- Elizabeth.
- Rodney, I need to talk to you.
- Can it wait?
- No. Something is very wrong here.
I ran a diagnostic on the ZPM.
These are the results I keep getting back.
- I'm not a scientist.
- Neither's anyone else here.
The laws of physics
have flown out the window.
- Problem with your equipment?
- I checked. It's fine.
If your solution doesn't work,
it's not your fault.
We'll have to accept the fact
that we can't go back.
What?
Our boys were pinned down. Hotshot here
takes his chopper right over this bridge.
- We're supposed to follow him.
- I'm not flying over enemy tanks.
- Over what?
- Tanks.
- You're welcome.
- Ha-ha!
I still love that, man!
Yeah, that was... priceless.
But we got that Special Ops team
out of there, didn't we, Shep?
- Yes, we did.
- That was some flying, Shep.
- Look who's in the pizza business.
- No, sir. I caught the guy on the way up.
I was thinking about you. Come in.
Looks like we are having a party.
- Yes.
- I got pizza.
All right!
- I've been relieved of my command.
- Oh. I'm sorry.
They're gonna militarise Atlantis.
Interesting. It was bound
to happen sooner or later.
So, you're OK with this?
How did you expect them to react
about the Wraith?
I thought I'd be kept in the loop.
Why don't you go home,
spend some time with Simon?
- Simon?
- He's important to you, isn't he?
Yes. I just don't remember
ever telling you that.
Well, how else would I have known?
We didn't know what to think.
This guy was supposedly one of
the most ruthless warlords in Afghanistan
and he sits at our table.
- Sir, you gotta hear this.
- I was there.
Yeah, you remember. Turns out
he wants to practise his English on us.
- Shep spent half the night talking to him.
- Yeah, that was funny.
He wouldn't even let you
go to the bathroom.
Then two days later
you guys were killed outside Kabul.
These results say this reality
isn't governed by any natural laws.
It's like looking at a cell culture
and seeing a thousand dancing hamsters.
- Rodney, you need to calm down.
- No, I need to get agitated.
I'm realising all of this is a lie.
This and this and this!
- What are you saying?
- Your chopper took an RPG.
There was barely enough left
to bring back for a funeral.
- What?
- You guys have been dead for years.
Don't get me wrong,
it's really nice seeing you.
- You too, Miss Watson.
- Sir...
She was my sixth-grade teacher.
I don't remember your name
but I remember you wouldn't date me.
Shep, I think you should see a doctor.
- Oh, really?
- You're acting pretty strange.
I'm acting strange, huh?
Major!
Now you see what I mean?
The McKay I know would never accept
the militarisation of Atlantis without a fight.
I don't think Major Sheppard would
agree to it without speaking to me.
You shouldn't take it personally.
Think of it like a blessing.
You have a life.
You can get back to it now.
No. I'm not buying this any more.
Who are you really?
Who am I? What do you mean?
- You shot me!
- You're already dead!
Sir, give me...
I'm beginning to have my doubts
about you. I wouldn't put them to a test.
Now, somebody explain to me
what the hell is going on here.
Dr Weir.
OK, no more lies. What is this?
What's happening to me?
There's no point in deluding you
any longer.
Now you know.
Where's Rodney?
The real Dr McKay and his team
reside in their own illusory worlds.
I wanna see them. Please.
What happened?
I drew you together
from your fractured realities.
- I'm talking about the beer I had.
- Sheppard discovered the truth first.
- He did?
- Home was a research base in Antarctica.
Although I did dream
about a bachelor pad like that.
He seemed uniquely capable
of manipulating his own fabricated reality.
The scenarios I could have cooked up!
The realities you experienced
were fabrications of your own minds.
Since you had no memories of Earth,
you shared in Major Sheppard's illusion.
I thought that was you.
It's unfortunate
you all became aware so quickly.
However, you may now create
a fabricated reality of your own choosing
for the remainder of your lives.
- What?
- That's not gonna work for us.
I'm afraid
the matter's beyond your control.
- Well, we'll find a way to fight you.
- That would be quite impossible, Major.
Even now you are simply experiencing
a shared fabrication.
It's best if you try
to make a life for yourselves.
This isn't life.
What do you want us to do, just pretend?
I'm sorry, but that's all I can offer you.
Wait.
- Why would you do this?
- To protect ourselves.
From us?
We did not intend to harm anyone.
Unlike you,
we exist in a non-corporeal form
susceptible to the destructive effects
of the Stargate on our home world.
What destructive effects?
The energy readings we had
were life signs. You were in the mist.
We are the mist. Every time
the gate is activated, lives are lost.
Over time, explorers have come and gone,
completely unaware of our existence.
Sacrifices are made to ensure our secrecy.
When you came back,
we grew concerned.
To learn your intentions,
we had no choice but to enter your minds.
When we discovered what you'd do, we
were forced to take preventive measures.
You said you'd let others come and go.
Why not allow us to do the same?
Your desire to return to your home world
was too strong.
The energy required to gate to another
galaxy would have killed millions of us.
So when we dialled the gate...
You never dialled the gate.
You just imagined you did.
You are unconscious even now
on the planet's surface.
So none of this is real?
The cute brunette. Of course.
How do you go from "You're a pig
but I like your cat" to "I missed you"?
We lacked a sophisticated understanding
of your world.
As a result, the illusions we created
from your thoughts were ultimately flawed.
The dead people were... a dead giveaway.
Dead people? What were you doing?
- If you had just told us...
- Wait. I just realised something.
Our unconscious bodies
are still on the planet?
- Yes.
- So we need food, we need water, food.
We won't live long in this state.
Make the most of the time you have left.
You're killing us to save yourselves.
In order to save millions of our kind.
I believe you would do the same.
If we do not go back,
our friends will come looking for us.
- Others of your kind?
- They'll show up.
What you gonna do, kill them too?
- More will come.
- They'll work out how to access the gate.
Then millions of your kind will die.
We don't leave people behind,
and if you were really General Hammond,
you'd know that.
But if you allow us to leave here,
we promise we will never return, ever.
You will not have to fear us ever again.
I give you my word.
How can you make such a promise
when you so desire to return home?
Sure, we'd like to go home.
We're not willing to kill millions
of your kind to do it.
You've been in our heads.
You're in our heads right now.
You should know we mean that.
I understand.
I don't mean to sound negative
because that would be so not me,
but how do we know this isn't
a double fake-out? How do we know...
This is your reality.
You have my word.
- I'm starving. He's gotta be right.
- I wonder how long we've been out.
I need to get the control crystal
out of the DHD. Shouldn't take long.
I'll give you a hand.
Thank you for trusting us.
Rodney, be careful with that.
I wanna make sure we can get back home.
- You mean Atlantis.
- I think that's what she meant.
She could have meant we pull
a double fake-out and dial Earth.
Forget the double fake-out and get
the damn crystal. I'll do the dial-out.
Subtitles: Lecavalier
For the BST